[Music]
hello everyone and welcome back to my
channel
it has been a hot minute since I've just
sat down turn the camera on and talk to
you guys one on one but today's video is
going to be a very special video that
I've been wanting to make for quite some
time now so in today's video I want to
talk about my journey growing up as
korean-american I felt very inspired by
watching Jenn's video Whaley's video
Amy's video it's really cool to hear
their story and how they overcame
certain obstacles in their life hearing
about their struggles I feel like I can
relate to them so much because a lot of
our stories are very parallel but I
still felt like even though there are
similarities it's important to share my
story and I and I would love to kind of
just open up to you guys about some
personal things in my life and just
going up Korean American so if you're
interested on hearing my journey then
keep on watching okay I just feel like I
need to relax
I'm just so uptight right now and I
think it's because I haven't just sat
here and talked to the camera in a while
and it just feels a little overwhelming
but it's okay I just want good energy
and I just want this would be super
casual and I really want to open up to
you guys about just my childhood so I
guess we should begin with question
number one
I am korean-american born and raised in
Virginia I am first generation my
parents moved to America when they were
young I'm not sure exactly how old they
were but they moved to America and then
had me and my sister Robin Robin is two
years older than me so we are pretty
close in age so I grew up in a small
town called Prince George and I spent
most of my childhood there just to give
you a little background about where I'm
from it was predominantly black or white
people and there were not a lot of
Asians at all I probably went to school
six or seven Asians and that's literally
me not even exaggerating it was a small
town so they're just yeah there wasn't a
lot of Asians so the first time I felt
like I was different or that I was a
minority was probably in middle school I
remember being called pancake face all
the time and I don't even remember the
very first time that I've heard it
because I've heard it so many times it's
almost like a blur
at first I never understood what they
were talking about because my face just
I don't know I didn't really get what it
meant I knew that I look different but I
wasn't sure what they were saying but
then I finally caught on and what they
were trying to say is that I have a very
flat profile so if you catch me at my
side angle you can see that my forehead
is quite pushed in I don't have like a
prominent forehead and like my eyes
don't come out everything is just a
little bit more on the flatter side even
the back of my head which you obviously
can't see but you can feel it it's very
flat at the top it doesn't feel like mmm
how do I explain this it just doesn't
feel like it comes out like a normal
head would but yeah I know that some
Asians have this not all Asians but a
lot of Asians have more of a flatter
profile and that's what I had it was
very different on my school for kids to
see because like I mentioned there were
only a few Asian so they were just used
to seeing what they were used to seeing
I feel like if no one ever mentioned it
I would have never even thought about it
but getting that drilled in my head as a
kid that I have a really flat face I
think that it became such a huge
insecurity of mine as I got older that
was probably just one of the names that
people called me I mean a lot of kids
would joke about my eyes and my eye
shape one being that they're small so I
would get called eyes and
secondly because I have
true monolids I have no lid as a crease
it's just one slab of skin so I would
get made fun of about that another story
which was very similar to Whaley and
Jen's was that I also brought Korean
food for lunch I think this was like
third grade and I remember my mom packed
me like rice with kimchi and some other
punch ends I it's kind of a blur so I
don't remember exactly but there for
sure was kimchi in there and I remember
opening my lunch at school and
immediately when my friend smelled
kimchi
they were so disgusted and they were
just making fun of me and saying that it
smells so bad like farts or they were
just going in about my kimchi I also
felt very humiliated and embarrassed and
I was a kid that's just something you
don't want to be teased about like the
food you eat I didn't finish my lunch
and I remember telling my mom I do not
want to bring Korean food to school ever
again I remember seeing the food that my
friend's parents would pack and it was
just you know traditional like cheese
and ham sandwiches and like a fruit
roll-up for dessert and I would just be
so envious of their lunch and thinking
to myself like why can't my parents make
this like why do their parents pack them
such great meals and I get packed like
this you know I wanted so badly to
eat American food and just be normal
I was definitely not proud of my
heritage through my childhood even high
school years that wasn't something that
I was able to feel until I moved to LA
during middle school junior high and
high school I hated the fact that I was
Korean because I was a minority and I
think that there was a lack of culture
in my hometown it was really hard to
deal with like I mentioned earlier there
was either the white kids or the black
kids and it wasn't like they were
segregated but I found that they really
kind of stuck to their own
that's just how it was in my school not
that I agree with it or anything but it
was like if you were white you kind of
hung out with the white kids and if you
were black you hung out with the black
kids and for me as a minority I didn't
know where I belonged and it was a very
confusing time but I found that I was
kicking it with the black kids more and
I hope you guys don't get offended by
that I don't mean anything negative when
I see black or white I'm just trying to
explain what it was at my school so with
that being said I had a lot of black
friends and it was great like I I
connected with them and I felt like I
started to make a lot of friendships
during like junior high and then high
school but I think I definitely got lost
in just knowing who I was as a person
and owning my culture I got into a lot
of trouble as a kid and I was not the
traditional Korean student that my
parents wanted me to be and because of
that it sparked a lot of resentment and
arguments with my parents my parents are
super traditional they wanted the good
grades they wanted school first no
social life they wanted me to have Asian
friends and it's like they knew that
there weren't that many at my school and
it's quite impossible to force yourself
to make a connection with them maybe six
or seven Asian kids at your school and
they're all in different grades at that
and I'm just I wasn't trying to force
anything and just be friends with who I
naturally connect with so with my
parents being super traditional and my
sister and I being very rebellious it
caused a lot of tension in the house
throughout my childhood I mean we didn't
see eye to eye with them on anything and
that really caused us to lie to my
parents every single day of my junior
high and high school life so being
rebellious I would
lie to my parents and say yeah I'm
getting tutored after school and I'd be
at a basketball game like I wasn't even
allowed to go to a basketball game that
was at my school so I just want to add
this story in here because I think it's
very important on my childhood and
explains why my parents were the way
they were so my parents came to America
when they were very young and then and
had been my sister when they came to
America they only had five dollars
my dad had five dollars in his pocket
and somehow someway they became
entrepreneurs and it's not obviously
like the entrepreneur business guy that
you're thinking they had to do a lot of
the the really hard labor work that put
in a lot of hours and I just kind of
want to mention a few of the things that
they've done so when I was in like
elementary and middle school they owned
a convenience store called Chang's
Food Mart and this store was in
Petersburg Virginia it used to have the
highest crime rate in Virginia and it is
a bit different now certain parts of
Petersburg will always be rough but it
over the years it has gotten a lot
better but back then when my parents
owned the store it was pretty rough so
yeah they had their first convenience
store and I remember as a kid just being
in the store all the time and there's
photos of my mom literally carrying me
and her little carrier like punching the
cashier and literally full-on working
while raising me as a kid so that store
they had for quite a bit of time I
remember one day my mom calls me my
sister and says that we have to sleep
over are one of our best friends house
who was Elena and you guys have seen
Elena in my vlog I literally grew up
with her but she told us to stay over
there and coming from my mom that was
like what do you want us to sleep over
our friend's house like what is going on
you know it was we were so excited and
we didn't know why she was being so nice
but you know we took the opportunity and
we stayed at Elena's house and then from
one day he became like two days - three
days - four days - five days
and we were so confused why we were
staying here staying there for so long
and come to find out our convenience
store got burnt down I don't think it
was someone like maliciously trying to
burn down our store I believe it was
something with a gas tank or wire or
something and it had burnt down and I
thought I was just so confused I didn't
really know why what happened and why my
parents weren't super vocal about it
with us but I feel like they always
treated us that way where it's like
where the parents will handle it like
you don't really need to know so after
that store they opened up a Fried
Chicken business and it was called
chicken box and it was actually like 10
minutes away from the other store that
got burnt down they did that for a few
years then it didn't do us well so they
stopped doing that
and finally they bought a gas station in
downtown Petersburg and my parents
bought the gas station when I was
probably in junior high and this is a
store that they actually owned until
this day
so this store is super busy and it was
such a great business move for them
however like I mentioned Petersburg was
pretty rough back then and now it is
better but there are certain parts of
Petersburg that will always be rough and
where my parents store is happens to be
one of the most dangerous parts of
Pittsburgh it's just a lot of drug
dealing crime robbery all of that my
parents have seen it all and they've
gone through so much with owning all
these different businesses because it
hasn't been in a great area I feel like
my parents got so judgmental of the kids
I was hanging out with during my high
school middle school years because of
what they saw at their store they
naturally associated like black people
all my black friends with what they saw
at the store because they didn't know
any better the way that these people at
the store would treat my parents was
white trash you know my parents both can
speak English but it is broken and my
dad is better than my mom but they can
they mean they can have a full-on
conversation
it's just you can tell that they have
accent or they they don't say certain
words and some of their sentences don't
completely make sense but it was really
tough seeing my parents my whole life
just moved from business to business and
the area that the business was in would
get worse and worse fast forward to 2010
I graduate high school I move out to LA
to go to fit him in downtown LA I saw I
remember starting college and it was my
first week at fit him and I was super
excited to just kind of have my freedom
for my parents but also just to start
this new chapter in my life and I
remember clearly the first week that I
started fitting I was in class and I was
getting a lot of missed calls from my
friends back in Virginia and I was so
confused because I didn't know why
they'd be calling me blowing me up so
right when class finished I first talked
to my mom and just like telling her how
school was she sounded normal and
everything was good and we hang up and
then after that I checked my voicemail
because my friend left me a voicemail
and when I heard it she was pretty much
sounding so concerned and it went
something like hey Sophia like I saw the
news I just wanted to make sure you're
okay and you know I heard about your dad
and this is that and so I'm over here so
confused like what is she talking about
and so I called her back and I'm just
like I have no idea what you're talking
about and then she goes you know I saw
that your dad his store got robbed and I
heard that he got hurt and all this
stuff and I like I mentioned I had just
got off the phone with my mom and she
was completely normal so I told her like
oh no girl like I just got off the phone
with my mom like everything is fine like
she didn't mention anything I think you
got the wrong store but you know thank
you so much for being concerned and
reaching out to me and I thought it was
really weird but I didn't think about
calling my mom back and asking her
because that's my mom like if something
happened to my dad she'll call me right
then it's the next day and I believe
it's like a Saturday and me and my
sister are sleeping in and
then my sister gets a phone call from
Elena's sister and her name is Brittany
and she's like we've pretty much called
her our cousin she's like our older
sister and we grew up with her because
we were always with Elena
and so she calls Robyn and we were
living in a loft at that time so even
though we were in separate rooms the
ceiling was open so I can hear my sister
all I heard was hello and she just
jumped up it was like screaming like
crying and at that moment I knew that
what my friend told me the day before
was true and I was so confused on how my
mom could have sounded like everything
was okay so then I before my sister
couldn't even get off the phone I called
my mom I remember calling her and I was
so upset and I asked her the thing is
like she tried to answer the phone and
sound like everything was okay still so
I call her and she's like hello and I'm
like in Korean mom are you lying to me
like did something happen to dad
she literally breaks down and she tells
me the truth and she told me that our
store got robbed and my dad got shot in
the stomach and he's at the hospital but
he's okay I started asking all these
questions and my mom told me that the
robber asked for all the money and my
dad gave him everything and he still
decided to shoot my dad and leave I
remember just screaming at my mom and
yelling like don't ever lie to me about
this like and I was like cursing at
her I was so upset oh I just wanted to
know why like how could you not tell us
and act like everything is okay like I
called you and you acted like everything
was okay when my dad was not okay and he
was in the hospital and her answer is
what her answer always is for me and my
sister is life it's so frustrating and
it's because I didn't want to tell you
in Robin because I didn't want to worry
you
like I didn't want to worry you she
literally gave me the exam
like she was in her own head thinking
like what if I tell them and they're
driving and they get into a shock and
dig in a car accident like she worries
so much and she always is me Robin's
emotions come first and she just wants
us to be okay
but that doesn't make it okay and I get
what she's trying to do but it doesn't
make it right and I think I thought age
I was 18 I just left my home and moved
out to LA I think I deserve to know and
no matter what age you are um I remember
being in such disbelief that like my dad
my dad was robbed and got shot and
almost died that is something that I
never thought in a million years would
happen even though you know they had a
business that was pretty much in the
hood but it never crossed my mind that I
would experience that and it was
probably one of the hardest things I've
ever had to go through because like my
parents insisted that I didn't go home
and because I had just started finem and
Finan wasn't cheap and my parents paid
for my entire tuition in two years they
paid it off and they have worked their
entire life for me and my sister to be
okay and for us to pursue our dreams and
that is why they sacrifice their lives
every single day until this day they
have that store I remember talking to my
dad for the first time since he was in
the hospital and I just I just broke
down and like me and my dad we're not
super emotional with each other but the
feeling of almost losing him is I I was
torn to think that if that ever happened
again I I don't know what I would do
because my parents mean so much to me
and they have given
me they have sacrificed everything for
me my sister literally everything to
think that they still have that gas
station today the one that my dad was
shot at he's still working there right
now but because my parents were in that
kind of environment all the time working
and having a lot of the customers say
racist things to them yell at them
because they can't understand them just
talk so much to them and my parents
can see what goes on like literally
right in front of my store there are
drug transactions happening every single
day I mean I went with Silas to Virginia
this past December and I showed him my
store for the first time and he was just
like okay so you're just gonna sell
drugs right there and I'm like yep it's
just part of it this I'm so used to it
doesn't even faze me anymore it's it's
something where you can't even really
get the police involved because even
with them being involved they can't
change what's going on sorry
so I feel like my parents had this bad
connotation about black people and I
feel like they didn't know any better
but they just hated the fact that I only
had black friends and I didn't have a
diverse group of friends where it was
like black white or Asian and I tried to
explain my parents like I just connect
with who I connect with I do have white
friends I do like at school I have white
friends but I you may just see me around
more with my black friends and like with
the Asians kids it's like I was so
frustrated with them so I remember
arguing with them telling them if you
wanted me to have Asian friends then why
don't you have me in Korea why did you
come to America and then now you're
trying to dictate who I can be friends
with you know how hard it is like
already feeling like a minority and
feeling different and then now you're
telling me that you don't have approve
of my friends because of this and that
it was that conversation always happened
in my household I tried to understand
why they felt the way they did I'm not
saying that it was right and I'm not
saying my parents are racist I have all
sorts of different types of friends and
they are cool with it and they
they're so sweet to them when they come
over but when they think about me
overall they just they were concerned
about my future and like how I was gonna
end up because of the friends eyes I
kind of vibe with and to be honest my
choice of friends until like junior high
was pretty poor I mean I was just a
rebellious kid there's so much that my
parents didn't understand and there was
so much that I didn't understand about
my parents I wouldn't say that I had a
great childhood going through all of
this because it was I I didn't know who
I was
sorry I feel like I'm just all over the
board here and getting kind of off topic
but I want to kind of refocus and get
back to the questions to answer this
question no I was never proud of my
heritage and my culture and I truly
hated the fact that I was Korean I
didn't have like the relationship I
wanted to have with my parents which I
saw you know a lot of my close friends
had such great relationships with their
parents it just wasn't the case for me I
remember I had my first boyfriend who I
thought at the time I fell in love with
and I remember he went to Target and he
stole some makeup for me and we were
together and he got caught we both had
to go to court and my parents found out
and when I tell you that I got beat I
agen parents don't play and I think that
that's another thing like nowadays I'm
so glad that that's happening less
because it's not like I'm trying to to
beat you because I just want to beat you
it's really like a discipline thing but
I feel like a lot of Asian parents back
in the day they went a little overboard
and I'm not gonna lie my parents were a
little overboard with my beatings
and experienced a lot of them but I in
hindsight i I get what they were trying
to do I just don't think that that is
the best way to execute that but yeah I
got into a lot of trouble had to go to
court and when mom had to see my
boyfriend who she did not approve of and
there was just so much lying in my high
school years I really got into so much
trouble and my parents thought they were
so concerned about my future I remember
coming home one day and my mom is just
at the kitchen counter crying she was
saying things like I wish I never came
to America and had you and I wish that
you were born in Korea and she was just
so worried about my life and I was so
worried that my parents were never going
to change they were always going to be
this judgmental about my friends and who
I date and all this stuff but it wasn't
until I moved to LA and I just obviously
had that distance from them I mean I
moved across the country and I was able
to just to live freely but I was put in
that position in the first place because
my parents supported me and they
supported what I was going to go to
school for even though they were very
traditional they didn't expect me to be
a lawyer or a doctor they let my sister
pursue fashion and they let me pursue
beauty and that is something that I was
so grateful for because everything else
my parents was very traditional but when
it came to this as far as like me my
sister's career they were so supportive
and that was really a blessing and
that's the reason why I am even in LA to
begin with they paid for me and my
sister's tuition like they paid it off
two years they worked their asses off to
do everything for my sister and I that's
pretty much their life to make sure that
we're okay and that we we pursue our
dreams while their reality is going to
the gas station every day that's
dangerous
and not something that they want to do
but they sacrifice for my sister and I
so I feel like with that move I finally
came to LA and I'm like whoa there's a
lot of Asian people here and I was so
taken back because I've never been
around so many Asians and then I went to
k-town and I'm like oh my gosh like this
is crazy and I think from then I slowly
and gradually started to really feel
comfortable with who I am and want to
get to know my culture and and that is
where it all began and from then I I
started dating I dated my first Asian
guy and it's not that I was specifically
trying to date someone Asian it just
happened and even till this day I
wouldn't say that I only date agent guys
I would date anyone I've dated everyone
and I'm very open-minded about that but
I think that it was a real cool
experience to date my first Asian guy
who is Vietnamese and to learn about his
culture and then share stuff about my
culture it moving to LA had really was a
game changer for me
because I did not have that in Virginia
and where I'm from it was you just
there's none of that there there's no
culture there I think that moving to LA
was the best decision of my life yes I
can speak Korean but it's like third
grade level I'm really bad at it
but I can get by if I need to I did go
to Korean school every summer my mom
would send me Robin off to Korea I would
have to go to Korean school and learn
Korean but I don't know where all that
information is because I didn't retain
any of it my sister used to be really
good and fluent in Korean but then she
forgot most of it as well but her Korean
is definitely better than mine it sounds
decent and good and whereas mine is just
like like a little kid so yeah I am so
proud to be korean-american I
wouldn't want to be anything else in
this world I love the fact that I can
say
I'm Korean and I was born in America and
I'm korean-american that is what I
identify with I love the fact that I can
be both I don't need to choose because
they are both Who I am I feel like all
that embarrassment I went through my
childhood years just feeling so shitty
about being Korean I was able to really
overcome that and fill in those those
really sad moments in my life by
embracing it so much more now you guys
have seen my vlogs I mean I love cooking
Korean food I love cooking Kingdom
jjigae soondubu known Tom kimchi jjigae
Doctore Tom Taku just anything I love
Korean food I love making it I love
making it for my friends I love you know
putting it on my channel and I remember
reading some comments on the Korean
students that I would make and this girl
was just saying like I really love how
you embrace Korean food like it was
always really hard for me and I was kind
of embarrassed
to embrace it and I didn't want my
friends to be around when I had it but
watching your videos really inspires me
to just love it and be more proud about
it and I'm like hell yeah that's how I
felt back in the day and you do feel
embarrassed and you feel like oh this is
different but why wouldn't you want to
be different and on top of that if it
tastes good to you
what everyone else thinks like if
it's su-sure tastebuds you better eat it
and love it it makes me so happy to know
that there are other Asian American kids
who watch my videos and at first they
felt the same way that I did growing up
but once they see me and other creators
who are Asian American embracing that
and being proud of your culture and the
food that you eat giving them the
strength to do that as well it's really
empowering and I can't explain how much
warmth that makes me feel I feel so
incredibly blessed to kind of have this
platform and encourage other Asian
American kids who are minorities at your
school and who have felt like you're
different and alone I truly want to
speak to you and and tell you that you
aren't alone
and I've been through it all - but at
the end of it all I could not be more
proud to be a Korean American and it's I
wouldn't have it any other way
I want anyone who feels like a minority
or just different I want you to know
that being different is beautiful there
isn't supposed to be anyone like
yourself I love the fact that I have a
variety of different friends who are all
different races I highly recommend for
everyone to be open-minded and want to
meet new people different people people
who have a different ethnic background
than you the more knowledge that you
know about all of these different
cultures I feel like you're only gaining
from that it's all positive who wouldn't
want to know 20 different cultures and
try 20 different types of food then just
knowing one thing and that's it I aspire
to travel the world and get to know so
many more cultures than I do now and
live in in in their shoes and get to
know their beliefs and their values I
think that that is what makes this world
so great nothing is special about being
a 1-dimensional you want to be like the
rainbow you want to see different colors
being different is what makes you you
and no one can take that away from you
as long as you embrace it and you're
confident about it
everyone else isn't a thing you got it
going on and if they don't who the
cares it clearly tells you that that is
someone you don't need in your life and
they're just one opinion of many in the
world if they disagree with you on
things and so be it let them say their
piece and move on and that is the
biggest advice I can give to you guys or
anyone else who is going through
something similar that I went through
you get so caught up about being this
person that people want you to be if
your mind is wrapped around on that
you're not really living you're just
living because people tell you what to
do you have one life to live why not
live it with your own opinions your own
thoughts and
no one else's that's for me is is the
best life that you can live and for the
last question my favorite thing about
being asian-american is that I get the
best of both worlds
I love being Korean just as much as I
love being American I love American food
I love Korean food I love Korean people
I love American people I love it all and
the fact that I can be both
and not just one I feel like that's kind
of cool before I close this video I just
wanted to take the time to thank my
parents for raising two strong beautiful
independent girls and I just want them
to know that I love them so much and I
would do anything for them and the
reason why that I work as hard as I do
is to one day retire them and to let
them finally be able to live a free life
their entire life they have been working
working working working and working in
very dangerous environments with very
long hours and they've pretty much I've
done that since I was a baby and even
till this day it still continues by
their own choice however still for my
sister and I they're always about
feeling comfortable and stable and
looking towards the future I just want
to thank them so much and let them know
that I am beyond grateful and
appreciative and I just love them Wow
that was a very long video I hope that I
can cut this down to I don't even know
but as short as I can I just want to say
thank you guys so much for making it to
the end of this video and thank you so
much for listening to my journey growing
up as a Korean American and I hope that
this can inspire any of you to just feel
confident and believing
who you are but yeah I think that is it
for this video I just want to say thank
you so much for watching and thank you
guys for all your support I hope you
guys enjoy this video and I will see you
in the next one
[Music]