hi guys I'm finally doing the Q&A video
I have the questions right here on my
laptop but before I get into that I just
filmed that get ready with me video so
if you want to see how I set this makeup
look then I will leave a link to that
video in the description box and you can
watch it before after you watch this one
if you want to in that video I kind of
talked about how I edited my summer
outfits
video game video so if you're interested
in learning more about that then you can
go watch it oh also I am wearing
contacts right now so if my eyes look
different that's why
and I'm also house-sitting for Karen and
Lee awhile there's gone that's why I'm
here
there you go so let's start with the
questions I got on YouTube Veronica Chan
asked how did you start your YouTube
career and what's your nationality
nationality I'm American if you're asked
about ethnicity I'm Chinese so I'm
chinese-american going back to the first
question how did you start your YouTube
career I don't know if I could call this
a career but I started doing YouTube
well I've always been really into blogs
and websites and coding and design have
always loved that like that digital
sphere I remember first starting on geo
cities if you guys remember geo cities
Zynga myspace tumblr Lisa explains calm
if anyone used like to learn coding
that's great sorry oh I was on Lisa
explains all the time as a kid and I
loved it it's a really old website that
teaches kids how to code so after
college I decided I wanted to start a
blog without involving all kinds of
blogs and I wanted to start my own and
talk about fashion because I love
fashion and self-expression through
fashion so I started blogging and around
the same time Karen also came out to her
YouTube channel like her first video and
we decided to get together help each
other out and she really encouraged me
to start posting videos as well and it
took me a really long time before I
started posting videos because it
freaked me out
eventually I did it and I loved it and I
loved editing and being creative but
that's how I started doing YouTube the
complex girls asked how has your
experience in LA been while working and
making YouTube videos love this video
can't wait for the Q
thank you in my last get ready with me
video I shared that I moved to LA and
started working at my friend's salon I
don't work there anymore I don't know
that I've ever shared that maybe on
Instagram
storage I don't think I have on YouTube
but I don't work ask my friend salon
anymore I'm still friends with them
thank goodness because they're amazing
people but I worked there for about two
weeks and then I quit I just wasn't a
good fit and I wasn't really a hundred
percent in it or feeling it felt like it
was the right thing to do I'm so
thankful for the opportunity that came
up and so thankful to Ivan for getting
me to come to LA because without that I
wouldn't have come here and I wouldn't
be making the content that I want to
make so now I'm just making content
full-time and how has my experience been
in LA it's been crazy I guess a lot of
things came up I had to move a couple
times I've honestly felt like a nomad
been moving around a lot and trying to
balance filming within that schedule and
it's been hard I don't really feel like
I have a home of my own and I feel like
this is all very temporary until I
figure out what I want to do with my
life or until I can make money to
sustain myself the experience has been
stressful at times but overall amazing I
don't regret the decision to leave my
full-time job whatsoever there are
definitely times where I'm pondering
like do I need to go get a full-time job
again but that is very different from I
regret the decision I made I shouldn't
have left there is no part of me that
thinks that this whole thing has been a
learning experience and if I find out
that it's not for me then I'll just move
on to the next thing I realize that's
pretty awesome I think to be wondering
about what's nice and what's to come
rather than dwelling on what I did in
the past because there's nothing I can
do about that now really nice to be able
to talk about it and share that with you
guys I'm still kind of learning and
processing everything I can't believe
it's been six months since I've been
doing this it feels way shorter I feel
like I should have done more but anyway
that's kind of what the experience has
been like Raquel where we asked are
there any blogs or people that have
influenced your style love your videos
xx
thank your Aikau I don't follow any
blogs so much per se
follow a China people like on Instagram
but there isn't one specific person that
I really really need to follow I used to
follow a lot when I was in college like
cupcakes and cashmere fashion toast to
gray layers chriselle lim I had a whole
folder of bookmarks that I would just
open every morning I don't do that so
much anymore I honestly don't know where
I'm drawing my inspiration frog I think
it's from music right now any time I
listen to a song
I think of a story and I pretty much
come up with the music video for the
song and that's kind of where I draw my
inspiration from like as you guys know
I've been so and to BTS and kpop and not
Korean fashion I look at a lot of style
nonde photos for inspiration I don't
know that I like to necessarily started
dressing like them but I do look at
their photos and get inspired by them so
I guess I would say music and mood
influenced my style more than a specific
person or people you're gonna ask what
do you do for a living I just do youtube
full-time now you're way more on 13s
what future goals do you have for
yourself that you want to accomplish
this is the hardest question for me to
answer at a front Chris if you're
watching you always ask me what are your
goals what are you trying to accomplish
like what are you trying to do and
honestly I don't know and I gave myself
a whole year to kind of figure out what
it is that I like to do what it is that
I'm good at and where do I go from there
what I do know when I was working
full-time was that I had a lot of ideas
in my head that I wanted to do
creatively and I didn't have a chance to
do that while I was working and now I do
have a time to do that and right now I
just want to push out all those ideas as
much as I can because I feel like it's
all been like pent up in my mind and I
just want to get it out somehow I guess
that's my goal for right now is just
keep making content and figure out what
it is I like and who I am and what I
want to be oh yeah it sounds very basic
and generic and sad but that's just kind
of my goal for right now that's what I
want to focus on Maria I'm going to say
was so wrong Maria elgu lay what
inspires you most in life all right I
don't know how to answer this question
is it like there's another question here
that says what keeps you going as in
motivated so I'm just going to mush
those two together because I don't
know how to hook answer these bonds
here's a second one what keeps me going
um what Jason you've motivated is
actually my family and this is going to
be a very spiritual answer but bear with
me on this one
so when I was trying to decide whether
or not to leave my full-time job I was
praying about it a lot obviously it's a
very hard decision to make and as you
can tell it's something that's very
different from the routine and the
security that I used to have it's very
different for the future my parents
planned out for me this is so hard to
explain I need to make it to the other
side and be successful whatever success
is maybe it's me finding out I need to
go back to full-time and leave being
independent going through this hardship
if I can make it on the other side and
show my family what I did and what I was
able to accomplish as an adult making my
own decision I can prove to them that I
got through this entire thing because I
had faith in God this is what I was kind
of want to show them is that I could do
all things because God is on my side I'm
sorry I thought spiritual there for a
little bit I hope you guys can
understand I'm very open minded when it
comes to spirituality I don't like using
the word religion post nostalgia
favorite songs at the moment glad you
asked this because I actually start
sharing my Spotify playlists in my
description bar below so if you're
interested in the songs that I'm
currently listening to you can click on
that link right now it's a lot of kpop
the kind of kpop I like is very
westernized if you're kind of curious in
k-pop I think you can listen to my
playlist and see that it's not what you
think
I guess I don't know okay I don't know
if that make sense favorite hobbies any
hobbies you want to take up hmm I love
to sing I'm not very good at it but I
love singing I used to take guitar
lessons I wish I still had time to learn
all Olli asked what's the most difficult
part when you came to deciding doing
something you like instead of living a
secure life
the most difficult part I think was
probably telling my parents the second
hard realization that I had was that I
doubt myself a lot and that's something
that I struggle with quite a bit I have
so much support from the people around
my parents
my friend from you guys of course but
when it comes down to when I'm by myself
and when I'm alone I doubt myself a lot
I'm working on it it's really hard like
inner inner battles and stuff but leave
also asked what was the biggest shock
you experienced after deciding to chase
after your dreams that was it the
biggest shock was me realizing like I
have support from so many people that I
love but I don't believe in myself this
is completely new territory to me and
I'm slowly like rediscovering the kind
of person that I am and how I handle
certain situations okay I feel like this
Q&A with super-long I don't even know
how many questions I've answered so far
but it's getting so hot and your device
I love dying so I saved my favorite
questions for last because you saved the
best for last
duh and there be chance related
questions which I love to answer because
I love BTS I really do a couple of you
guys asked to draw bias and BTS my bias
is jungkook he was my bias after I heard
him do covers of Adam livings lost stars
and Tori Kelly paper hearts and I love
the song so when I heard him do covers
of them I was like in love for sure the
sense that I really loved me I think he
was my bias wrecker as he slowly
becoming my bias or he already is my
bias I don't know they also asked
favorite BTS Tara
I'd have to say fire I loved the music
video for fire I loved the aesthetics I
love the style it's amazing it's very
fun and eclectic
favorites BTS song of course I love
their title songs their singles fire
blood sweat and tears save me I love
them but when it comes to like my
favorite favorite songs currently it has
to be autumn leaves and cypher three I
love autumn leaves cuz it's very
emotional issues a really good song and
cypher 3 is a really fun badass song to
listen to right now I really love a lot
of their older stuff and they're sweeter
stuff their songs makes me really sad
sometimes I've definitely gotten very
emotional listening to like whale Ian 52
I love that song but I also love them
more fun the cut of poppy songs like
where you from coffee embarrass just one
day I remember Karen showing me dope and
blood fun tears and I was like oh yeah
they're really good but when I saw the
video for just one day and hurts
I was like enamoured I don't know why
but I love that song and it just stuck
with me that was my first favorite song
just one day so those are the questions
that I'm answering for this video I'm
sorry that I didn't get to all of them I
feel like I've just been talking a lot
and I don't want to make this video too
crazy long and boring so I'm just going
to end it right here I hope you guys
enjoyed watching this video and just
having a little chit chat session with
me let me know in the comments what your
favorite song is it doesn't have to be a
BTS songs it's ending song that you'll
love that you think I should listen to I
hope you guys really did enjoy this
video like I say that every time at the
end of every video but I really hope
that you've got something out of this
and you don't feel like you just wasted
your time I'm really sorry if you feel
that way truly I am so sorry well thank
you again for the questions and for
watching I will talk to you guys in my
next video bye