[Music]
hi everyone welcome back to my channel
if you're new to my channel welcome my
name is sandy today I'm finally doing
the college slash post-grad Q&A I asked
you guys for any questions you had about
college and post-grad life on my
Instagram and now I am finally going to
answer them
I have all your questions compiled on my
macbook actually I tried to pick the
ones that were most frequently asked and
the topics that were like really
standing out to me without further ado I
guess we can just get started and I will
start doing my makeup I'm really excited
today because I am going to use the 3c e
palette that I just got I already did my
base because I had a big breakout that I
really which is not not wanting to show
the world but for my base I used the
herb Orion glow creme which I've been
raving about recently and also my it
cosmetics bye bye foundation full
coverage moisturizer and then for a
concealer for those giant breakouts I
used my Kevyn Aucoin
super natural concealer yeah now I'm
just gonna move on to my brows and let's
move on to the first question while I do
that so the first question comes from
post nostalgia she has two questions
what's the biggest difference between
high school and college and how do you
put yourself out there freshman year in
college I think the biggest difference
between high school and college is that
in high school
people are still kind of keeping tabs on
you people are still checking for your
attendance they're still checking that
you're getting to your classes on time
and you're doing your homework you know
your teachers your professors they know
you by name they know your face they can
track you down if they really really
wanted to but in college there's none of
that unless you're in a really small
class your professor your teacher is not
going to know your name classes instead
of being 20 to 30 people it's now like
300 people and I think that is on the
lower end there's really no one telling
you what to do and telling you that
school is good for you you kind of have
to learn that on your own you have to
learn how to appreciate school and your
education on your own
not something that I don't think I
really appreciated when I was in college
I was just going through the motions and
trying to graduate and get through it
unless you're going into a smaller
college you're pretty much like a little
fish in a big pond is that how this
thing goes I'm not sure and if you are
going to a big school a big college
there's no longer a popularity contest
personally loved that there was no more
like popularity concept in college I was
never a popular kid in high school and I
hated wanting to be popular and in
college I just felt like I could finally
just do my own thing and be myself and
no one really judged you for that
because there's just so many different
people in college who are into different
things and I think that's where you
really learn to appreciate the
differences and uniqueness and people
and then for the second question how do
you put yourself out there as a freshman
honestly freshman year is the time to do
it especially if you're in dorms
everyone is just so happy and excited
and eager to meet people and to make
friends that's the time that you should
really put yourself out there and just
say hi to people ask them what they're
interested in where they're from what
they like to do that really is the time
to get to know someone because after
that it gets a lot harder as a freshman
you can be seen as like that eager
freshman that's just like trying to meet
people because you don't know anyone but
sophomore junior year senior obviously
it's a little bit harder to use that I'm
a freshman excuse yeah just really put
yourself out there and be bold you
probably don't know a lot of people in
your college like you did in high school
and I find that it's a lot easier to be
yourself and not be afraid to be
yourself you can join clubs or like
fraternities organizations whatever it
is that you like there's probably a club
or an organization created that suits
your passions and your hobbies college
campus is so huge your feel for sure I
find someone who likes the same things
that you do you just have to put
yourself out there and find it because
if you don't if you don't express
yourself and who you are and what you
like how are you going to attract the
people or bring yourself to the people
who could be your best friends having
brows on my face just makes me feel like
a whole new woman and the next question
is from hi you Lurie Hillary I always
want to say it hi you Larry how do you
stay motivated for school I need help
how I say
motivated personally is I surrounded
myself with people who are motivated I
sucked their energy just kidding but no
seriously during sophomore year of
college I joined a business fraternity
because I felt like I needed people
around me who knew more than I did that
I could learn from and that I could grow
from when you join a business for
eternity like everyone is just hustling
at least majority of people are hustling
and they're getting their done
they're studying they're working hard
they're applying for jobs so the way
that I stay motivated was that I studied
with them I hung out with them and like
obviously they were my friends so I
enjoyed hanging out with them also but
seeing how motivated those people were
made me want to be motivated and do more
so definitely surround yourself with
good people and people who you look up
to and who are already very motivating
and that you just like gravitate towards
and push you to do more and be better so
I think I'm going to take these colors I
don't know we'll see another way to stay
motivated is to kind of remember why
you're in school and why you're doing
what you're doing
honestly can be a little bit hard if
you're in school for your parents I was
kind of in that position where I was in
school from my parents like I didn't
want to go to school first I wanted to
take a year off to figure out what I
wanted to do but they really wanted me
to go to school and so I did and I did
it to make them happy and I didn't
really appreciate an education or why I
was there I know that's not always the
case for everyone you know if you're in
school to get your dream job like
remember that remember that's why you're
getting good grades it's why you're
sticking through with all the hard stuff
it's so you can get your dream job I
know I can be hard to stay motivated if
you don't know what your dream job is or
you don't know what your major is and
you don't know what you want to do with
your life but honestly I wish I
appreciated education and getting an
education a little bit more I wish I
knew what it meant
to be able to get an education because
it's so hard to do that now it's such a
privilege to be able to go to school and
to get that higher education so that in
itself I hope is motivating enough
because not everyone gets the chance to
do that so the next question comes from
from Yvonne and she asks hardest
adjustment after graduating college for
me the hardest adjustment after
graduating college
is having to make my own decisions even
in college you're still being told what
kind of classes you need to take what
you need to do in order to graduate but
after you graduate you can do whatever
you want and you have to decide do I
want to travel do I want to take a year
off and not work do I want a job what
kind of job do I want it felt like a lot
of weight was put on me to make the
right decision and you don't know what
the right decision is you don't know
what one path is going to take you a
versus another like you can't see that
and you can't know that that was a
really hard realization that I had after
I graduated I have to make my own
decisions I don't know what to do okay
now I think I'm going to use this middle
color I just used these two colors as
like a base the next question comes from
Jael xvii what was one of the most
important lessons you learned from
college and how did you use / apply it
to real life after college it doesn't
have to be school related it can just be
a life lesson - can't wait for the video
and love you I love you - thank you so
much for the question
it's a little bit of what I said earlier
and it's that you are responsible for
your own future like college gives you a
taste of it after graduation is when you
really are responsible for it but in
college is when you get a taste of it
and you have to take responsibility for
your future and then and what you want
your future to look like and the life
that you want to build no one really
exactly knows what you went through like
your parents and your siblings were
there for you growing up but they're not
there for you in college they don't know
what you're going through and like your
friends they know what you're going
through now but they don't know what
your childhood dreams were like they
don't know that much about you just yet
and so you really are responsible for
yourself and only you know yourself the
most I still struggle with that
sometimes where I don't really know what
I want and I don't know myself that well
but college is definitely the best place
and time to start figuring that out take
control of your future no one's gonna
force you to go to the TA
no one's gonna force you to go talk to
your professor if you're struggling no
one's gonna come like scoop you up if
you're really in trouble
if you fail a class you fail a class
that's it no one's gonna scoop you up
and tell you what you need to do to
succeed you have to figure it out on
your own and that was one of the hardest
lessons I learned next question
comes from Chris I think it's Christian
Christian what did you discover about
yourself that you already didn't know
while in college one I'm not good at
school that is one of the first things I
discovered about myself because growing
up I always had someone telling me what
to do like parents keeping tabs on me
teachers making sure I did my homework
and I obeyed I was really good at obey
and doing what I was told because I
wanted to avoid punishment and that was
my main motivator going to school I did
everything a good student was supposed
to do once I got to college and I had to
study on my own and like really learn
for myself I was not good at that I was
not good at school I was not good at
studying I didn't like it I just didn't
know how to discipline myself and that's
when I realized like schools not for me
I know I've been going off about
appreciating your education and I still
think that's really important but for me
the way that I learned in school and
studying and disciplining myself it was
so hard they were joining like a
business fraternity I learned a lot
about myself personally and that's where
I learned like hey I'm pretty decent at
public speaking I can talk I can make a
PowerPoint presentation I can relay
information I learned what I good out
what takes me off I learned a lot about
myself through the friends that I had
the relationships that I made you just
grow a lot as a person by surrounding
yourself with different people and I
think that's one of the most valuable
experiences about going off to college
so I just added a little bit of this
brown from the three seee palette but I
also wanted a darker Brown so I'm using
this brown from my NARS palette the next
question comes from me Lyons solo 7 do
you recommend to find a job or an
internship after college I recommend
personally from experience that you get
an internship while you're in college at
least the summer after your junior year
if you really want to be an overachiever
then get an internship at the end of
your sophomore year it will help you a
lot I think so like I wish I got an
internship at the end of my sophomore
year instead of my junior year so that I
could have more experiences under my
belt after you graduate and you'll have
a lot of experience to hopefully propel
you into a full-time paid job I'm going
to go back to
three sieep out real quick and just add
some color to the under eye area I'm
gonna use this Center shade and then
this brown on the bottom okay I'm going
to pop on some brown eyeliner this is
from Susie lux I caught this a while ago
and it's the only brown liquid eyeliner
I have so I'm just gonna go with that
put on some lashes this is from I don't
know it's an Asian brand there alright I
just want to try something different
today and go for like a different look
but yeah I'm gonna do that off-camera so
I will be right back
I wasn't feeling these lashes at first
but now that I've curled them I like
them a lot more I'm gonna apply some
mascara to it actually picking it up
because it'll look kind of sparse these
are actually some really nice lashes I
don't know why I didn't like them the
first time around okay
now I'm going to move on to contouring
and answer the next batch of questions
so I actually got a lot of questions
about figuring out what is right for you
let me just read these off I have
absolutely no idea what I want to study
and when I think about it it's a whole
mess whenever I find what I want to do
my parents disagree how do you figure
out what's right for you hi my question
is did you know what you wanted to do
right after you graduated and if not how
did you figure out your life post
college how is it transitioning from
graduating college to finding work how
did you get your first job or first real
job was it mainly because you had a ton
of experience under your belt prior to
graduating I'm going to graduate soon
and I don't know what I'm doing after
how do I start the post-grad life okay
so lots of questions about figuring out
what you want to do with your life and
let me just tell you a little bit about
my experience so in high school I had no
idea what I wanted to go to college to
do I thought I wanted to be a marine
biologist because I really loved the
ocean so I applied to a marine biology
school I got in but I decided not to go
because income-wise
it's not the best and I didn't know if I
could actually do that it just didn't
feel right so I ended up going to UC
Davis as a political science major I
really wanted to make a difference in
the world and I thought being a senator
was the best way I could learn how to do
it
I'm just going to contour real quick
this is the Avon true color contour
stick I'm gonna use this to contour my
nose but as I was saying I thought I
will want it to be a political science
major so I was taking political science
classes and when I was in there in those
classes that's when I realized like this
isn't for me this isn't what I wanted to
do then I thought this looks crazy then
I thought you know I really like writing
so maybe I'll be an English major and I
was in that English major for a class or
two I took like some writing class and
then some like literature class when I
was there I realized I loved to write
but I hate writing for this class and
maybe that means like this isn't for me
maybe I just like free writing writing
on my own free time so then I thought
maybe I will give business a try it's
open-ended I can be creative I can get
into marketing I've always liked
marketing like in high school I did a
little bit of marketing like for this
class and then I was taking economics
classes and it just kind of stuck it was
something that I felt like I could do
this I belonged here I was also
interested in fashion so I did a fashion
marketing internship and you know it
wasn't the best internship it just
sucked do you know honestly but I still
loved it enough to stick with it even
though my experience my internship
experience is kind of shitty like I
still knew like I wanted to do fashion
and I want to do marketing like that
didn't stop me from doing what I wanted
to do I just knew that even though this
experience sucked I still want to keep
at it
and so I ended up graduating with a
double major in econ and communications
and they didn't have a marketing major
at UC Davis and that was kind of one of
the closest things I thought to it so
then I went off to get my first
marketing job and I worked in marketing
for about four years in an office and
then I realized I want to work in an
office anymore and that's when I you
know quit my corporate job and started
doing youtube full-time and doing
something even more creative than
marketing numbers and analytics and
whatnot yeah my parents probably
disagreed with me you know like they
gave me a lot of freedom in college to
figure out what I wanted to do and then
after college when I you know when I
decided to quit my job I'm sure they
didn't agree with me surely
my mom is a little bit disappointed in
me I was like on the right track to do
really well in marketing I was on her I
was on a pretty great track I had a
great job but it wasn't for me and so to
answer one of the questions what happens
in your parents always disagree with you
it happens parents are gonna disagree
with you your friends might disagree
with you society is gonna disagree with
you and what you want to do you just
have to be confident in yourself and
believe that you're making the right
decision for yourself a lot of my
success in school was because I wanted
to avoid punishment I wanted to avoid
conflict with my parents and I did
everything that I could to please them
and to make them happy Indiana didn't
make me happy
so even though you're dealing with
disagreements with your parents now in
the end if you feel like it's totally
completely worth it to follow your heart
and do what you want to do because if
you know you can prove yourself and be
successful at what you want to do one
day it's worth the disagreement when my
parents doubted me it was because they
could sense doubt in myself I didn't
believe in myself because I didn't
really I thought I wanted to be I felt
like I had to prove that I could make my
own decisions and make my own mistakes
and learn and grow from them and that I
would be okay
I needed to be confident in myself for
them to be confident in me and what I'm
doing
you just have to believe in yourself and
stick with what you want to do and
sometimes you might not find that right
away but it's okay I put a lot of
pressure on myself to be successful but
I was doubtful and I was scared and I
like I don't know what's gonna happen
but in the end I realize like you know
what I don't know what's gonna happen
but I know that this is my time to learn
and to grow and make my own mistakes and
I think once I told my mom not she asked
me if I'm ever scared or worried that
I'm not making money or that I'm out
here doing this kind of stuff and I told
her like yeah it's stressful sometimes
it's stressful but I'm learning and I'm
growing and I'm really happy and this is
what makes me happy but stressful but
it's worth it I just need this time to
learn and grow in my own and if this
doesn't work out then I'll move on to
the next thing and it'll be fine
everything will be fine I think for my
mom to hear that and to be reassured and
to hear that I'm happy doing what I want
to do was enough it was enough for her
to support me because I believed in it
myself that you know I'm gonna be okay
no matter what I'm gonna be okay
and I think you need to find that
confidence
and yourself to figure it out your own
way in order for your parents to agree
with you or to support you I think it's
just in the end finding that
understanding and that common ground is
what is just really important you don't
have to know the answers your parents
for sure don't know the answers but I
think at the end of the day you need to
know that you'll be okay I need it to
accept that I don't know what's gonna
happen I don't have all the answers I
don't know what my future is gonna be
like but I'm confident in myself and
what my parents have taught me and what
I've learned that no matter what I will
be okay in the end I had to redefine
what success meant for me to when I was
working a corporate job I was like
success to me means I'm a manager I'm a
director at this really amazing firm
this amazing company I make X amount of
money I'm gonna have a house by a
certain age you just kinda have to
redefine what happiness and what success
means to you because those things will
hinder you they hindered me because for
the longest time I was thinking like I'm
not gonna own a house by the time I'm 30
I'm not gonna make X amount of money by
this time and I think for the longest
time I was hindering myself because I
believed it had to be this version of
myself like this version of a person in
order to be successful and I really had
to change my mentality I'm not in order
to to continue doing this okay I've gone
back and forth a few times with the lip
color but I finally decided I'm going to
use frente beauties Redis is called like
their mat mat Mosel mat mat mat mat okay
whatever and this is the color up to no
good that was so tight and then I'm
going to layer that with Pony effect
magnificent I really love this color but
it just doesn't go that well with my
skin tone on its own like I feel like a
Kardashian right now so I'm just gonna
layer this on
wow it's raining really hard outside
right now but just to go back on the
last few questions about figuring out
what you want to do with your life and
or what you want to do post-grad what
you want to major in I have three types
of advice I guess so one listen to your
gut follow your heart do what you love
to do and follow what you're really
passionate about to be bold
be afraid to put yourself out there and
to try anything that you're even mildly
interested in or curious about do it if
you feel like in your heart like you
really want to try maybe like art you
want to be a painter or something put
yourself out there don't say like I'm
not good enough I can't take that art
class I can't I can't don't say that and
don't hinder yourself
be bold put yourself out there and try
it out because that's how you really get
to learn and know if that path is for
you like when I went to college I went
in as a political science major you know
sitting in those classes it really
forced me to think like is this where I
want to be right now am i passionate
enough about this to put up with all of
that pretty much like when I went to
those classes I just felt really
different from everyone there I felt
very out of place it just didn't feel
like it was well suited for me because I
would look around in all the students
and they were so well educated they were
so smart and still passionate about
politics
I thought I was passionate about
politics and helping Society and whatnot
but seeing all these other students and
seeing how they had that drive and I did
it that to me told me like I don't want
to do this this isn't for me like I love
aspects about political science but as a
career choice this isn't it this wasn't
for me after that I tried writing like I
didn't know if I was a good enough
writer I just knew that I loved to write
and maybe it could be a career Avenue I
took my first writing class and I loved
writing but in on closeted just I wasn't
passionate how will you know if
something is for you or not if you don't
put yourself out there and try it that's
number two just be bold do it try it if
it's not for you it's not for you and
you'll learn that throughout that
process and if it is for you and you're
passionate about it then you'll push
forward and you'll find that place
that's just for you and third third
thing is just know that what is right
for you now can change in the future and
that's exactly what happened to me like
I thought I wanted to work in a
corporate marketing job and wear
business casual attire all the time not
the case not like hazel at all I changed
my direction like I'm doing something so
different from what I used to do and
initially that really scared me the idea
or the thought of starting over
starting from zero starting from scratch
really scared me but you can't let that
hinder you from living like your
life even though there are times where
I'm stressed out or I worry like I'm
still so much happier now that I
followed what I wanted to do and I
followed my heart it just makes me so
much more happier yeah those three
things let me recount one listen to your
heart two people try everything three
what you want now may not be what you
want in the future
or what you want now may not be what you
have one and then same thing at the end
of the day I am still kind of learning
how to live my life and these are just
kind of the experiences that I've had
that I want to share with you but every
experience is different every experience
is unique so you know take what I say
with a grain of salt but if it helps you
then I am so incredibly happy that it
does and that you can relate to it that
it's helped you in some way it like
that's amazing and that's just a great
feeling so yeah those are the questions
I'm going to answer for today because I
feel like this might be a really long
video ho I'm sorry if I didn't get to
your question if you have more questions
feel free to leave them I will try my
best to answer all of them so leave
anything that you want to say or share
or if you have questions about college
post-grad life leave them all down in
the comments yeah with that I just I
guess that's just that's all I've got I
hope you enjoyed watching this video and
found it helpful if you did please give
it a thumbs up and subscribe if you want
to see more videos from me and I will
see you guys in my next video
[Music]