hey guys welcome back to my channel so
today I wanted to record a video where I
give advice to my younger self.
I'm turning 28 this year so I thought it
would be a really good way to reflect
back on the past ten years of my
life considering I went to high school
went to college and essentially started
this adulthood and started working so I
thought it'd be a really good way to
reflect back and show you guys some of
my experiences. So if you guys are going
through this hopefully you guys can
relate. So without further ado here are
advices that I would give to my younger
self. High school. You will think that
high school is everything. It'll be
really hard for you to get past these
years because you'll quite frankly think
that you're an adult, know everything, but
you'll quickly realize that your life
hasn't even really started, and you have
so much potential to grow into an
independent woman. First heartbreak.
You'll fall in love and you'll have your
first heartbreak. You'll think that it is
the end of the world
and you'll truly believe that this
moment will never pass. You will move on.
You will get into other relationships,
and then you'll find that one person who
has been by your side this whole time
and be extremely, extremely happy with
him. Makeup. Stop wearing wild colors on
your eyelids with nude lipstick and
teased hair. It'll be fun for you to look
back on but trust me it's not a good
look. Listen to your parents. They only
want what's best for you and will only
give you advice that will help you
become a better person and essentially
give you the life that they have never
had. You'll bump heads with your dad
quite a lot but then you'll realize as
you get older that he's honestly
genuinely just looking out for you. You
guys will bond him more than ever and
you will be his daddy's little girl
again. Quality time. Spend as much time as
you can with your friends and family. As
you get older it'll get extremely hard
to coordinate time with your friends and
family so cherish those moments cherish
those free times that you have and spend
it with the people that you love. Don't
be a doormat. Stand up for yourself.
Because you get into an unhealthy relationship
you'll put your happiness aside and do
whatever makes the other person happy.
Don't worry eventually you will leave
the relationship because you'll realize
that your happiness is way more
important than sacrificing yourself. Take
care of your body. Stop eating the Papa
John's Pizza at midnight. Stop going out
five days a week. You will gain 15 pounds.
You will start to learn to eat healthier,
get rid of those bad habits, and only eat
Oreos and Papa John's on occasions.
Listen more and talk less. You have two
ears and one mouth. Listen twice as much
as you talk. Take more risks. You'll come
to find out that when you're in
uncomfortable, challenging positions you
grow the most. Just remember. If you're
complacent
you're not challenging yourself to your
fullest potential. You will not have life
figured out and even turning 28 I still
don't feel like I have my life figured
out. Some days I'm super motivated and
other days I'm unenergized. So just take it
day by day and I promise you'll do great
things. Don't stress yourself out. While
stress is a part of life, just remember
that whatever you're stressing about at
that moment in time, you're probably not
going to be stressing about it a month
or a year from now. You tend to be a
people pleaser, but that's okay because
you are really empathetic towards
other people's feelings and you're very
cautious of what you say so that you
don't hurt other people's feelings. But
always remember you cannot please
everyone. A sure way to fail is trying to
please everyone. So make sure to look out
for yourself. Don't get so caught up in
buying things. Fill your life with
experiences not things. You'll appreciate
having stories to tell and not stuff to
show. Letting go. It's okay to let go of
people. Sometimes holding on causes more
pain and more damage to yourself.
Lastly, love yourself. Social media
becomes increasingly popular. Trust me.
You will compare yourself to other
people. Find love within yourself early
on and learn to appreciate what you have.
Remember, no one can love you as much as
you can love yourself. So those are all
the advices that I would have loved to
give to my younger self. If you guys are
in your late teens or early 20s,
hopefully this can resonate
with you guys. And let me know down below
some advices that you would give to your
younger self. That wraps up this video. Thank
you guys so much for watching. I love you
guys so, so much and I'll talk to you
guys next time. Bye.
[Music]