That's when I started getting a lot of
like a racial derogatory comments about
being Asian. Hey guys welcome back to my
channel. I am Ray Lee here on YouTube.
If you guys are new to my channel, hello.
But today I'm so excited to record this
video because I'm going to be talking to
you guys about my experience growing up
as an Asian American in America. I
stumbled across this video that Amy had
posted about growing up as a Korean
American. She is  on YouTube.
I will link her video down below. I think
this topic is very common as far as like
the struggles. You know, growing up
especially if you have parents who don't
speak English,
who were immigrants, and I could create
like a whole nother video about like
growing up with immigrant parents. But
yeah. So I just wanted to take the time
to share my story with you guys and Amy
had created a bunch of questions, so
without further ado, let's get started. I
am a hundred percent Korean. I actually
was born in Korea. I was born in Kangnam
and I moved here when I was five years
old. My sister was 8 and both my parents
came out here as well. So we actually
moved out here for my dad's work and I
believe we were supposed to go back
after 3 years and you know live back in
Korea but we actually ended up staying
out here and I actually didn't know how
to say anything in English. I wasn't born
here and neither was my sister so
technically like we're not the first
generation. My kids would be first
generation but since I moved here when I
was so young I consider myself being a
first generation. So when my parents
decided to move to America we actually
moved to the San Gabriel Valley in
Southern California and if you guys
aren't familiar with that area there are
a ton of Asians. Granted I think when I
had moved there, there weren't that many
Asian people. I remember going into first
grade and there was one other Asian girl
in my class and I believe she was Korean.
And so my teacher paired us up together
so that she can like help me through the
school and she was so mean. Like I
remember she would like make fun of me
because I didn't know how to do like the
monkey bars because like that's not a
thing in Korea. I mean I don't
think it was. I don't know. And anyways I
don't think I had a lot of like bullying
because I was Asian even though I was
completely a minority at the time. I
think progressively as a years went by
there were more and more Asians that
would attend my school. But I do remember
in elementary school
like my grandmother, because she also
moved out here to raise us for a little
bit. So my grandmother made me Korean
sushi which is called kimbap and it's
freaking bomb. But I remember like I
opened my lunch pail and, at school, and
everyone was like oh my gosh, like what
are you eating, like that looks
disgusting, like all this stuff. And so
similar to the show fresh off the boat
if you guys have watched that before.
Like there's an instance in there where
like the character is eating I think like
black bean noodles or something and then
like everyone's like, ew he's
eating worms or like whatever. And I
remember going back home and just being
super sad and essentially just like
telling my family that like I only
wanted like Lunchables because that was
like the cool thing. I just remember like
food was als- just a big thing that like made
me feel really like embarrassed
embarrassed about being like Korean
because I also remember. You know those
food drives that schools do so that you
could like donate the food during like
the holidays and stuff. And I remember my
dad gave me this box of chocopie. And chocopie
was my favorite dessert and like I
still love it to this day but it's
basically a chocolate cake with like
marshmallow in the middle and it's just
delicious.
And I remember my dad had given that to
me so that I could drop that off during
my food drive and I was so embarrassed
that like I wasn't coming to school with
like a can of peas and a can of corn, and Here
I am like walking around with like a box
of chocopie. And I remember like running to the place
the drop-off place and like just dropping and like running back
because I didn't want people to see that
like I had dropped off this like weird
dessert. But I will say like the biggest
time that I had like this huge Epiphany
of like oh my gosh I'm a minority was
when I went to college. I went to college
in Illinois. That was like the biggest
culture shock for me because that's when
I finally realized that I was Asian. Like
an Asian American.
That's when I started getting a lot of
like racial derogatory comments about
being Asian. And it was like, it wasn't
even like hurtful. Like it was just it
would just make me so mad that like
there are people out there who are so
ignorant. And I remember like a friend of
mine actually came and visited from um
California and we were just like walking
across the street and this was pretty
late at night. It was like when um I think like
when the bars were closing or something
like that. And I remember people yelling
like go back to your country. Like you
don't belong here. And like saying like
ching chong whatever. Like all this stuff.
And I was just like I cannot believe I
go to a school where like you know if I
saw these students at school they
probably wouldn't say anything but the
fact that they could hide behind um. And
they were actually in a car so, you know,
they could hide behind just like saying
that while they drive past. You know
that's when I realized like oh my gosh like I
I'm not white. And I mean clearly. But like I I I'm I'm
different. By the time that I went to
high school my high school had a
thousand students in just my graduating
class. So there was four thousand
students at my school and I want to say
like at least 70 percent were Asians. So
I always felt like I belonged and I like
belong to as like an Asian. I don't know
necessarily if I ever thought like oh my
gosh like Korean pride because um I
don't know I just never felt like any of
us we're like oh my gosh like Chinese
pride Koran pride like Mexican pride or
anything like that. We just kind of like
all got along really well. I don't know
sometimes like I feel like I would be
embarrassed to talk in Korean in like a
public setting, but as I've gotten older
like I just don't care, and I'm proud to
be Korean. So you know I'll talk to my
parents in Korean, and anytime that I can
I try to because I don't want to lose
the fact that um I am Korean. One was that
obviously Asians are smart. And I'm the
second child. My older sister is the
brains of the family and I'm like
completely okay saying that. My sister
went to an Ivy League school. She was
su- she was and is super super smart.
She's a doctor. Like I definitely did not
take that route and I felt like that was
a little bit hard for me because I
remember in high school because there
were so many Asians at my school
everyone I felt like every
was so smart and I remember everyone
taking like AP courses and people were
applying to like UCLA I was like a back
up school which like I couldn't even get
into UCLA so to me I was just like oh my
gosh like these people are so freakin
smart. And I always felt like even though
you know I did take AP classes and stuff,
I wasn't like in the top tier of like
super brainiacs. And I don't know. Like I
always wanted to like I always grow up
like wanting to take dance lessons so I
started like cheerleading when I was
like in the third grade, I like attended
drill team I was in the drill team all
throughout middle school, and um took
dance classes like throughout high
school, and I just felt like I wasn't
like the stereotypical Asian. I felt like
I was forced to take on these
stereotypes. Like for instance I played
piano growing up, I played cello growing
up. I think as I've grown older I've
realized that like yes some of those
stereotypes are true but I don't have to
be a hundred percent of those like
stereotypes and it's okay to not feel
like you have to be like completely like
extremely smart. And um you know like people are
like oh you're like super loud and
you're like very vocal. It's like not
very Asian of you. And it's like well
what does that even mean you know.
So I think you know like I struggled
with it in the beginning like as a child
but as I've gotten older I just don't
care. And honestly like some of those
stereotypes like I fit into. I'm Asian
and I love to save money. I don't like to
spend money on things that I don't have
to. And you know if that's me being Asian
then so be it.
I can speak Korean but because I moved
here when I was five I have like the
capacity of like a five year old. Which
is really sad. So I can talk to my
parents about just like basic things but
I can't talk to them about like politics
or things going around like in the news
and stuff. So that's a little bit
frustrating. My hopes is that when I have
a kid that they learn to speak Korean too.
Like I want my parents to speak Korean
to them. I think it's just really, really
important to keep my Korean culture
alive. And so yeah.
Growing up with parents
who did not speak English very fluently
was such a struggle for me. Especially in
like my teens, I felt like I could not
communicate with my parents at all. I
wasn't like the best in my teens. I think
I was just like a brat and I feel so bad for
my parents, especially my dad, because I
clashed with him so much. Like he and I
were so, so different I think we didn't
have a lot of like common ground. And I
think as a teen it's really hard for you
to like communicate in general and have
this like open dialogue with your
parents because you think like your
parents are like the biggest enemies. So
that was just like really difficult for
me. I remember like we used to yell at
each other and um I felt like it was just
like never gonna go away
but honestly I think um you know growing up
I've I've learned to be A less of a brat
right and B just understand like where
my parents are coming from because at
the end of the day the reason why we
were like having these like screaming matches
is because I clearly wasn't doing what
they wanted would be like the best for
me. As I've gotten older I've gotten even
more and more close -er to my dad and like
honestly I'm like a daddy's little girl.
And um it it's I think it was a lot of
obviously like me learning that you know
my parents aren't there as like somebody
who's trying to make my life worse. Like
if anything like they're trying to make
my life way better than they you know
the experiences that they had growing up.
I am so proud to be Korean and not even
Korean but just like Asian American. I
lived in Illinois. I went to school there
and then I actually lived in Minnesota
for a little bit and I also lived in DC
for a little bit. And I think being in
the Midwest I was able to kind of like
educate other people about being
asian-american. Since I couldn't like
obviously like teach my friends you know
Korean I would try to like introduce
them to food because I think that's just
like. Eating is such a great way to
experience another culture. There's so
much tradition and so much culture
behind food so we're trying to introduce
a lot of my friends who obviously
weren't familiar with like Asians with
food. I feel like any time
I have like the chance to kind of just
open doors for other people to like
enjoy and like experience a different
side of like America then I do it
through food. One of my favorite things
about being an Asian American and Korean
American is the fact that we're very
very family-oriented. I think that my
parents were a little bit different in
the fact that a lot of Korean parents
don't say I love you to their kids. Or I
don't only think like Asian parents
really saying I love you to their kids.
It's not very common but my parents
literally would tell me that every
single day. Like to this day when I
talked to my parents or my sister on the
phone we always say I love you. When I go
to bed I always say good night and I
love you to my dad. That's not as common
but I think the family oriented part is
very very common because I grew up with
my grandmother and I had the chance to
grow up with my grandmother. In the
Korean culture grandmothers take a
really big pride in raising their
grandkids. So my grandmother and I like.
She was my best friend and I'm so, so
happy that that was like part of my my
childhood. And another thing that I love
about being korean-american is the fact
that we really, really appreciate our
elders. From a very young age you're
taught to be very respectful of your
elders which I think could be like a pro
and a con because there's a lot of like
authority and stuff like that ,but just
like you know if you think of like the
good parts of it. In Korean there's
actually different ways that you say
words if someone is like of your peer or
someone who is higher than you. So. And by
higher than you I mean like older than
you. When you say the word like hi for a
friend you say annyeong_cs but when you say it
to an older person you say annyeonghaseyo_cs.
So there's like two different ways of
saying it and I think that's pretty
similar in Spanish too which is like usted
I think. I don't know. I could
totally be making that up. I took Spanish
for like eight years in my life and I
don't think I remember like anything.
Lastly I know I talk about food a lot
but I think it's because that was a big
part of my childhood.
From like traumatizing to you know
educating other people with food. But
like honestly I love Korean food.
I know this was a super long video but I
feel like I got super caught up talking
about my childhood. I'd love hearing
about how people grow up because I think
it says a lot about like who you are
right now. But anyways I hope you guys
like this video and if you did make sure
to give this video big thumbs up. Thank
you guys so much for watching. I love you
guys so so much and I'll talk to you guys
next time.
Bye.