what's up hi okay I just need to jump in
and do this video because I keep like
thinking about it and if I keep like
thinking about it as much as I have then
I'm just gonna like stress myself out
even more where do I begin this video
can like have come at a better time like
the idea of it because Malaysia's
elections happened super recently it is
May so it's Asian Pacific American
Heritage Month I knew it was four words
long and finally oh I'm doing a new show
this weekend with so my asian-american
friends so that's he really couldn't
have come at a perfect time I saw that
genom had uploaded a video what it's
like growing up Korean American last
week and I kept meaning to watch it and
as I was working out yesterday as I was
on the treadmill I watched it I was like
well I need to do one of these videos I
try to YouTube Malaysian American I
purposely left out growing up because I
just wanted to cast the net wide uhm and
so far Lee found like one or two other
Malaysian American youtubers one is the
Malay American guy and he addresses
himself as the American male guy or the
Malay American guy his channel will be
right here and then we have Steven Lim
from BuzzFeed I found out that he was
like what Malaysian Chinese like a few
weeks ago I was watching worth it and
there was an episode where he had
breakfast somewhere I think and then he
thought it would be like something that
his mom would make so he called his mom
in the car and I heard her speak English
and I was just like wait a second
because you just like know like this and
Corian and Malaysian accent it sounds
like super similar so I just like
quickly googled Steven Lim and turns out
he is a Malaysian Chinese descent so
that was pretty exciting for me so let's
get into these questions I am a
Malaysian by nationality and Chinese by
race Malaysia is one of those countries
where when you fill out a document they
have a slot for nationality where you
put like okay Malaysian and then they
have a slot for race and then you put
like
well race deworm the main races in
Malaysia arch Malay Chinese and Indian
and my axe is gonna break like I talked
about Malaysia of course like 99% of the
time when I talk in English I have an
American accent
because I'm I don't know I just I spend
most of my time here growing up 1% of
the time if I'm talking about something
that's like Malaysian my Malaysian
accent will like come out a little bit
some I guess minorities in Malaysia we
have a solid Japanese community there
are some Eurasians and we have we
definitely have Caucasian people leaving
leaving living in Malaysia my friends
that are Caucasian that live in Malaysia
are normally of some sort of like direct
European New Zealand or Australian
descent none of them I know are American
and where I'm from in Malaysia is
pinning Penang is one of the States and
Malaysia it's made up of an island and
some part of the state is on the
mainland of Malaysia the island is off
the west coast of Malaysia and from the
island part and it's exactly what you
think an island would be like it's very
tropical
there's jungle there's Beach but it's
also one of the most urban places in
Malaysia - so there's a lot of City and
things that are being built up and
changing especially since it got its
UNESCO World Heritage recognition years
ago a lot of things have been changing
it's been getting a lot cleaner and
honestly the cleanliness used to be part
of the culture shock for me going back
home because it would be so different
like the cleanliness and the US versus
in where I was in Malaysia
what generation am i I'm the first
generation I was born in Malaysia and I
moved here when I was four years old I
moved to the Bay Area in California when
I was four I went to college in
Massachusetts and and then now I'm down
here in Southern California we moved in
the beginning because of my dad's tech
job we were supposed to stay here for
about six months in the u.s. six months
became two years and it just it just
kept going from there okay so I grew up
in the Bay Area well it's in the US and
Malaysia Penang itself is also Penang
and the Bay Area are both really mixing
pot like places
they're quite diverse I never really
felt that I was I I knew there were
other people that looks like me
basically but of course I felt that more
when I went back to Malaysia Malaysia I
didn't feel so special but I think you
guys are asking for like oh like what
experiences did you feel different we're
like isolated you do remember few when I
was younger and they're not gonna be as
like nightmarish has some people get
some people's experience I know are like
like their mom's packed them like a
certain lunch and they brought it to
school and like their friends are just
like wait what is that that's so gross
and they get embarrassed by it but I was
lucky enough not to go through that um I
mean I sort of did in like fifth grade
basically what happened was that I
I brought a snack that had dried
anchovies and peanuts which is a Gumby
lace that was the terrible pronunciation
ikan bilis
it's a really good savory snack because
it has like protein a lot of protein in
it and keep see fall and it's tasty and
we serve it as a side on some dishes
this snack was from actually a Japanese
market but it had traces of dried
anchovy whole and roasted peanuts in it
so I got really excited because when
people especially if you're like a child
of an immigrant or an immigrant yourself
you eat a snack from your home country
and you're not there it kind of like
fills in a place like in your heart that
like no other food can where you are but
I brought to school and of course since
it's like a dried whole fish that I'm
enjoying I kind of knew that I would be
made fun of so whenever I brought it out
my friends would notice and that I would
just be like I'm eating a whole fish
like it's dried and it's gross but look
here goes the head and I like eat the
keep the head by itself and they're just
being like you're so weird I think there
was one person that like really called
me out on it and shoot anyway he was
like a South Asian descent I'm not gonna
say Indian because I'm not sure and he
was just like you know which eye he's
eating fish like and this is like you
know the first break you have in school
if you go to public school in the US
like you have that first morning break I
was eating it then and she was like and
it's like he's having eats fish in the
morning like all dried in like
Oh's house it's like yeah I do because
it's good I think I felt more different
actually going home going back to
Malaysia we went back to Malaysia for
about two months every single year
growing up because um you know we still
my family still has their house there
and I remember once in the car I was
with my one of my cousins so my cousins
in Malaysia so much of public school
where Malay is taught heavily and then
some what's your international school
which is sort of like private school
there and a lot of international schools
around the world especially it's a
mostly American taught one of my cousins
that went to public school and one of my
cousin's that went to international
school in the car with me in the back
seat and they were just like the one so
a lot of kids that go to international
school sometimes don't know Malay as
well as the ones that go to public
school or like normal government school
okay we were all talking about something
and then my cousin goes the one that I
went to international school she goes
like she says a phrase in Malay and then
my other cousin laughs about it and I'm
just like wait what does that mean and
then she goes like you don't know what
that means
and I'm just like no and she was like
you how can you believe be Malaysian if
you don't know what no no no means and I
was just like um whoa it's it's a really
hard thing to answer because like you
it's something that you can't help yeah
I was kind of awkward because you don't
feel isolated every single day but
they're just like some moments like that
where you do but you don't feel Asian
enough or Western enough in some
situations and then there was like this
time a hawker stall hawker stalls are
basically like are like food carts and
they all gather in like a market and
it's great but anyway I was trying to
order something and when I order stuff
in Malaysia or they use my different
dialects of Chinese or I ordered it in
English and I chose to order it in
English this time and of course when I
spoke English my American accent was
very prevalent a person who was working
it didn't understand me once and then I
repeated it didn't understand me twice
and then she's like oh my god there's
something wall I was just like first of
all I was born here
I'm wanted
it literally means American but it's
sometimes used in a derogatory like form
like this outsider and that I don't know
it's just it feels kind of weird hearing
that I like coming from like home home
you know what I mean what people like
referred to as home if you're if you're
not just like a major Asian American
people ask you oh like where are you
really from and it's just like I
associated both places with home to an
extent when I was back in Malaysia for
like the summers and stuff my cousins
would introduce me to their friends and
actually my grandma would actually
introduce my whole family to or like her
friends as like be like oh this is my
cousin from America and I'll just be
like um yes you kind of want to go back
and be like I traveled like 27 hours to
get back to where I came from like this
is my I was born here oh this is my
cousin from us and I'm just like okay
well actually I was born here I have
always said that I was born here and
then I moved and then I come back every
summer because that's exactly what
happens because people say like in like
a certain friend group here I feel like
I'm the Asian I don't really get that
feeling but when they go back to where
their mother country is they'll be like
oh I'm the American that I can really
relate to people definitely when I was
doing like my internships or whereas
basically like socializing with my
cousin's are their friends in Malaysia
they would definitely see me as the
American were you always proud of your
heritage or was there a time you
rejected it um I don't really remember a
time where I like rejected my Malaysian
açaí always grew up I think my mom
always made sure that I knew I was I was
born in Malaysia duh and came here when
I was four and that Malaysian culture
definitely like runs through my blood
and even though I I feel mostly American
I got really confused in college though
because um I know a lot of my college
friends are gonna watch this but like
and it's not your fault
College was a time when a lot of my
friends from Malaysia their siblings
would come to college with me because
Emily Penang at least
a very small island but is heavily
populated and so you know people even
when you go out like marketing or
something or to the mall you'll know
someone by like three degrees I once
rented a car with my mom in Connecticut
and the woman who rented it to us was
Malaysian and we could tell us I mean
guess where we were from because she
could clearly tell from us too and she
we were like oh we're from Malaysia and
she was like oh we should part and we
say oh we're from Penang and they just
like I'm from Penang too and we knew we
were gonna be related to somehow turns
out that her mom goes to church and his
friends of my grandma on my mother's
side a lot of my friends like their
family members who are my age started to
come to college in the same area as me
and we would hang out sometimes which
was pretty cool but they would hang out
a lot more with each other and I felt
like I wasn't it was because they
weren't inviting me to hang out with
them because they couldn't connect to me
on that
Malaysian level like I wasn't Malaysian
enough to be invited to hang out
sometimes and he became a huge identity
crisis because I was just like do I try
to hang out with my Malaysian friends or
do I hang out with like my American
friends that I'm used to like for most
of the time I spent growing up I got
really worked up about it and I remember
telling my Malaysian friend who was like
the closest to me in college majoring if
you're out there I I remember telling
her that I didn't know what to do
she was like the thing I thought all you
like av season in many Asian Americans
is that like you're both and you don't
realize it I'm like yeah I do realize it
I never fit in anywhere like completely
and she's like well just realize that
you have the best of both even though
you won't really fit into one so I guess
I guess that's what I'm stuck with
there's some stereotypes that you
struggle with the general Asian American
stereotype that I struggle with is the
stereotype that all Asians are supposed
to be good at math and science
honestly music art in English from in
languages where my strongest subjects
school and I had to work twice as hard
in math and science to just keep up with
everybody else I remember I really
remember in kindergarten like everyone
would be out at recess and I would still
be working on 2+2 just trying to figure
out why does 2+2 make for and I remember
I would always be let out to recess late
because I would always be stuck on math
problems but reading came really easy to
me and so did spelling I just hear it in
my head and see the words and because I
spent so much of my time studying for
math and science just to make you know
like what sometimes I didn't even make
the grades I wanted and I would like
study like twice as hard as my friends
my friends would always see me studying
like my classmates would always see me
studying and they'd be like if you think
I would be like super smart or something
and I remember one of my friends in bio
we were in the back and we were taking
an exam who's like do you want to do you
want to cheat and I was it's like not
really it was like but you're like super
smart you're like always like studying
and you must you must know what to do
I'm just like no I'm studying because I
suck at this
I'm stereotype really like that's the
one that really like affects me everyone
thinks grades and Asian households are
just like number one and yeah our
parents my parents that really do set
that bar really high if I got something
that I didn't wanted I would just take
it so badly and I still do that
sometimes like I would get like a mark
that I didn't want and I'd be like oh
even though I worked so hard for that
mark and I'd be like it's still not this
mark I still can't change myself to get
this mark grades man grades kill us
Asians like seriously the other
stereotype that really gets me is a
Malaysian stereotype and that is
speaking several languages so Malaysians
are really multilingual if we speak
different languages too depending on who
we're talking to I kind of really like
learning languages and so I've picked up
some language is the basics of some
sometimes for like work or for fun and I
would try to practice them speaking with
people that are like around that speak
that language like around here because
this place is so diverse California is
so diverse and they'd be like what are
you doing like why are you speaking
you try to speak Japanese to me cuz like
because I just want to and you know it
if you try to speak like different
languages like in Malaysia like no one
cares like they think they don't think
like it's cool they don't think like
you're trying to be like someone they
don't think like you're Korea
boo-boo-boo no they just think like
she's just trying to speak different
languages here if you speak like a
different language or someone especially
if that person is so like the same
generation as you they're just like as
me at least my generation they're just
like what are you trying to do
can you speak your language yes and no
so Malaysia as I said is made up of like
several different languages the national
language is male and that I am the worst
at I can
I know phrases to get me by but I don't
really know census how I learned how to
count to four for example was the a
local aquarium my favorite aquarium
Monterey Bay Aquarium in California the
Monterey Bay California had four waters
for Southeast Asian river otters that
were on loan I think from Singapore Zoo
and their names were 1 2 3 & 4
in Malay so stock to do what you gonna
but were their names people who I think
people are like oh my gosh their names
are so like foreign and like cool but it
really just means 1 2 3 & 4 and that's
how I learned how to say 1 2 count to 4
Emily I speak Hakka hookean because of
my parents because my dad speaks hookean
which is very prevalent in Panay it's a
Chinese dialect and so he mixes that in
with English my mom speaks Hakka and she
makes it that in with English it's to
the point where she hasn't become
comfortable with my friends hanging out
at my house and she's just speaking in
both languages to me and I'm just like
mom they don't understand you you have
to speak English only should just be
like but I'm comfortable like this and
I'm like okay never mind
Mandarin Chinese that is probably my
second strongest language and it's
because my mom heavily insisted that my
brother and I learn Mandarin in school
to the point where she sent us to
elementary school where about half of
our classes were in Mandarin Chinese I
would know I wouldn't say that I
wouldn't understand it for
because it's gonna sound really snobby
to some people but my mom would
sometimes use being monolingual as a
threat to me and my brother she just
really didn't want my brother nights
missed out on being multilingual like
people were in Malaysia like how kids
were in Malaysia like how they would
speak Chinese to each other in school
and learn English in school and they
would speak Malay to like someone
outside she would be like oh you want to
just speak you just want to speak
English like all those kids out there
you don't wanna you want to be multi you
don't want to speak Chinese and like
open more opportunities for yourself and
I was just like no like because it's
nice I would get hard it would get hard
balancing math and Chinese and math in
English I'm definitely really thankful
though that I did learn Mandarin Chinese
growing up because I used a dish every
day like at work and trying to find more
work for sure being multilingual
definitely has inspired me to take on
more languages and because when you try
to learn more languages you kind of like
build a bridge it's like connecting with
more people and that's really
fascinating me it has definitely had its
pros and cons being asian-american and
affecting my relationship with my
parents the hard part is that as I said
I'm stronger I was stronger like
languages growing up and art growing up
in school but I was interested in
working with animals so the road to
being interested in working with animals
was very math and science heavy and that
was really that's really hard for me but
then I always knew that I had a creative
side hence the YouTube I know I just got
more into like making like videos and
like being more crafty and so I'm
currently trying to like chase that a
bit I'm currently trying to be more
involved in thumb and videos video
making producing specifically if you
meet a producer please hit me up anyway
so that part has been hard because you
know how the stereotype how easy Asian
parents don't want like their kids
picked chasing arts because it's
unstable that stereotype is definitely
true for me
America is like the hub of entertainment
of the world and some in some aspects
so chasing the industry
makes it hard on my Asian side but in a
way being asian-american has definitely
made me more connected with my parents
to in a way that like will have like a
family conversation back in Malaysia
with some of my Malaysian like family
members and they will have a perspective
on how to solve a problem that I will
have that that is very Western influence
that my the Asian side of my family like
would not be able to see and so that's
sort of like what brought has brought me
closer to my parents which is really
unique and definitely I something I
would not have seen coming when I was
younger it's like they understand you
yeah no my parents what's really funny
is that my dad is very very very
American to the point where he doesn't
really like to associate with his Asian
Asst but when he's pissed like when he's
mad like all of that accent will drop
like and he'll be like speaking his like
hook down like mom though my mom really
embraces her Asian side for sure she
embraces her agents her like her eastern
side I think like probably a bit more
than her western side she definitely has
a western side to her and I think that's
a that's true for a lot of like
immigrants like in their home countries
because or children of immigrants
because like you will identify with your
like home country a bit like it differs
per person to what extent they identify
with it how do you feel about your
heritage now do you identify with it
I do identify with it how I feel about
it now is pretty good especially after
college I think yeah I think college is
when I felt the worst about it I've
accepted that I'm never gonna be truly
home
somewhere like I can't completely
associate a place with home kind of
learn to be to like represent the best
of both have fun with the best of both
worlds Hannah Montana reference right
there instead of just feeling incomplete
with both what's your favorite thing
about being an Asian American or about
your heritage
I mean having the best of both cultures
is always plus honestly the best part
about being Asian American is just like
being open to more cultures I think
just like being able to connect with
more people because there are
similarities and differences between the
Asian cultures just like being able to
connect on some things that are common
or being introduced to things that are
different and sort of giving you a new
perspective that's really cool also the
food is bomb like I'm just gonna leave
it there I like being a Malaysian
because like I think I'm very lucky in
that I'm part of a culture that is super
diverse and open to new cultures
honestly like if you listen to like the
Malaysian like Spotify top 50 its
Chinese pop western pop kpop in like
there's some Bollywood and Malay songs
in there and it's just like it's it's so
much fun that diversity is pretty lit in
Malaysia
especially Malaysia's music makes me
more like open to different music genres
use it just opens more doors it's it's
kind of crazy so that's it for the
questions if you guys want to know like
a little bit more about what Malaysians
you like cuz we're pretty funny and
easygoing um there's some awesome
YouTube channels that are by Malaysians
that are shot in Malaysia I mean they
travel too sometimes but you know I
think my favorite if you guys like skits
my favorite Malaysian youtubers are
jinny-boy TV dan KU productions and the
main thing if you guys like you guys
like Beauty crease crease ao is my
favorite
she also vlogs to her vlogs and really
nice and her challenges are really funny
and who else do I like ooh
of vlogger so he doesn't walk he used to
vlog daily and they were so awesome his
vlogs were like his daily vlogs were lit
very Casey nice dad um Sean Lee he is a
beatboxer and who used a daily vlog and
his videos are pretty cool so just a lot
of Malaysians but apparently you not a
lot of Malaysian Americans on the
Internet okay so that is my what is this
tag called I feel like this is the
growing of like insert Asian country and
then American tag like right here yeah
and I guess I'll tag some channels to do
this tag I just like really enjoyed like
seeing different people's perspectives
thank you so much for watching and like
through this whole thing so yeah series
in Ryan excellent bye
there we go
okay as I said I'm stronger I was
stronger in English and math in English
this took so long to film and I have
water here but my voice is just like
going Penang is a very mixing pot
culture and so it's the Bay Area