ever since I was a kid my favorite
holiday has always been Christmas having
grown up in the East Coast I associate
winter and the holidays with my
childhood I'd always look forward to the
snow and the jingles and the lights
every single year and then I moved to
Southern California and discovered that
Christmas kind of sexier all the
snow-capped pine trees are replaced with
palm trees charred by fires from the
previous summer and I don't know if
you've noticed but we're on fire a lot
there weren't nearly as many Christmas
lights illuminating the neighborhoods
and the Christmas jingles just didn't
hit the same anymore now I know these
are all trivial firstworldproblems but
I've been living here for almost a whole
decade and I can't remember a single
California Christmas I've had I remember
the summers because the summers were
always a blast but every December I'd
miss the cozy and fester feeling of
Christmas and winter back in college
when I used to work part-time as a sushi
cashier every December the plaza I
worked at would do this thing where they
place these snow machines in the trees
and at 6:00 p.m. every night they'd
release a flurry of fake snow to make it
look like it was snowing for like ten
minutes this was mostly for the children
to enjoy but I remember being excited
for it every time if it was a
particularly slow night I'd occasionally
step outside to watch and I felt like I
was back to being 12 years old again
it's like my holiday spirit and cheer
has been stuck in this a nostalgic time
capsule you know that scene in The Lion
the Witch and the Wardrobe when Lucy
discovers Narnia and everything is just
covered in snow with cute little street
lamps and she's like got this like a
Wonder in her eyes as she's walking
around that was me every winter as a kid
and I just want to be able to experience
that again at some point back in
elementary middle and even high school
there was something really magical about
waking up and just seeing nothing but
white outside my window and getting that
automated voice message on the house
phone about how school was closed for
the day
my best friend up the street would call
me up from her house phone and ask if I
wanted to go sledding we would end up
bruised and sore from crashing into ice
and snow for hours but we wouldn't even
notice because we were numb from the
cold and from all the fun we were having
and then finally when we'd
back to her house with our gloves off
and our hand steaming we'd be greeted
with the smell of hot chocolate and
cinnamon then maybe we'd see it start to
flurry and hope that school would be
closed again the next morning in the
mornings where I did end up having to go
to school I'd wake up and spend a good
20 minutes sitting in front of this
box-shaped electric heater that we had
just soaking in that warm toasty
goodness and if my shoes and socks got
all wet from the snow on the way home
from school I'd head straight to the
bathroom to fill the tub up with hot
water and dip my icy cold feet in and it
feel like a mini spa for a couple
minutes I feel like the cold just made
everything smell and taste better to
that feeling of your body slowly warming
up as you eat warm soup and buttered
biscuits and then falling asleep and a
warm pile of fuzzy blankets right
afterwards to the sound of classic
Christmas songs in an eight-hour loop of
crackling fire that someone put on the
TV and who could forget the presence of
course presents are one of the few
Christmas activities I still do and I
really enjoy wrapping presents although
I'm not very good at it but as a kid I
really liked watching my mom wrap
presents because she did everything so
quickly neatly and she'd do that thing
where she'd cut through wrapping paper
like it was butter which I've still yet
to figure out how to master okay so
these are the presents that Christine
wrapped and put together we've got cute
little decorations on them they're
elegant they're gorgeous they're neatly
put together they look like something
off of Pinterest honestly and then on
the other side you have the presents I
wrapped which are kind of sloppy but you
know an attempt was made especially on
this one where the bottom looks like
this and I know it looks like I didn't
try but this was actually my fourth
attempt at trying to wrap this object so
you can only imagine how awful the first
three attempts must reflect and and then
you have the present Sun Moon raft um
they're very straightforward just like
he is I'm still not that great at
wrapping presents so usually for
birthdays or something I'll just throw
it in a gift bag with some tissue paper
on top and
call it a day but Christmas time is when
you bring out all the effort in wrapping
gift boxes that's when you bust out the
glittery at a holographic wrapping paper
and ribbons and the cute name labels
doesn't matter if it's like sixty
degrees outside and there's no tree to
put the presents under whatever holiday
spirit I can muster up is put into gift
shopping and gift wrapping but the
winter memory I look back on most fondly
would have to be when it snowed during
the evening let me set the scene for you
after the Sun went down the whole sky
was that cloudy dark blue color that
made everything looked like it had a
blue filter over it nobody was outside
at this time and there were also no
passing cars just the snow being faintly
illuminated by the Christmas lights on
people's houses I wanted the sweet
satisfaction of taking the first steps
in the fresh snow so I got all bundled
up and walked out into my front yard
there wasn't any wind and there were no
birds or animals or even people it was
so still and quiet that the only thing I
could hear was the sound of my own
breathing and the sound of the snow
crunching under my feet I thought it'd
be interesting to lay down in the snow
on my back and stare up at the sky until
it quickly changed from dark blue to
pitch-black I couldn't see the clouds so
it looked as though the snow is just
spawning out of nowhere for a moment it
felt like time had stopped and the only
thing in motion were the snowflakes the
cushiony feeling of the snow felt so
comfortable and relaxing and with my
coat keeping me warm I felt like I could
just fall asleep right then and there
you know up until what a my parents
inevitably busted out of the house
worried that I'd fainted in the snow or
something I'm not saying you can't enjoy
hot cocoa or Christmas music or wrapping
presents in California
I still do those things of course but
ever since I moved here Christmas has
just always felt kinda off like
something was missing maybe it's the
lack of pine trees the lack of snow the
fact that there isn't really a need for
scarves or coats because the weather's
always like 60 degrees here or it just
feels like any other day in the year
because the seasons don't change very
much so you don't even notice Christmas
creeping up on you and then I wonder do
I only have a fondness for it because I
never had to deal with the winter as an
adult I moved to California at age 15
before I had to deal with the strug
of driving on icy roads or having to
wake up early and go to work in freezing
weather or having to scrape ice off of
my car maybe because I've only ever
really experienced a winter as a child
that's why I've never really lost that
childlike wonder for it and maybe I
wouldn't feel the same if I'd never
moved away from it as they say the grass
is always greener on the other side and
I'm sure a lot of people would argue
that having sunny non humid weather for
the majority of the year is way better
than dealing with the annoyances that
come with each passing season but
whether you're spending the holidays in
a winter wonderland or not at the end of
the day what matters the most is that
you're spending it with people you love
or at the very least
enjoying yourself however you like not
to sound like a cheesy hallmark movie or
anything I hope you all have a wonderful
holiday season and if not then a
wonderful start to 2020 see you then
[Music]