greetings daisies
today's video I'm
gonna be doing the new youtuber
challenge I've been
a little sporadic
with uploading
videos mainly like a
couple of travel blogs
etc but you know
2018 planning some new
things for day by
day starting ok it's
15 questions what
is your name my name
is deja that's a
funny question no
okay yeah my name is
deja spelled Dai Zha so creative
spelling of deja
question number 2 where
are you from so I kind of like a
two-part answer this
question every time
someone asked me I'm
like this is what
I'm going to say anyway
so I was born in
Champaign Urbana
Illinois but yeah so I
live there born there
and lived it for
nine years then I
moved to Phoenix
Arizona from Oh
Niles 9 to 11 and I
lived there for a
little bit it was so
hot like I can't I
can't imagine living
somewhere that's over
a hundred degrees
on a regular basis I
can't I don't even
go outside here if
it's above like 85
so that was a little
stint in the hot
desert but for
majority of my like
adolescent teen young
adult life I've
been living in
Seattle Washington
well technically
Tacoma but Seattle for
college so long story
short born and
partially raised in
Illinois and now in
Seattle Washington
so there's my story
with that next question
how tall are you
I am 5 foot 5 inches
I've been five five
since seventh grade
I thought I was
gonna get taller but
I've been five five
since I was 12 years
old so how many
siblings do you have
I have one order
sister she is 31 years
old so that means
we are nine years
apart and yeah she
lives in the same
area is this your
first channel yes
this is my first
channel I started a
YouTube channel if
you scroll all the
way back my first
video was about five years ago
five years five years
ago and I was just
me and my friend
dancing in bathroom in
high school um but
yeah this is my first
channel I'm pretty
sure I changed the
name right around
probably last June
when I started to
do like hair videos
and I wanted it to
coincide with the
name of my blog day
by day yeah so I was
originally called
diva deja and I just
changed the youth
user name to fit my
news theme so yeah
so within the past
five years I've blown
a couple dance
videos back in high
school then I like
restarted trying to
be like hair videos
in 2016 and when I
studied abroad I was
uploading some
frequent study abroad
vlogs when I was
travelling throughout
Europe and now I'm
back here with a new
you know new plan to
upload content more
frequently and you
know what more
quality content I
guess what is your
channel about day by
day is about taking
things step by step
and day by day so
what that means basically
so with travel
taking that day by
day my nostril hair
journey it is day by
day even though you
know you think you
know everything about
your hair and then
year three you have
to figure out how she keep it
moisturized still with
the new length so
everything really
is day by day with
life in my 20s and
30s 40s 50s 60s
everything really
is a day-by-day
process and so my
channel is about doing
the things that I
love things that I
like things that I'm
learning I just
want to share my
journey with other
viewers and also
just do something I
like I really like
creating and you know
doing things are fun
I love hair so just
like you know putting
my own creative
spirit out there you
know having my own
piece of YouTube piece
of the internet I
guess why should
anyone subscribe to
your channel you
should subscribe to my
channel to become a
daisy but basically
I'll be doing some fun
DIY tutorials for
natural hair I think
I'll be having some
creative content
coming up you know
based on my own hair
journey subscribe
for some college
advice I'm almost a
graduated so I could
share my insight as
a college student you
know study abroad
interviews
in the bag getting a
job things of that
nature so I really
hope to share things
like that subscribe
for inspiration
whether that is with
traveling how to
travel on a budget
how to study abroad
on a budget basically
subscribe for some
positive vibes so
good contents and
creative content and
a smiling face ok
um where do you see
yourself in your
YouTube channel in
five years so in five
years I can't believe
the question
there's my question
of my age well
anyway and in five
years I will be 27
years old Wow well
that honestly look
you sounds like
you're like almost 30
you're basically 30
so okay I see myself
at 27 years old I'd
like to see myself
just like living out
my dream traveling
every month a couple
times a month
myself I see my hair
just like wasteland
it better be waist
length in five years
it has to be creating
things that are
mine having my own
business my own brand
own business working
for myself so I
stayed a Friday as a
global brand that
inspires and encourages
young women of
color to be their best
selves and taking
it step by step and
day by day and
whatever it means
to them so helping
women all over the
world with self care
natural hair
entrepreneurship and really
like helping other
women start their own
businesses that's why
I see it like I'm
on big scalp things
day by day is gonna
be something that
makes a stand in the
world
so yeah that's business
side YouTube in
five years let's say a million
subscribers and five
years I see day by
day having 1 million
subscribers with
lots of collaborations
with other you to
other youtubers my
favorite brands doing
collaborations
having my my input
with brand product
product marketing
product innovations
being and having my
creative insight to
help other brands
I'm also having day
by day as a brand
that is a major
staple in the natural
hair world so big
dreams big dreams with
YouTube also crossing
it as in one whole
brand YouTube my
day-by-day blog I see
day by day apparel I
see some day by day
at coming out you're
about to have some
day-by-day journals
and planners some
day-by-day hair
products so day by day
travel gear all of
that five years
let's give it got a
dream--big you know
I see it I see it
who are some of your
favorite youtubers
some of my favorite
youtubers oh my gosh
I wish I had all the
names memorized I
don't know them
the name is my heart
but nappy foo is
fun she has 4c hair
just like I do
Jackie aina for makeup
I don't know how
to have much our
advanced makeup like
that as you see I
keep it pretty simple
but I'm getting there
I'm gonna get a
nice beep one of these
days but Krishna
sure Bray I'm kind of
naming all the big
huge ones but it's
okay um natural
natural eighty five
you know Whitney
I'll post them all
below cuz I really
can't memorize you
know the usernames
like that I just
feel like watching
stuff so advice for
new youtubers be
consistent and make
videos that you're
actually interested
in because it'll be
more fun to actually
edit and you'd be
more inspired to
actually post it being
consistent is my own
like advice for
myself and to you that's all the
questions for the
new youtuber tag it
was fun pretty
simple to answer the
questions watch
yourself so if you're
new youtuber tag
you're it no one
attacked me but
is that I Huckle off
foot thank you for
watching this video
don't forget to Like
comment and subscribe
and of course take
it step by step and
day by day