I just take it day by day
greetings daisies
welcome back to my
channel today is
wash day I will be
reviewing two products
that I got from
Imani beauty boutique
it has all natural
hair products from
black-owned companies
as well so it's
really your one-stop
shop for all natural
ingredients in from
black-owned businesses
so I was really
excited to show some
support so I wonder
two products from
their boutique to try
out the website and
see how things were
going and then I'm
gonna review my
products here so
check out all the
amazing brands and
hair care skincare
products from Imani
Beauty boutique all
the products there
so far have great
ingredients and
from and different
products I had never
seen before one of
them being Creole
essence and it's with
Haitian black castor
oil I didn't know
Haiti had some black
castor oil oil too
you know you always
have bought Jamaica
but let's see what
the Haitians are up
to you and then I
also got the island
breeze body butter
this is from natural
aunty essentials I
was really like due
for some shea butter
for my body because
that's the only
moisturizer that I use
is really shea butter
or almond oil or
vitamin E oil butter
this is the only
butter I use we're
not this was it
really shea butter is
only butter I used
and so my review of
this I love this
when I when I start
to run out of shea
butter I start just
using coconut oil on
my whole body and
then shave it on my
face to present for
the jar because shea
butter can get so
expensive here in the
States and so I was
excited to try this
out it feels like
my body looks like
enveloped in a cream
so I really love
this
the ingredients are
all Jews aloe vera
juice shea butter
organic jojoba seed
mango seed butter
vitamin E all these
like really great
products so I'm loving
that
so with this deep
conditioning hair mask
it's to promote thicker
longer healthy
hair that you love
and then they have
like the list of
for all for clean
weight for all hair
types no men are all
know you know
starts with the pea
no sulfates pyramids
and SLE like no
harmful stuff basically so the
ingredients water cetera alcohol
polysorbate sunflower
safflower oil
castor oil eccentric cetera okay
Oh has yet the
ling-ling oil and some
lavender oil at the
bottom it has some
like a sensuous
it's interesting it
smells kind of lemony
but live doesn't
really smell like that
much was I just a
lemon type of really
my wash day is has
been going really I
know a lot faster
because my hair has
been super stretched
and detangling that's
one thing I've
added to my routine
is like detangling
and I had my hair
and twist the whole
week so my hair was like pretty
stretched and didn't
have too many you
know things to comb
out the first couple
of strokes with this
it is it's a really
really thick mask
I like the way it
feels as far as the
consistency of the
product because it
is SuperDuper thick
it is so thick and
that's what I need
for 4c hair so I
tend to really enjoy
the thicker thick thick
thick product so
that's something I'm
liking so far with
how it feels on my
hair it's definitely
thick so if you have
like very fine hair
then probably wouldn't
select a product
like this but if
you have like more
porous hair or dry
and coarse hair this
might be something
for you 4c hair with
some for be around my
edges I guess like
to show like 4b what
I think is 4b for
me is like these
little pieces that are
more defined spirals
and then other ones
I like maybe let's
defined you're gonna
have to find 4c hair
but just like what
I see is just like
the curl is like so
much more like a
spiral then my for see
once more zigzag but
I have learned to
love them all when I
first met now show
I was like oh my
hair's gonna be so
curly like this I
think this little
piece got me so high
oh my god I'm have
like super loose
curls and be cute and
I really like one
in my hair like that
cuz I thought that
was like that's pretty
natural hair um
and so I feel like
it took me like a
year to like my actual
natural hair just
afro just an afro
not like having to
manipulate my curls
do it twist out all
the time to like
mimic the 4b that I
thought I had all the
time and I'm just
like well I like
it just like that
just a regular fro
just with out doing
anything to it you
know take some time
to love but now that
I I do love it you
can't tell me nothing
but that's really
the journal with a
journey with natural
hair and I just want
to share my piece
on it cuz that you
can transition to
eating you're like
oh yeah I love my
hair but then you're
like oh it's 4c and
I was like how old
was I like 19 when I
first hit that so I
still was just like
you know learning to
accept what my hair
looked like and growing
through that and
growing up and now
like yay my hair has
different textures
equally so here's my
shedding that's just
expect it I thought
were shedding honestly
but I'm not due
for another trim until
okay I'm definitely
feeling like a
tingling feeling
on my scalp and at
first I was worried
um and then I
realized and looked back on the
ingredients that
there's peppermint oil
inside of this cuz I
was like did I like
cuz I did put
essential oils on my
detangler but I rinse
my hair already
and watched it so I'm like there
shouldn't be any
feeling of this and
then I look on the
ingredients in there
is peppermint oil
even it even though
it's at the bottom
like the very end of
the ingredients
peppermint and essential
oil it seems to be
like strong enough to
where you'd fill it
you know if you add
a couple drops I
definitely feel that on
my scalp
but I detangle it
like where I apply my
conditioner just like
any other like I
apply that condition
of the same every
time so if more you
watch my videos I'll
power PETA if you're
new but I start
from the ends I put
it so much on the
ends that's probably
why I keep on
buying so much product
cuz I use it so
quick and then I go
from up all the way
up and like massage
it and then I do
Tanglewood make sure
it's thoroughly on
there so far I'm
really diggin the
thickness of it it's
hard to find like a
thick conditioner
cuz I feel like I
don't know I like the
kind - where were
you turn it over and
it just sticks like
I'm turning it over
and it's not going
nowhere that's the type of like
conditioner I need
that's what that but
mask and I need a
mask mask my hair you
know
you
oh my god you guys
I'm almost done with
this jar oh my gosh
oh that's the thing
I'm so heavy-handed
I honestly thought
there was a like this
was a deeper jar
but I'm literally
already touching the
bottom I thought that
I had at least a
couple more more
inches into this jar
but oh man
you
okay so overall they
got through my hair
pretty easily smooth
and very thick so
let's see how afterwards
I'll just like
I found just feel
my hair to see like
okay was this a good
wash day or not did
this do what I say
is gonna do and
that's how I read
the product okay so
I'm gonna leave
this on my hair for
probably thirty
minutes of a little
slushed an hour um
that's a bad example
but really I need to
eat and wash power
during that time so
I'm gonna try to be
responsible and take
it off at a good
amount of time right
and just like that
another successful
wash day has been
completed I'm all
done deep auditioning
my hair and just
gonna put it in four
sections for like giant
bantu knots wrap
my hair and call it
a day thank you all
for watching my video
don't forget to
Like comment and subscribe
I'm officially doing
one video a week so
new videos every
Sunday and yeah stay
tuned for more content
as always take it
step by Steve all
made it through one
video without Spencer
coming into it
he's okay he asked to
make an appearance
you guys uh-huh
so as always take
it step by step and
day by day