hello I'll go back to my channel so
today I'm going to be doing the Mexican
American tag and actually Diego tagged
me in a while back I just haven't been
able to do it so yeah I'm gonna do it
now okay let's just jump right into it
because I really I didn't do a get ready
with me and I don't have food to eat for
a mukbang so I'm just gonna talk to
y'all if that's okay so the first one is
which ethnicity are you I'm gonna say
Mexican American I feel like I have
trouble with just defining ethnicity and
I even googled it before um but yeah so
I'm just gonna say Mexican American
because my parents are from Mexico and I
was born here and I'm yeah so Mexican
American okay number two which
generation are you so I am first
generation because my parents actually
immigrated here like in the early 90s
and I was born here so I feel like that
makes me first gen sometimes people use
first generation for even just
educational purposes like first gen
college students so I was the first one
to go to college in my family so yeah
first generation I feel like except that
like five times already but point made
Stephanie um anyways number three what
is the first experience where you felt
that discrimination of being a minority
/ different it's kind of tough because I
live in a primary lefty next community
in Inglewood
I feel like English kind of sped up with
black and Athene X and I'm in that
laughing next side obviously that's
gonna start changing soon but when I was
in Middle School where it was equally
black and equally lucky necks
I felt like different from other people
for sure I just didn't have that
American high school chair kind of add
sometimes it was obvious that it was
uncool to not have that so that's when I
feel like I started assimilating to the
dominant culture its controversial but
I've noticed that some of the the black
students in my middle school would make
fun of how I set things like England i
--q Peaks like all these things so and
like people joke around make fun of how
I say things now
I'm just like it's like triggering
because you know like I've was made fun
of it before so it's just like little
things like that it's not really big
things and I'm never gonna say that you
know we're the most oppressed community
cuz we're not but definitely like it was
kind of like a culture shock to be in a
school that was half black half latina
'xs
when I was in a school that was
primarily lucky next in elementary
school and it was a reality check number
four
were you always proud of your heritage
or was there a time you rejected it
there was a time I rejected it of course
I feel like a lot of people who are
first gen go through this experience it
doesn't matter with it what ethnicity
you are I feel like living in the United
States it's kind of inevitable to want
to feel shame or rejection for your
culture so I definitely felt that like I
said I feel like in middle school when
my cousins and all like everyone around
me started simulating more to the you
know dominant culture and it's not
really necessarily white culture because
it could be like hip-hop or whatever so
it's just like when other people start
telling you that being proud of your
culture is wrong you start believing it
at one point and I don't remember when
that switched in my head but I
definitely other people definitely
influence how you see yourself and how
you see your people how you see your
community and you know for a really long
time in my youth like a really long time
like the majority of my upbringing I was
trying to reject my culture so that
question were you always proud no I
wasn't I think college actually helped
me become proud of my heritage my
culture and embrace it and not be
ashamed of it
um and I know a lot of people don't have
the privilege of going to college but I
feel like college really helped me learn
unlearn these kind of I don't know learn
like hating my heritage or maybe the
whole time I was like from like
elementary school to high school
yeah I hated my culture um I didn't want
to be me and it's funny because I had
done the body and I forehead so
like obviously like I can't fully reject
my culture because I'm not white Patsy
it makes me happier than I'm not why
passing because I feel like if I was I
wouldn't be doing this video right now
like I wouldn't be so about my culture
because I rejected it for so long that
it like would have affected me if I
physically match that rejection if that
makes sense I don't really make sense I
think in colleges when I started hanging
out with my friends who actually taught
me more about myself than I knew yeah I
was it was really eye-opening and I'm
still friends with these people and I'm
really happy that they came into my life
because I don't want my kids or I don't
want like people other people in this in
this country who are not white to hate
who they are because they aren't why so
that's kind of like my thing and that's
why I focus a lot of my content and I'm
so happy I work that me too because I
got to create content for the Latina
community but I also want to keep doing
that in film TV and all that because I
don't want that to be lost anywhere and
I want us to be able to have these
stories told in the big screen or the
small screen whatever but I just don't
want that to be forgotten
okay this students really serious really
okay let's just go number five what are
some stereotypes that you struggle with
I feel like as a whole I personally I
feel like I don't really struggle with
stereotypes I haven't I haven't been
surrounded by white people personally as
much I just know stereotypes on TV and
stuff like that I mean I guess we can
talk about those I feel like those
stereotypes that we are lazy and more
like the help or we have a heavy accent
or were this curvaceous like latina I'm
just like listing all the stereotypes
that I know of or that were like
irresponsible it's like all these like
different things um I feel like those
are just stereotypes of Hollywood has
implemented on us but don't necessarily
representative us
so yeah just changing that up in
Hollywood would be a great thing to do a
que that's what I want to do but also I
think within you know like media always
reflects the greater country or the
greater world so I feel like there's
always a stereotype that we're like
stealing people's jobs or you know thank
documented are just you know immigrants
from Latin countries are stealing
people's jobs first of all you wouldn't
even do half the job that my parents do
you know they're doing these jobs that a
lot of people don't want to do so if
you're down to go clean your friends
big-ass mansion and Pacific
Palisades or if you're down to go put up
drywall in you know these mansions these
big ol houses all over the the west
coast then go for it take my parents
jobs and see if you can do it because if
they're taking your jobs right so go for
it try it but I just know that you won't
last
not even a day you know um so I think
that's a big serotype that I hate um
yeah and that word lazy and like
excuse me like our parents don't let us
sleep in on Saturday mornings cuz they
want us cleaning like even my mom now
when I live on my own my own she's like
are you up well I'm just like mm-hmm
you know so yeah um and just um that
were like moochers and stuff like we're
definitely not
we are definitely I feel like one of the
most hard-working community out there
and we're always hustling especially
when you see people in our community
that are you know selling flowers by the
freeways and they put it down the
streets I think the malleus model was
like those are hustlers and it's like we
never stop
mostly so stops having us pretty lazy
and stop telling us we're taking your
jobs cuz we're not and there's probably
a lot more but these are just things I
could go to the top of my head number
six
um can you speak your language yes I can
I have the privilege to be able to speak
Spanish but you know I think that's
something I strolled with too because my
parents did teach me Spanish first I am
yes so so I did take a long time to pass
out like ESL test I think I even had to
take it like ninth grade because I just
wasn't passing it I'm like not ashamed
of that because that just means that my
native tongue was so prevalent in my
upbringing in my language that it just
wasn't going to be overthrown by English
you know so I feel like I made a mistake
with um speaking English to my brothers
when they were growing up because now I
feel like even the youngest English is
his primary language is his first
language is the language he's
comfortable with because my parents were
speaking to in Spanish but I was
speaking to them in English and if I
speak to him in English and everyone
else does like in the freaking world
like school and all that like that's
gonna be the language he's more
comfortable with so right now he's
trying to relearn Spanish but I feel
like I could have helped stop that if I
helped him just speak more Spanish at
home but that wasn't a time where I was
like legit rejecting my culture and like
knowing that if he knows I'm English as
a primary language that he will
assimilate easier and have less trouble
growing up in this world
getting a job all blah even though
that's obviously it's better easy to be
bilingual but you know me and high
school thinking that in middle school I
didn't allow him to have Spanish as a
first language so that's my bad but you
know we're trying now and it's hard
because now you have to reteach these
things but I know that if I ever have
kids I don't want them to have English
as a first language because I want them
to at least keep something from their
culture you know so yeah Spanish is my
first language and
I know how to speak it kind of write it
and definitely read it so yeah I
actually learned the Spanish ABCs before
I learned the English ABCs and I was
actually just spanish-speaking when I
came into kindergarten because my
parents both taught me and read to me in
Spanish when I was growing up so I don't
remember those times but I'm very
grateful for them number seven
how has being mexican-american affected
your relationship with your parents me
wanting to continue to assimilate
growing up really affected my
relationship with my parents because I
was trying to reject the very thing they
were trying to treasure and you know
ingrain and you know bond with me about
and I just wasn't letting it happen like
I would reject other Spanish music ever
checked all the TV shows I would watch I
would you know these conversations would
go on and on and on and um now I'm
trying to be more open-minded about it
but I was like it'll take that bad knock
off like I don't like that I'm gonna
listen to that I want to listen to
all-time low or blink-182 or wood you
know whatever so definitely like
everything everything everything that
they said for I was trying to reject so
I feel like that really affected our
relationship while I was growing up
especially in my like teen years yeah
and I feel like now I'm a fighter for
the for our culture within my household
now I do try to talk to my brother's
about how important it is to keep our
cultural life and I'm on my parents side
and I completely understand my brothers
but I also now understand my parents and
I'm trying to bridge that gap and be the
middle person in that feel like over the
years our relationship has gotten
stronger and I feel like a lot of y'all
can see my relationship with my mom
being really really really strong so it
wasn't ever it wasn't always like that
so I feel like me being able to be more
open-minded about stuff like that has
actually helped my relationship with my
parents I've become closer than it was
way like then it was like before so yeah
it's got him better but it was never
this good and number eight how do you
feel about your heritage now do you
identify with him um yes um so I
actually am a fighter for my community
I'm a fighter for my culture and my
heritage and all that now and like I
said it was a really long journey to get
here like extremely long but I just felt
you know that switch in your head where
you just don't want to simulate it
anymore and you do want to be able to
continue to tell these stories of your
culture and these traditions in your
culture so I feel like now I identify it
with a hundred percent I'm still
mexican-american though you know I'm not
gonna be completely like Mexican I'm not
gonna be completely American like they
say any that Keeney that yeah I like
that is me and that is a lot of people
that um are my age and around that age
you know yeah so I do identify with it
I'm still struggling with trying to
rebuild that inside my head because I
did reject it for so long but I'm doing
it you know I'm here for it I feel like
I wish I identified as Chicana and I
feel like the only reason I don't
identify as Chicana and I haven't really
told a lot of people this is because I
feel like I don't deserve it because I
rejected it for so long and I feel like
Chicanos a certain type of term I didn't
identity that I still don't fully
associate myself with and it's not like
oh it's like lower than me like all
these things it's definitely not bad
it's just that I feel like I don't
qualify to be a Chicano y'all let me
know because I don't know what that
means but um you know I feel like I
haven't learned about that term enough
and all that so that's why I say am i
latina or I'm mexican-american but
identifying as Chicana for me is a
little bit harder because I don't I know
it means X again American but I don't
understand exactly house 1 is a Chicano
down in the comments let me know what
did she gotta means to you or to the
culture because I'm struggling
I'm still trying to struggle if
identifies chicken or not but definitely
not be not definitely Mexican America so
number nine what is your favorite thing
about being mexican-american I feel like
my favorite thing about being
mexican-american is the community that
we have and how strong the bond is
between a lot of people I do want to
bring in more different identities
within the Latin American population um
I feel like being mexican-american
American is cool and all but I feel like
we're still very like we need to let in
other communities in the whole latina
identity Latino a lot the next identity
because I feel like right now a lot of
mexican-americans are gorgeous Mexicans
in general are like here and there like
putting down all the other cultures and
I feel like for me um even making
content at me too I was always trying to
keep an eye out for being able to do
videos that were not just for
mexican-americans Chicanos I wanted to
bring in Salvadorian coach I want to
bring in you know I feel like they need
that and what that means and all these
things so like my goal is always to you
know help other cultures come up because
there's so much content out there for
mexican-americans why can't we have that
other people oh yeah so that sense of
community I really love I love the
language I love the slang that you know
that we have within the Spanish language
I love the fact that it brings people
together and you bond over one thing or
another because not every that Phoenix
is the same or even each other's
backgrounds are completely different
even if you do come from Mexico like
Mexico so huge like my parents are from
different coasts my dad's from an IAT my
mom's from a deck crew looks like their
cultures are so different you know like
well how god I have the day FA they have
northern Mexico as Bobby and Oh Bobby
Emily's always talked about that so you
know how different everything is and I
really appreciate it and I really
appreciate the different backgrounds
that we are but we all still identify as
one um so that's pretty cool and I'm
still learning a lot I'm still open to
new things I'm never gonna
stop learning about Who I am especially
now because it took so long to get here
but yeah I'm not perfect but I love my
peeps and and I'm never gonna stop
fighting for us and I'm always going to
be pushing for representation and I feel
like that's my mission in life and I
know a lot of people have different
missions and stuff but I really want to
focus on that because I feel like it's
really important for us so yeah that was
a tag it was a lot of information I
don't know how long this video is gonna
be and I'm sorry of a monotone kind of
low I'm literally just trying to be
chill like chillax cuz I'm always
yelling in my videos I feel thank you
for watching my video and I'm going to
tag okay so lipstick kitty and then I'm
gonna tag a nice a tunnel I'm gonna tag
Melly whose brown bunny Melly - so all
three of y'all y'all better do this tag
I'm gonna put the questions down below
if I didn't have you you could still
definitely do this video let me know I
want to see the videos yeah see you next
week bye