I'm getting so sweaty I'm so hot right
now I'm like my nipple pasty imma
nowhere why am I wearing these nipple
pasty it's so hard
there's no a/c in this room as you guys
know okay anyways let's continue welcome
back to my channel today I am reshooting
this Q&A for those of you who have
submitted your questions about a month
ago you're probably wondering girl
where's the video so I filmed this video
about a month ago and I just I was just
filming off that day overall I just was
not happy with the video and I thought
maybe I just need to reshoot it so today
I am in a very positive mood I'm feeling
good so let's tackle this Q&A I wrote
down all the questions in my journal
what is the greatest growth you've
experienced in the past year there there
are so many layers to this question
because I feel like as human beings we
all grow and evolve so much every year
I've grown as a person as an individual
I've grown a lot as a partner to wall
I've grown a lot as like a dog mom and a
daughter I've just grown in a lot of
areas I guess I'm just finding more of
my own voice and my own confidence in
the last year I feel like I've learned
to be more just like forward about how I
feel and if I didn't agree to something
or I felt differently about something I
would just voice it and not worry about
how the other person may perceive it
because that's just kind of who I was
all the time I've always been worried
about coming off the wrong way to people
but in the last year I've realized that
if I'm just being myself and I'm being
the best version of myself in the most
honest version of myself however I come
off to another person that's just the
way that they're gonna perceive me but
that's not the truth of Who I am you
know I feel more confident in expressing
how I feel and I don't feel like I need
to be apologetic for who I want to be
and I don't feel as much of a pressure
of living up to other people's
expectations another example that I can
share is I grew up on YouTube pretty
much I was 15 when I made my first video
I was very very young
and even though it's very young at the
time a lot of people who watched me were
even younger than me and at the time I
remember a lot of people would say
things like I really look up to you
you're like the big sister I never had
and I always go to you for advice and
everything and I think with that I took
a lot of kind of responsibility about
the way that I would appear on YouTube
and I was still being myself but there
was that sense of where I always have to
do right by other people and that I
can't let people down and I can't make
mistakes
that's like one example I think in the
last year I've learned that there are a
lot of people who will try to tell me
like hey Whaley like I don't like the
way you're thinking
or I feel like you shouldn't have said
that and immediately I'd be like oh my
god I knew I shouldn't have said that
like I really made a mistake but
sometimes those truly are my opinions
and I think I've really learned that I
don't need to share all of my opinions
even if I feel strongly about something
there's just a time and a place for it
not that I'm saying I'm silencing myself
but I realized that there are a lot of
opinions out there and if I feel
strongly about mine and I don't want
someone to tell me otherwise I think the
best thing to do is just keep those
opinions to myself and like just let
myself process it and grow from it
instead of having it being like a public
thing does that make sense I've grown a
lot as far as just really letting myself
be human and like letting myself have an
opinion and not feel like I am
responsible for everyone else or how
other people perceive me because I just
need to do right by myself so yeah
that's like the biggest growth I think
for myself and I'll talk a little bit
more about like my growth in my
relationship with wah - because that's
actually one of the other questions but
yeah hope that answers the first
question how have you been supporting
local the past few weeks I've been
trying to support local mom-and-pop
restaurants as much as I can or actually
that's actually all I've been doing like
there was a day where I was really
craving Shake Shack but I'm like let me
just spend my money on like a local
burger joint instead of Shake Shack
because Shake Shack will survive but
maybe not the mom-and-pop shop you know
but you know I thought the soup
plantation would survive
through it all but I just heard that
Souplantation is not gonna make it which
is just really really devastating
because it's like one of my favorite
salad bars they have like such good
prices such good quality all right piece
of vision we did launch our shop small
campaign which I'm so proud of on woman
if you guys missed it just to give you
like a little idea of what it was when
the whole pandemic first started we were
like okay this is crazy but we also were
aware that a lot of other small
businesses like us are taking a huge hit
so we thought like okay what are some
small businesses that we love that are
local that we can collaborate with and
support each other during this time so
we launched our shop small campaign and
I feel like that's what woman has always
been about for me where I mean obviously
we have our own brand but how do we
expand ourselves beyond that you know
how do we connect with our community and
other women and I think the shop small
campaign really just like hit hit like
the it hit like the jackpot or like it
really is exactly what I would envision
women to be so I was really proud that
we did that so that's another way we've
been supporting small businesses and I
think that's about it I think like you
know the best ways that you can if
you're wondering like how you can help
support your local community is just
whenever you're about to make a purchase
think about do I really need to buy this
item at Target or can I find it at like
a smaller mom-and-pop local market or a
restaurant do you let your dogs on your
bed um I think if I didn't live with wah
I probably would let the dogs on the bed
I used to always actually like growing
up our dogs were allowed on the bed here
and there as long as they were cleaning
obviously if they're muddy they're not
gonna be allowed on the bed you would
think after so many years he'd build an
immunity to it but no he's still really
allergic to them so anytime they lay on
the bed and if the dogs laid on his
pillow or on the sheets like he would
get really really severe allergies from
it so because of that we don't usually
let the dogs on the bed but we also
learned from our trainer that you have
to set these boundaries with your pets
once in a while we'll like if they're
clean and they have just been bathed
we'll let them on the bed for like a
little bit but they sleep on their own
beds we have like so many dog beds so
they're comfortable and I think it's
kind of nice having that balance our
bedrooms really small so we have a
queen-size matter
which is a decent size but if you put
two full-sized humans on a queen-size
mattress and you put three more dogs on
top of that that's just like too much so
yeah to answer your question they don't
sleep on the bed and we let them
sometimes how is woman doing during this
difficult time if I'm being completely
honest we like most small businesses are
not doing so well I am hopeful that
things will get better and yeah I I
don't I don't know I don't really know
how to answer that because I feel so
fortunate and lucky that we're in a
position where we're still able to stay
afloat for now and I know there are so
many businesses who are closing down and
I just I don't even know what to say
like I feel like you know we're doing
okay I don't want to sit here and say
like oh we're doing great when we're not
but yeah we're doing okay and I'm just
grateful for what it is right now
I am just hopeful that things will get
better I am very excited for our summer
collection and we just have new ideas
for the company that hopefully will be
more exciting for you guys but for now
I'm very grateful and glad that we're
not closing down it is a very scary
thing to think about but yeah I don't
know I don't know what the future holds
and if the pandemic continues to go on
for who knows how long I think us along
with a lot of small businesses we would
really be struggling but as of now we're
trying our best and I'm I'm just hopeful
I think I'm just being optimistic about
the future and I want to say thank you
to all of you who supported our shop
small campaign or are continuing to
support us it really really means a lot
and yeah thank you how do you cope with
the lockdown how do you stay positive
I've been reading a lot more self-help
books during this time and I think
that's been very helpful in the
beginning when all of this kind of first
went down I was watching the news a lot
and I think that kind of drove me into
like a state of panic and just worry and
anxiety and now I've just lessened the
amount of the news I'm watching because
I realize like that was kind of the
source of me feeling so stressed so I
think if you're feeling very stressed
out and worried and you happen to be
watching the news a lot I would say like
first start by just cutting that down a
little bit I know it's important to stay
informed
you can't just like overwhelm yourself
with information you know because a lot
of the information right now is very
scary and very negative so the best
advice that I can give is that you just
have to keep trying and keep believing
and being optimistic about life like
whenever anything bad happens to me or
like in life in general I feel like
there are just two ways you can look at
the situation you know you can either
take the route where you crumble and you
fall into fear and anxiety or you can
take the higher Road where you can try
your best
to be optimistic and positive about the
situation I think naturally our minds
are just geared more towards like having
negative thoughts it's a lot harder to
convince yourself to be positive and
keep pushing forward
but if whatever is happening to you or
whatever is happening right now is
happening regardless would you rather
make yourself continue to go down a
deeper hole or would you rather push
yourself to get out of the hole I think
that is like the best advice that I can
give any time you're faced with any
challenges there are always two ways to
look at a situation one thing my dad
said to me years ago that I still carry
with me till this day which is very
surprising because I don't really talk
to my dad that much but one thing my dad
said to me years ago that really stuck
was that as long as you keep trying it's
not over and when he said that it made
me really think like wow like as long as
I don't give up there is still a chance
I carry that with me for a lot of things
in life whenever I feel like damn like
this really sucks or like damn how do I
get out of this I remind myself that as
long as I don't give up there's still a
chance whatever you're going through no
matter how shitty the situation is right
now you are not alone and that things
will eventually get better because if it
doesn't it's not the end just surround
yourself with positive people if you can
and if you are around people that are
really negative during this time try to
be the light in their life you know it's
easy to just like fall into that I used
to be that type of person to when like
I'm around someone that's just negative
I will absorb all of that energy and I
will just be negative with them but I
realized that I would rather be the
light in someone's life and even though
it's hard to try to be that positive
person just be that person's light you
know like if you can be the positive
person in this situation and you can see
beyond the negative
right now why not help that person get
there so try your best not to let other
people's negativity whether that be in
your household or your roommates right
now bring you down try to be the light
in their life and I'm sure that one day
they will appreciate it and that one day
they will see what you've done for them
and that one day they will be that light
for you what are some things you realize
you could live without during this
quarantine well this is finally a
lighter question I've realized that I
can live without my eyelash extensions I
realized that I don't have to get mine
we're just gonna wait I realize that I
can do my own nails I mean I've always
known that I can do it but of course you
know it's nice getting your nails done
just like I think a lot of like the
maintenance things that I would use to
do you know I think I can definitely
live without those things I've always
been able to live without those things
but you know what I'm saying oh I can
live without going to coffee shops yeah
that's another big one because I would
always go to coffee shops it was just
more of the experience I really enjoy
the experience of like meeting up with a
friend at a coffee shop but I also spent
a lot of money on coffee shops you know
and I can make my own lattes and I make
some really Bond lattes shout-out to men
espresso machine what jobs have you had
before or while starting youtube so if
you guys are like ogee viewers you
probably have known of every single job
of mine but let's go down the list so my
first job ever was actually on my
parents restaurant and if you group saw
something and some people may think like
oh well you worked my parents it's not
really a real job no bish it was a real
job like my sister and I legit ran the
restaurant and we learned the ins and
outs of how to run a restaurant
obviously like a small restaurant it's
not like a big chain restaurant it was
like a local mom-and-pop Chinese
restaurant and I seriously grew up in
that restaurant at the time I hated it
and I was really embarrassed by it
because every summer all the other kids
at school would be going on family
vacations but for me summer vacation
meant that I would go and work at the
restaurant and I remember I would used
to lie to my friends at school and I
would say like oh yeah my parents are
taking me to Disneyland oh yeah we're
gonna go here and there but in reality
literally the day after school ended I
would be working at the restaurant all
summer long
and at the time I really hated it but I
think like that whole experience I'm so
grateful that my parents had me and my
sister work at a restaurant at such a
young age I was 8 when we first started
we had the restaurant up until I was
like 13 and we worked we worked at the
restaurant pretty much every single day
after school obviously after we did our
homework and stuff but that was my life
from 8 through 13 almost every single
day I had school and then I had a job
afterwards and my parents weren't like
the type of parents where they were just
like letting us kind of slack off we
actually had to really run the
restaurant take all the phone calls pack
all the orders take care of all the
customers I would come in and I remember
at the time like people would just kind
of laugh because they would see me and
my sister behind the counter and they
would think like Oh like what did these
little kids know but in the end they
would always be so impressed by the way
my sister and I handled the whole
restaurant and yeah like I grew so much
until this day I look back to that
experience and think about how much that
whole experience of working at my
parents restaurant has molded me as a
person today so that was my first job
and then after that my parents opened a
flower shop I was the delivery girl so
some of you guys may remember some of
the vlogs from back then where I would
deliver flowers I think I deleted those
blogs already but yeah I delivered
flowers from my parents for quite a few
years and then at one point most of my
friends worked for my parents and they
all delivered flowers too and then wall
worked at the flower shop too so it was
like a family and friends business so
that was my second job experience and
then when I was in college I worked
retail at Victoria's Secret I didn't
work there for very long but I was there
during college just to make some monies
and I remember at the time when I first
received the call from the person who
interviewed me she was like hey you got
the job is $10 per hour okay and I was
like yeah I felt so proud because it was
like my first job outside of working for
my parents I didn't care how much the
pay was but ten dollars an hour was not
bad and I worked at the San Francisco
Union Square location so being in a big
city the pay was higher too compared to
the suburbs I lived in I think at the
time minimum wage was like eight
something in the town that I grew up in
but working in San Francisco is getting
paid $10 an hour so I was like yeah or
was it $9
somewhere between their $9 or $10 and
then while I was in college I interned
for Stila cosmetics which was a really
really cool experience I was really
proud of that experience because it was
like my first corporate job so I was
interning and I was doing like customer
service for Stila so just answering a
lot of emails and stuff like that and I
had a supervisor who I would help her
like pack orders and stuff so yeah and
that kind of pretty much catches me up
to date and then after college I wanted
to work corporate that's what I majored
in infinim I wanted to do like product
development or something like that for a
beauty company but I ended up just
taking YouTube full-time because right
after I graduated I think I got my first
big like opportunity with Bobby Brown
and that I think was like kind of like a
wake-up call for me where I was like
this could actually be my career like I
can't believe a big company like Bobby
Brown would ever come across my channel
and want to film I campaign with me so I
thought like there is definitely value
in this so like let's see where this
takes me so I was faced with either
continuing to get my bachelor's which
would have been another 60 grand or take
you to full-time and just start working
so I decided to start working um are you
baking and have you been experimenting
in the kitchen I've been seeing like
literally everyone I follow bake during
this quarantine and I haven't gotten
into it because to be honest I don't
really have a sweet tooth I don't really
like eating sweets it's just not my
thing I'm more of like a savory tooth I
like it when people bake for me you know
like if if my friends brought me over
like a brownie or something like I'm all
for it but yeah I'm overall not super
like crazy about baked goods
so no I have not do you think you would
use dating apps if you were single well
I don't know I mean it's hard to say
like I am not in that position so
obviously I don't know maybe maybe no I
would say like a 50/50 because I am more
like traditional and like conservative I
don't know if I appear that way but like
who I am as a person I am very like kept
to myself you may not believe that
because I think on YouTube I portray
that I'm very like outgoing and I am
when I'm comfortable you know like after
doing YouTube for so many years I am
with speaking in front of the camera and
I'm comfortable with my friends and
people like that but to strangers I am
more shy and reserved so I feel like
something like a dating app although I
can see I can see why like people use it
because during this like day and age
especially like with living in LA - I
think it's so hard to meet people and if
you work full time like what like what
time do you have to go meet people like
naturally I think dating apps are a good
place to like meet people so I say 5050
because I feel like because of who I am
I am just more like I guess like
traditional where I would want to meet
someone in person rather than online but
I think if I reached a point where like
it's just been drive for a long time and
like you know I'm not meeting anybody
you know single then I would give dating
app to try like I wouldn't be opposed to
it what's your favorite part about being
a youtuber there are lots of things that
I love about being a youtuber I think if
the first thing would have to be if
you're able to create a career out of
being yourself you know like all the
other jobs that I listed earlier to you
guys is that all of these jobs I'm
working for someone or I'm working for
something and it's fulfilling that
business or that person's goals it's not
my own you know I think being on YouTube
has really allowed me to make a brand
out of just Who I am and like my beliefs
that part about YouTube I think is just
absolutely amazing
and especially just looking at where my
parents come from my dad was like a
villager from Vietnam and he came to
America as a refugee and as for my mom
she came here as an immigrant as well
and my families they have nothing like
they literally had nothing I remember my
parents would tell me these stories
about like their upbringing and what it
was like when they first came to America
and when I just compared my life and
what I get to do in my career compared
to like what my parents come from like
what what more can I ask for you know
I'm so so blessed to have this
opportunity like I can't believe this
thing that I started doing when I was 15
because I was bored
became my career like not a day goes by
where I talk about this but yeah like
not a day goes by where I don't
appreciate this but
yeah hope that answer your question and
on top of that another thing that's
really rewarding about this job is just
knowing that like how do I put this so I
remember like one time this person was
saying to me how you know in life you
have to leave behind your legacy you
know whether that be your children or
like something philanthropic that you
did and I was just thinking like oh you
know I don't really care to have a
legacy like I just want to live my life
but then the person was like well think
about it like once you die if you didn't
leave behind something whether that be
another generation or like something to
your name then you like never existed
and which is true you know not that I
would care honestly like if I'm dead I'm
dead so like it don't matter but then it
kind of did get me thinking where I'm
like okay well it's kind of cool to
think that beyond my family and my
friends there are so many other people
who know of my existence who've got to
be a part of my life or people that I
had the opportunity to like impact you
know or they have an impact on their
life whatever it is that like I preach
and show it's crazy to think that it can
have a positive impact on someone else's
life and that's really really rewarding
like how many people can go through
their life and say that they were able
to touch and impact a lot of people you
know what I mean like I think that
part's really really cool and really
rewarding about YouTube how are you and
while keeping your relationship strong
okay can I talk how are you and wha
keeping your relationship strong during
quarantine in this relationship with wha
oh my god we've been together for going
on nine years this September so it's
been like eight and a half years now and
we have just grown so much
when this quarantine first happened I
was thinking like oh damn I'm getting so
sweaty I'm so hot right now I'm like my
nipple pasty imma nowhere why am I
wearing these nipple pasties it's so
hard there's no AC in this room as you
guys know okay anyways let's continue I
think just being patient with each other
is my answer like if you are struggling
with your relationship during this time
just be patient with each other
understand that you both are equally as
stressed out of whatever's going on you
know sometimes I think it can feel very
one-sided especially if you're feeling
something so stronger like
I'm going through this like you just
need to understand but in a time like
this we just gotta be there for each
other you know both parties are feeling
the anxiety and the stress of what's
happening in the world so how can you as
a couple be strong and be there for each
other and be supportive but also be a
listener for each other yeah so patience
patience really is something that will
take your relationship so far if you
just have the patience for each other
and I think that's what's kind of helped
wanna I get through our relationship too
like we've always been patient with each
other even though sometimes we're not
patient initially at the moment but
we'll always have that space in our
hearts to be patient and be a good
listener for each other and just hear
each other out the first thing you want
to do after quarantine you guys probably
already guessed it but I want to go
camping I am having the itch to go
camping I just want to be back in nature
so badly and maybe not even just camping
even hiking like I would love to be able
to just go hike again I just want to be
like out of nature again you know I
could be obviously in my backyard but
it's different like I want to be on a
hike I want to be like in the mountains
I want to like smell that air like oh I
just love camping it's like one of my
favorite things to do in life camping is
just something that brings me so much
joy
like I've learned so much while being in
the outdoors anytime that I'm faced with
any problems being outdoors
I feel like always helps me find an
answer I love the outdoors and I just
really cannot wait to be like on the
road again that's what I'm really really
looking forward to and that's what I
miss the most how do you deal with
negativity from people even when it's a
family member so actually this is kind
of like something I answered earlier but
whenever dealing with negative people
you can't there's just like two options
you know you can either just be negative
with them let their negativity affect
you or you can be the light in their
life and my biggest thing with people
that are negative is that you don't have
to be them you know like if you're
around someone that's super negative you
don't have to be them you don't have to
let it affect you it's up to you like
you can't change how an another person
feels but you can change how you react
to it and how you feel find it in
yourself to just have more patience
you know and we're like find it in
yourself to be like confident and
express how you feel without being
negative you know so yeah hope that's
helpful
what are pros and cons about living
together before marriage there are lots
of pros and cons I think I think more
perrault's than cons I made a little
list so some pros are that you spend a
lot of time together you can help share
expenses and responsibilities especially
if you guys have kids or if you have
pets like having someone to share that
responsibility is very very nice you
never really feel lonely you know you
always have someone to sleep next to
you'll always have someone to watch
movies with have someone to eat with so
you don't feel as lonely and then
someone to help you when something
breaks or need repair which is a huge
thing in this household things are
always breaking or leaking it's really
nice having someone that you can count
on like someone that you can lean on
like obviously I take it upon myself to
do a lot of the things to in the house
but I love that I'm able to like share
that with someone for example when the
whole house flooded you know the
backyard flooded I was able to share
that stress with someone but yeah some
cons is that there are no more surprises
not that there's no more but it makes it
a lot harder and you don't miss the
person like you don't have time to miss
the person that's one thing I really
miss about just like the honeymoon stage
where like I'm really looking forward to
seeing him but now it's like I wake up
and there he is so there's like no time
for you to really miss each other or
like planned surprises for each other
because you're always together so that's
one con you don't really have so much
personal space anymore because you
obviously are sharing your space so it's
all about like being more mindful of how
you can live with each other but still
have your personal space because you
still can but it is different than like
if you were to live alone if you lived
alone you can have everything exactly
how you want it you know you can have
your space whenever you need you can
have quiet time whatever you need but
when you live with someone say I want to
have quiet reading time but was like
watching TV like we have to find a
balance between that and another con
would be living habits this is something
that one I struggled with a lot in the
beginning of our relationship we're a
lot more into now but early on he was
such a clean freak that I just didn't
know how to match up to that and we
fought so much about it because he is so
cooller about how he wants things and i
just didn't care you know i would be the
type where I'm just like throwing my
clothes all over the place I didn't do
laundry I would leave dishes in the sink
but he's like a clean freak okay like a
germaphobe he's a lot better now he's
like he's not so crazy anymore but yeah
early on our living habits did not match
up and that was very stressful for the
both of us I hated hearing him nag about
how he wanted me to be more responsible
and more clean and he hated the fact
that he had to always bring it up so and
then the last thing that I listed here
I'm sure there are more pros and cons
but this is just like when I came up
with quickly another thing is that
you're sharing all of your life
basically obviously you have your own
things but majority of the things you
share so you have to be mindful of these
things anyways I hope you guys enjoyed
this video it was very lengthy but I
think I covered a lot I think we talked
about a lot thank you guys so much for
watching I will see you guys in my next
video I hope you guys are safe healthy
happy wherever you are all right take
care