[Music]
hey guys what's up my name is Qi and
welcome to channel of Qi if you guys are
new to this channel make sure you hit
that subscribe button down below and
turn on my post notifications because
I'm on the road to 8,000 subscribers if
you guys are already part of my own G
little YouTube gang here thank you so
much for your consistent effort and your
consistent support I really appreciate
every single comment every single like
in every single view it makes the
biggest difference so with that being
said getting all of that out of the way
I also just have to make sure I say
happy Chinese New Year's especially to
the people who are the year of the rat
because it's your year and for all of
you guys who are the year of the tiger
like me just you know sit tight and be
patient be ready because in two years
we're just going to you basically get
all our blessings - we're gonna own it
period like what else can I say so with
that being said happy Chinese New Year's
and I hope you guys all have a safe and
happy blessed year coming up if you're
watching this video you probably are
seeking to fill your curiosity or you're
trying to gain some relatability just
because of the nature of the video I'm
gonna be talking about what it was like
growing up Asian it's called the growing
up Asian American tag and I'm kind of
new to the YouTube world
obviously and I just feel like I don't
know when this tag actually started but
because it's Chinese New Year's I've
been inspired and I just thought it'd be
a great time to make this video cuz I've
been wanting to for a while now so by
the end of this video if you guys stay
up till the very end you guys are gonna
probably know more about me then
basically people who don't see me and
talk to me everyday that's crazy but
after watching these videos you guys you
guys have to subscribe knowing all that
stuff about me like seriously but
anyways thanks for clicking on this
video and I'm gonna get started
so the first question is what ethnicity
are you guys I'm Chinese um for all you
other Chinese people out there hey
what's up
and I know all you Asian Americans can
relate to me when I say like how many
times people ask me this question and oh
my god it's so annoying especially when
people are like I'll tell you people
like to say I can't tell you guys apart
oh my god just like brah like leave me
alone like just let me be Chinese apiece
you know like whatever moving on to the
next question
what generation are you so I was
actually born in southern China I'm
gonna put a map up right now so yeah
that's where I was born
it's Q Ming or my pronunciation in
Chinese is very bad yeah it's really
embarrassed roast me I took me a lot to
actually say that but yeah so um I was
born in southern China and I became
asian-american aka I became an American
citizen when I was adopted right before
2000 and I've been Asian American ever
since
question is what is the first time that
you felt different / you felt like you
were a minority and there's a few
difference I guess I will talk about my
first different is when I felt different
and it didn't feel good or bad my second
different is when it felt different and
negative and then my third different
when it felt different and positive so
I'm gonna get started with that my first
time I felt different I was in
kindergarten and I my teacher was going
over the continents and it was like you
know North America South America Europe
Australia Australia Europe Asia Africa
Australia and I just remember that
remember she pointed to me I was like
gee like you're from Asia and I was like
[Music]
no seriously in all seriousness I
remember that and I really felt
indifferent like I was like oh okay and
the funniest part was going up because I
was adopted my parents are not Asian
they're not the same race as me but they
always made sure to make me feel like I
was valued despite that and that it
didn't matter as much what my grace was
but it mattered way more like what kind
of person I was and how I treated
everybody and how I was treated by other
people like that mattered so much more
and so I always kind of felt like I was
different but my mom would always be
like no you're my baby like you know
like it doesn't matter so I was like
okay but then when I got to kindergarten
and my teacher said that I was just like
wow I knew it like I was seriously on
some
um yeah so that's basically it kind of
confirmed my suspicions that I was
different but other than that I didn't
really feel positive or negative about
it at the time so then next you know the
first time I felt negative about being I
guess the first time I felt negative
about being different it's kind of hard
to pinpoint an exact time because I was
so young and it's kind of hard to
pinpoint it but also because it would
happen so frequently the first thing was
that there was this Nursery Rhyme where
it would go like Chinese Japanese dirty
knees money please and I don't remember
the beginning but that was the end part
of it I think and during the Chinese
Japanese part you know people would do
that little like Chinese Japanese like
with their eyes like making their eyes
look slanted and I remember that in
itself made me feel bad for some reason
like I remember I would feel kind of
embarrassed and sad when people would do
that thing with their eyes because and I
didn't even know why actually and it was
weird because I don't understand it so
how would I ever explain that to
somebody else that's how I felt at the
time and I remember this girl turned to
me I was just like oh my god she like
you don't have to do that part because
you're already tiny he's like your eyes
already like that and for some reason
that hurt my feelings a lot like I
remember thinking about that all day and
just being upset about it and you know
wondering why my eyes were different
from everybody else's and you know it
hurt a lot at the time and it's weird
because now I can put words to all my
emotions I'm feeling but back then when
I was younger I didn't have them I
didn't have the maturity to understand
what I was feeling to kind of explain it
to myself so you know what's interesting
looking back but the first time I felt
um different in a positive way and wow
we're starting early I do feel kind of
emotional about this because it means so
much to me um I didn't start feeling
different in a positive way I would say
until I almost got to college I'm not
gonna lie and a big thing that changed a
lot for me I'm not going to lie was the
black lives matter movement believe it
or not and it's because I feel like that
movement was a movement that kind of
started the ripple effect of everybody
talking about the ways they're you know
perspective in America as a minority is
and you know that was the first time
being different was really
valued and being like foreign quote
unquote started coming into play and
that kind of feel like I feel like kind
of started the ball rolling for a lot of
these other things that are going on now
and I think that's when I was finally
realizing like around that time that I
was like being foreign and being an
immigrant and being looking different
and being notably not from here is good
and that's when I finally clicked where
I was just like guys like I'm happy
being chinese-american I'm happy being
American I'm not here to settle for
anything less I don't want people to see
me as anything different I want to be
asian-american and that's where it
really finally ran home guys also
motional I'm so like it makes me feel so
happy like to think about it like oh my
god it's a lot a lot of feelings but it
also makes me happy because it makes me
like growing up and I don't know if
other comment down below if US also felt
this way but I would constantly be
worried about you know the future of my
kids and I know that's really weird but
I would always worry that they would go
through the same exact thing as me and
they would have to deal with like I
guess prejudices stereotyping and just
that the embarrassment of being Asian
and different but now I really really
really feel hopeful that being foreign
being an immigrant all this lava is not
a trend and that it will actually uphold
itself and I hope it does because I want
so much better for my future kids and
that's so weird
to say I know but I feel like that kind
of answers a lot and the question and
tells you guys even more about me so
that's that next question
I'm always proud of your heritage or was
there time you rejected it um after that
last question I can't even front like of
course there was a lot of rejection of
me being Chinese me being immigrant me
being foreign a lot of it like I just
remember growing up I tried so hard to
fit in with the kids around me and
basically you know I was going to
schools all white kids basically and I
just remember one thing that really like
was like fives like I didn't do
something right like was that growing up
until I was in second grade
I couldn't say the th sound and I would
always say the D sound instead of th and
then finally one of my friends was like
it's not done its God and I was just
like yeah I remember thinking that I was
like oh man like I
like it was just like without me even
really consciously knowing it I was on
this mission to fit in with everybody
else and to act more American and
basically it meant act more white at the
time and I was just like man and then
throwing up that same theme kind of
ensued like when I was older you know
middle school high school a lot of my
friends would always tell me oh my god
she like you're Asian but I think of you
as white Arthur they'd be like your
agent that I don't really see you as
Asian or they'd be like your agent I
don't think of you as Asian and it's
weird because like why do I have to be
seen as not Asian to you like to make
you guys feel comfortable like that's
something I've always personally
wondered and it's not coming at anybody
but it's just a question that you know
maybe other people can evaluate deeper
within themselves like why do you need
friends that are your own race for you
to feel comfortable but I'm not gonna
get too deep not too philosophical I'm
still trying to keep a good vibe so
basically that is you know the times
I've rejected it was just constant
growing up constantly trying to fit in
and assembly and be like everybody else
around me and it's it's you know it's
funny because growing up like I feel
like Asian people when I was growing up
we're fit into three boxes and it was
that asian person trying to act white
the Asian person trying to act black and
then the Asian person who was just a fob
like completely foreign and I guess
because I was always surrounded by white
kids I just wanted to be that asian girl
who acted white and I always felt proud
when people said that about me so there
was always like that underlying you know
rejection of my culture but I do regret
and I do regret that now looking back at
it but at the same time I don't think me
my newfound pride I guess I being Asian
would mean so much to me if I didn't go
through that growing up so you know it
is what it is there's a silver lining to
everything I guess but um yeah I
definitely rejected it growing up I I
felt proud you know so yeah
what are some stereotypes that you
struggle with guys the biggest
stereotype I struggled with growing up
was that shy docile quiet
you can't walk all over her you can't
tell her anything she won't say anything
back
asian girl stereotype and I struggle
with that a lot because honestly growing
up I was actually pretty shy like and I
don't want to be like those girls who's
like oh my god I'm so cocky I'm loud
with my friends and quiet with people I
don't know but that's really how I was
growing up I remember there sometimes in
dance classes where I would literally
just bury like this like under the bar
and wait for dance class to start and
not talk to anybody because I was so
nervous and scared and I just you know
was socially awkward like you know I
mean and I think that is really kind of
what ade away at me when it came to that
stereotype cuz I actually fit it and I
was like oh man like I don't want to be
like this I don't want to be that so
when I got to college I really started
and like expanding myself talking to
more people like doing new things and
really just kind of like saying I don't
care and just doing what I wanted to do
because you know I didn't want to fit
into that stereotype anymore so it's
crazy how that stereotype really drove
me to being who I was ultimately Who I
am today because I've worked so hard to
be the complete opposite of it so that's
the stereotype that I think has really
affected me the most I say another
stereotype is that Asian people just
kind of like our goofy not goofy in a
positive way but goofy know like whoa
like what are you doing kind of way like
that type of thing I don't ever want
people to think that I'm just clumsy and
awkward because of that but you know I
don't know well like it's something I
struggle with but it's also not
something I've ever actually like
actively tried to change so I stuck with
it a lot less than the shy awkward Asian
girl thing
okay next question can I speak Chinese
can I speak Mandarin ah no and I'm
pretty sad about this but the weirdest
thing is I can speak element very
elementary Mandarin like I can count to
ten I can say I love you I can say happy
new years how are you my name is like
you know random greetings like that I
know what my Chinese name means all that
stuff but I can't pronounce it really
well I know in the beginning of the
video I mentioned that my pronunciation
of something really bad at and I'm very
insecure to be honest about how I
pronounce Chinese words and I don't even
like to say I know any of them because
like you know it's just like what's the
point like I can't say it just I feel
like if I said it to a native Chinese
speaker they'd be like what like you
know what I mean like so I don't know I
just I kind of don't say it not because
I'm rejecting it like oh my god like
Chinese is bad nothing like that because
I did do that growing up but now it's
just kind of like I don't want to just
embarrass myself you know what I mean so
yes but not really and I can't have a
conversation so I would say mostly No
how has you being asian-american
affected your relationship with your
parents okay guys so this is gonna be a
little bit different just because I'm
adopted like I mentioned before but the
fact that I'm asian-american and the
fact that my parents are a different
race I feel like has never been an issue
with us like they've always made sure to
tell me that like at the end of the day
the thing that you need to worry about
is how you treat other people and I've
always kind of carried that with me
throughout my life and I think that they
did what they could to you know show me
my culture they told me about Chinese
holidays they took me to Chinese events
and they also sent me to Chinese school
on Saturdays and I just think because of
that it's made our relationship very
strong because they care about me being
Chinese and they care about me being in
touch with my culture and they care
about me caring about my culture which
is a huge thing but they also see me as
me they see past the outside of me and
they see the inside of my heart like you
don't know it makes me feel warm and
fuzzy whenever like people ask me
questions like this but at the end of
the day that's my mom and dad like
that's it you know I mean like our souls
were meant to be family like period and
that's why I feel like my relationship
is just so strong with them especially
because I'm Asian American because it
just shows that your love and your
family transcends you know biologic
stuff and like jeans and all that
because they they love me regardless so
I feel like that actually strengthened
my relationship
do you feel about your heritage now and
do you identify with it good question
okay so this one I would definitely say
that it's a loaded question as well
because my heritage to me means a lot
more than me just being Chinese because
it also means me being American like I'm
chinese-american to the fullest extent
the way I define being an American is
like someone who comes to this country
or someone who is currently in this
country and it's trying to do the best
they can to succeed and the best I can
to fulfill their own dreams and it's
just like I'm doing that like so to me
I'm an American
you know you mean I know not everyone
like would see me that way but that's
why I see myself I see myself as an
American I've worked hard to be an
American and all that stuff and it's
just like I just feel like you know at
the end of the day if you're living here
and you're trying to do your best and
fulfill your goals that's the American
dream so I would say that when it comes
to feeling Chinese I feel this innate
like belonging to China and does innate
belonging to being Chinese because I am
Chinese so it's literally in my blood
like there's nothing that will ever
change the fact that I was born in China
my my genetics are Chinese and it's just
like it feels so strong that it's like
that will always be this huge chunk of
my life despite everything else I do
that may be different from traditional
Chinese culture or traditional Chinese
stuff or even modern Chinese stuff you
know like I just always feel like no
matter what I'll always have that little
piece of my heart of China's yeah I do
identify with being chinese-american
your favorite thing about being
asian-american / your heritage so when
it comes to being American my favorite
thing about being American I guess is
that America is really good in a sense
of you get a lot of chances to be
creative and you get a lot of chances to
try new things meet new people and just
get so many different perspectives
because the like America has so many
different people in it and I think
that's my absolute hands-down favorite
another big favorite of mine is just the
general like ability you have to kind of
write your own story it's my favorite
thing about being American when it comes
to being Chinese of course the food of
course there's like I love Chinese
culture because there's this overarching
like need and want to always do better
and always be the best and I know
sometimes that can be negative but to me
it's always positive because I
constantly want to better myself I
constantly want to be someone who
increases my growth and I just think
that's so important and you know what
else has been funny about being Chinese
is that even though I was raised
American by American parents I feel like
I have a lot of Chinese like traits and
I wonder if its genetic I did read once
that there are certain traits that can
be genetic and for instance I save a lot
of my money and I don't like spending a
lot of my money and on top of that I
think about my future a lot that's more
of a Chinese way to think is thinking
about you know the future generations
and future wealth and finally I do try
to overachieve I do always try to better
like do things better and I want to be
the best like I'm very competitive when
it comes to certain stuff like that as
much as I don't want to admit it so I do
think that I appreciate both American
and Chinese values and I like the fact
that I'm chinese-american because I can
kind of pick and choose between positive
and negatives from both sides and I
think that's a really big blessing so
yes I do love being chinese-american
guys so that's the end of my video thank
you so much for watching I know it was
kind of a longer video hopefully you
guys didn't get too bored hopefully you
guys know a lot more about me and if you
guys want make sure you comment down
below and tell me if you guys can relate
to any of these or if you guys see
anything that you feel and that I
done clearly because I must have not
said it but yeah if you guys have
anything to add to the conversation
please leave it down below and I will
see you guys next time have a happy
Chinese New Year have a lot of blessings
and be safe
[Music]