[Music]
hey guys what's up welcome back to my
channel it has been the hottest second
since I've lost uploaded which is like
not a regular for me my bag full of
stuff now we're gonna start off with
like the big stuff I got three new
binders this year and oh my god these
colors are so cute so I have this one
which is like a mint greenish color
already put some like pictures in the
back of it I'm too lazy to like decorate
I've been too lazy since freshman year
I don't decorate my binders anymore but
I just do some pictures in here and then
I have this like pretty lavender purple
oh my god these like colors so pretty
then these are all one inches I have my
pictures in the back two pockets this is
like one of my favorite colors ever this
also one inch my pictures in the back I
have my dog on this Thailand and this a
panda from China I also got some
loose-leaf to fill that up this is my
first year buying this paper the ones
that aren't like reinforced this is
college rolled double the strength five
star I got three of those I also got two
packs of the binder separators with
pockets in them next I got this five
star five subject college-ruled notebook
this is like not a normal size this is
normal size out like a notebook I guess
and this is the size of this notebook
also one of my favorite things okay I
already use it as you guys can tell it
what you like marked it up this is a
addenda book or planner whatever you
guys want to call it it's so cute is
this 2020 on the front with flowers and
stuff next I have some index cards
I do use Quizlet and I normally use
Quizlet but also I like writing things
down so I got these from Thailand from a
store called Moshi Moshi I got these
hand sanitizers I got Ice Bear and
grizzly bear I also got some LED this is
0.7 I always use point 7 and then I got
4 sharpies I also got these pack of g2
pilot pens these are my favorite pens in
the world
these are colorful ones but I have like
40 like I got like big boxes of the
black ones because I go through them so
much this from Thailand also have stuff
inside of it it was just a pencil case
zips with this little thing this is also
from moshi moshi okay
Oh everything's following first thing
you guys already saw which is this cute
little oh my god I'm not gonna use this
for school at least I don't think but it
is this thing it's like a yogurt drink
this is unlike tall boys I've loved
before that like thing that everyone
obsessed over I've been drinking this
since I was like a child and if you
freeze it and then like you peel it off
it's really good I'll serve these
absolutely in love with them so it's
like an eraser that like it pushes up
with this thing and then y'all the back
opens and it has this little duster for
like you know the racer dust that comes
off you can like brush it away so cute I
will literally never use this in my life
but like I needed to get it so I got two
I also got this eraser honestly I got
way too many erasers for someone who
does not use pencils so I got these two
from China these came in one pack but I
like opened it cuz I already used them
these are astrology pens kind of sorta
they're super cute look like this okay
so the last thing I have is just this
highlighter marker type of thing I got
this from Thailand so the front opens -
it's like a fine point marker and then
this side is a highlighter so that is it
for my back to school supplies haul I
hope you guys enjoyed it so so much if
you have start school ready I hope it is
going good if you guys have not started
school yet I hope you guys the best of
luck for this school year please take
care of yourself mentally and physically
take a break for your mind and do
something that you actually enjoy don't
get caught up in school cuz that - one
test that one grade is not gonna kill
you so I love you guys but I love you