[Music]
hey guys welcome back to my channel I
was scrolling around YouTube and I saw
no it's called like growing up Asian
American tag it's basically just like a
couple questions explaining what it's
like growing up Asian American I saw it
and I was like I really want to do this
so we're gonna do it I have some tea
here because I am sick I saw this by Amy
Lee I think she's the one who created
this tag
I am Chinese full Chinese that's it
I'm the first generation I think I was
the first generation born in this
country
I moved when I was like around six when
I lived in New York City I was just with
family all the time obviously I was too
young to like have friends and stuff I
lived with my extended family as well as
my immediate family so everyone was
Chinese and that's just who I saw where
I was in New York it wasn't really
predominately Asian so I knew there was
other people in the world then after I
moved we moved to a predominantly white
area from kindergarten to like third
grade that school was like all white
people from what I remember there was
probably like ten Asians that I saw it
was a really small school all its
teachers were white all the staff or
white I would get bullied for being
Asian but I don't really blame the kids
I guess because they didn't know any
better well I'm sure some of them knew
better some of them were just I would
get bullied a lot about my eyes and why
I'm Chinese that was probably my first
experience of realizing that I was a
minority
I'm like ashamed of saying this but I
did sort of reject my heritage and my
culture around early teens kind of I
refuse to speak Chinese like in public
because I was like people are gonna look
at us and it was true like people did
look at us weird when we spoke Chinese
people were just like oh my god like
they're talking about us when like rude
probably talking about what was on the
menu or something
growing up in a mostly white community
where people are racist I did start to
kind of reject my culture and it's not
like I really had the opportunity to be
in touch with my culture there wasn't
really a lot of Asian culture
surrounding me we started speaking
English at home and there wasn't really
a lot of family around me so I adapted
to my surroundings now I am very proud
of where I come from I'm proud to be
Chinese some part of the Asian American
it makes me like Who I am
people can say I'm whitewash but I will
always have this skin I will always be
Chinese I will always be Asian I will
always be perceived as an Asian American
I'm proud of it
I am decent at school I wouldn't say I'm
like super smart because I'm really not
super smart I'm like a little bit above
average and I think people have always
just assumed like oh she's Asian you
know she's just good at everything it
just bothers me because that literally
does not like make any sense
I put an effort and the only reason why
I'm a little bit above average as
opposed to average is because I put in
so much effort into my work I ask
questions if I need help with something
I will go get help things don't come
easily to me
they have never come easily to me
especially math I am awful at math I'm
telling you like awful the only reason I
am at the level I am is because I've
tried so hard is because I've asked for
help and ask questions it really
aggravates me when people are like oh
you're just good at school like
obviously you're good because she's
Asian that's not the case at all because
I put as much work and as everyone else
does maybe even more just because of
that stereotype on like the flipside I'm
also very against all Asian stereotype I
am NOT scrawny not saying that Asians
are scrawny but like I have a more
athletically built body I would say
compared to like some other Asians
I'm also very tall I am 5 8 so for an
Asian girl like that is it's pretty tall
I'm not into math I like writing I'm not
good with like drawing or any of that
I'm really bad at drawing actually the
stereotypical norm for Asians I am sort
of the opposite I wouldn't say I'm like
a petite little like i'ma just do and
irena i'ma go along with whatever like I
like standing my ground I like knowing
what I want I just don't want to reform
to that stereotypical Asian girl where
when you get a husband you are pushover
and you just do whatever your husband
wants like I am a strong independent
woman I think it's kind of growing where
there's more Asians like this and that
makes me so happy because why should we
be that house what Asian housewife that
men push over
yes and no my dialect of Chinese is not
Mandarin I can basically do the basics
of my dialect and also Mandarin I can
somewhat understand Kanto
I mean growing up asian-american we have
like different struggles that is kind of
harder to relate to especially because
they didn't grow up in America or at
least my parents didn't so it is harder
to have like a mutual understanding of
kind of what's going on
I kind of like touched on this earlier
on but I love my heritage now I wish I
could learn more about my heritage it's
hard because I can't really speak to
like my grandparents and I would love to
sit down and like have a conversation
with them about like life and how they
emigrated here and just like all that
stuff
I love being Chinese I love being
asian-american and I wouldn't change it
do you identify with it I would say so
my favorite thing about being
asian-american is that we have this
chance to create a new identity identity
I didn't identity I don't know why that
words sounding so weird to me right now
but we have this chance to create a new
identity for how people perceive Asians
before they would just be seen as you
know math people who are shy and not
outgoing not athletic and we have the
chance as Asian Americans to prove them
wrong to show them that we can do
whatever the heck we want we can be
great at math we can be great at English
we can be rocket scientists we can also
be artists we can also be photographers
we can be chefs we can be
we have that ability we have that
control to change how Americans perceive
us because we are the living examples
also being Asian American I like that I
have American culture and I have Asian
culture I have school and friends and
just living under certain like American
style and I can also come home to a
traditional Chinese dish I love like
that just the whole concept of being
able to have both everything about my
heritage in general I think that there's
just so much background so much history
so much tradition especially in Chinese
culture there's so much tradition there
are so many things that you have to
follow and like sometimes they're a bit
like like why but that's probably my
like American side like why do I have to
do that why do I have to follow that but
it's also really cool because there's no
other culture that is like that every
culture is unique in its own way and I
think it's cool that I am trying to use
and that I have that heritage but yeah
that's basically it
for this growing up Asian American tag I
hope you guys enjoyed if you guys are
watching this and you guys are Asian
American do this tag spread your story
because there are a lot of people that I
know that have no idea about what it's
like to be Asian American I'm sharing my
story of growing up as an Asian American
and there's a lot more growing up to do
I hope you guys enjoy it so so much make
sure to give this video a like if you
guys liked it - make sure to subscribe
if you guys haven't already I will see
you guys hopefully soon bye guys
[Music]