hey guys what's up welcome back to my
channel
so today's video i'm gonna do a
collective thrift haul
every time i go to the thrift store i
get like one or two things so i can't
really do like
thrift with me and then a thrift haul
for that one day because i'll be showing
two things
this is like a summer editions type
clothing because i have a lot of
sweaters and stuff that i'll probably do
a haul on in like the winter time if
you're wondering about my hat i started
a small sustainable environmentally
friendly
bucket hat making business all of my
hats are made from recycled material
so go check it out on instagram no
planet b we have
no planet b so please please please
please
save the one we're on right now shop
sustainably shop eco-friendly
shop anything that helps the planet we
only have one
so yes let's just get started with the
video first thing i have is this tank
top i got a goodwill
it was with a skirt but i did not like
it so i just took the tank top and not
the skirt this is from charlotte russe
and it is an extra small that is why it
is so freaking tight
i was like why is it so small so i don't
really wear it that often but it is a
really cute piece
there's this green lacy detail and then
the back is like this
cool texture next thing i got was
this sporty tank top it's this pretty
i don't really know what color this is
this pretty like
purplish blue color and it has a
razorback i wear this for
tennis it is from champion in a size
medium just another basic tank
moving on to like the jeans section i
have
this armyish green jacket
jean jacket from calvin klein this
is in a size medium i was so excited
when i found this because it like
actually fits me and it's like a cute
crop like it's not fully cropped but it
is
a cute crop i'm pretty sure i got this
for like under
ten dollars at goodwill all of like my
actual thrifted things are from goodwill
next i have this jean jacket i just
thought i got everything from goodwill
but i actually got this
from thailand when i was studying abroad
there from this place called
cool monkey it was like right across
from my apartment building it is this
cute little denim
it's like a light wash it's kind of a
stretchy material
it's from the brand global works in a
size medium it was 300 baht so it was 10
in the u.s next i have my only pair of
actual jeans that i have ever thrifted
so
it is these they look really big because
they are really big
i had to resize them because they
wouldn't fit my waist
so i have like stitching here stitching
in the back
and then stitching here just to cinch it
in at the waist
they're cute little mom jean
type of things i cuffed the bottoms and
i would normally wear this with a belt
because even though i
stitched the sides up it's still a
little big it's a really really good
material
there was a little patch in the back so
i took that off
so i'm guessing this was like the
original color of the denim this is just
what it looks like now thrifting jeans
is
very hard for me because i just don't
like the way
jeans fit and i'm trying to get into
like mom jeans and like bag your jeans
but they just don't look good on me i
see pictures of like
these type of outfits okay and then i
try it on and like
i don't look like that but that is okay
so that is it for my video i hope you
guys enjoyed
please thrift instead of supporting fast
fashion fast fashion is the second
leading cause of pollution in the world
next to the oil industry
also because most items of clothing are
produced in countries such as china
and bangladesh their main type of energy
source is coal which is
the most polluting energy source so
please don't support fast fashion go
thrifting it's a unique experience you
get unique clothes
and it's cheap thank you guys so much
for watching i hope you guys enjoyed
make sure to give this video a like and
subscribe if you haven't already i will
see you guys
hopefully soon bye guys love ya
foreign