no
no my microphones stand
[Music]
hi it's annabelle it's nice to see you
again i can't wait to catch up through
this q a
um thank you to everybody who submitted
questions
also in the description you can jump to
specific questions or come back to them
i think the easiest thing to start off
with many people are excited to
learn about bambi and prairie how
they're doing i expected that prairie
would be very standoffish
i said give her a week i think it really
only took her
four days we were at lillis for the
first week
when i had to organize my storage unit
but i don't want to
explain all of that process to in detail
because the vlog is coming out next week
show not tell right good news is after
we settled into
this new york space three days or so
they were already playing
chasing each other grooming each other
and i think like the only step left is
for them to cuddle i was a little bit
worried whether or not they would feel
disappointed or cabin fever from being
in
this studio apartment bambi's been
living in a two-bedroom
two-story house for a year and even my
sisters are kind of
put up at apartment is bigger it's a
huge downgrade
but i do keep in mind just like what i
feel
would be healthy i almost got
another studio apartment with no view
right off the bat i just had a bad
feeling about that place my sister was
just like this
jeopardizes cat vitality or something
like that maybe i can
take them out on walks again but from
experience
neither of them liked it very much i
don't think that the space is actually
too small for
the three of us here because like
they're two tiny cats
and i make sure that there's plenty of
perching spots for them whether it be
like
all over this couch they have their own
couch they have the castle
the table top and the bed and they love
to switch out their resting spots
and they kind of have like this routine
maybe i'll do a day in the life of
prairie and bambi one day on to me
what am i most excited about living in
new york
explore more of the city of course and
to
make new friends i've been really
anxious
all my life when it comes to making
friends and i have a really
great set of friends how do i say we're
not like in a big group or anything
i have really strong one-on-one bonds
but now that i'm an adult and
self-employed it's just a lot harder to
meet people right one of the reasons why
i wanted to move here is the culture
and the arts scene and like maybe i
could get a studio residency and just be
more hands-on
yeah in terms of that living in new york
eating and exploring cool
oh you know what clubbing i've never
gone to a club or like even a party
where i'm like
my sister has a lot more expertise than
me
so luckily she doesn't live far just a
train ride she's gonna come over
and in the uh occasional nights where i
don't sleep
before 10. so i have to figure out how
i'm going to
did i always know i was gonna come to
new york no
there were maybe two or three times i
was like hoping i can come to new york
and even making plans or looking at
apartments but it never even solidified
in the back of my mind i just sort of if
this dream was a balloon i just kind of
let it go and
watched it flow far away in the sky i
was like it's okay
it doesn't have to be my life i'm proud
of myself for being here
i'm never bored when i was reading the
book flow they were kind of saying
you don't want to be in a state of
either boredom or anxiety you want to
find
flow i'm always on the anxiety side but
occasionally
i do find that nice flow and i enjoy my
day
when i plan it out nicely do i miss home
i've not been here long enough to feel
homesick i really enjoy the independence
i'm sure as time goes
on i will begin to miss my family but
now that i'm not in school
i okay i've been having extreme brain
farts i don't know what happened here i
meant to say
now that i'm out of school my schedule
doesn't have to work around going home
only on holiday breaks which is nice
do i miss home it definitely gets quiet
sometimes at night
i kind of just get myself in a mood to
really enjoy the evening
and like take it slow and stuff i can
make videos about this
if you're interested in terms of just
being homesick in general i moved around
so much growing up
i never feel attached to any one place i
used to be a lot more attached to
objects
which have has changed recently but like
i think what i have the hardest time
letting go of are like memories
of a time where things were once like
this
and they would never be like that again
my yeah yeah which is
my wait what paternal
grandfather and i had a really close
relationship and he's
he passed away from cancer a long time
ago i had
some of the most happiest memories um
of my life so i still
ruminate on a lot of those memories it's
like equal parts
sorrow and joy so here in new york do i
feel free or released
the main difference is being able to do
things
by my own schedule cooking my own meals
right like my grandma's not there to
take care of me
but at the same time i won't feel the
pressure and the guilt
to say like i need to eat dinner an hour
later like organize my time
without needing to explain myself has
definitely saved
some mental energy but at the same time
it was never
too bad because living in my family
house
it was really comfortable the only huge
difference is like the first time
i went grocery shopping i was just like
what the [ __ ] living at home for a year
has like screwed me over
because i completely forgot my meal plan
it's been a long time since i've shopped
for myself i definitely don't think i'm
gonna stay in new york forever
the way i eventually want to live my
life maybe have like a little store
or a cafe and have like a nice
quiet home with my family and i can't
afford anywhere
like near new york city i just don't
think
that's realistic here the worst parts of
living alone
having to face the crises all by
yourself
at school you know those nights where
the cats would catch this mouse maybe
one was missing its head or whatever you
know you have to pick it up yourself
so i've been paying for my own bills
since i moved out of my college dorm the
only main things
i rely on my mom for is phone like we're
still on a family
phone plan other responsibilities that
i'm going to look into
that i haven't previously done is like
renters insurance
cat health insurance we don't have
dental insurance
so i'm going to have to go like i have a
cavity
uh poopy parts of being an adult of
course but inevitable
probably gonna have to spend 300 on that
cavity lilith doesn't live so far from
me she's in rhode island still
and she's gonna take the train in next
week and i'm gonna see her so i'm
excited it kind of reminds me of the
gilmore girls
uh intro song all you have to do is
call my name and i'll be there
on the next train where you lead
i will follow anywhere
that you tell me to i can go and visit
hair and a train
anytime so in terms of my current job
uncertainty
what the hell i'm doing how many jobs am
i juggling so the
main thing i'm doing is youtube
full-time and my shop i would say i
spend
equal energy on both of those and then i
run my patreon
i have like a little bit over 400
amazing patrons
that have stuck with me even though i've
been the most unproductive
ass in the last three months in the
beginning
i was like overworking myself i don't
know like just needing to prove
something to myself i think
do i fear the uncertainty of this
self-employment
yes yes every
day every waking moment
you know i haven't been as active on
youtube
i appreciate when people say they miss
me on youtube because i'm just like it
makes me realize
that i used to be a lot more productive
so as soon as i cover all my bases
like make a nice spreadsheet of my
financials
i want to make enough for savings then
we can talk about
um like what do you call it like
expendable income it's worth it for me
yes i can be saving like thousands of
dollars by living at home
but like not only is being in the
suburbs just
too it's like drying me out full on
spongebob in the spongebob movie
bird needs to leave the nest as one of
my friends
put it and a viewer asked me a sort of
personal question about
if they should go into engineering
because it ensures
their livelihood in the future because
if they instead major in their passion
which is literature like maybe they
would be unemployed and struggling i
guess my advice would be ask yourself
could you imagine yourself being happy
doing engineering if you had to
go into work five days a week probably
four decades
doing this field could you actually be
happy with it because if you're pretty
content
and you can get a stable livelihood then
you can definitely take
classes or go back to school for your
passion but
if you just if you cannot like go on
living like that
which is kind of how i feel about why
i needed to pursue art full-time even if
it means like
a life of uncertainty like to me that
rigor is really worth it but also if you
want to get a degree
in literature and you feel like you
might not immediately find a job
related to your field that's so normal
even people
who graduate with stem backgrounds might
end up somewhere not even in
remotely related to their actual major
if i were to get a stem job well
i am very passionate about biology i've
always enjoyed biology
i used to think i would be great as a
nurse i realize i'm kind of faint when
it comes to thinking about like surgery
or like injuries so i actually don't
think i would be great
dream job okay would be some sort of
biologist
and i get to go in the field to research
marine biology
or just ecosystems in general i've seen
organizations that
do rescue and animal rehabilitation or
is that like a veterinarian
field or a mix of both some of you might
know that toby
ran away last month and that was really
unexpected and
totally messed up my shop or operations
because i kind of just shut down for a
few
months for a few days and during those
days one of the things i did was watch
our planet on netflix
and i've always loved animal
documentaries and i really liked that
one too
i just never got the chance there were
some scary parts like seeing
an unbalanced ecosystem way too many of
like this one species and how that
affects other species
it was just super insightful and quite
inspiring at the end
okay so how am i really
i thought i would be a lot more concise
when answering this question but
in general i'm doing uh like
i'm i just realized how much work i have
to do on myself and it's cool my mental
health has been
so bad for so long i didn't even notice
when you're not really thinking about it
and you have coping mechanisms that like
act as crutches for you to be able to be
high functioning at the things that you
need to get by with
there's no more pretending admitting to
myself hey i actually don't feel okay at
all about this
why do i think that and i'm packing it i
found
pretty cool books that have been helpful
podcasts but
finally i i'm going back to therapy
yesterday i signed up for it i'm trying
a service i haven't done before
so i'm still waiting to get matched to a
specific counselor
and start the session i just hope that
all around my mental state will improve
and that could impact my productivity
how do you really expect anyone to be
thriving with the year that we've had
so i give myself a break in terms of
that but like also
hey how can i make the best with what
i'm given that's sort of
what i'm trying to do right now so i've
been having a long art block for a long
time
and yes i question my abilities am i
doing enough
am i as good as i think or i just
question that all the time
one of the ways to calm down a little
bit is to get off social media when
you're on the explore page sometimes
you find so many inspiring people and
that
fires you up and you want to paint but
other times it
totally over stimulates me and i just
get into this paralyzed like
huh i can't do anything just a few
decades ago
we weren't exposed to so many hundreds
and thousands of different
people living different lives so in our
head we kind of compart
to mentalize all of these internet
strangers
always thinking that other people are
doing
and being more productive than us that
they're struggling less thriving way
more than us
and that we're falling behind seeing
like my peers sometimes i love seeing
their illustrations
sometimes it just makes me question
myself feel like i'm getting nowhere
i do feel like right now i'm nowhere
like as in
i don't really know where
i want to go my life because
in college i have this huge dream that
was
shattered like i became really
disillusioned i started school
wanting to do textiles for fashion and i
wanted to do
fashion because i was just one person
and that person just doesn't exist
anymore like i'm not that person anymore
so it does make me question like do i
want to
even work for a fashion company because
the person who
wanted to work for a fashion company
thought that her life was going to be
like this
i really want to work on illustration
because see if i didn't do
fashion and if i never pursued that
career i would want to do
storytelling probably animation
or write graphic novels um my muse
currently
they're my cats i'm freaking cat
creature i live with two
of the most charming little things and
i've been sketching my cats a lot and
i'm prepared to see a lot of cat
paintings because i'm just like hey
i have an artist blog what do i do i'm
just gonna paint my cat like there's no
tomorrow
and maybe one day i will expand my
visual vocabulary do i want to continue
doing textiles
yes even if i don't want to do it on
like a corporate level
a freaking textiles is like the most
magical thing ever if you learn the
craft
of textiles whether it be weaving
crocheting knitting
dying i would never regret having
learned
what i have learned and the appreciation
for textiles
i love it i have a knitting machine i
purchased from a friend that i haven't
started using
so expect some knitting struggles from
me
sometimes to calm myself i think about
me as a 60 year old as an 80 year old
i'll probably be making art
that speaks to me a lot more time is
just such a gift every day is such a
gift
your health your body is a gift don't
don't forget that
don't let the fast-paced world the
consumer's capitalist world like
convince you that you're never enough or
you'll never get there
not feeling as rushed and knowing like i
have the time to get
there someday even if it takes me
decades given that i will be blessed
with a long life i hope to live into
three digits
you're right that the world is still
around and not burned to the ground
by that time what will my art be then so
in that sense i'm not so worried about
where i'm going and how many skills i
will obtain because
every day is just a new opportunity to
improve those skills to learn more
lastly the miscellaneous stuff
has my style changed i'm kind of at this
blank
canvas point in my life where like you
know my hair's grown out now it's all
natural
the funniest thing is that i kind of
miss having damaged
dyed hair because when it was kind of
dry and crispy it had some
texture i need some volume you realize
that my head is extra small
when i was in middle school i had an
inside joke with a guy who i called
bigfoot
right before puberty his feet started
growing faster than the rest of his body
so
i called him bigfoot every time i saw
him he called me small head he'll be
like bigfoot
small head so i'm excited i think i'm
reinventing myself
definitely want to make a glow up video
i really enjoy watching those
as well as transformation videos i still
haven't transformed myself into my high
school self
i saw uh some footage and i was like
i was sexy when i was a minor look at me
now i like your hair
i quite enjoy how my dark hair looks the
last time i had long black hair was when
i was 15
so it's been a long time i might as well
try try to see if i can grow it out
and before i had a lot of it thinned out
due to
the trendy layer cut at the time
everyone was getting their
tips thinned out so i want to see how
nice and thick my hair might look like
hopefully it won't be too
flat and maybe i can even donate my hair
if i could resist myself from dying it
we'll see
lastly i just want to talk about music
for one hot second what's my favorite
song of the moment
okay so in the last couple months
i really fell in love with joji sad
songs about love um
yeah i i really enjoyed joji's albums i
can't remember the name of it was it
broadcast like the album name i like
nectar i have that one
dan's slow dancing in the dark which is
the most
famous track i also love claire oh a lot
immunity is wonderful but her ep uh her
favorite song from her is hello
that song just makes me wanna go like
play the song to me dancing just now
what was my favorite song from lana del
rey's new album i actually
just listened to it for the first time
this morning
i didn't like it as much as i thought it
would however i find that
all lana songs i have to listen to it a
lot and it will grow on me and then i'll
become obsessed with it like exactly a
year and a half after the release date a
lot of the songs
seem super similar whereas i feel like
in her previous albums
they all had their own story whereas
this one was like the whole album was a
continuous
song in a way with different chapters so
my favorite song as of now
is probably not all those who wander
lost or yosemite
and again this is gonna change
because from norman [ __ ] rockwell my
favorite song
was cherry wait was bartender
and then now it's probably
mariner's apartment complex for sure
those are all the questions for today
it's getting hot and i don't shave my
pits i had fun catching up with you
thank you for keeping me company i feel
a lot better because with this last week
i've just been
with everything that's going on in
current events i want to talk about a
fundraiser that i'm doing
the link is right there in the
description and just by
announcing it on instagram in the last
day we've raised 1500
which is incredible i made this nice
painting of bambi sleeping
need a little bit of peace and con one
winner is gonna be drawn in a week it's
open worldwide the shipping is included
so in order to enter it's five dollars
minimum to purchase an entry ticket
or you can share it on a social platform
i think
for one free entry and the drawing would
be generated on
better world the organization 100 of
profits are going to
be donated to the asian american pacific
islander
community relief fund so i hope that
doing this video would
notify some people who don't follow me
on instagram also if you
are not interested in getting this
painting because you just don't like it
you can also
donate to other organizations and
gofundmes of members of the aapi
community
so you don't have to actually use my
fundraiser but i just wanted to let you
know that's happening
and yeah i'll see you pretty soon next
week is gonna be
the moving vlog until then take care
goodbye
bambi doesn't normally chill over here
by the toaster i just put him there
because i almost
filmed the video with that backdrop with
this
cat tree
over here
uh