[Music]
what's up you guys it's Joelle and
welcome back to my channel
today I'm starting a new series on my
channel that I want to start for quite a
while I'm going to be calling it the
best life and this was inspired by Amy
vagabonds the am with Amy where it's
basically like a get ready with me kind
of situation but she also just talks he
talks about things that she's interested
in and stuff that she's been thinking
about lately and can address topics that
you guys requested and stuff like that
so I wanted a format where I could
combine my love for beauty and makeup
and all of that with just the deeper
things because for all of you makeup
lovers I know that there is a lot of
multidimensionality behind what goes on
on your face so I just wanted to provide
a space for that here on YouTube since I
feel like a lot of times you know beauty
gurus can kind of get relegated to only
doing you know beauty cuz of course
that's what they're good at but I
personally love hearing about what
people are thinking about and just
what's going on between their ears
behind all of the stuff that is just
seen on camera the turtle of this series
the best life is inspired by a verse out
of proverbs 3 that I love it's how
verses 3 to flourish and from the
passion translation it reads let your
life be shaped by integrity with truth
written upon your heart that's how
you'll find favor and understanding us
both God and men and you will gain the
reputation of living life well and
personally that is something that I
would love is to be known for living
life well and so a lot of the topics
that I'm going to be discussing in this
series are just you know the everyday
topics of being a human on this planet
and figuring out how to live our best
lives so for my first episode I decided
to really pay tribute to Amy and do her
Asian American tag which she started
this past spring I want to say as so I'm
gonna be answering her questions as they
get ready and I'll have people tagged
down below but if you make youtube
videos and are interested in doing this
tag I invite anyone watching to answer
the questions as well starting with my
face I actually already put on sunscreen
and BB cream and moisturizer today so
I'm just gonna get on into eyes I'm
gonna be putting on my NYX
shadow base to get started and her first
question is what ethnicity are you and I
am Chinese Korean American my mom is
Chinese my dad is Korean for eyeshadow
I'm getting into my Too Faced just
peachy mattes palette that my sister
mica got me thank you very much mica and
this is gonna be your just a really
summery everyday peachy look so I'm
using peach tea I'm gonna use that all
over my lid and the next question is
what generation are you and I am
technically second-generation my dad
moved to the States from Seoul Korea
when he was six but since he grew up in
the States
he's considered like first generation
American I believe I don't Christ me on
that if I'm wrong and my mom is also
first generation because she was born in
the States because her parents moved
here from China when they were around
college-aged next I'm gonna get into
peach punch and I'm gonna put this on
the outer half of my lids okay question
number three is what is the first
experience where you felt the
demarcation of being a minority or
different and I would say I knew all
along that I was considered a minority
because my parents would mention it when
they talked about why we settled down in
San Francisco is that my mom wanted us
to grow up in a place where we wouldn't
really have to experience as much racism
growing up I think I really felt it
regarding to my like specifically
regarding to my race in high school I
went to the same elementary school from
like second grade to eighth grade but
when I went to high school I was when I
was you know kind of cognizant enough
and I was gonna be around new people
and my sister had already begun at that
high school and she was telling you
about like the social groups and how
there was like how people would self
separate segregate and there is like a
group of the cool cool Asians and then
the nerdy Asians literally like Mean
Girls and I was like well how do I get
to be with like the cool Asians like
what's the difference between being a
cool Asian a nerdy Asian like I don't
really know what that means and she's
like well like the nerdy is like kind of
quiet they're like pretty book smart and
just keep to themselves and with that I
did
super self-conscious as I began to say
that high school because I was like oh
no people are just gonna take one look
at me and IRA me like she's a nerdy
Asian cuz I was a nerdy I was very nerdy
in middle school and I just felt like
people are going to pinpoint me from the
very beginning as being super quiet and
never give me the chance to become one
of their friends I choose this moment
rather than you know that moment in
middle school when someone makes fun of
my lunch or something because I honestly
don't think I really put it together
that it was because my food was
different or like I was minority than
they were laughing I was just like well
that's weird you don't like good food
but like whatever but I think it's
because I was so lucky to grow up in
such a diverse place was that I was with
a lot like I literally went to middle
school in downtown Chinatown of San
Francisco so like sure people could be
rude and be like oh my gosh Oh like what
is that it was literally mon Dieu or pot
stickers you can buy them at Costco like
come on I literally saw as their problem
not mine and I was like okay I'm sorry
like I'll try to make it smell less but
I'm still gonna eat it cuz like you live
in San Francisco how can you like how
can you be like this oh yeah I mean just
to follow up with like the high school
thing thankfully after I got to high
school I was like super extra brewed I
was like the most talkative like funny
silly bubbly person I tried I could
possibly D so that people win it
immediately pinpoint me as like a quiet
Asian and like in a weird sad way to be
honest it worked like people likes me
they didn't see me and like delegate me
to the group of like quiet Asian girls
but I realized later on that I was like
why I being like this like it I of
course like I wanted to be close with
everyone and I wanted to be friendly but
I realized was coming out of a place of
insecurity of being you know stereotyped
incorrectly rather than just being my
like true authentic self and then
throughout the rest of high school from
like junior to senior year I was like
you know I'm gonna be friendly but I can
just be myself
and relax I don't need to feel like I'm
compensating so in a weird way I wasn't
changing so much what I was doing but it
was coming from a different motivation
of being authentic and being a good
person rather than trying to make people
see me a certain way and it was so much
healthier and I was so much less
exhausted
and yeah I was so thankful that it came
to that like revelation Oh another thing
that I would do in high school though
was that I would constant like right
starting freshman year oh no super
insecure was that I would always make
Asian jokes about myself before
something else could like I would assume
that if I was talking about my grades or
that I play piano I'd be like oh yeah
you know cuz I'm Asian so like we just
do that and it wasn't till one of my
friends who's half Chinese pointed out
and he was like Joe well like why do you
always point it's being Asian like you
know people aren't always gonna assume
that you're doing these things cuz
you're Asian and it really took him
calling me out to be like oh wow like
I'm internalizing it like this is
internalized racism like I am so afraid
of someone making fun of me that I feel
the need to make fun of myself and call
myself out for being Asian as if it's a
bad thing
so they don't have to do it first and
after that I was like I need to stop and
that was really good wake-up call so if
you ever see this love you dude thank
you so I put the pink on my lower lash
line upper lash line and I think when
you say I take peach sangria and use a
little bit of it to deepen up the outer
corner but next question is were you
always proud of your heritage or was
there a time where you rejected it and I
would say at that time in high school
when I felt like I am a classic model
minority which is a myth for anyone who
hasn't seen Amy's video on this go watch
it until one about the model minority
myth I felt like I needed to compensate
for me being Asian even though I
shouldn't have seen it as a weakness I
did and I was super unhealthy and I
didn't necessarily want to reject it I
would still do what I was naturally
going to do but I felt like I had to be
okay with like taking a hit for it
almost like socially that people look
down on me when really I shouldn't have
expected that that's just not the
reality that we should live with and
internalized course number five what are
some stereotypes you struggle with I
would say that I struggle a lot less now
with stereotypes I think one thing I do
still kind of struggle with is like
being compared with other Asian girls
like I think going to a predominantly
white college it's really easy for like
Asian girls to be you know kind of
next to each other especially if they
have similar interests and whatnot and
just being like okay who's like the
superior asian girl or who's the
prettier asian girl and I definitely
struggle with that especially in my
sophomore year where I felt like after
rushing and enjoying a sorority like I
felt like that was you know Augmented
just me being compared to other Asian
girls because there was like some sort
of quota that Greek houses were trying
to fit because Greek houses can be
racist but I think I've gotten over that
a lot first after taking a gap year what
you can hear all about my gap year vlogs
so this is really messy as you can tell
but I'm gonna blend it out with blending
brush and that makes everything better
but going back to the stereotype thing
when I was younger I definitely
struggled with being like the goody
two-shoes a lot and I felt really
self-conscious in like middle school
that like I know I was just so nerdy and
I did everything right and I felt like
it was a bad thing I felt like people
were gonna call me out for because I was
Asian and instead of giving me credit
for it and being like wow that's really
impressive that you can like play piano
and you get good grades and all of that
they just be like well it's just cuz
you're Asian and I was so annoyed that I
was not getting credit for hard work
because it was being just thrown on my
race and that actually connects to the
model minority myth that Asians are you
know somehow genetically
good at things and it really discredits
a lot of Asians for what they've done
and what they've contributed to society
and also is really good at causing
division between minorities when there
should not be any and it's really good
for causing division between Asians when
they feel like they don't fit into the
model minority myth and I feel like they
failed in some way next I'm gonna take a
little bit of peaches and cream and just
throw that on the center of my lids and
next to line my eyes I'm gonna use milk
makeups shadow liner in the shade BP
just a brown color question number six
is can you speak your language so for me
that would be Chinese or Cantonese and
Korean I cannot unfortunately which is
something that I'm really sad about but
I've been trying to learn Korean
last year a little bit I went on a
missions trip to Korea and I picked up
some words and I can kind of like read a
little bit in Hangul but I'm really bad
at it but my boyfriend's Korean and he
helps me out try to learn a few words
question number seven is husby engaging
American affected your relationship with
your parents and I think it definitely
affected a little more when I was
younger my mom wasn't a create like a
legit tiger mom but she was a little
tiger mom ish you know definitely
whipped us into shape but I was honestly
very thankful for it like I said I was a
goody two-shoes kid my parents are both
first generation and grew up in the
States and can speak perfect English and
I'm really thankful for that that we
never had communication issues but
definitely you know generational values
that they grew up with or a lot harsher
and more strict than what we see as
Americans we were just like no other
family or no other kids have to follow
these kinds of rules like doing the next
year's math over the summer before the
school year or just strictness and how
we had to dress and stuff like that but
at the same time I think I was really
I'm really thankful that I saw the value
and everything my parents did and wanted
us to do and also my my family is very
strongly Christian and I think that
really helped interestingly my parents
got less strict as they became more
Christian because the stuff that they
wanted us to focus on became very
different so rather than being so
concerned about math and reading and
scores and stuff they're like okay we
want you to be happy we want you to grow
up we want you to grow up loving God and
knowing your identity and knowing that
you're valued so we're gonna focus on
that and that was honestly so so helpful
for my relationship with my parents and
I'm so thankful for it on the other hand
going up Asian American has definitely
made my relationship with my
grandparents and extended family very
interesting especially my grandparents
just like a lot of different values I
know there's a lot of racism also in
especially in Korean culture I know
that's obviously not true of all Koreans
but it's just like a thing there's a lot
of pride in like your nationality which
is awesome but also it can result in
like discrimination against people who
are not Korean so I
a half chinese half Korean family that
obviously can cause some issues as you
can imagine my trip to Korea was
honestly so like super healing of that
and I feel like God just like did a lot
my heart that trip to like give me
empathy and show where their time from
and also show that it's like something
that like they grew up with just
historically through Wars through
whatever and it's also got a lot better
where they don't openly show as much
discrimination towards Chinese people so
oh that's good
course number eight is how do you feel
about your heritage now do you identify
with it and I would say I've definitely
throughout college high school and
college going to be a lot more vocal
about like my Asian pride I guess I've
learned a lot more about specifically
what it means to be Chinese or Korean
American through friends and through
just life education and growing up and
realizing that it's something so
valuable to hold on to I also feel like
my relationship with God has also helped
me to really just acknowledge the fact
that I was made intentionally like me
being half chinese half Korean was by
God's design and that I should look for
the strengths and that which to me is I
have the opportunity to help represent
and help elevate people of color and
other Asian American girls help push the
Asian American representation forward
through media through education and
whatever and though it can definitely be
seen as like a burden I'm like you know
what like if that is what something
God's called me to I'm gonna take it and
run with it
sorry I totally just stop saying yes
what I'm doing but next I'm gonna
contour with my Too Faced cocoa contour
palette and Amy's last question number
nine is what is your favorite thing
about being Asian American slash your
heritage I would say I love that I feel
like I have something to bring to the
table I love that I have a family with a
history and I love the values of Asian
culture of working hard and those are
things that are kind of often lost in
Western culture I love the art and
aesthetics of Asian culture both Chinese
and Korean I love the food both Chinese
and Korean I don't know I feel like it
gives me something about myself that
provides community in a really
full way just you know uniting with
other asian-americans and also just
something to protect as I get older
since America is this amazing wonderful
melting pot of cultures but there's also
like the integrity of it that I've
started to learn the value of as we
become a culture of like you know the
mixing pot and whatever that it's really
important to see the distinction and
hold on to the history of what it means
to be Korean American or Chinese
American and I'm actually gonna answer
one bonus question because I get this
question a lot and that is do you feel
more Chinese or more Korean having grown
up as you know a mixed Chinese
korean-american as I'm putting on this
blush from was this from the faceshop
it's just a really peachy blush Dee with
her
peachy makeup look and I actually
personally so I grew up in San Francisco
go there's a huge huge tiniest
population and so I grew up with a lot
more Chinese culture I was also largely
raised by my mom who was Chinese my dad
worked a lot and I sought to say that he
wasn't present in my life but like the
value systems and like the ways of
thinking the food that my mom prepared
was largely Chinese so I feel like I
grew up with a lot of Chinese influence
not even realizing it just cuz it was so
normal like we would go to the Chinese
grocery store and we would make wontons
together and you know stuff like that
you know we got Chinese New Year off for
school because it was such a big there's
such a big Chinese population also
highlighting with a face job highlighter
but as I've gone to college I've gotten
to get to know a lot more Koreans and
learn what it even means to be
korean-american I literally didn't grow
up around any Korean Americans until
college like high school there was one
of the Korean Roland and we never went
to a Korean Church what we did but I was
like an infant so it's been really cool
getting to know what it means to be
Korean I would say it's really hard like
I don't ever want to choose one and say
that like oh I feel more Korean or more
Chinese and just kind of ignore the
other one but I would say they came into
my lives at very different points in
time just because of the environment I
was in and the people I was around but I
would say they're both equally valuable
to me and you know my parents are both
equally valuable to me and
different influences on me personality
wise and culturally are both really
important and play I think equally heavy
roles so I'd say I'm pretty even split
as boring of an answer as that is a
whoops I forgot my lip color oh my gosh
okay I'm just using siren by Revlon okay
I first discovered this lipstick because
Jenin talked about it when she was like
a college student
so thanks Jen okay now here is the final
look that I'm sporting today even though
it is literally 5 p.m. thank you guys so
much for watching I hope you enjoyed
just hearing my sponsors to these
questions and kind of getting ready with
me today give me a thumbs up if you
enjoyed this series as well as leave
some comments down below just your
thoughts on are you Asian American
what's your experience are you minority
immigrant child of immigrants let me
know it love to hear about you guys and
again let me know if you do this tag you
are all tagged but yes thank you so much
for watching I love you all jesus loves
you and i'll see you in the next one
peace
[Music]
you