I'd always get the questions like do you
ever want to meet your real parents do
you ever want to go back do you know how
to speak Chinese do you ever wonder if
you have siblings or not I'm freaking
out because I think I'm stressed out
about this video and I'm talking about a
lot of things that are kind of
controversial and just things that
sometimes people don't think about and
you want to make sure that you don't
portray it in the wrong light so and
also we got Cheerios and a low bun so
you know things are about to get real hi
everyone my name is Kari and welcome to
our YouTube channel today's video is
something that I've really been looking
forward to filming and playing that I've
been seeing going around on YouTube
growing up Asian growing up Asian
American let's talk about growing up
Asian American various titles and I'll
leave some of my favorite ones right
here and down below but I also wanted to
use this time as may is Asian Pacific
American Heritage Month I really wanted
to film this and get it out because it
is timely and also include what it's
like to be adopted I think that there's
a lot of amazing Asian American
youtubers way more than I ever saw
growing up I remember watching Close
Encounters genom and Michelle Phan and
Phan Michelle Phan and those were like
the only two and even then you know they
weren't as dark as me they had Asian
parents and I loved watching their
videos don't get me wrong but I think it
is important to share adoptee stories
because there is a lot that comes with
it so I think there are questions that
Asian Americans are asked all the time
you know like where are you really from
oh say something in Chinese Korean
Japanese and you're just like or they
like yell me how to you and you're just
like please stop but I am also here to
probe and answer question
based on my experience of people
frequently asking you ever want to meet
your real parents Oh like what time were
you born in Cary uh I don't know because
I don't know my real birthday so this
video goes in chronological order of my
life just to give context as to how
young I was and the challenges that I
was facing because I think that when you
are adopted when you're much younger you
don't really think about you know what
people say as much or you don't realize
how much it affects you until you're
older I also interviewed my friends in
my adoption group and the adoption group
is basically just a group of girls who
were also adopted from the same part of
China and live in the same geographical
area as me right now obviously some have
moved around but it's been amazing that
we can still stay in touch so there'll
be clips from them throughout this video
because I wanted to get their
perspective and see what it was like for
them also because obviously not
everyone's experiences are the same so
let me begin by saying that being
asian-american has its own complex
feelings and then being adopted has
difficult challenges and I'm still
definitely processing how I feel about a
lot of things I also don't want it to
come across that if you don't check
these boxes or you don't feel the same
way that I do or how my friends in my
adoption group feel then that
invalidates your feelings because it
absolutely does not everyone has
different experiences and ways of
processing with that this video was very
personal and vulnerable to film so I
hope you will enjoy and if you do be
sure to give this video a thumbs up
subscribe and let's get into the video
so I'm just gonna begin with some
background information basically I was
adopted from China when I was 14 months
old and the reason why I was adopted
mostly was because of the one-child
policy
in certain tik-tok right here it all
started my mom met my dad I don't know
if they were in love but then they had
me then China had a one-child policy and
they wanted a boy so they didn't want me
then I was left on the street and put up
for adoption then two white people from
America came and adopted me then two
years later we went back and adopted my
younger sister hi I'm Eleanor and my
life it's kind of crazy
also when my parents want to adopt me
they said that the local people living
in the village caught us when we were
babies they called us lucky babies my
mom said that the translator made that
very clear wherever they went when they
were holding the babies they saw these
white people with these Asian babies
they called them lucky because I was
adopted when I was fourteen months old
the only thing that I remember has been
American influenced besides my godmother
who is Japanese she would make me congee
she would make me authentic Asian dishes
growing up because my stomach at that
time could not handle like McDonald's or
Burger King my parents told me that the
night that they got me in the hotel room
they got McDonald's and I threw up from
eating french fries because I wasn't
used to the grease so when they came
back they realized that Bonnie my
godmother knew how to cook dishes like
that and it was really comforting to
have her in my life also being adopted
was never really in question because my
parents would read me childhood books
that had to do with adoption like a fox
would adopt a chicken and it would all
be good so
Cody you want my milk
[Applause]
[Music]
so elementary school was confusing as it
is for any kid but I think it was also
because I was in a predominately white
suburban area and I only had one other
Asian friend and she was Indonesian so
she really looked like me but
nonetheless I could definitely tell that
my white friends would get whatever they
wanted and for some reason I could just
tell that teachers would treat them
differently and I think that teachers
would have like microaggressions to me
like about being good at math or like
expecting things for me and I can't
pinpoint any specific examples but I
really do remember feeling a little bit
clouded at that time and not really
understanding what it meant to have a
different skin color or maybe have
smaller eyes and everyone else I know
that's not very helpful but I think that
when you're little as a kid you don't
think that much into things like that
and you may not realize how much of a
lasting impact they have on you when I
saw I think jazz you talked about this I
was like yes girl like oh my god when
you're little you want to wake up white
so badly like I subconsciously
definitely did and for the longest time
I thought that I was white like I
thought that I should be treated like I
had white skin blond hair like I have
these white parents my white brother
point is is that I would wake up and
want to be white which is so messed up
and this is embarrassing to say probably
like 7 years old I was like oh I have
blond hair like my parents are white I
have a white brother like why am I being
treated differently like why do people
expect me to be good at these things
like X Y Z you know the classic like
Asian stereotypes and I did not
understand why it mattered so much if I
was different you know what I mean like
obviously I looked in the mirror and I
was like okay I don't really like look
like my parents but I didn't understand
the concept of race which really does
any like six 7 year old I don't know for
so long when I was a little I did not
want to resemble any Asian elements in
my life like I wanted to have big eyes I
want to tap curly hair I wanted to be
the exact opposite of what I was which
is so messed up and crazy to think about
that I wanted that I think it was also
because london tipton on suite life of
zack & cody we loved brenda song we do
but I think it was because her character
was portrayed as dumb she
was rich she didn't really have to think
for herself and she was so well liked
like she was still popular and whatever
but it's what you do when the only
person that you see on TV that kind of
looks like you and even then does it
really is that so
I feel awkward now again I don't want to
offend anyone this is just my personal
experience so we're gonna go on to still
elementary school because there's a lot
packed in in elementary school for
Chinese New Year my mom would bring in
clementines and traditional Chinese New
Year decorations and you know when
you're young and it's your birthday and
you get to go out and like deliver
cupcakes or whatever to teachers and
other friends in different classes
that's what I did but twice a year once
for my birthday and then once for
Chinese New Year's so I loved it I
really enjoyed this because I gotta have
a classroom number one but also I could
definitely see my mom trying to
integrate Chinese culture into my life
which I appreciate is like I said
adoption was not in question and yeah
like I said I didn't have a concept of
what I really look like but I knew that
I was adopted but I didn't I didn't
match up like I didn't match up being
adopted did not looking like my pair
this is so hard to talk about oh my god
they didn't put together that like being
adopted with my white parents who looked
like my other friend's parents and
everything I understand why me being
adopted from a different country would
result in other people expecting me to
have habits from somebody who grew up in
China I don't think that that's really a
crazy thought I don't know if that made
sense I hope it did we're just gonna go
on to the next point so kids are really
curious and I'd always get the questions
like do you ever want to meet your real
parents or your biological parents do
you ever want to go back do you know how
to speak Chinese do you ever wonder if
you have siblings or not these are all
valid questions I would say it's just
because of how frequently I got them
that when I grew up I was just like oh
my god like please stop asking me these
questions
between ons the first point and I don't
want to get too dark but this is gonna
get a little dark does anyone know how
impossible it is to find two people that
are a still alive or two both know about
the pregnancy or three there's just one
point four billion people in China
I guess person was just really off put
it by this question because it felt like
people didn't see my parents my my
parents as my real parents when I did
and that's kind of all that matters and
I know that some adoptees have found
their birth parents and want to and
that's great and I know that there's a
bunch of technology like 23andme and
ancestry that you can go and find these
people or at least siblings or cousins
and that's great also at the same time I
had to think what that would do to my
parents um I think that they genuinely
would have supported me if I wanted to
find my birth parents but it's not like
they wouldn't be hurt and I don't think
that I would want to put myself through
that hurt or hurt them I know obviously
everyone's parents are different but I
think that when you go looking for your
biological parents at least in China you
have to be prepared for kind of more
dark morbid thoughts and I'm not saying
that for every person but I think that
you don't want to go in there and have
these ideas of what your parents were
like and then have that come crushing
down like not to be dramatic but I don't
think it's all roses and rainbows and I
think at least personally for me it's
not like something that I want to
explore and you guys like going through
that process for me it's just too much
and I'm happy with the life I live now
I'm grateful and uh I watched an
adoption documentary that my one friend
posted and I will link it down below but
it was really interesting to see and it
was kind of the first thing that I've
seen about like adoption and you know
the effects of the one-child policy on
other people other than me or people in
my adoption group so I would definitely
link that
I feel the same like Naomi how you said
like when you get to the birthdays I was
like this probably isn't my real
birthday so why am i skipping the
birthday right now I just think about
like for weeks going on like this we're
out there at this coz so that gets me
the most cuz I don't know when it is a
conversation that's kind of hard to play
into as a kid is oh what time were you
born like I was born at 11:58 and 3/4 of
a second and I'm just like I don't
actually know when my real birthday is
well as adoptees the orphanage will
typically estimate when you are born but
you won't actually know your real
birthday and definitely not the time
that you were born that's just something
that's like funny to me now and I think
that as a kid I felt ostracized I felt
really left out by that but I think that
was just because I wanted to be like oh
yeah like I know what I was born at this
time I don't know about other people
watching this video but I think it's
definitely weird not to know that the
birthday on your birth certificate is
not technically your birthday like it
could be off by a couple days or max
maybe a week but obviously the month and
everything are for the most part correct
but yeah you you could be celebrating
your birthday on the totally wrong day
you wouldn't know I remember growing up
I would ask my dad like if he thought
that my biological mom was thinking
about me around April 11th and he said
oh she probably thinks about you all the
time and especially during that day I
think that got me down into a rabbit
hole of what-ifs and I started to like
paint a picture of what she was like
then even still to this day I don't get
as emo but I definitely get a little
weird during my birthday at least like a
week before leading up to it because
there's no way that you're gonna stop
thinking about your biological parents
and I definitely don't think of them as
frequently as I did when I was growing
up but you still kind of wonder what
your life would be like and how crazy
your life worked out the way that it did
especially around your birthday
I feel like adoption is a lot about
coming to terms with the unknown
and that's um so dramatic and not here
to like be like Oh like play the violin
for the adoption kids but I'm just like
I feel like I there has not been a voice
in the adoption community as much as I
thought there would be or like growing
up it wasn't like there was a lot of
people to look up to who were adopted so
just know that it's okay to feel weird
for five days out of the 365 day
calendar for your birthday if you're
adopted this is so long oh my gosh reef
we this thing
[Music]