if you are looking for a sign this is
your sign what's up guys welcome back to
my channel it's your girl Nikki aka tan
honey aka your fade Lindo on YouTube
how's everybody doing today I hope you
guys are doing great if you guys are new
to my channel welcome today I have a
special video for my Southeast Asian
girls struggles of a Southeast Asian
girl is a series I started basically
highlighting things that girls like me
go through that we don't talk about but
we should and I started this because I
noticed that on YouTube and just in
social media in general there's
definitely a lot of Asian youtubers and
beauty gurus and influencers but I feel
like most of them are East Asian which
is totally great I'm a supporter of all
Asian girls of all girls in general but
I just felt like there was a lack of
someone who was similar to me in my
first video I talked about being a brown
Asian woman in a world of whitening
products but this video I'm gonna be
talking about Southeast Asian girls and
careers and in particular nursing first
and foremost for anything else I just
want to clarify that nursing is an
amazing job I still think that our ends
are severely underpaid and
underappreciated especially when you
factor in the amount of work they do
compared to like the doctor so many of
my best friends are RNs and they
love it and I think it's a great career
but only if you actually want to be a
nurse one question that I always like
just think about why aren't there more
Asians in the creative field
I feel like Asians are some of the most
creative and inventive people on the
planet like just just look at our food
for God's sake looking at it rationally
most Southeast Asians who are around my
age are probably first generation and it
makes sense because if your parents are
immigrants like mine then you know how
hard they work they came here to another
country speaking little to no English
they are overworked at these stressful
jobs where they don't get paid nearly
enough but they did all of this for us
and they did it so that we wouldn't have
to struggle like they did so it makes
sense why most of them want us to be in
a field where it is going to be stable
and it is always going to be needed I
spent two and a half years in college
doing
Rex for nursing and even though I knew
since high school like oh I'm gonna be a
nurse going to be a nurse anytime I had
to talk about what I was going to be or
what I was working towards
I freaking hated it everyone around me
was so excited to talk about like their
future career and what they were
striving for when it came down to me I
just didn't understand like why do I not
feel the same sense of excitement that
everybody else does I never got a chance
when I was younger like in high school
middle school to really think about like
what is it that I want to do sometimes I
do wish that I figured it out earlier
but you know it's all in God's timing so
I am right where I need to be at this
moment so I'm happy for that but of
course back then I was very very
depressed
I remember at my first serving job there
was this couple that I served and they
really really liked me they were older
so then they were asking me like Oh what
do you want to do it was like my
automatic response oh I want to be a
nurse and I remember they told me like
Oh like where do you want to go and I
was like well of course I want to apply
to Loma Linda because it's pretty much
like the best nursing school in my area
turns out they are good friends with the
Dean of Loma Linda and then they slid me
their number and they were like when you
apply to Loma Linda give us a call and
then we will call up the Dean and let
them know that you're applying it was
pretty much solid like they loved me but
despite all of that you know even though
my grades were good and now I had this
into one of the best programs in
Southern California there was still like
something in my heart that just told me
like no there was just always something
like heavy that still sat with me I
think the best word to describe how I
felt all those years was trapped I
literally felt like I couldn't escape
this life this is the pot that is chosen
for me this is the path I have to follow
no matter what but like I said there was
a time where it came to a crossroad I
was almost done with my prereqs I just
had to take Anatomy and then I could
apply to the nursing programs I'll never
forget that summer I remember I was
taking summer school friend out of me I
called my friend one of my close friends
Miguel love that guy in the gala if
you're watching homie for life till the
day we die called him up and I was like
hey like can I come over so he was like
yeah like I thought you were going to
class
no I mean I need to come over so he's
like okay when I came over and I just
like was so freaking emotional and I
told him like all this stuff that I was
feeling and I was like I have no idea
why and then he was like dude you know
why that just sent me over the edge and
I remember just really thinking about it
yeah I don't want to be a nurse and that
was the first time I ever said that out
loud it was definitely freeing in a way
like being able to say that but it was
like now that I said it it's like oh
where do I go now and obviously the
next step was to tell my parents they
are the reason why I stayed quiet I was
just scared of disappointing them you
know because if like my parents get mad
at me if they like yell at me if they
crowned me if they do anything like that
I can handle that that's fine just the
thought of them being disappointed in me
that was what scared me and that was
what I wanted to avoid completely long
story short not gonna get into that
because I'll probably just start crying
but once I did that it was like this
huge weight lifted off my shoulders and
I felt like I could finally fully be
myself and I'm not gonna lie you know
there are still times where I get
frustrated like even today where it's
like obviously I'm not at the level of
achievement that I want to be at
career-wise and sometimes it just makes
me wonder like what would have happened
if I just stayed in nursing I definitely
would be a lot more financially stable I
wouldn't be working in a restaurant with
bitch-ass customers and I'd definitely
be able to afford a lot of the things
that I wish I could afford now but at
the same time I know that I wouldn't be
happy because even though I am still
building and working towards my dream
career I am so much more happier and
full of life now that girl all those
years ago who was a nursing major she
feels like a stranger to me so on a
lighter note I just want to say that if
you are looking for a sign to go after
your dream job this is your sign you are
not watching this by accident you are
watching this for a reason Southeast
Asian or not take this as your sign and
with that I do want this video to be
helpful as well so I have a few tips
that I want to share with you guys that
I wish I knew the first is to be honest
with yourself in every decision you make
anything you do any choice you make make
sure you are being completely honest and
being true to yourself the second is to
figure out a plan before going cold
turkey yes you should go after what you
want but definitely don't just drop
everything like I'm not telling you to
drop out of university I'm not telling
you to quit your job there's all these
steps in between before you get
to your dream career so figure that out
first that brings me to how to tell your
parents Southeast Asian parents they
want their kids in the end to be happy
but they also want them to be
financially stable so instead of telling
your parents hey mom and dad I'm gonna
quit school and be this piece yeah don't
do that because that's just gonna spur a
lot of arguments you know your parents
better than anyone so know what kind of
questions that they'll ask you know what
kind of things they'll say to you and
then make sure you have a rebuttal for
it that way when you present it to them
you're like hey mom and dad
I don't want to do this anymore instead
I want to do this and here's my plan on
how to get there and how to make money
don't forget to add that last part in
and my third tip that I would want you
guys to take after is to if you can
afford it definitely try to take some
time off to soul-search and what I mean
by that is to travel to try new hobbies
to meet new people to just do
experiences that you never would have
done before and know this is not an
excuse to do a bunch of drugs so that's
not what I'm saying but you will be so
shocked at what you can learn about
yourself when you step out of your
comfort zone before I figure it out oh I
want to be a director I did journalism
on my school newspaper for like a
semester I switched my major to
communications I even went to check out
a culinary school I don't know I want to
be a director until I took a trip to
Thailand and I was like filming
everything and making like a video about
it and I realize like dude I
love this I want to do this all the
time and through that experience
that's how I discovered something about
myself that is very crucial and very
important to me today honestly the most
gut-wrenching part is the crossroads but
like once you make that decision and you
choose to be happy and you choose to do
something for yourself
everything after will be hard work and
it might be tedious but you will be so
much happier because you're finally
pursuing something that you love to do
I'm right there with you guys I know
it's so easy to get discouraged and to
feel like you just want to give up and
when it comes to that just remember that
God has a plan for all of you watching
you guys are not here by accident you're
here because you were created and you're
here for a purpose it's hard I know it's
hard but you can't give up you can't if
I can't give up then you can't give up
anyway thank you guys for all the love
and the support and for 400 subscribers
I just feel so blessed and I'm excited
to see where God continues to take me
please subscribe if you haven't already
and give this video a thumbs up I hope
you guys have a blessed 2019 an amazing
2019 and I'll see you guys in the next
one bye
[Music]