what's up everyone
welcome back to my channel today's video
has
one purpose and one purpose only and
that is to convince
you yes you to go to community college
this fall especially if you are
watching this in the year 2020. there's
a lot of stigma behind community college
but i feel like a lot of that is over
inflated you know by
the media by high schools for some
reason a lot of high schools don't push
community college they just want you to
go straight to university
and you know a lot of this stuff also
depends on who you are as a person
if you see perspiration on my upper lip
please just ignore it it is hot in here
because i had to turn off the ac
so it wouldn't be noisy in this video so
i'm doing this for you okay
let's just move on the number one reason
i would
push and encourage someone to start off
at a community college
is if you're not sure what you want to
major in
from the time that you graduate high
school as
barely adults to the time when you're
like in your mid-20s
um like me a lot of things change
and i'm not just talking about your
growing bodies or you know the people
around you
or your circumstances but you yourself
as a person
mentally spiritually emotionally all of
those things
change looking back at who i was when i
was like 17
18 when i first graduated i
i just cannot believe my mother allowed
that person to
walk out of the house because i was so
stupid and what i thought i
wanted at 17 and 18
is so different than what i want now
what i prioritize now
college you know that four to five year
mark is such
a great time to figure out who you are
what you
love who you love when you attend
community college
it is so much cheaper and cost effective
that it gives you
a lot more leeway to kind of you know
switch between majors
figure out what piques your interest or
to figure out if school is even for you
because let's be honest school
isn't for everyone all right so let me
tell you about what happened to me
um oh so good
this is my spin drift by the way
sparkling water only five calories
when i first graduated as a dumb a dumb
in this big world i pretty much thought
that i knew what i wanted
when i started college i went in as a
nursing major
and if you guys want to hear the full
story i'll put the link up in the cards
in the description box
but basically all i had known my entire
life was nursing nursing nursing nursing
get to the two-year mark when all my
prereqs are done and i have to apply to
nursing school
and i'm like holy i don't want to
be a nurse and let me tell you for the
next two years
i did communications i did journalism
i was even on the newspaper at my
community college
and i even considered culinary school so
i really
explored everything that i could and the
funny part is
in the end i didn't even end up pursuing
a degree for any of the majors that i
thought i was interested in
one thing i found out through my
community college experience was
wow school is not for me and i ended up
dropping out and going on a
completely creative route just making
videos
freelancing and just honing in on my
craft
and because of that last year i was able
to get a job as a
content creator working for this amazing
company that i love
doing what i love and it's just it's so
funny how like that all
worked out had i went to a university
right out of high school
then things might have been different
maybe i would have been like you know
what i am not going to waste all this
money that i put into the school
you know so i probably would have just
stayed and continued pursuing one of the
degrees that i
switched over to or maybe i wouldn't
have even
you know touched on my creative side
because i would feel like it was
irresponsible because i'm like
dude you just paid tuition this year
like why are you gonna go waste time
making videos or doing something
creative you know what i mean so
community college allowed me that
financial freedom
to make mistakes and to grow and to
finally come to terms with who i was as
a person who i am as a person
and i just would not change my
experience anyway at all
and i say that last part very seriously
because
when i first went to community college
all i could think in my head was regret
like oh my god i'm not getting the
college experience
i'm such a loser for going to community
and for all of those years
i just had that thought like always in
my head you know
but looking at where i am now i am
so grateful that yes i did go to
community college and i'm proud to say
that i'm proud to say my story so
i wanted to give you guys some insight
on that as well
um but you know it's not all fun and
games over here i'm gonna keep it real
with you guys so i'm going to talk about
some of the things to watch out for as
well
so the main thing to watch out for is
the community college trap
and yes it is real what does that mean
community college trap is essentially
when you go to a community college
there's going to be a lot of people who
are kind of just like getting by
and they're not really doing anything
they're not really like
you know going after like what they want
wholeheartedly and you might fall into
that as well you might get lazy you
might be like ah whatever
it's community college i can just go
back next semester
i'll take a break i'll do this and then
you end up just stuck there
or you end up you know not going after
your dreams so that is like
one huge thing to look out for but there
are ways to prevent that
and again it comes down to who you are
as a person
so here are some tips number one
visit your counselor every quarter
semester
whatever system your school is on make
that appointment
and yes it's annoying but get it done
because
your counselor is going to be the key to
you getting out of community college
and pursuing your dreams because they
will help you figure out what classes
you need to take
for what college you want to transfer to
essentially they are the key
number two even during the breaks take
an online class
i'm a strong believer that you work hard
you play hard
but in community college you know for
those first couple years it's
all about grind time baby so when you
have uh a winter break
summer break whatever you don't need to
take like a full
like like workload of classes but take
like at least
one online class that way you're still
connected and you won't like
fall back and you won't get lazy and
it'll just help you get out of there
faster as well
number three do not skip class it is so
important that you don't skip class
you attending every class is the key to
you succeeding and getting the hell out
of there okay because once you skip one
class everything else falls behind
so it's not worth it don't skip a class
and number four
take classes that fit you and your
scheduled best
now what does this mean that means if
you're not a morning person
no do not take that 7am class because i
promise you
you will not make it you won't and it's
just going to be a waste of time
and money so you know get an afternoon
class and also
don't take more online classes than you
can handle because online classes you
really have to be
disciplined i am not one of those people
therefore i have pretty much
i pretty much dropped out of every
online class i had
so you know word of warning to the wise
if you are
watching this in 2020 when the pandemic
is
in full force and you are
attending or going to attend a
university that
is going to make you pay full tuition
for online classes don't do it and if
you're worried about the college
experience
the parties and stuff like that like
hello
just go to like one of your friends
college parties or something like
it's it's not that big of a deal and i
promise you you are not going to care
about the time you did seven shots in a
row
with kyle from sigma apple pie because
in the end it doesn't even matter there
are much more important things out there
to worry about and to put your
creativity and your thinking
towards if you guys have any questions
uh leave them in the comments below and
i will get to them i'll try to answer
them to the best of my ability thank you
guys so much for watching and thank you
for 2 000 subscribers
no idea how that happened but i
appreciate it so much make sure to
give me a thumbs up if this video helped
you at all
and also be sure to subscribe to my
channel
um i am going to go crank the ac wipe
this sweat off my
upper lip and pour myself another spin
drift so i'll see you guys in the next
one
bye
you