- [Noelle] Thank you Squarespace for sponsoring this video.
I am so excited to show you all
how the website is coming together.
Hello everyone, welcome back to my channel.
It's me, Noelle and I'm here to read a joke.
Well, I'm here to do more than that
but we're gonna start with this joke.
What's a hamburger's favorite story to read?
Handsel and Gristle,
(laughing loudly)
I didn't think ...
It didn't look funny on the page
and then when you say it,
you know, it just ... It works.
So there we have it.
Whoa, so yes hello,
on today's video is going to be the reading habits tag
or my reading habits tag.
And I'm very excited
not only because the questions seem really fun,
but also because I have a very special guest.
(laughing loudly)
I have been without this special guest for a while.
And so I'm glad he could make an appearance,
the King himself.
So let me just say either ... I mean, let's talk about it.
You can just make your own video
with the same tag questions or in the comments below,
you can either answer all of them
or answer your favorite ones, I don't know.
I just, I love hearing how we all slightly ...
Like how we all read slightly differently from each other.
You know, it's an activity that you think
would have no variation and yet we all enjoy
and ingest literature in very different ways.
So let's go, I'll also leave the questions
in the description box if you'd like
to see them up close and personal.
So the first question is,
do you have a certain place at home for reading?
(laughing loudly)
No, I think I most often read in bed.
If I'm reading a physical book and not listening
to the audio book,
it's gonna be in bed
because I usually like to ...
like if I'm gonna take up the time with reading
then I'd like my boyfriend to at least
like have the main TV
and be able to watch whatever he wants to watch.
So I love reading in bed,
but I especially love when I wake up early in the morning
and I just have a cuppa Joe
and I'm laying on the couch
and the heater's on first thing in the morning
and I'm all snuggled up on the couch
or, hey hold on, one more.
We also ... I just bought my boyfriend,
I mean, I guess I bought the house
like a chair for the living room and I ...
you know, it was supposed to be a gift for my boyfriend
but it's kind of just my chair now.
And also Parker's chair because I do a lot of reading there.
A lot of annotating,
there's just something about a supported back.
You know what I mean?
Where you are annotating
and you just needed the little extra angle
to really get on that highlighter.
I'm not sure if I'm making sense,
but yes, I read all over the place,
but specifically the bed and the couch and the new chair.
(laughing loudly)
Bookmark or random piece of paper?
This is where the controversy of this video
is going to come into play.
Because people have very strong feelings against what I do.
How do I know this?
Well, I often do reading vlogs
and whenever people see me do this,
I always get comments where people are telling me
how disappointed they are in me.
(laughing loudly)
And that is that, I don't really use bookmarks.
I love to dog ear pages, I love it.
It's me making a mark on a book,
like literally marking my own book.
Even if it's not like through highlighting and writing,
which I love doing in books anyway,
but which might be a future question.
I don't actually know, I might be skipping ahead,
but I love a good dog ear.
There's nothing wrong with that.
I'm definitely a dog person anyway.
So ...
(laughing loudly)
and I also have noticed that
like I think because I take my books a lot of places
like I might take it with me in the car
or I might take it to my mom's
or I might ... I don't know when the gym was open,
I used to take it to the gym.
Bookmarks, just slip right out.
Whereas a dog year never fails.
So ...
(laughing softly)
that's that answer.
Okay, next question.
Can you just stop reading,
or do you have to stop after a chapter
slash a certain amount of pages?
I can stop in the middle of a chapter,
if there are paragraph breaks.
I usually always make sure to get to a paragraph break.
I don't, bake.
(laughing loudly)
I usually don't just like stop in the middle of dialogue
or stop in the middle of a description
or plot development, cause it just will not make sense to me
when I pick the book back up.
But usually I can stop in the middle of the chapter
as long as there's a clear indication
that there is going to be a new section of the chapter
but I'm not a barbarian, okay.
(laughing loudly)
I'm not, I won't just stop
in the middle of a dialogue conversation
but I can stop in the middle of the chapter.
Do you eat or ...
(dragging sound)
drink
(laughing softly)
while reading?
Yeah, I mean, why not?
Right, like, I don't know.
If I'm gonna dog ear my books anyway,
then I don't have a problem
with getting like food smudges in my books.
Oftentimes if I ever spill water or coffee near a book
I'm almost delighted by it
because I know there's gonna be like
weird crinkling to the pages.
I'm really about ruining a book.
I think it's awesome.
So I'm gonna move her,
move her or I just whack it over.
But yeah, I love eating and drinking.
Well, just in general
but when I read as well.
Because if it's already one of my favorite activities,
why not combine the two, right?
If I have a cup of coffee,
why would I not enjoy it with a nice novel in hand?
(laughs)
And if I'm hungry
bitch the pages are not gonna stop me, okay?
I love eating Chex Mix bold
while I read, oh God,
and I love eating oatmeal in the morning.
So like if I've got my cup of coffee and my oatmeal
and then my book propped up on a knee,
oh my God in my reading chair, are you kidding me?
Absolutely love it.
I love all three of those things.
So put your hands together.
Multitasking, music or TV while reading?
Honey, if you're able to read while the TV is on,
I don't understand how your brain functions properly.
My brain like skits out when I get literally,
it's like a CD skipping.
If the TV's on, there's no way
that I can pay attention on what I'm ...
pay attention to what I'm reading.
But I often have headphones in while I read,
especially in reading blogs
and people we'll always ask,
what on earth could I be listening to while I'm reading?
So the first one is that I'm either just listening
to the audio book while I read.
So while I'm following along,
because I think that audio books are such a splendid way
to bring a story alive with like character voices
and dialogue and emotion.
I feel like when an audio book is done well,
it really elevates the way you experience story.
So oftentimes when you see headphones
in I am listening to an audio book
with the book that I'm reading.
But I also had,
past tense, had an amazing reading playlist on Apple music.
But I recently, as in this morning switched over to Spotify
because I was sick and tired of at the end of every year,
having such a shite music wrap-up
compared to all the Spotify users.
I always wanted to know,
like who did I listen to the most this year?
Or like, what was my most played song or album?
It would have been Ariana Grande across the board,
but I still would have liked to see that in numbers.
And instead, Spotify users had like blew up Instagram
at the beginning of December of 2020.
And I just was waiting and waiting and waiting.
And then Apple finally launched
some like Market Pantry half-assed version
of what Spotify was doing.
And I was like, no, no, I did not get a history degree
to not reflect back on my life in a satisfying way.
So I switched over to Spotify,
which means that I no longer have
my beautifully curated reading playlist.
I did take screenshots of it.
So I'm hoping, that I can go find
all of those songs on Spotify.
And once I do that I'll share a playlist on Instagram
because a lot of people have been asking me
to share a reading playlist
and I will once I have all of them together.
So yeah, that's my thing.
I'm either listening to audio books
or I'm listening to a reading playlist
that is only instrumental.
It can be beats, it can be classic,
it can be piano, it can be whatever,
but it can't have any lyrics in it.
Cause it is super distracting when I'm reading.
But first, before we get to the next question
let's take a quick break
to thank the sponsor of this video, which is Squarespace.
- [Noelle] So as I mentioned
in my previous video with Squarespace,
I wanted to make a book review type of website.
So we have a whole page where I will rant
about the books that I really didn't like.
And then we have the raves,
which is, I mean are we surprised
"The Hating Game" and "Misery" are the top two.
And then from the raves,
we have this, which is shop the books,
which I thought was a really cute idea.
I would, obviously these are not my T-shirts,
but I would love to instead have books here.
So either the books that I rave about or rant about,
if any of them caught your attention,
I would then link them here,
so that you could click on the book
and then go buy the book on another website
since I don't own these books.
But I just thought it was a cool way
to kind of make it a more interactive experience.
If you really liked one of my reviews
you could go read it yourself
and I'd make sure that it was accessible to you.
So there we have it my friends,
head to squarespace.com for a free trial.
And when you're ready to launch,
go to squarespace.com/NOELLEGALLAGHER
to save 10% off your first purchase of a website or domain.
Next one book at a time
or several at once?
Here's the deal, before starting BookTube,
it was always one at a time.
There was like no way
that I would have been able to focus
on more than one book at a time,
but through ...
I don't know, through BookTube
and through documenting my reading
and just like, I don't know, watching other people's vlogs
and realizing like I guess I kind of thought like,
Oh, when you're reading,
you have to focus entirely on one thing.
You cannot pivot to something else.
And I think once I realized
that that wasn't actually the case
and you could actually like be capable of reading a book
realizing you were a little bored
and then pivoting to another book
and returning it to the first book.
I realized that I love to read several books at once.
Usually, maybe two, maybe three.
It's usually not over that
because after that point
one of those books is just going to fall off.
But usually like two or three
is my sweet spot for tandem reading.
And it's usually all from a different genre.
So sometimes I'll be like enjoying
like a nice non-fiction and then I'll be like,
"Okay, but I need something to kind of just distract me
for a little bit."
And then I'll like pivot to a romance.
I also would say,
that's a big tip for reading more
is that sometimes when you put yourself in this box
of only reading one book
and you can't switch out of it,
like you've decided I can only read this book
and then you get to a boring part of the book,
then you just don't want to read for a little while.
And so if you end up reading more like two or three books
it's easier because then you can like pivot
and be like, okay, I'm in the mood for a romance
and you can finish that book and then be like,
"Oh wait, and now I wanna ...
now I'm in the mood
to go finish that memoir I was reading."
Or whatever it is.
So if you've ever wondered how I read so much,
that's definitely a huge tip of mine,
is having several books at once.
Reading at home or everywhere?
So realistically,
I'd love to be a read anywhere to everywhere girl,
just cause it sounds like super fun.
(laughing loudly)
Like, it just sounds like,
"Oh my God, like it's just me and my books
and we're like on the bus."
I mean, right now, obviously there's no way
that I could read anywhere but home
because we're all stuck at home.
But I mean, if I'm traveling somewhere,
like I'm gonna be on a plane for five hours,
I'll bring a book.
But like, I feel like when life is open,
I also never like just like go to a cafe by myself.
I just don't do that.
Like I wish I was more like that
but I just ...
I'm like, "Why do that
when I could just read at home
or like be at home and make my own coffee."
So I feel like there wasn't ...
if I was going anywhere outside of my house,
it was to either like go to work or go to school
or see people that I wanted to spend time with.
And so usually, I'm just a home reader
but I wish I was more of a read anywhere, anytime.
But usually if I'm out of the house
and I need to fill my time,
Instagram is just a click away.
So that's what I ended up doing.
Okay, question eight, reading out loud
or silently in your head?
Silently in your head.
I've tried reading out loud,
like sometimes when I'm like,
"Oh my God, that audio book was so good.
Maybe I can narrate it better."
And then I try and I'm like, wow, that sucks.
So I've tried it, but it's gotta be in the head.
I can never ... I've never been able
to like successfully focus on what I'm reading out loud
when I read out loud
and I always get so scared because in class,
even now in grad school, when people are like,
"Does anyone wanna read that paragraph?"
"Anyone, anyone?"
I'm like "Prof, if you make me read this,
I will not understand what I just read.
Because I'll be too anxious
about not tripping over any of my words."
So it's gotta be silently in the head.
Question nine, do you read ahead or even skip pages?
Neither, I never skip pages,
I never skip paragraphs, I never skip sentences
because there's kind of like this thing
where I feel like if I skip anything
then it's incomplete.
I might do it for school.
Like I might skim some paragraphs
if I'm like ... It's right before the class
and I needed to finish a chapter or something.
But when I'm reading on my own
if I'm that bored where I need to skip paragraphs
or skip ahead, I'm just gonna DNF the book.
I'm not gonna finish it.
So if I get to a place where I feel like I'm skipping ahead
or skipping details, then it's probably not a book
that I even wanna finish to begin with.
So I won't finish it.
Okay. Two more questions.
Breaking the spine
or keeping it like new.
I mean, we already talked about how I dog ear my books.
So I will break spines before I even start reading.
Like just to get the book in a better place.
I actually have one right now.
Hold on.
So I bought this book Little Leaven by Nick Cutter
and it's kind of a thick bitch.
And so it was like a little stiff
before I even started reading.
And I was like, "Who cares?"
And I just went and broke the spine in multiple places
because I was like, "If I'm going to have
a good reading experience
with this thick ass book,
I'm not going to have this book
that wants to keep shutting on me."
So I literally just sat there and like broke the spine
over and over again.
I'm all for it.
I think again, it kind of like leaves your mark on it.
I just read a book.
What was the book I just read
that talked about used books?
I think it was 84 Sharyn Crossroad,
Sharon Crossroad.
In any case, I just read a book that talks about used books
and there's like this whole kind of letter
that's describing why she loves used books so much.
And what she said was like,
she loves picking up a book
that you can tell was loved by someone else.
And so sometimes when you pick up a used book
and it like immediately flips open to a random page
you know that the previous reader
really loved a passage from that page.
So you kind of take it time with it a little bit longer.
And so right when I was reading that,
I was like, that was stunning.
I loved how that it was written.
And I just thought that's exactly how it feels
when you have a really well-loved book,
either by yourself or someone else.
It just feels like it's a little more special
because you can feel it like it's a tangible love.
It's not just like, "Oh yeah, I saw that this book
had a really great rating online,
so like, that's why I read it."
Instead you can like, hold it and feel how loved it was.
I'm not gonna cry.
This mix is not making me,
gonna cry over a fucking book
but I love breaking the spine.
I love writing in it.
I love creasing the pages.
I love it all.
Oh, wow.
And then the last, last question is, do you write
in your books?
And I do.
I don't write in every single book
because oftentimes I feel like there's just some books
that I might be loving in the moment or really enjoying
but I just know that I'm not gonna read it again.
And so if I'm going ...
If I'm reading a book that I know
I'm going to love and cherish and keep
then I will write all over it.
I'll write stars, I'll write smiley faces.
I'll highlight, I'll write sentences.
I'll talk to myself in the margins.
I'll do it all.
But usually if I know
that it's a book that might not be leaving
a total lasting impression,
then I won't write in it unless it's for school.
And then I need to annotate anyway.
But like with this,
I knew within like the first 20 pages
that this was not gonna be a book
that I was like,
"Oh my God, I love it so much.
I can't wait to go back in time and see how I felt."
So I'll probably read this and then one day give it away.
And so I'm not gonna write all up in it.
But if I was going to look at perhaps ...
I don't know let's pick a book off the shelf.
Whereas, if I picked up like North and South,
first of all I had to read this for school.
So I already knew that I was going to write in it.
But then once I got like 20 pages in
I knew how much I was gonna love this book.
I knew that it was going to be something spectacular
and wonderful and so not only did I just annotate it
'cause I had to for school.
But also I knew that I was gonna wanna
look back on it and see how I felt about it
in the years to come.
And so I'm actually planning
on re-reading North and South sometime this year.
And so it'll be really fun
to see like what was I really into?
What did I love about it?
What were the passages
that really called to me the first time
so that I can see if they still affect me this time.
And yeah, I love it.
I love it.
Look at this.
Like it's almost like a time capsule.
I'm going back to look at these pages
that I haven't looked at it over a year
and I can see that these two pages
obviously meant something to me.
There's something valuable on these pages.
And once I re-read it, it'll become very obvious why.
So ... That's it.
That's the tag, my friends.
I hope that was fun.
Let me know if there are any other tags you want me to do.
I kinda wanna do that anti haul tag question, video thing,
that's going around right now.
It seems really fun.
And I actually wanted to film that today.
And then once I was looking for the questions,
I was like "Maybe you don't know what you're saying."
So I decided not to film that today
but that is on my radar.
Let me know if there are any other tags
you want me to explore
because I had fun.
They're really quick and easy.
And I just feel like they're like a cute way to talk
about books without like talking about specific books.
You know what I'm saying?
Anyway, that's it my friends.
I hope you liked this video.
I hope you had fun.
And I hope to see in the next one.
Bye.
(upbeat music playing)