[Music]
this is future Yanni jumping in after
I've already filmed everything this is a
long video clearly I was gonna make it a
part 1 in part 2 but then I think it's
such an important story art that it's
just better that it's one video so you
know what I want to recommend pause this
video right now go grab a snack go grab
some tea coffee eat while I speak
whatever it's it's a journey that we're
gonna go on together so there's that
disclaimer it's a long one but it's a
special once I hope I hope you'll enjoy
it
but yeah it's a long one you can clearly
see I hope you enjoy okay bye
hi guys it's me Annie welcome back to my
channel I apologize for the background
situation right now I'm in the middle of
a move
today is Tuesday April 21st and I'm
moving to Seattle finally this Saturday
so I've been living out of a suitcase
for the past week but I can't make a
camera because I knew if I felt inspired
making a video would be really good for
my mental health and self-care so here I
am making a video today on a topic that
I think is really really important and I
think it's really important to make this
video because so much of my identity is
morphed into my work and what I do I
started doing some research into how I
would put this video together and then I
remembered a few months ago I actually
did a quick interview with a non-profit
up in Canada called Project T like te a
and I spoke to the founder her name is
Lexi I believe Lexi and the founder
Alexei reached out to me asking if I if
she could ask me a few questions about
my identity as an Asian American and how
that has shaped you know where I am
today being a mental health provider and
you know answering those questions was
such a cathartic experience for me and I
was really happy to be able to share a
little bit of my experience to maybe
help with what their missions and values
are and you know getting into that I
have their website open here their
project TTA because they want to teach
and educate the East Asian community
about the concept of self identity and
emotional wellness and how they're doing
that is they want to engage the youth in
the East Asia
communities through like open
conversations and hosting events so a
lot of what I wanted to say in this
video I already said in the interview so
I'm pretty much going to regurgitate my
answers in that interview in video form
today and kind of add on a little bit
more at the end of what it's like being
an asian-american therapist and the
challenges and the rewards that have
come with that so it's gonna be kind of
a long video so let me just get straight
into it so the first question that they
asked me was what's your ethnicity and
multicultural experience
I am South Korean born in Seoul I moved
to the state's when I was six years old
in 1999 I believe I was born on April
4th 1994 I was only in first grade at
the time when I moved but I distinctly
remember how stark the transition was
for myself and my family I just remember
feeling like my family had landed into
this vacuum where I could not understand
anything going on because of a language
barrier all of the signs and everything
was so confusing they all looked like
worms to me you know we moved to a
predominantly Caucasian town there were
not many Asians especially we first
moved there there was like no Asians and
at the time we didn't have the language
or the awareness necessary to put like
labels on what our experiences were like
my family and I but now that I look back
we faced a lot of racism and
discrimination while living in that
community one example would be like when
I would go grocery shopping with my mom
and my mom would you know my mom doesn't
know English she was just trying her
best and I remember we were at the
checkout line and the cashier
started laughing at my mom because she
had an accent
and then he I remember specifically
being angry because laughter that kind
of nonverbal cue is clearly something
that you don't need words to understand
mime I could see my mom was visibly
upset
this man was laughing at her I became so
angry and he brought more of his friends
over from like the other cash registers
and if I remember correctly they were
like egging her on to keep speaking so
they could make fun of her and no one
stepped in we didn't have smartphones
back then to document it and you know
expose these people so
it was really rough growing up in that
environment and it really really mess a
lot with my identity the second question
that they asked me was growing up as an
Asian American if you felt that you
faced more expectations from your
parents to achieve greater success in
your peers who are not Asian and I said
of course at the time it felt so unfair
that like susie-q and Jeremy and Stephen
and all these people were like they
whether they were trying their best or
not it felt like their interactions with
their family was a lot more casual like
not as scary or strict as my
interactions were with my parents I felt
like my parents are being really strict
unreasonable and having really
unrealistic expectations for a child
because you know like when you're a
child I think at least for me I was
aware I was a child you know that I'm
not gonna be perfect and and I was in
like first grade I'm like if I screw up
first grade like I'll try again and
second grade and third grade now I'm
like you know I learn and whatever but
now that I look back you know there's
always a lot of more clarity in
retrospect that kind of stepping into my
parents shoes at the time in their
perspective what a good parent was and
what a good child was those terms had
very different they looked very
different to them then they looked to me
or to my environment so their standards
were different but I you know I can't
blame them for that there were cultural
reasons for that generational issues for
that and me having been thrown into this
kind of like Western culture and
education I was coming home with a lot
of information that my parents had never
learned before like they learns
differently from their Korean background
educational background so it was kind of
the beginning of like a wall that I felt
between me and my parents because I was
starting to kind of come into my own
identity of who I am and blah blah blah
and Who I am in the outside world was
very different from who I was in the
inside world with my parents and yet no
matter where I was I didn't really feel
like I truly belonged and that leads to
the third question which was which
mental wellness related issues have you
personally experienced or thought deeply
about
and I'm gonna just read this part
because you know when you type something
out you have more time to edit things so
I feel like I've worded this pretty well
so I'm just gonna read it I think as far
as I can remember I struggle deeply with
wanting to feel like I belonged whether
it was the family environment that I
grew up in as a child or being the only
Asian kid in town or honestly probably a
lot of both I always wanted to belong
this desire led to many childhood and
adolescent years of self-criticism and
people-pleasing behavior that were
absolutely debilitating to my sense of
self when I entered college I
experienced some severely traumatic
experiences that hurt me physically
emotionally and mentally I have been
dealing with things that I'm not crying
it's just allergies I promise I have
been dealing with anxiety panic attacks
and depression all my life and only
through finding my own coping skills
supportive circles and therapy have I
been able to deal learn and move forward
but it's a continuous journey of
checking in with myself and doing soft
care like eating food to sustain my body
I need to engage in self-care to sustain
my mental health you know this part when
I answer this it's initially an essay I
had to kind of shorten it up for up for
them but I struggled a lot with wanting
to belong I wanted to just I wanted to
belong with my family but I felt like I
was already so different I wanted to
belong at school with the other kids but
I looked different I spoke a different
language I came from an entirely
different background moved from another
freaking country on the other side of
the world I wanted to belong in my
community and wanted to belong and that
kind of wanting to belong as I already
kind of said in the interview led to
excuse me led to a lot many years of I
think I just kind of blamed it on myself
a lot I had a lot of social anxiety
growing up because I was eager to please
anyone who would help me to feel like I
belonged and I was a people pleaser I
was a goody two-shoes and that people
step all over me I was fake that was a
big thing like you know I can admit that
now I was really fake I didn't want to
do certain things for people but like I
did it just so they would give me
something out of it which was the
feeling of acceptance and feeling of
belonging so but then like when kids
would accuse me of being fake
I'd be like so heartbroken because I
couldn't connect like the deeper issue
that I had with why was I being such a
people-pleaser I just thought I'm just a
nice person why are people so mean to me
and I do think I was still a nice person
I think my intentions were pure but the
execution was just not transparent to my
peers because it was so really quick
what I start explaining to them that all
of this stems from my deeper issues of
wanting to belong like where do you even
begin a conversation like that
how has your culture shaped your
identity yeah so I struggled immensely
with my cultural identity maybe because
it was the age that I moved to the
states where I wanted to you know belong
so much but the way I looked the food
that my parents packed for me for lunch
the language that I spoke it all was
like other other outsider outsider and I
hated that you know so I did not want to
be Korean I didn't want to look like
this or speak my language I felt like
because I was like this no one was
liking me and I had a lot of like
aggression and anger towards myself and
a lot of aggression and anger towards my
parents and there was an incident that
happened when I was eight so two years
after moving to the States and I still
remember it now and it's just kind of it
speaks volumes on how like my childlike
brain was struggling so much with my
cultural identity it was Halloween and I
remember you know the burette there was
like a Halloween party at school you
know so like kids can stay safe and
stuff so like they would change the
gymnasium and put like games in there
and kids would come and like all dressed
up and blah blah blah and I remember I
wanted to be a fairy that year you know
eight year old girl you know I wanted to
be a fairy and then there was a blonde
wig that came with the fairy outfit and
honestly I was so excited my parents
didn't want me to wear the way cuz it
was it was like a cheap wig it looked
really ugly but when I put that blonde
wig on and looked at myself in the
mirror I felt was so beautiful and okay
now I'm a little teary eyed now thinking
of like like poor baby girl like having
that blonde wig and not having this
black hair I felt
and I felt like I belonged him when I
went to that Halloween party I was like
I am so cute I had the best time and
even when I got home that night I took
off my fairy costume I was in my PJs but
I wore that blonde wig and I almost
worked at school the next day but my mom
yelled at me so I could have but thank
God thank you mom now that I look back
but I struggled a lot with my cultural
identity as you can see and before I
move on to the next part like because it
took me so long to appreciate and love
my culture and being Korean I cherish it
so much more now I think I feel so
thankful that through those difficult
times it's like I had to kind of like
claw my way to the appreciation part
where I pushed it away and I hated it
and now I'm just like it's a it's a part
of me that makes me so much stronger
than I was ever before and it's just
like my cultural identity is it doesn't
look like my parents identity you know
if there was like a color to it or like
some sort of artistic representation of
what my cultural identity looks like
that's a really great art therapy
project actually anyway sorry the
therapist in music I could use that
anyway so yeah my cultural identity
looks so different from my parents and
how their canvas will look looks so
different from any other korean-american
out there and because of that it's so
important and because of that I cherish
it so much more now how did you think
your degree in psychology helped you
find your calling I love to this
question because I never really thought
about it until they asked me I really
had to sit down
I like held on to these questions for
days really processing the answer so I
could be as transparent as possible but
I didn't go into college wanting to
study psychology I was actually when I
was going into college I had turned down
like a full scholarship to an art school
I got full presidential scholarship to
Pratt Institute in Brooklyn and all of
high school was prepping for art school
because I really loved art and then I
ended up going to a big like state
school because my parents didn't really
want me to dive so like hard into such a
niche like art you know studio art they
wanted me to try out
friend degrees in different kinds of
classes and I don't know why I didn't
fight it more I don't know everything
happens for a reason so I ended up going
to a bigger state school and so I was
like I still want to do something
related to art so I thought I was gonna
be an art historian so I went into
school with an art history major and I
took an art history course and I needed
to you know take some random extra
courses so I took a psych 101 course cuz
everyone was taking and apparently was
easy and faint just kind of had its way
of working with me where and then again
like it wasn't after that psych class
where I was like I'm gonna be a
therapist but I've loved that psych 101
class everything was so fascinating like
studying the way people think and the
way they feel and how it's all connected
and how people like respond and react to
one another and in contrast our history
was so boring for me I'm sorry like I
love museums I love going there but like
the act of shoving so much information
into my head like this was painted in
this period by this person using this
technique using these materials like I
didn't give me a chance to really
appreciate art so that's when I realized
okay it's not really for me but that's
really what sparked my interest in
psychology and I wanted to take more
classes and I feel like as I was getting
to know more about psychology and these
concepts and terms
I think deep inside of me I wanted to
find out what was wrong with me in a way
growing up you know I kind of explained
you a little bit of what it was like
first moving to the states and growing
up in the environment but I always felt
like there was something wrong with me
you know like maybe that's why I
couldn't belong with my family or like
my friends there was always like this
idea or a theme of like I explore my
feelings too much and it's like a
detriment to me and it's not good to
linger too much on feelings that was
kind of like what I was taught at home
and so I was like okay there's something
wrong with Manny to figure that out and
I think that kind of subconsciously made
me more interested in psychology and
little did I know this journey to kind
of fix myself became this journey of
self-discovery where I realized this
this thing that I thought was a weakness
or an
shuh that i had was actually kind of a
gift in a way something that i could be
proud of something I could really use to
not only get to know myself better but
help others and get to know others
better and the fact that like processing
emotions is good like having good
insight and being a good listener and
understanding and wanting to know more
about feelings is good and it's good for
me because I'm human and humans have
feelings and it's good to talk about it
was like psychology gave me like a new
language that I feel like all my life I
was just screaming to try to understand
and try to put into words my experiences
and it was like an enlightening
experience when I started to learn more
about psychology number six what is your
current profession and how did you
decide to pursue this career path this
was while I was still at my last job but
I said I make I am a clinical team lead
therapist at a substance abuse
outpatient program after setting
undergrad I knew I wanted to get into a
field where I could have more human
interactions and help people and I
actually didn't know about the field of
Social Work until senior year of college
I knew I wanted to do like clinical
psychotherapy I cared a lot about a lot
of social justice and advocacy and when
I learn more about Social Work and like
the ethics of Social Work and how it's
so client centered and where it's so
empowering for the client I really felt
like this was the right field for me we
know that you have a successful YouTube
channel
what was your initiative for starting
this YouTube channel you know this isn't
my first YouTube channel actually in
high school I had a YouTube channel for
song covers because I like to sing it's
deleted now so don't try to look for it
the second time around when I started
this YouTube channel I think it was in
2014 when I started uploading like my
face onto YouTube
I wanted a channel where I held
discussions on mental health and social
justice topics because I couldn't find a
lot of those on YouTube and maybe
YouTube isn't the place for those kinds
of serious discussions sometimes when I
have controversial videos controversial
my videos they aren't that controversial
but a lot of people are like why did you
post this people come to YouTube for
entertainment and
I understand that but my mission is if
they can stop by one of my videos and
get some tips on how to deal with their
anxiety or if they've been depressed and
they've been watching 20 hours of cat
videos to deal with it but if they come
across on my videos on you know letting
them know that it's okay to feel
depressed and if they get something
positive out of my videos I could help
them with their mental health that is
amazing
so it's like a gateway in a way and what
I make like fashion videos and vlogs
like not only are those fun for me
creatively but I make those videos
because I understand that they there's a
lot of them so they get recommended more
so they get a lot more views so which
means that other people will come to my
channel and when they click on my
channel I want them to see that like
this channel has other videos that could
potentially help me and it means so much
to me that I can just sit down and make
these videos and talk and it could make
someone's day a little bit better it
it's so powerful and just reminds me
that this isn't just a job for me this
is a joy and this is such a passion of
mine to talk about these topics and yeah
that's why I do my YouTube so I can
connect with you guys who I could
hopefully help out even just a little
bit number 8 are there any changes in
people's perceptions of mental wellness
that you hope to see in our Asian
community I'm gonna read this one too
just because it's really important and
took me a while to word it succinctly
I am hoping for more safe discussions on
mental health in our Asian community I
emphasize safe because of the strong
negative stigma that exists there are so
many Asian Americans who suffer in
silence and I envision a future where we
can begin to explore and embrace
conversations on dealing with mental
illness and grappling with asking for
help when you say vision I find myself
seeing a physical vision of a group of
Asian Americans sitting in a room
together Asian Americans who are young
old members of the LGBTQ community abled
and disabled and everyone else sitting
in a room together sharing their
thoughts feelings and experiences and
crying laughing experiencing anger and
all of the range of emotions because
they can and they want to I work hard
every day and keep speaking up as a
mental wellness advocate to work towards
such Empire
some day I totally even now have those
interactions with people in my community
where they ask me what do you do for
work and I tell them I'm a therapist and
there's always like a dot dot dot just
because and you know there's probably
lots of layers to that as well depending
on who I'm talking to but I want to be
able to have these conversations that
I'm having with you right now the camera
and see my camera died because this is
too long but what was I saying
that's what I want I want to be able to
have these candid conversations with
people in my community whether it's my
friends my asian-american friends
whether it's my asian-american family
that's that's a whole nother mountain to
climb but you know I want it that's my
vision that's what I work hard for
that's why I make these videos and do my
work and why I speak up that's my that's
what I want number nine
any advice for East Asian peers who are
struggling with self identity or mental
challenges my answer was remember that
you are not alone while we are at times
grossly underrepresented in mainstream
conversations on mental health and
mental illness we exist like we're here
I'm feared and I know for a fact I've
spoken to a few of you a lot of you and
you are there you exist and it's
important to not isolate and support
ourselves and support circles whether
it's friends campus counseling centers
entities like Project T I want to tell
everyone who may identify with me in my
situation in this conversation in any
way that you're not alone your story
whatever your story may be is essential
to this movement of raising awareness
and combating negative stigma in our
Asian communities like your story can
change lives and that's powerful when
those are the answers that I gave to
project T for my interview but I wanted
to finish off this video by talking a
little bit about what it's like for me
being korean-american and what it's been
like for me being a mental health
provider and certain words that came up
for me isolation under representation
and complacency and let me dive into
those real quick and isolation I feel
like being in this path for me for the
past when did I really like commit
this it's like 2014 2015 because before
2014 I was kind of like a dead person on
the inside and 2014 is when like my this
journey of self-discovery really started
so for the past six years I'd say it's a
pretty lonely road I'll say that I have
really amazing friends really amazing
family but specifically when it comes to
age in America mental health and social
justice in these topics it's been it's
been kind of a lonely road and a lot a
lot of the times that's been really hard
for me because it's hard to talk to my
family about the job that I do because I
know it makes them uncomfortable and
because I know more now about why I like
the cultural implications of the things
that I'm talking about I understand but
it doesn't mean that it makes it any
easier on me who was a mental health
professional but because of the
isolation I think I've really been
training and doing a lot of advocacy
speaking up more you know agreeing to do
these kinds of interviews and putting it
out there I am an Asian American
therapist I am here we are important
putting it out there speaking up
visibility trying to find a community in
that sense and trying to it's it's an
ongoing process you know there it's hard
to find community when there is such
there's not many people out there and
that goes into the second one which is
under-representation Asian Americans
just in general are underrepresented
when it comes to the conversations on
mental health and mental illness
treatment and not only in the sense of
like patients there's not that many
patients because many Asians it's hard
for them to seek help or they a lot of
them they don't even understand that
this kind of help exists I had a Korean
client like my last month of work and I
wanted to work with her so badly but I
knew I was leaving so that won't be good
for her but I had to explain to her what
therapy was and she was like why would I
do that I'm on medicine and like there's
so much like countertransference or as a
girl I feel you I know what you mean
because so much of like Asians so much
of the asian community of understanding
mental illnesses there is no
understanding there's a you're sick
here's medicine take it you'll be fine
like when someone
answer you wouldn't be like oh you have
cancer okay take medicine you'll be fine
don't talk about it anymore
no like there is an outpouring of love
and the community and like solidarity oh
yes when you hear that someone is
schizophrenic you know or has some sort
of is bipolar borderline there's all of
these the trigger labels that make
people treat others in ways that are not
fair and are not accurate and add with
that already and like add on the layer
like the cultural stigma and generations
of that it's just there's a lot of
under-representation of us when it comes
to patients but also in the field of
mental health and interestingly from
what I noticed in undergrad and also in
Social Work school and also working
there are more Chinese Americans I
realize more chinese-american providers
not that many korean-american providers
and I don't know what that's about but
it's fascinating and obviously I want to
do more research and figure that stuff
out because being korean-american I
obviously have like a very strong desire
and will and passion to help my
community as well and there's not that
many korean-american providers out there
and the way I deal with the
under-representation I think is I
represent myself
I don't quit I go to conferences I sign
up for trainings I know I'm the only
Asian American they're like 95% of the
time if there's like one other Asian oh
my hey hey what's up and I try to engage
with them share numbers like follow each
other on LinkedIn do that kind of
networking stuff but the networking is
like not important it's the fact that I
see you you see me we're here
representing and there's kind of like a
yes
like you know I'm representing my people
and I'm gonna keep doing this and this
is a statement in itself that we exist
and thirdly was complacency I believe
and this is just something I've come
across a lot in school where everyone
seems to a lot of people seem to know
that Asians are underrepresented both in
both sides where the clients
patience and like providers especially
mental health there's a lot of Asian
doctors that's for sure but mental
health providers but I come to wonder
what's being done about that I've read a
lot of journals about you know like
engage them there's some articles that
were like engage them but don't talk
about like the big words mental health
I'll keep them coming by doing case
management helping them with practical
things and then eventually like you'll
work on your rapport and they'll start
to trust you more so there are papers
out there but it's like I feel like so
much more can be done outreach is so
important in this field outreach and
engaging and using words and terms that
are friendly and understandable to asian
communities as a provider there have
been times where I was like it is what
it is there's like no one that looks
like me is in this field oh oh she came
for the intake but didn't show up for
the therapy session
oh she's Asian okay it makes sense it's
like no no it shouldn't end there it
makes sense understanding the numbers of
Statistics that many Asians don't follow
up and there's a lot of different
reasons for that however what's being
done about it
and I myself have my personal mission of
what I'm serving my clients and my
agency is that I offer my opinion and
two cents all the time especially when
it comes to working with Asian clients
and a lot of times it's hard for
minorities because we are expected to
represent ourselves in every situation
and like that's a lot of pressure on one
person and I get that but I make it my
mission to represent myself and my
people in this field because who else is
gonna do it if I don't so if I have a
client who's Asian and who doesn't want
to do group therapy but like it's better
for their substance use treatment that
they do group therapy I have advocated
for those clients saying hey you know
because this person is Asian you know
talking about their substance use issues
with one person is already hard enough
but in a group setting that's really
really kind of unheard of in our culture
and I'm not saying that I like put my
experience on that person but it's kind
of like putting it when we have like
kind of clinical meetings it's kind of
like putting it out there by the way
don't forget
this person is asian asian american this
person's culture is very against what
we're all doing here and we want to be
as extra sensitive and caring and
accommodating to this person to help
them the best because if we lose them we
can't help them that's what I've been
experiencing and seeing a lot of
isolation under-representation
complacency and as you can see it roused
me up because yeah it gets me down
sometimes it's hard it's a lonely road
like I said however I exist other Asian
providers exist like I said I see them
across serve and I'm like hey I see you
but it's awesome and I talked to you
guys that message meaning like you may
not be asian-american you may be like
Hispanic and whatever other
underrepresented populations are in the
mental health field you exist I exist
we're here we're breathing and I'm not
gonna shut up until I until I show the
world that we exist so yeah this video
is so long I apologize that it was such
an important video I brought you guys
along on a journey of where I'm from how
I grew up how my identity and my
cultural identity my mental health has
been affected throughout the years of my
life and how that has led ultimately to
where I am I'm sitting today being an
Asian American mental health provider I
kind of gave you more of an insight into
what that's been like for me the
challenges but clearly the rewards of it
all and just what I do on my channel I
try to be as honest and transparent with
you all and share with you something I'm
so passionate about that I love so much
and yeah I really really really hope
this video was helpful to any of you out
there to feel like you belong like you
are seen and if anything you've learned
a lot more about me that's for sure so
that's great too I want to make more
like Asian American and Korean American
focused topics on here so yeah I mean if
you have suggestions let me know that'd
be great too
I love making videos yeah
this video please give it a thumbs up
let me know that you like saw make more
of these things and yeah I hope everyone
is staying safe mentally physically
emotionally all of that sending all
positive vibes and strengths through the
lens to all of you I hope you have an
absolutely wonderful day and I'll see
you in the next one I
[Music]