saying you don't see race is the most
racist thing you can say paint color
wine is being blind to the thousands of
years of oppression so I'm sorry sister
but I totally see race with Amy I'm your
lovely host you guessed it Amy and today
we are going to talk about growing up
asian-american and right now I'm just
finishing up my concealer because I
already did my base and my brows so I
can speed up the process a little bit
but I wanted to make this a tag video
just for fun because I know a lot of my
Asian American content creator friends
have expressed concern to me that they
wanted to talk about this but just
didn't really know how to and secondly
if you guys want to do it I would love
for you to answer these questions you
don't have to do your makeup that's just
my thing with the am with Amy I'm
sitting down here drinking tea doing my
makeup talking about some heavy ship
sometimes but you don't have to do your
makeup so I mean you can but it is a
little bit hot I will say that also if I
sound a little sick it is because I am
on day 8 of recovering from I think the
flu so my nose is crazy I have my tea as
I said so just bear with me
korean-american
born in Korea and I was born here in the
states in California
I'm from a city in the Los Angeles
County the Greater Los Angeles County
it's not LA itself but it's in the
county and it's kind of on the border of
LA and Orange County and it's called
Cerritos and for those of you who are
familiar with Cerritos it is very much
so like Irvine it is predominantly Asian
lots of good Asian food lots of boba
spots but it's just a lot of Asian
families and it's just a very aged in
place but the city is neighboring it
like Artesia Bellflower Norwalk are
predominantly Latin or Hispanic
communities and so I think growing up I
never truly felt like a minority but the
first time that I understood that I was
different or I understand it there is a
demarcation between you know me and the
Latin kids or whatever was I remember in
second grade I was probably eight years
old and we were sitting on the classroom
floor and there was a guy named Bobby
who was Mexican I believe and he asked
me straight up to my face
he said Amy why are your eyes so [ __ ]
and I was just like whatever you know
he's just being mean and it kind of
brushed it off but then then he proceeds
to say that there's so kinky that I look
horny and I was eight years old and I
remember distinctly thinking like what
is funny mean like my I look like I have
horns on my face or like I look like a
unicorn I was just so confused and I
said what the heck is horny I was just
like what do you mean and he was just
like never mind he was like just she
just just kind of laughed about that but
I remember he would say that to me a lot
he would always bully me from my eyes
and growing up I did experience quite a
lot of bullying from a lot of the Latin
kids for my eyes but even for me that
was my biggest aha moment that I was
like oh wow my eyes do look different
from them and I'm different from them
and that is when that kind of all
started as a concept I also really
wanted to learn what horny was but I had
- like way later I feel like was crazy
to me is that happen so long ago when we
were in second grade and I remember
exactly
his full name which I will not say and
what do you look like and where we were
and exactly how I felt and it just it's
like crystal clear in my memory even
though everything else from second grade
is really not that clear
so elementary school was pretty okay and
I feel like I got bullied mainly for how
[ __ ] my eyes were and I can't really
remember what race they were so I really
can't tell if they were Asian people
also making vitami because Asian Club
also made fun of me for my [ __ ] eyes
which is so bizarre but anyways so
middle school is definitely what I felt
there were a lot more Hispanic people or
Latin people and I would be believed for
being Asian or for being too smart or
why I always got A's on tests or
whatever I kind of falling into that
model minority myth but high school is
when I finally went to Cerritos high
school which is a school that was not on
anywhere of the border of these
neighboring cities and it was all Asian
kids I remember going to the first day
of school and I was like well there's so
many people here that look like me and
I've come to school and it'd just be
like a group of Asian kids like smoking
and listening to like fly like a g6 and
it was just very I just felt like I was
like in a Far East Movement music video
I just so many Asian kids so who thought
they were cool or nerdy ones whereas in
middle school you know Asian kids were
just like nerdy and one-dimensional in
that sense because we were surrounded
with other minorities but in high
schools all Asian people and we had you
know ancient nerds the cool Asians like
in Mean Girls and the Asian jocks
retired football team was Asian we had
literally had no diversity in this
school and so I think that was when I
realized like oh my gosh I'm surrounded
by so many people like me and Who I am
as a person I think I've always been a
very anti-establishment and meri I like
to stray from the norm and I'm very I
don't like conformity I don't like if
everyone says to do this I'm always like
why why why and so soon as I got into
high school I noticed that a lot of like
the cool Asians with popular kids were
really into like R&B and hip-hop and
they were amazing at dancing and
choreography and our drill team or dance
turtle team looks like so good they're
always competing and I was just like
okay that's what's cool but to me I
want to be that way and so I think in my
high school it is very normal uncool to
be Asian because literally everyone is
Asian and that is the norm and so I
think I started to really reject my
culture when I was in 15 when I was 15
to like 17 years old because I was just
not I just didn't want to fit in with
that crowd and so if everyone will
listen to R&B and hip-hop I wanted to go
listen to rock and like heavy metal and
that's when I discovered I made it and
Slayer Metallica and stuff like that and
if everyone was wearing like this
certain type of shoe like I would want
to wear something completely different
from that and so in high school I really
started to reject my Asian culture I
didn't even drink buh-buh-buh-buh it's
like the hugest thing in cerritos like
people go out to bubble spots at 2:00
a.m. and that's like it's it's a good
thing it's neck tivity and I remember
and all throughout high school I only
started liking boba until I met one of
my best friend's Sharon who caught me
addicted to boba
but even then I just I just I just
didn't want any part of it
and I think a lot of that was because I
just didn't want to be like everybody
else I just really didn't want to
identify with that and all my
personality tests if you guys believe in
like the myers-briggs like I'm an IAT
Jay and if you believe in the zodiac
with Aquarius and all of my personality
tests always talk about how
nonconformist I am I even won best dress
in high school my senior year and I
hated that I won it because I always
felt well one I thought none of the
electives were actually indicative of
how that person actually was so the best
dress was never really that best dress
and like most most likely to succeed
would never really be successful and - I
hated that I was a popularity contest it
was completely not backed on anything
other than whether or not people knew
you and liked you and stuff like that so
I actually stayed home from that day
when they announced and they crowned you
put you up on stage to give you a sash
[ __ ] sash so that was when I was 18
and I think that's when I became way
more in tune with myself and my politics
and where I stand because that is
definitely the last year that I strayed
away from wanting to not be age
if that makes sense I think that was
when I was rejecting what I thought was
too perceived as being Asian which was
like listening to Far East Movement but
it's hard to say that I wouldn't just
simulate if I went to a predominately
white school because I didn't go to a
predominantly white school and I who's
to say I would be here from the norm
then because maybe I wouldn't want to
fit in then I don't know so it's hard to
say it but I just do know that my
experience is very idiosyncratic to me
because a lot of people I talk to don't
have this experience is like literally
my graduation when they sign up all the
names it was like Pak Pak Pak Lee Lee
Lee Kim Kim Kim Jun dejected changing
changing changing changing for like
hours and I was probably the funniest
Lee that they said and when I tell that
people they're like what the heck that's
crazy
so but I just do know that I perceived
Asian being Asian American to be a
certain way in high school because I was
surrounded by that one type of image and
so I wanted to veer from that
one of them is the model minority myth
and that type of stereotype because
growing up for me it's we're all as
Asians were expected to be good at math
and to just be naturally naturally
gifted in matters of school and academia
and I am also the second child and so
growing up I was never ever you know
superbly brilliant as I'm sure a lot of
you are not as well but I think being
compared to my older brother I was
always kind of seen as a lot less
intellectual or smart and so I feel like
I always grew up with this underdog
mentality which then propelled me to
stay after school ask for tutoring come
before school and really really study
the extra hour is like I would go crazy
with no cards I literally had a color
chart for color coding with my
highlighters and that has always been
the driving force as to why I worked so
hard and it has nothing to do with me
being Asian and being this model
minority and being naturally gifted for
me personally is because I was always
told that I was not very smart growing
up and always being compared to someone
and so that drove me and my insecurities
to not be that way and so the model
minority just tells us that as Asians we
are naturally good at math we are good
at sciences and you know it has nothing
to do with how hard we work and find
that the model minority is so
destructive for a lot of my
asian-american friends who no matter how
hard they study or no matter how hard
they work they just cannot get the
results that their parents want or that
society deems that we should have it's
like they work their ass off and still
cannot get even you know a C on the test
and I find that that's so detrimental
because so many of us don't fit into
that model minority I know so many of my
friends who are not good at math and
honestly I'm only good at math
because I stayed before and after class
to get tutored on it literally calculus
I remember going in to school at like
5:00 a.m. and then leaving at 5:00 p.m.
because I just wanted to get tutored on
calculus and I've always had a lot of
extra help in the sense that I use Khan
Academy and I asked the smartest kid in
class to tutor me but that's not to say
that I'm naturally gifted at all these
things without trying I find that it's
problematic because it really minimizes
people's work ethic and the actual sweat
and dedication they put into it as
opposed to genetically being predisposed
to being good math or schooled another
one that I have a hard time grappling
with is being this submissive trophy
wife and I took a lot of classes of this
on this at UCLA Asian American feminism
specifically because it was very
interesting to see the underpinnings of
how Asian American women became this you
know submissive trophy wife that's
supposed to be sexually promiscuous and
also really obedient all at the same
time and it's really weird because when
I date people outside of my race people
will say bla bla bla worshippers so if I
date you know like a white man let's say
a white man worshipper or if I date
someone black like oh you have jungle
fever and I'm just I'm sure a lot of I
mean all all races definitely have this
being that whole so having that
stereotype on you it kind of makes you
where when you're dating outside of your
race to know it to try and gauge whether
or not someone has quote-unquote yellow
fever are they asking me out because
they have a fetish are they asking me
out because they fetishized Asian women
and what that entails and for me I have
dated all races I know that I've showed
one relationship here on YouTube and you
guys probably think that's the only race
that I date but I'm a very open-minded
person I really truly date all races I
feel like it's more of a for me it's
more of a taste issue like do we have
similar tastes and in whether that's a
music or food or clothes do we have the
same taste and taste is definitely
all-inclusive as far as race but I'm
here I'm not here
say oh I don't see race I fly a day all
races saying you don't see race is the
most racist thing you can say being
colorblind is being blind to the
thousands of years of oppression and
systematic incarceration so I'm sorry
sister but I totally see race but for me
dating wise it's just a tasting so
anyways but yeah so just dealing with
that is very interesting and I make it a
point not to date people who
specifically only date Asian women and
that's just personal preference to me
and also shows that they're not super
open-minded like I am so there's a
couple reasons why I don't date people
who only date Asian women and I guess it
is because I am a little bit marred from
that stereotype actually I'm probably a
lot more
I speak like that of a four-year-old I
can ask for directions I can't order
food ask for more food ask where the
bathroom is
but I really can't have a huge
conversation in Korean
you guys have a bet my entire family now
here on YouTube I have videos with my
brother
my mom and now my dad my last video was
my dad picks my outfits which you guys
can watch up here in the cards it's
pretty funny so as you guys might have
guessed but I have a very strong and
close and positive relationship with
both of my parents and I find that
that's because one they're super
open-minded for being korean-american
parents and two they trust me there are
definitely some cultural differences and
sometimes politics that don't align but
we both understand and recognize that as
a cultural thing and you know creating
politics are definitely not as
progressive and I consider myself super
super liberal I am very very liberal and
I'm very open-minded and so hey I think
the only thing that sucks about being
Korean American is that because I don't
speak my language very well I can never
ever get to know my dad or really talk
about where my family is from like my
grandparents my great-grandparents and
that really honestly breaks my heart and
if there's any driving force to me
learning my language it's so that I
could one day sit down and talk to my
dog about politics and philosophy
because my mom speaks fluent English and
so I'm super open with her about the cut
we can talk about the economy we can
talk about politics we can talk about
philosophy we can talk about pretty much
anything and I feel super close to her
but was my dad it sucks because I can
barely speak about you know what's going
on with our current geopolitical climate
and I think he's such as wise and smart
and an intellectual guy that it really
makes me sad that I can't talk to him
because he's always reading the
newspaper and he seems really really
woke in layman's terms but I think
that's the biggest thing about being
korean-american and the language we're
here is that it really hinders my
relationship with both my dad and any
one of my grandparents
as of today I am 100 150 percent so
proud to be korean-american even though
I'm so for unity and dismantling of
racial segregation I do believe that
culture is such a beautiful thing and
culture or something that should be
celebrated and it's honestly what makes
this world so beautiful and colorful and
even if I wasn't Korean I would have if
I was Nigerian I would have a Nigeria
tattoo if I was Chinese I would have a
Chinese tattoo I think culture is
something and heritage is something that
should be celebrated soon as I hit 18 I
really honed in on what it meant to be
Korean American and towards the end of
my college career I had a lot of extra
classes to take for fun like a lot of
units to just basically use up and I
think my last corner it was I
strategically made it out so that I
could only take classes that I really
want to so I took an art history class
and then all the other ones on the first
day it was like what it means to be
Korean or asian-american
and I took asian-american feminism it's
a Korean history formation of Koreatown
I think that was the class and then I
also took an entire year of the Korean
language and I still suck at it but I
never went to class it says he know
which in Korean means literally exert
strength but it's something that Korean
people say as far as you know like cheer
up keep going like endure it like stay
strong so you say he knit or white team
fight team it's kind of the same thing
and it's basically just saying how for
me Korea if you learned about its
culture and its politics and its
historical background it has been
divided by so many different other
external forces and the fact that it
still remains and is strong I'm just
like Korean people are resilient and
it's it's just not staying strong and
it's a it's definitely paying homage a
lot of omage to my Korean culture I will
say that I do not listen to modern-day
Korean music because I know a lot of
people love kpop but honestly I don't
really listen to even American pop let
alone like other people's pop music but
if there was like a Korean Stevie Nicks
you know I would be down I mean any one
of my friends
I'm so proud of my culture because when
I moved out into my own place here we
are I could have lived anywhere in LA
any neighborhood in LA because it was my
jurisdiction and of all the places I
chose to live in Korea town I live in
Koreatown and so many of my friends are
like Amy's the ambassador of Koreatown
she literally knows every plot every
place every pot every sways every spot
every place in Koreatown definitely love
Koreatown and I think the reason why I
love Korea tells so much I remember even
at UCLA I used to drive all the way out
from Westwood to Koreatown which is
almost like a 40-minute drive with
traffic if you guys have been to LA
Koreatown is still very Korean it has so
many mom-and-pop shops and pulling the
walls but it's also in the process of
being very gentrified there are so many
new high-rise apartment buildings luxury
apartment buildings and there are so
many hot spots for going out so many
cool bars and so many hipster little
cafes shops if you want an Instagram
Abul cafe place Koreatown is chock-full
of them and so I feel like it's the
perfect amalgamation of being Korean and
being American and so I feel like
Koreatown is a very strong
representation of Who I am
it's like I still at my heart have very
Korean aspects and at the foundation I
am a Korean person but I had a pink
gentrified no that's all but a little
very traditional but still modern and
progressive all at the same time
honestly because I love food so much I'm
probably just gonna say the food because
I can enjoy a nice vegan bowl of kale
and quinoa with hummus and couscous but
I can also go down for some you know
beef table or some bone marrow soup with
oxtail and I love that I can enjoy two
types of cuisines and really feel at
home with both of them because I love
food I love Korean food I love American
food I love cheeseburgers on front
drives I think it kale food I love it
all I love it all so that is the end of
the tag by the way I wanted to quickly
mention one of my favorite TEDTalks it
is called I am NOT your Asian stereotype
and it touches upon a lot of the topics
I talked today but way more eloquently
and humorously it is just as humorous as
it is cerebral so please watch it I love
it so much here are all the lovely
people I tagged and I also tagged you if
you're watching this if you do this
video be sure to tweet me a link because
I want to watch it and I want to leave a
comment hit that subscribe button like
this video if you liked it I'm here
every single Monday every other Monday
doing the and with Amy but every Monday
just a new video comes out in general so
I love you guys and I'll see you guys
next time
oh I feel like I should his dad
[Music]
you