hmm what else Papa heebie-jeebies it's
uh and today I just wanted to check in
say hi and give you a quick channel and
life update so the past month was kind
of a whirlwind for us we finally got
some help with air-sea so that we could
film get some work done but
unfortunately in LA it's really funny
because all the nannies are all
actresses actresses performers so we
loved our nanny but she got another
acting job or something that's more
aligned with her acting career so she is
no longer gonna be with us which is so
sad but we're totally happy for her I
know that I'm super supportive of anyone
going after their career goals and stuff
so super excited about that but that
left us a huge gap in terms of childcare
so we finally found someon she's gonna
start soon that's why I haven't been
able to update as much in terms of
regular content I know you guys are
seeing a lot of sponsored content that
was filmed maybe a month ago and I hope
you guys always find value in product
integrations sponsored videos that I do
I always try to make it authentic and
make it real to what you guys would
normally see with the addition of
products in there that I personally like
and I would totally recommend so let me
know what your thoughts on er are about
that if you think you are seeing too
many on the channel not seeing enough or
that if it's just right I definitely
don't want to overdo it in any way and
lose you guys lose your trust cuz that's
the most important thing to me but like
I said these are products that I will
always recommend if I like them plus I
think they make pretty delicious recipes
too like the almond breeze wanted to use
in hummus like who would have thought
chef Brooke was so fun to work with and
I love collaborating with chefs and
stuff like that because they give me so
many new
yes for me I get inspirations by going
out there to eat seeing what like the
real professionals do and then I come
home and I put my home cook spin on it
for you guys so it was nice to have like
a celebrity chef professional in our
kitchen doing her things so that was
super fun
so for fall let's talk about upcoming
content that we're gonna be doing so for
fall I want to start doing more baking
challenges so it's gonna be a mix of
like nostalgic items look here I have my
mini animal cookie cutters I'm not gonna
tell you guys what I'm doing with them
yet cuz I'm still testing and perfecting
the recipes for that video I want to do
really fun baking projects I love to
bake but it's been so hot here in LA
that I haven't really been baking much
but once fall rolls around baking is
like one of my favorite activities to do
another area see is a little bit older I
could kind of play with her she has her
own kind of like kitchen set that I've
recently bought her and she likes to
kind of play mix so it'll be really fun
for us to play and do that in the
kitchen together in which case let's say
if we don't have child care how do you
guys feel about having air seat in the
video I mean it's not gonna be as like
straight-up professional like it
normally is we're gonna make it work
somehow and kind of have her in the
background but to be honest I have to
find a way to make it work for us for
you guys and have fun right I have a
feeling she's gonna be a really good
helper in the kitchen cuz all the
kitchen toys that I've gotten her
already she loves and I want to say that
she learned how to say strawberries and
Apple because of her toys because I'm
always like Apple here's an apple apple
and she'll goes ah oh so cute anyway so
yeah that's one of the plans that I have
and then another one talking about chefs
and stuff like that I kind of want to do
like a baking challenge where I follow
along
famous chef recipes and see if they
actually translate to home cooks I don't
know we'll try it out see how that works
cuz for me I still have a lot to learn
in terms of cooking technique stuff in
the kitchen I am NOT a pro at all I
would say I'm a pretty advanced home
chef but by no means am i a professional
like chef like they do so that would be
a really fun challenge for me aside from
that I want to keep doing like fall
hulls great finds that I have and I want
to know I know that monthly favorites
are super popular amongst beauty
youtubers but I haven't really done that
for baby mom products food stuff like
that so what do you guys think if I
started doing like monthly favorites
like that just to recommend products I
know when I post something on Instagram
stories I always get questions about
where did you find that like where can I
find that bold or where can I find that
plate that bid for air sees so I thought
that would be a really fun way to just
kind of package it up together so you
guys can have one place to look for
things let's see what else we try be out
and about content filming outside but
just in terms of environmental stuff
that we can't control I don't feel like
it's up to par with what I want to show
you guys like what we've done at home on
our channel and what we create outside I
feel like it's always super stressful
and it's always not very it's not very
put together so I think we're gonna put
a kibosh on that for a little bit and
then see how it goes maybe I'll be able
to do something a little more planned
out so that it tells a better story for
everybody and it's not just me
scrambling trying to get this footage
here there and then putting it together
because that's kind of stressful so like
I said this past month was kind of crazy
there's a lot of like personal stuff
that I've been going through as well
I'll just share it to you guys I went to
the doctors today
nothing serious but I felt like this
bump on my wrist and it kind of freaked
me out because finding lumps and bumps
on yourself is never a good thing all
right so I found it actually two weeks
ago after I was doing push-ups and I
think I might have put too much pressure
or something on it because they like I
have this little bump the size of a
pimple
so I finally called the nurse and they
had me go in and today when I went in
basically what happened was that my
joints and tendons I guess there was too
much pressure or like overuse of I guess
my thumb cuz I'm on my phone too often
yeah basically I have a fluid-filled sac
on my bone right here it's called like a
ganglion cyst and to be honest it
doesn't hurt too much unless I'm on my
phone so I'm thinking either that or
because I was doing push-ups putting too
much pressure on my wrist my wrist have
always been kind of weak when I used to
be a server I had to wear like this
brace cuz I got carpal tunnel from it so
that's kind of a bummer and then I also
had food poisoning when we went to San
Diego for a mini vacation I don't know
what happened but I was pretty much in
the bathroom for most of the trip AJ was
it was just awful food poisoning is so
worse anything that has to do with like
your stomach that whole thing just I
don't wish it upon anybody because you
just feel so miserable that happened and
then I also went to the doctor's earlier
in August to get a physical and when
they took my blood test my doctor I'm
not sure I'm gonna go back to her I'm
not really loving her by the way but the
doctor sent me an a letter saying that
basically that I have abnormal test
results that my cholesterol is too high
but when I compared it to all of my old
tests it actually was going down so I
really didn't understand
and so this morning when I went to the
doctor I asked her about it a different
doctor about it and she said no your
levels are actually all in range I'm not
sure why she said that to you did you
ask her and I'm like actually I didn't
ask her cuz after that and after
stressing about it I just wanted to get
a second opinion basically I just didn't
really trust her anymore
so it was really good for me to hear
that this doctor thought all the levels
are normal and I even went online to
search I talked to my sister which
coincidentally we have like the same
numbers which is really weird but her
doctor says she's in perfect health so I
was like why did mine say this anyways
the only good thing that came out of
that was it made me realize that I need
to exercise more so my LDL cholesterol
levels were a little higher they were in
no shape or form bad at all according to
this doctor she says they are lower than
your past they're in range but if you
are concerned about high LDL levels
which is the bad cholesterol I would
recommend eating less animal fat and
exercising more so that's exactly what I
started doing I started doing the pop
sugar fitness videos three times a week
for about 30 minutes each if I can't
then I'll try to do really like
high-impact cardio to get my heart
levels up the cardio like cardio has
always been a concern for me because my
dad's side of the family had such like
terrible track record and so many of
them had heart disease so that's
something that's been always concerning
to me and always on my mind so I want to
work on that some more and just make
sure that I'm in the best shape that I
can be whatever I could control so
health-wise I'm okay everything's okay
this bump either will go away or it'll
stay there but if it gets worse then I
have to get it drained or surgically
removed which is not fun but everything
is Oh
kay and that's pretty much all I could
hope for but that's been my health
journey in the past month I'm also
trying to have a smoothie a day just to
make sure I get enough vegetables and
nutrients in so that's been another
daily goal of mine and hey maybe I'll
start doing like a smoothie challenge
either on Instagram or YouTube who knows
I would love to share more smoothie
recipes with you guys once I get that
kind of figured out and yeah come up
with some new stuff anyways I am talking
too much I'm sure you guys have plenty
to do with your day as well thank you so
much for watching and if you guys have
any suggestions for baking projects I
will still do our normal Sunday recipes
which I usually give you guys so many
different ideas on snacks breakfast
meals I'm not sure I'm gonna continue
with the week Wednesday weekday meals
because I want to do baking stuff with
that but I'll be posting more often
regardless once our new nanny is able to
help us free up some time so I'm so
excited to share that with you guys if
you guys want to see more daily updates
from me be sure to follow me on
instagram at honeysucklebee and I will
see you guys tomorrow we have another
video coming out three sandwich ideas
that will be hopefully super delicious
for you I will see you guys tomorrow bye