[Music]
hey PCBs so you guys have been sending
me so many questions about just various
cooking things like where I get my miso
soup where I get my bowls what kind of
food I like to eat Bullis goes on and I
thought today I would have lunch with
you guys and answer all those questions
you guys are kind of like my co-workers
in a way since I don't really have any
working at home Nate is my coworker but
yes so it would be fun to how much with
you guys and answer some questions for
lunch though let me share with you what
I'm having I have some bull ball way
which is a spicy lemongrass Vietnamese
soup it's all the credit for like
the Vietnamese beef soup but this is
actually one of my favorite soups at
home there was a place called gamau that
I would always go to with my co-workers
and my mom especially but I haven't
exactly found one that I've loved here
yet my favorite thing about Boombah way
is the pork blood I know that sounds
gross and some people hate it but I
freaking love it they don't have it in
here sad but I will I am still searching
for my favorite soup noodle here in LA
and all the good ones are down in Orange
County so whenever I have time I will
make it down there but first let me go
ahead and put all the accoutrements in
there we have bean sprouts some purple
cabbage I love purple cabbage in my
soups or just cabbage in general because
it has that nice crunch in there so good
and then some mint leaves
I'm gonna add a lot because it adds a
lot of freshness and it just kind of
changes the flavor a little bit making
it fresh and finally a nice douse of
lime I always put a ton of lime into my
Vietnamese soups whether it's full
Boombah way or even crab noodle soup
all right stir it up
what are you guys having for lunch today
or what did you have for lunch today
hmm hmm so my review on this soup it's
super spicy so if you guys like spicy
food order this if there if it's
available at the Vietnamese restaurant
but I have to say I'm a little
disappointed it does not taste like the
authentic one at home the broth is a
little bland and tastes a lot of
lemongrass but it does the job for now I
guess
I'm still on the search though so if you
guys have a good Vietnamese restaurant
that you recommend in LA please let me
know alright so we're gonna move into
our question um and this is from youtube
from manola s what brand is your miso
paste just want to know so I can compare
the amount of salt in yours to paste
I might get and then Andy Pearson on
Facebook also asked I loved miso soup
what is the sodium content I had
mentioned in my video that you guys
should add just the amount of liquid
accordingly for the miso soup because
sometimes miso paste can be SuperDuper
salty this is the brand that I use it's
called
Maru comm a organic miso and this sodium
content is actually 710 milligrams for
one tablespoon which is super duper
salty you guys to be honest I don't know
if I would buy this brand again just
because it was so salty the brand that I
love is the yellow miso from Whole Foods
it comes in like a squeeze packet and
it's just in the grocery aisle so if you
guys ever go there check that one out or
there's also
really good brown rice me so that they
keep in the refrigerated aisle next to
all the tofu and hummus area have you
guys made the miso soup yet let me know
someone else from the miso soup video
Brenda Roman from the miso soup video
wanted to know is there a substitute
you'd use for seaweed for picky eaters
traditionally you would use seaweed but
if you have picky eaters I would just
leave it out altogether or if they like
spinach or kale I would substitute it
for that and then on Instagram a lot of
you guys talked about my sweater that I
warned that miso soup videos thank you I
love that sweater too D Malta G sorry if
I mispronounced it asked I'm a big fan
awesome sweater by the way I want to get
one like it this sweater is by blank
denim it's called the puppy sweater and
I got it from shopbop and a link it in
the description box below I usually make
my own lunch at home but like at least
once a week we'll try to go out or at
least bring food into the house order
out just because we want to try all the
food that's available here in LA there's
just so many good things mmm this is
like a sausage patty that they made kind
of like I call it circle meat it's like
jello but they made their own and it's
actually really good she's probably my
favorite thing from the soup but there's
just so many good things to try around
here and sometimes it's a hit or miss
but I really just like number one not
having to cook and number two trying new
things I get a lot of inspiration from
that okay this is from mrs. Coleman on
Instagram if there was only one
Vietnamese food you could eat for the
rest of your life what would it be that
is a really hard question
I love Vietnamese noodle soups um
there's a dish in San Jose from this
restaurant called boom cow or a volatile
restaurant and it's called Houthi openam
said egg I know it sounds sordid I know
that's like a mouthful to say but pretty
much it's a noodle soup it's from the
central region and they serve it with
glass noodles and there's a meat sauce
that goes on top of it you can order it
wet or dry and I always order it dry so
that it has that meat sauce and it comes
with crab like a crunchy deep-fried
shrimp thing and just all these
different herbs oh my gosh I miss home
just talking about that I haven't found
anything like that here yet but if I
could eat one Vietnamese dish every day
for the rest of my life it would
probably be that just because it has
fresh herbs and all the different
flavors land sea glass noodles soup all
of my favorite things the soup actually
comes on the side so if I wanted to I
could like thin it out and just make it
my own
well would you guys heat for the rest of
your life let's do some rapid fire
because I'm talking a lot on yellow on
IG stories as what's your favorite
guilty pleasure food chips kettle chips
salt and vinegar or peperoncini what is
your husband's ethnicity or background
he looks mixed-race not MIT nummies this
is by M M's obsessed 22 he's actually
half Korean and half Caucasian
I'm trying to convince someone to do
like a husband tag so you guys help me
get him on let's put out a bait for him
if this video gets 5,000 likes he will
make an appearance I will make him make
an appearance yeah let's do it guys
from Becky xx will you and your family
dress up for Halloween and what kind of
food do you give your doggie yes we will
definitely dress up for Halloween we're
gonna be pineapple people so neat and I
just have lame t-shirts but era C and
all we definitely have costumes and I
will show you guys their costumes once
we get them all dressed up more and more
I've been trying to give
fresh foods and he was steamed
vegetables yesterday I gave him steamed
broccoli and green beans just whatever I
cook up I'll give him a little bit and
then we use Kirkland it's salmon and
sweet potatoes dog food and yeah he
loves that stuff too I apologize I can't
pronounce it but it's peace uch i t KR r
z0 one how do you even say that where do
you get your bowls they are so cute this
is probably like the number one question
that I get on my channel all the time
and you guys I get them from various
places but 90% of my bowls are from
Anthropologie they have the cutest bowls
and measuring cups and everything all
the knickknacks that you can find so if
you guys are ever bored go there check
out their home section it's amazing but
I also get a lot of things from Crate
and Barrel Amazon and West Elm Len no in
what are your countertops called Dzung
so this one right here it's a marble
slab and I will link it for you guys in
the description box below as well as
just a marble slab from Crate and Barrel
and then these are just plain wooden
counters a butcher block another
question from speechless double zero
what kind of blender was that from the
seven life-changing healthy smoothies
video
it's the Vitamix s55 it's a personal
blender and I love the size of it it's
perfect for two drinks and I use it all
the time so again I will link it in the
description box below ah another one
from the five chia pudding video where
did you get the jars I always get this
question you guys I get all of my jars
the little ones are all from world
market and it's by a brand called wek
jars and I love the shape of it it's not
like your traditional mason jar it's
like a glass jar that has like a bulge
at the bottom so it's easier to hold on
to and they're like 399 apiece so
definitely go check out world market or
I think you can find it at
williams-sonoma as well but it takes a
while for it to come did did you did you
huh I like this one I like this one
Sarah whines why don't you have more
subscribers I absolutely love your
channel you're so sweet and charming
thank you so much you guys but um I
don't know why I don't have more
subscribers so please share my channel
with your friends and family and help me
get the word out one day I hope to make
it to a million but in the meantime I'm
actually really happy with how
everything's going
um we're just trying to work really hard
and I want to come up with more fun
content to be honest sometimes I do get
bored with making recipes all the time
which is why I'm doing more of these
kind of formats where I talked to you
guys I get bored working alone and with
me and baby that's pretty much my
coworker and I'm with them 24/7 so
talking to you guys and she's building a
community on YouTube has been really
really great and kind of therapeutic for
me especially since I moved down to LA
and don't really have any friends yet so
this is not a question but a lot of my
Vietnamese viewers often comment or ask
me questions in Vietnamese and I just
wanted to number one practice it because
I do want to teach era see how to speak
Vietnamese and mine's kind of rusty so I
think just kind of talking a lot just
practicing it with her and hopefully you
guys will help me improve but gamma gat
bang a guy video good yo my name is
young and Vietnamese goodnight and boom
away
come along you new Mukunda toy so yeah
anyways I wanted to thank you guys again
for joining me at lunch I don't know if
it's fun for you but it's been totally
fun for me to just talk about random
things and just really have a real lunch
hour with my buddies you guys are all
buddies so if you guys like these videos
be sure to give it a thumbs up and let
me know if you want to see more of it
that really helps me to figure out which
direction to go if you guys don't like a
video I'll stop making them if you like
them then I will continue and honestly I
think you guys like the
and hack videos right that I posted
yesterday so I will try to come up with
some more fun ways to save you money
anyways in the meantime this weekend I
will be sharing another soup recipe and
you guys will stay tuned to see what it
is have a good day guys bye
[Music]