good morning my friends it's actually
noon I love my friends it's Nina and I
am currently barefaced as you can tell
by the title of this video I am doing a
get ready with me I'm going to do my
makeup with you guys because I'm going
to be talking about a certain topic and
I need to be doing stuff with my hands
so I'm doing my makeup so I was sick for
like 16 hours I don't know what that was
I thought I was actually sick I had a
sore throat and all that so I thought I
was actually sick and I was really like
shook I thought I couldn't film video
but you know I took one day to rest then
I'm fine now so I don't know what
happened that was a weird experience but
I'm okay for now
my throat is kind of okay my nose I
might sound a little different but
that's fine but as you can tell by the
title of this video I am going to be
doing a get ready with me as I talk
about a certain topic and I'm gonna talk
about a topic that I feel like is
interesting before you guys and really
just explains a lot about me so I am
korean-american I was born in America
but ethnically my family is entirely
from Korea I was the first one born in
America and so korean-american I also
don't know what that is I don't know if
it's a pimple or if it's a mosquito bite
whatever it is I haven't touched it
because I'm not dealing with it I'm just
gonna let it heal on its own whatever it
is I don't know what you are but you
better leave soon my makeup routine is
actually really short so I might finish
my makeup before I even finish talking
about my story so don't mind that just
if you're actually getting ready just
keep going anyway so about being a
Korean American even though I'm the
first to be born in America I am a
second-generation Korean American now
you're probably wondering how that works
well so I was born in America which
makes me culturally very American
because that's all I've ever known so my
dad grew up in Korea he was born there
but then when he was nine he moved to
the US with his family with his mom and
sister and then started a life here
so he's considered the first generation
or 1.5 generation because he was the one
to really
first experience transitioning to the
American lifestyle and all that so his
story is definitely very different from
mine because he was an actual immigrant
who came to the US and had to deal with
a lot anyway he came here when he was
still very young so he was able to pick
up the American culture he had to pick
it up really fast because obviously he
needed to blend in with everyone else
and he was kind of like he was the new
kid you know there weren't a lot of
Asians where he grew up I don't think
there were really any Koreans or agents
around him but my dad definitely picked
up the American culture very fast and he
can speak English perfectly
he speaks both Korean and English very
perfectly the first language he will
speak is English he'll speak Korean if
he has to but otherwise he'll just speak
in English he spent literally most of
his life in America so he's definitely
very Americanized now moving on from
that my mom she came to the US for
college so she spent her entire
adolescence and youth in Korea so
culturally she's Korean very Korean I
can't even tell if I finished my BB
cream the first language she'll speak
its Korean she's culturally very Korean
she only really cares about Korean media
entertainment and culture and all that
so the next thing that happened was me
being born I was the first of my entire
family to be born in the US I was born
in California specifically the Bay Area
so I was fortunate enough to be growing
up in a place that is very diverse
we were very culturally diverse and so I
never experienced being the only Asian
aren't the only Korean I was literally
surrounded by a lot of Asians and a lot
of Koreans so I never felt different in
that sense where I grew up specifically
in my city there were a lot of Asians so
I didn't experience that much racism
it was mostly chilled because if you
were a racist you would get attacked so
so that was good I didn't go to
preschool I spent most of my life at
home with my family my mom my
my brother my one brother because my
other brother was born 14 years after me
so it was first my older younger brother
so we were all just together so my
childhood before school really was
surrounded by my parents and so I was
exposed to both Korean and English which
honestly got confusing and really
affected the way that I grew up because
I was having 2 languages spoken to me at
the same time it did affect the way that
I developed language wise so because I
didn't go to preschool I kind of missed
out on that first year or two of
socializing with other kids when I first
went to kindergarten I actually didn't
understand the concept of going to
school I honestly didn't know what it
was so when my parents dropped me off on
the first day I remember leaving the
classroom with them because I was like
where are they going why are they
leaving me here so I was like following
them but that my parents are like no you
got to stay here and I was like what is
this
but yeah so kindergarten was my first
exposure to other kids I was always
surrounded by you know like my mom's
friends children but other than that
this was the first time I really had to
be in like a social environment so it
was terrifying anyway moving on when I
was in school for the first few years I
experienced sort of being behind most of
my peers and that was an obvious thing
because I didn't go to preschool so I
already was behind socially but also
education wise I was also behind my
peers because I had both English and
Korean in my head that I didn't pick up
either language well so I couldn't speak
English now while I obviously didn't
know how to read that well all that kind
of stuff so was obviously behind my
peers and I was eventually put into an
eld program even though my first
language was technically never Korean
never I never learned Korean and then
forgot it like most people know it was
never my first language or anything like
that so I was just literally developing
slowly just because it was confusing so
I was put into LD which really kind of
took a toll on my confidence in school I
already felt very behind my peers and it
was
you know just like a feeling of kind of
embarrassment and shame that you know
why am i so behind already
and I was like freaking what five you
know give me a break
but I was put into LD but I left the
program so fast - it was my first year
of you know being in a social
environment so I needed time to adjust
I had experiences in the past word you
know I would experience kids being mean
about me not being so smart or not so
you know quick I actually had this one
kid make fun of me for being a slow
reader and I was like looking back I was
like we're in first grade what do you
expect from me but there were lots of
moments like that that just kind of
really affected my self confidence so
growing up for me I became more and more
distance from my Korean identity just
because as I got older you know I I was
going through a lot of physical changes
and I just physically didn't look Korean
or I didn't fit in that well with my
peers I was tall or at least bigger than
most Koreans and so I already felt this
kind of physical and security but I
didn't look Korean and I also as I was
growing up because my dad spoke English
in the house and because I only went to
American schools I only picked up
English I didn't pick up Korean because
I wasn't very involved in Korean
communities growing up I did have Korean
friends growing up and there were a huge
part of my life and they still could are
but they're all kind of doing their own
things as everyone really does after
high school and all that you know I was
mostly surrounded by Korean and friends
just because it was kind of like being
with people you can relate to but as I
got older personally for me my
insecurities were getting a little too
out of hand that it started affecting my
relationships with not only just other
people but also with myself I was
becoming more self-aware as usually one
does you know you start to really think
about yourself as you grow up I already
carried this insecurity throughout most
of my youth of being behind other people
just because that's kind of how I grew
up I became more and more insecure about
me not being able to speak Korean
or you know understand Korean etiquette
and culture and that kind of stuff and
more and more I would make mistakes that
kind of really affected my self-esteem
you know I went to Korean church and all
that but whenever I was part of these
communities I felt this personal
detachment from everyone else just
because I felt like again I wasn't
blending in I felt like I was lacking
something and when I was in these Korean
communities they would be able to speak
to each other in Korean for fun and I
always felt kind of embarrassed that I
couldn't participate like this there was
always this kind of it was really more
of like a personal insecurity that I
just couldn't communicate even though it
really didn't matter that much because
you know obviously they could speak
English and it was just the thing that
they were able to do and obviously my
upbringing was different than them so
but because I wasn't very confident
myself already it really took a toll on
just how I felt about myself and just my
identity in that kind of stuff and
communicating with Korean adults
especially really affected my
self-esteem because I wouldn't be able
to communicate with them and it really
just felt embarrassing for me that I
couldn't speak Korean and I was just
like I just felt like they were judging
me and like the way that I grew up like
this Korean can't speak Korean what is
she so it was always like a personal
kind of feeling I never really
complained about it just because I
didn't want to or feel like I needed to
complain about it but inside it was very
it was just disappointing for me that I
couldn't participate like this and you
know everyone else could blend in so
easily between being an American and
being Korean and for me I couldn't
really identify with being Korean
because I honestly couldn't relate to
the culture or speak the language so it
really was just kind of it was just
frustrating really I was already a
pretty socially anxious person so this
adding onto that kind of really just
made knowing who I was really difficult
eventually this insecurity of not
blending in with my peers really got to
me and I just kind of detached myself
from these communities just because I
already felt like I didn't belong even
though it really didn't
have to go to that extent it's just
personally it got to a point where it
kind of needed to leave because I didn't
feel great about not being able to
communicate my own language firstly I
already felt physically different from
other Koreans just because I have
naturally curly hair which is kind of
strange for an East Asian especially for
a Korean was really bright I honestly
still don't know how I have curly wavy
hair physically I already felt like I
didn't belong and then culturally I
obviously didn't belong in that sense so
I was just like then what makes me a
Korean and so at that time I really
didn't understand the concept of it so
it really just really got to my
self-confidence my self-esteem because I
really didn't know how to deal with it
so in high school I was surrounded by a
different social group because my
friends were moving around people were
you know moving on that kind of stuff so
naturally I went to a new friend group
and my friend group was entirely not
Korean just because that's how things
turned out okay see so I already
finished my makeup actually I should do
my mascara so naturally I just had this
different friend group that was not
Korean so I didn't really have that
opportunity to be immersed in Korean
culture just because there was really no
tie to it other than obviously my
parents and my family and all that and
nothing in my life really
urged me to you know be connected to my
Korean side I was very much immersed in
Western culture you know I was watching
programs from the UK and stuff from
America American TV shows that kind of
stuff obviously because I'm an American
so that's what I was kind of into I
didn't I didn't pay much attention to
Korean media at all I wasn't watching
Korean dramas or listening to kpop or
anything in my in high school really
because that wasn't part of my social
circle my social environment so through
that time I was really just not
emotionally connected to myself I was
really kind of living every single day
just to get to the next day and
eventually graduate and you know I was
just having fun I was very much still
kind of insecure in high school but at
that point I wasn't letting it control
my life or affect
I felt living my life and so in high
school I really didn't think about being
Korean it wasn't just like something I
had to worry about the crucial point in
my journey of being korean-american
really happened in my last year of high
school and on from that so there was a
personal situation that affected my
entire family and myself especially and
it was in my last year of high school
when my great-grandma who was a huge
part of my family really she was dealing
with Alzheimer's and she was getting old
and she was in the hospital and why did
I put mascara on I probably should have
put mascara on after this this was
really wrong timing in the last part of
2014 / 2015 my great-grandma was in the
hospital dealing with Alzheimer's we
only got to visit my grandma about once
a year just because she lived in a
different state
she lived in America that's how my mom
was able to come to the u.s. because my
great-grandma also came but my
great-grandma was sick and she was
dealing with Alzheimer's so she already
couldn't really remember who we were and
because we were only able to visit her
once a year we didn't know how she was
doing we didn't know that she got to
this point and and so she was in the
hospital and this was the first time I
was dealing with a family member being
sick and at this stage in life and it
really was kind of surreal for me just
because just because I didn't know how
to deal with it because throughout high
school
you know I didn't worry about this kind
of stuff even though you know obviously
time was passing and for me it was just
I it was something I couldn't comprehend
but when I visited her at the hospital
it started to hit me that you know she
didn't remember us and after being so
careless about not about myself
but you know not really thinking about
myself at a deeper level suddenly it was
all kind of hitting me at the same time
that so much time passed and there was
so much that I wanted to do I didn't
think about why did I wear mascara so at
this point my grandma didn't really
remember us that well my great-grandma
by the way is my mom's grandma so she
was a very huge part of her life you
know she basically raised her my
great-grandma was a huge part of my life
as well when I was younger I would look
forward to her staying over with us you
know even though there was this literal
language barrier she was a huge part of
my childhood and I would be excited
whenever she would stay with us and when
she would brush my hair every single
morning even though my hair you're not
really supposed to brush it like the way
that she did she didn't really
understand that you know curly hair
you're not supposed to brush it with a
certain brush and she didn't really
understand that but she still did
because she wanted to make my hair nice
and pretty and so there was that
cultural difference that always made me
kind of laugh as I got older as I
understood my hair more but um so she
was a huge part of my life but the thing
that kind of really hit me when all this
was happening was the fact that I
realized I never really had a full
conversation with her nor do I even
remember having a conversation with her
so this sort of guilt started Wow okay
okay okay oh stop so this sense of guilt
was kind of just jumping out at me from
nowhere because I didn't think about it
I kind of took it for granted I always
for some reason thought my grandma was
just gonna be around for a long time and
this overwhelming sense of guilt kind of
just came at me and I was like I really
never had a conversation with her
because she can't speak English
I never bothered to speak with her in
Korean because I couldn't and so that
was really when I started realizing yeah
literally I don't know why I did my
makeup I should just left my face bare I
also just felt helpless because at this
point there was nothing I could do she
already didn't remember who we were so
it really was just a hopeless time that
you know there was nothing I could do at
this point except be there for her as
much as possible and from then on that's
kind of when I took myself more
seriously and really thought about how
you know I can't really be distracted
from myself anymore I really should
think more because things changed so
fast so few months later my great
grandma did pass away that was kind of
the end of that part of my life
so that's kind of when you know I became
more self reflexive and started really
taking myself more seriously because I
was really away from this part of me
that you know I could have spent more
time on so it was just a very
frustrating time because at the time too
I was still dealing with insecurities
that I kind of pushed back so moving on
from that I graduated high school it was
my last year of high school when this
happened so I was about to finish high
school so I finished high school
and this was when you know I finally was
going to college being independent
really learning a lot being by myself
that kind of stuff and because I was
being more self reflexive because I was
analyzing all my life will have been
more this is kind of when the process
happened when I started becoming more
aware of my background and everything in
college I learned a whole lot more about
you know the self and all that I was
taking a lot of psychology classes
sociology classes all that kind of stuff
really just being more exposed to
everything and I was just becoming more
educated about a person so I was being
more self reflexive and more empathetic
at this point because before I didn't
really care so much about these deeper
things you know I was kind of just going
through the motions just trying to get
their life that I never really thought
about people
or myself or anything at a deeper sense
so in college I was becoming more aware
of how you know people work just I'm not
a psychology majors I'm not an expert at
this kind of stuff but I was definitely
becoming more exposed to it so my mom
never really showed us how my
great-grandma passing away affected her
I I assumed she was heartbroken because
obviously if I was heartbroken she would
have been much more broken but I never
really realized how much this affected
her until she told me as I got older my
parents would just talk to me about more
things and you know relate to me on a
personal level that kind of stuff and
there was this one day when my mom told
me how much you know how important my
great-grandma was to her and it was
because my great-grandma she spoke only
Korean you know she was culturally very
Korean so this was kind of how my mom
was able to connect to Korea and connect
to your old family and so when my great
grandma passed away that kind of side of
my mom just kind of vanished and it just
felt a little more lonely for her and I
never realized that because I always
kind of took her speaking English being
able to speak two languages being able
to switch from culture to culture I took
that for granted
and I didn't realize that it's still
hard for her to understand American
culture even though she's able to speak
English that doesn't mean she's part of
the American culture so when my dad and
I are speaking to each other we can
speak for a long time about anything
because we actually understand the
context and all that but my mom she
sometimes doesn't understand that it's
just like how I'm not able to understand
or I wasn't able to understand you know
Korean culture and etiquette and I felt
that shame and that embarrassment and
that detachment but I never pieced it
together and saw my mom was experiencing
the same thing but kind of the other way
around and so at this point I realized
that my mom too was very heavily
affected by my great grandma passing and
this kind of side to her was kind of
gone and she didn't really have someone
she can fully 100% communicate with
heart to heart even though she had
family here there was still the cultural
difference no matter what and it really
was just difficult to understand but
because I was becoming
are aware of things outside of myself I
started to really see the value in
owning my Korean identity and you know
being part of my culture because it's
not just being able to speak a language
or not it really affected me at a much
more personal level because I realized
that if I'm not able to speak Korean if
I'm not able to have a sense of Korean
culture I'm gonna have this distance
from my mom as well and I didn't want
that I just got tired of this distance
and this detachment just looking back I
wish I was just more secure of myself so
I could just be part of it because you
know being distant from your culture it
really is a lonely feeling and so at
this point because I was really by
myself and I had nothing to lose
I wanted to immerse myself more in the
Korean culture because I didn't want my
mom to feel so lonely and for myself I
didn't want to feel detached anymore and
at this point social media was becoming
a bigger thing you know I had the
Internet
I finally had these resources around me
that I was like I think it's time to
just own it and just immerse myself more
because I really had nothing to lose I
would only be able to gain this part of
me that I was always kind of afraid to
gain and kind of always far front even
if people might not think I'm a Korean
even if I'm not able to communicate with
other Koreans or relate to them no
matter what it's still 100% a part of me
my entire family is from Korea even
though I was born in America it's still
100% part of me even if other people
don't think so it's still Who I am and
that kind of just took too long for me
to realize sorry my camera died but
anyway there was just nothing stopping
me from finally being immersed in my
culture I was 19 and I became much more
aware of myself
and all that that I just didn't want to
be ashamed anymore of trying to be
myself you know obviously growing up I
may have you know developed slowly I may
have not been able to personally relate
with other Koreans but that was when I
was younger and I can't let that affect
my life anymore so from then on I
decided to finally start learning Korean
because I finally had
I had resources to finally teach myself
Korean but also an important part of me
finally being proud of my Korean
identity was definitely kpop my parents
have always exposed me to kpop you know
I grew up with BIGBANG and Girls
Generation I knew about kpop since I was
a kid but I never there wasn't really
the stand culture of kpop in high school
obviously things have changed and kpop
is a huge thing now but when I was in
high school even though it wasn't really
that long ago there wasn't that kind of
culture so I wasn't able to you know
really be immersed in kpop and actually
my mom introduced me to BTS which was my
first k-pop group that I really started
standing my mom actually introduced me
to them because it was the Billboard
Music Awards and my mom was talking
about BTS getting the nomination all and
I was like huh kpop cool and then I just
for some reason I wanted to check them
out and then it changed my life but
because of that it was kind of this
gateway into Korean culture I started
watching more Korean dramas listening to
more Korean artists in general just
finally being able to find stuff to
relate to with my mom my mom was always
watching these Korean dramas and all
that and I never knew what she was
watching her and talking about now I
actually understood and it kind of just
felt nice that I was able to finally
relate to my mom in some kind of sense
obviously k-pops not the epitome of
Korean culture but it definitely is a
part of it and it helped me kind of be
more exposed to whatever my mom cared
about and I'm very much in love with all
of it and it definitely shaped me to
become the person I am today for the
last year and a half I've been learning
Korean and I'm definitely better I still
have a slight insecurity about it just
because growing up you know I used to
get teased for trying to speak Korean
that kind of stuff there still I'm not
perfect there's still that underlying
insecurity oh if I speak Korean it's
gonna be embarrassing so even though I
don't speak Korean all the time you know
I speak it with my mom and I speak it
was my dad sometimes but I'm definitely
able to understand it more now I'm
actually able to speak to my grandma my
dad's mom in Korean because we always
spoke in English to her and we never
bothered to try to speak
in my first few months that I was
learning Korean I surprised her by
suddenly starting to speak Korean and
she was so surprised she was so happy
and really appreciative that I was
actually learning Korean and it was
really just such a nice experience I
want to be able to make my family's life
easier because even though we're all in
America it wouldn't kill me to speak in
Korean with them and just make their
lives a little bit easier but that it's
really my experience so far growing up
korean-american I was very much afraid
to be connected to that side of me
because I always felt like I wasn't
enough and I felt like I couldn't relate
to other people this doesn't just have
to do with being korean-american this
applies to anyone who is a child of
immigrant parents coming to a country
where you know you're not the dominant
people it can be very difficult to know
who you are because you may not feel
confident enough to own your ethnical
background but you obviously physically
don't fit in with everyone else and it's
just really weird and hard and it really
can affect you negatively but there's
really just nothing wrong with
identifying as the ethnicity that you
really are I only gained more by
identifying with this part of me like
there was nothing that I lost from it
this journey so far of learning is just
so eye opening and rewarding I still
obviously don't always 100% feel Korean
it's still you know I it's still hard
for me to blend in with the Korean
community especially in my school
there's a huge Korean community but you
know obviously there are some
differences but now I'm just not taking
it so personally because oh well and
also lately in Korea they've been
styling their hair to kind of make it
wavy and it kind of just makes me feel
both happy but also triggered at the
same time because I always used to be so
ashamed not ashamed but like I used to
you know kind of be sad that my hair
wasn't straight but you know now people
are appreciating different hair styles
and so that's nice I guess but now it's
just I'm not afraid to be in touch with
my Korean side there's nothing wrong
with
identifying as my ethnicity that was my
experience growing up as korean-american
and honestly the past 20 years have been
a lot but it's been a lot of growth and
there's just a lot more for me to learn
and it's just a nice journey and it's a
lot of fun I hope that you guys can also
if you're also dealing with something
like this you can not be afraid to be in
touch with your ethnicity even if people
don't think you're enough who cares this
is my background this is who I am I'm
going to do as much as I can on my part
to learn about my ethnicity and own my
nationality as well people should learn
more than one language honestly the
world is so interesting and people are
trying their best so people should learn
more I hope this video was interesting
and eye-opening and wholesome I don't
know let me know your upbringing your
story let me hear it I want to hear it
that is all I need to say I am
emotionally tired for this video thank
you so much for watching we are going to
end it with a hug and I hope that in
your journey of knowing yourself don't
care about what other people think about
you just own your own identity and just
do the best that you can okay that is it
for this video goodbye my friends I will
see you next time