good morning everyone
I really hate long
intros for get ready
with me so we're
just gonna jump right in
firstly I'm going to
pull my hair back
out of my face
it's crazy today you
get started with
the moisturizer and
primer so yesterday
September first
my one of my best
friends and her
boyfriend are visiting
Atlanta they're
staying with me for
Dragon Con which is this weekend
and I went on a whim
yesterday I bought
a one-day pass and
it was only $40 so
that I could attend
my first ever Dragon
Con and to be honest
it was very fun I
am pretty ignorant
on the whole like I
guess reasoning behind
Dragon Con like
all of the characters
that were there
and all the anime
and all of that I
don't know I don't
even want to I don't
want to offend anyone
but I went in one
of my friends costumes
as Princess Leia
and I'll insert
photos and I'm just
going in with primer
after moisturizer
and it was so fun and
I got to meet so
many nice people and
see so many cool
things I'm going to
apply a little bit
of concealer for my
problem areas right
now my friend Melissa
calls played as a
character called
Maya from this game
called Borderlands and she did a
fantastic job and she
and her boyfriend
are going for the
rest of this weekend
and I'm not I've been
meeting today at
2:00 p.m. that I'm
getting ready for but
it was so fun I saw
Harry Potter I saw
Disney Princesses who
else did I see oh
I saw Death Note
characters I do watch I
have seen Death Note
so I was familiar
with that it was just
it was so fun just
going to blend this
out now um today my
meeting I'm meeting
a friend that I go
to school with here
at Georgia State and
and I'm also meeting
with a friend who
produces music we
are going to talk
about
a proposal for this
podcast that's run
here in Atlanta it's
called how stuff
works and basically
they have a topic
for everything except
for fashion on the
podcast and so my
friend who works for a
app who specializes
in what's hot on the
runway and like what
people are wearing
and why it's popular
and like season
trends and predictions
like she really
does everything
with fashion and of
course me with my
experience modeling we
are going to propose
the idea to the
company of expanding
their genres and
adding like a fashion
genre so that more
people will listen
I think it'd be
really cool and my
friend and I have I
would say significant
experience so
we're going to come
up with a paper and
go there someday
soon and submit our
proposal
so hopefully that
works out and um my
friend who produces
music who we're
meeting I'm just
connecting those two
because I just
feel like you know
whatever you feel
like you meet one
person and then you
go and me to another
person and you're
like they would
benefit by having each
other's contact I
don't know so today
we're meeting for
coffee and right now
my roommate is out
she just left for her
day and my friends
are are at DragonCon
right now for the
parade happening today
okay after a concealer
I'm gonna go in
with this NYX color
correction palette
mmm this is kind of
uh I don't know it
just seems kind of
gimmicky whenever I
first saw it in
stores and then I saw
someone use it on a
YouTube tutorial and
I was like oh I need
that in my life so
anyways I went to got
it and I've been
using it for about
a week now it is
awesome let me tell
you so right now for
the yellow in the
palette I like to
brighten areas I think
it's a lot like a
banana powder and
I'm not sure how
familiar you guys are
with makeup I do
watch a lot of
tutorials so I like to
put the yellow to
brighten I like to put
the green on my red
areas which I like
my cheeks to be have
some flushed to
them so I really apply in the
around my acne which
would be my chin
area right now I'll
apply this here in
terms of like media
that I'd like movies
that I've seen recently
I really don't
go and watch movies
at the movie theater
all too often I put
the purple where I
want to be black more
concealed I guess
you could say so I
like to put purple
around my nose and
then the lighter
shade I used to contour
like softer on
my forehead and then
the darker shade I
use for my cheekbones
so anyways I've
seen this movie
recently called good
time and it was so
good and I really
don't even like paying
the prices of the
movie theater because
it's so expensive
to go see a movie now
it's like twelve
dollars that's crazy
but whatever um anyways
I went to a good
time and it was
such a real movie I
cannot I cannot
explain to you enough
how crazy that was
the movie was crazy
it had me thinking
days after I saw it
like I'm still
it's just like one of
those very I guess
realistic movies
where you know this
situation could
happen to you and how
grateful you are that
you're not in it
and that's the best
way I can explain it
it has Edward Cullen
from Twilight
Robert okay I was
just about to ask
it's Robert Pattinson
Robert Pattinson
is in it he does a
fantastic job and has
a lot of new and
upcoming actors as well
so it gave a lot of
exposure to them and
it won a lot of
awards at the Cannes
Film Festival this
year at one Civil War
so I don't know if you
guys can tell but
it really that lidar
contour shade
really helps blur out
any problems you
have around your
hairline I love it
I don't know about
you guys are where
you live but here in
Georgia it's really
hard to wear a
foundation without it
coming off during
the day so I really
I'm skipping it
altogether today I'm
just doing a concealer and color
correction somedays
I will do the full
fledged full-face
foundation full
coverage everything
but today I want to
go a little bit more
natural after that
I'm gonna take
actual contouring brush
I blend out this
harsh contour oh I
guess I could talk
about the book cover
I have been chosen
to be a part of it's
gonna take place
later in September I
don't know if you
guys can hear my
voice but I'm still
sick and I finally
pass by finally town
I finally found the
penicillin that I
brought with me here
to college but I
really don't even
like medication I'd
rather myself like
fight it off like my
own immune system fight
off but I'm what
I've got down my
nose and between my
brows and on my forehead
and I really don't
even like applying
makeup on my forehead
because of my
bangs but I am going
to let them grow
out and they're almost
long enough that
I can part them in
the center and like
shape them to the
sides of my head but
they're not quite
there so I only apply
concealer like right
up here I'm going
to take a Real
Techniques brush and
blend this out and
I really stopped
using a sponge
because I read this
article on all of the
bacteria oh if you
don't wash your
sponge or even your
brushes like once
twice a week there's
so much bacteria that
builds in them and
the sponge was just a
lot worse than the
brushes I use because
of the water and
it if it gets warm
then it like is
harvesting terrible
bacteria for your
face I was like oh
my god so I threw
away my sponges and
now I'm just using
brushes that I'm
cleaning more regularly
oh my gosh so today
I have that little
meeting at 2 p.m.
and then tomorrow I
have the opportunity
to go to Six Flags
which I would totally
love to do but I'm
having to save money
oh my gosh if
anybody's watching
me if you're in high
school middle school
elementary school
please hon please
save your money
because you're going
to need it later on
in life don't spend
it on ridiculous
things and I'm not
saying going to Six
Flags or any amusement park is
ridiculous but if you
have other goals
and you have other
priorities oh my god
I feel like there's
a hair oh my god
there is
that's still annoying
when you can't
find a hair okay I'm
going to set this
all with some NIC
setting car anyways
there's a trip I want to take in
December if I don't
have any plans I
want to go somewhere
during my break off
school I possibly
want to go out of the
country but if I
financially cannot
afford that and
I'll go somewhere
domestically like
there's this train
ride that goes from
Southern California
all the way up to not
Vancouver Canada
I'm sorry Seattle
Washington for like 90
something dollars
so really your only
major expenses getting
a plane ticket to
Southern California
if you don't already
live there
of course I live
in Georgia so it's
quite an expense to
get from the east
coast to the west coast
but I would love
to do that because
of only been to
California three times
I really want to
go experience like
Portland Oregon as
well and I love
Seattle I've been to
Seattle three times
and actually and
like if I ever have a
job that allows me
to stay in Seattle I
would love to live
there just because
of the weather and
the coziness and the
coldness and of
course I'm studying
Mandarin and there's
a lot of Chinese
spoken in Seattle and
Vancouver Canada just
the west coast in
general there's a lot
of Asian influence
and I love it so much
with a night another
NYX palette just a
cool tone go in
there and define a
little bit more the
sides of my nose and
my chinny-chin-chin
so anyways I just
think that would
be so fun to do in
December because a
plane ticket if you
plan it far enough
in advance is only
about three hundred
and fifty dollars
and then you sleep on the train
overnight I'm gonna
go in with a little
bit of blush on my
cheeks okay on to
eyes I am going to
be using my masking
tape today to get
the perfect I shall
look but to finish
that story I just
think that that would
be an amazing trip
and you get to see
so much of the West
Coast for so cheap
and like you'd
actually get to
experience it because
you're not
taking like the
touristy route you're
taking like an actual
train route and
you get to sleep on
the train overnight
and then you get to
have like a full day
and each stop and
then you get like say
if you want to like
go somewhere you can
take a bus from that
stopping like go
further into California
or Oregon or
Washington State today
I'm going to do a
smoky I think with a
cut crease perhaps
I might actually zoom
you guys into this
oh my gosh that's
great okay moving on
to base the white
color I've already
just applied I'm going
to apply a little
bit more and then the
transition shade
in the crease and then a darker
transitions shade
closer to the actual
crease of your eye
and then even darker
one lower
I'm going to pop like
an orange II shade
right in the center
and they're like a
brown in the corner
and then like a dark
brown just to blend
okay now for a cut
crease I'm realizing
I'm not very good at
talking while I'm
doing eyeshadow I think
it's hard enough
already and then I
tried talking about
the stuff oh I love
looking at myself at
having eyelashes
yeah I know that you
guys really want to
see more videos on
that I just felt
awkward honestly
talking about I don't
feel awkward I
just felt sad maybe
when I'm talking
about trichotillomania
I don't know why
I guess because I'm
battling with it for
so long it just is
something annoying
and whenever you
have to talk about
something you don't like it gets
annoying but like
it's fine for me to
talk about I just it's
not like my first
choice of a topic
video but I realize a
lot of people do want
to hear about it
and I do need to
spread awareness so
anyway it's going in
with a brush for a
cut crease I have
a little bit of
concealer on my hand
and we're going to
apply that just on
the center on my
natural eyelid so I
didn't bring it all
the way across I'm
only doing the very
inside okay now
time for a shimmer
shadow I'm going to
apply this with my
finger just because
I feel like it a
adheres better to the
cut crease I think
I'm gonna choose a
gold yeah this color
right here whoa that's
really put there
I'm gonna choose this
color and pop this
right there
huh that's okay it's
pretty nice nice
I'm going to take a
black now and blend
the Browns on the
outside together with
the gold
I'm taking my original
brush I'm going
to take an orange
II color and blend
those okay we're not
done with eyeshadow
I'm just gonna take
off the tape so that
we can do the bottom
lash line this is
why I should do I shadow before
foundation oh and it
even took some of
it off Oh No correct
this right here I
don't know what happened
right there I'm
gonna take a touch
of concealer on
either side there
we go he's gonna
repair the damage don't
really like this
it's being really
patchy today hmm oh
this is really bad
oh wow okay that's a
little better I'm
just gonna highlight
my brow bone with a
white shade for my
bottom shadow I'm
gonna take the orange shade the
transition shade and
just line under my
eye ooh I kind of
like that actually
okay it's coming
together I'm not being
and then we're gonna
blend that out I'm
gonna take a break
from my eyes and a
highlight and just
blow that out okay
for my brows it's
gonna darken them
using a NYX mascara nice
I love the bold brow
if you can't tell
so just looking in
the monitor I think
that my black is
pretty patchy on the
outside so I'm gonna
go back in and
darken that up and
blend it okay I think
that corrected part
of the problem okay
now that my lips are
line I'm gonna go
in with this berry
color sorry for my
acne right here it
happens this color is
very dark as you can
see and I kind of
want to lighten it up
in the center with
a nude color so I'm
gonna grab that real
quick
think I'm just gonna
stick to mascara
honestly I'm just
gonna curl my lashes
and do mascara on the
kind of hurts and
it's funny because
whatever I used to
pluck my lashes it
did not hurt and
people will whenever I
tell them that I have
trichotillomania
and like I used to
pluck my lashes
they're like oh my
gosh this I heard and
no it doesn't actually
and I don't know
if that's because I'm
like a chemical in
our brain that makes
it not hurt or what
but honestly this
hurts like curling my
lashes hurts more
than whenever I used
to pull them out it's crazy
see how my bangs are
almost long enough
to blend in if they
go to the side it's
such an awkward length
right now because
then if I pull them
to the front they're
kind of long I think
I'll just leave it
at that I'm gonna
change clothes and be
ready for the day
thank you guys for
watching so much let
me know if you want
to see videos kind
of like this I know
I'm pretty bad at
multitasking but I do
love makeup and I
do love catching up
with you guys so it's fun for me
hopefully it's fun
for you other than
that I'll see you
guys soon with a new
video bye