hi everyone and welcome back to my
channel today I'll be filming a Q&A
it's been a while since I filmed one of
these and I received a lot of questions
on Instagram so I'm gonna try my best to
answer as many as I can today so let's
get started when are you coming to LA
I'm actually in LA right now and Abe is
actually here as well he's actually
helping me film this if you hear his
voice
it's Abe what's on your 2019 bucket list
I don't make these lists anymore made me
because I don't want to get disappointed
when I don't fulfill them but one of the
things I wanted to do this year was to
visit a country that I haven't been to
and I already did that I went to Spain
and then I'm gonna go to Philippines and
I don't know I want to travel as much as
I can before I settle down
but I don't even know when I'm going to
settle down I don't know when are you
going to the Philippines I'm finally
going in the first weekend of May with
Christine we're going to Boracay one
country you've always wanted to visit
but haven't yet Israel do you plan to
live in Seoul for good or go back to the
States eventually I want to move back to
California and that transition is
probably going to take a few years what
do you like most about living in Seoul
you don't have to drive and everything
can get delivered to you everything and
anything can get delivered to you what's
your job
I'm a full-time youtuber and I also talk
on the radio are you not doing joan date
vlogs anymore I kind of answered this
question in my video with Charlotte and
I'm taking a break I am thinking of a
way to start Jody again I'm still in the
process of thinking you just watch my
vlogs Biggers there you go
what is your favorite thing about having
all the Jody vlogs to look back on their
memories and I documented them and I
could go back and watch them and relive
that moment I'm confused about how your
hair grew so fast their extensions
the video dedicated to my hair
extensions so click up there to watch I
got a lot of questions about products so
I'm going to answer them all right now
and I'll link it for you guys in the
description box favorite lipstick
currently I love Mac chilly favorite
perfume
I love la la voz until 33 where is your
marble mousepad from yes style where's
your phone case from rifle paper where
do you buy your PJs Reformation Western
brand recommendations for skincare I
really like drunk elephant and for
makeup I love hourglass eyeshadow
palette recommendations currently I'm
using 3 C e in smoother top closer its
products of all time if do you wanna
just doormouse
oh yeah so the MVP cream centolla
blemish cream the fire lotion oh and
also
that's ceramide cream I've been really
into these days oh really and of course
the patches that's like a no-brainer and
their cleansers are fires here so ok my
personal favorite would have to be the
patches
I love the patches and the snail essence
because that actually helped me fade a
lot of my shingle scars on my leg I know
I used to like it has to help feed
everything on my body so I tried it out
and I love this nail essence who are the
youtubers you like to watch he was like
I really like david dobrik yeah you like
PewDiePie you like Petey Pablo I love
david dobrik
because he does the blogs and those are
vlogs that I can never do cuz he's just
wild you've watched his blogs right this
means you have to know people are gonna
get hurt are you hyped for endgame a do
you want to answer this what kind of
question is that nice question are you
hyped for endgame did you buy your
tickets yet or so who are you gonna go
watch it with are you gonna block him
you should plug it I might see my blog
watching endgame with dad
well I might
dad's reactions like fun fast you can't
you can't you can't film India
no I'm gonna asking questions fun fact
I'm gonna see em game before ape because
it releases in Korea before America I
got a lot of questions about marriage I
don't plan on getting married anytime
soon
but if the right person comes into my
life then maybe I'll get married what is
the best thing that happened to you
during the past week since I'm in LA
I've been meeting up with a lot of my
friends and catching up with them so I
guess that has been the biggest
highlight and it just got to LA so he
doesn't want to be in the video cuz he
looks like he just got off the plane
no seriously is not a good site not that
he's a good guy James figures what made
you like kpop 2002 World Cup what is
your favorite song from the latest
black/pink
album I really like kick it favorite
Marvel superhero spider-man
because he's a nerd but he's also very
powerful and when it comes to
superheroes I really like characters
with a brain so I love Iron Man Hulk
rocket racoon and who else is really
smart yeah did you dr. strange how do
you overcome heartbreak
this might sound sad to you but I've
never been in love so I don't know if
how do you deal with heartbreak he just
cries for a week hey he was so emotional
it's annoying and he gets over it so
quickly maybe it was a serial dater I've
never seen him single I've never seen
anything maybe for like two weeks and
he's like oh okay um okay last question
what's your favorite scene from infinity
war my favorite scene is when Thor has
like the Magnificent come back with his
new hammer and he's like yelling
bring me down else yes yeah yeah yeah i
watch that scene like so many times on
replay so good
that's it for today's Q&A I hope you
guys enjoyed watching if you want to see
more of these please ask questions into
discussion description box in the
comment section down below and I'll see
you guys in the next one bye
[Music]
dead