[Music]
hi everyone welcome back to my channel
and in today's video I will be sharing
with you guys something that I have been
wanting to share on my channel and it's
about my life as a Korean American so
Amy actually tagged me to do the Asian
American tack but I wanted to do it a
little differently by sharing with you
guys my background story first before
getting into those details so I'm gonna
start my story now so if you didn't know
I was born and raised in Los Angeles
California and when I was about three
and when my brother was born our family
we moved to South Korea because my
grandpa was diagnosed with cancer and my
parents wanted us to spend time with him
and I remember going to preschool you
chew on in Korea and you know I just
grew up like learning how to speak
Korean and that's all I knew but then
when I was five I moved back and then I
started attending school and I was the
only Asian in my school so obviously I
looked very different and I didn't know
the language so I mean as a kid I'm kind
of like very similar to what I am now
I'm very extroverted and I love meeting
new people so I didn't really have a
problem with making friends but of
course there was that language barrier
but I don't really remember like
traumatic experiences like from
kindergarten at all so in first grade
that's when I kind of realized that I
was different because during reading
time I was always asked to you know come
out of the room and then go to another
classroom and do ESL courses with
another teacher and you know that was
very helpful for me but I also hated it
because I felt very different from my
classmates and they would always be like
oh thank you - you - so that actually
motivated me to study harder and
actually I'll be going into details of
this later but every time people pointed
out that I was different or like a
certain stereotype I would always work
extra hearts just so that I would know
Irby and ESL and that I could get better
grades and things like that so yeah in
first grade I had to deal with feeling
different because I would always have to
step out of the classroom for those ESL
courses and then I also remember a time
when my like classmates they were
looking through a magazine and it was a
Britney Spears magazine and I remember
not knowing who she was and my
classmates made fun of me for not
knowing who she was and like I grew up
liking kpop so I'm a very
oh gee kpop fan like i listened to it
back when pink girl is around baby books
geode ebola kannada like dolls were like
those are my idols so for them to hate
on me for not knowing who Britney Spears
was like that was really sad on my end
but I remember like going to like
Ralph's and Albertsons just to study the
celebrities because I had no idea who
any of them were so 2nd grade comes
around and a Korean moved to our
district and I was like whoa that's
really cool and I remember teachers
asking me to come out of the classroom
just to help her because I knew how to
speak both English and Korean now so I
felt really good about doing that
because for the first time I felt a
sense of worth because now people were
praising me for knowing Korean and
Korean culture so I remember for like a
whole year the teachers would always let
me sit with this girl and I would always
translate for her help her do her work
and things like that but then like later
um I realized that she didn't want to do
anything Korean than you were so I kind
of felt how do I explain this
so I remember this girl kind of avoiding
me because she just didn't want to
practice Korean anymore and I remember
coming back home and I told my brother I
was like Abe from now on we're gonna
only speak English at home and we
started doing that to our parents as
well and I remember my mom feeling so
sad afterwards because if you think
about it now well if I think about it
now my parents Bulls sacrifice their
comfortable life in Korea
do move to America for me and my brother
and even after we moved we still came
back after two years of living in Korea
because my parents wanted us to have an
education in America so I felt terrible
about that and I also got in trouble for
trying to only speak English at home and
then after that I was like you know I'm
just gonna embrace Korean and at home it
will just be Korean and outside of it I
will just speak English so I always kept
it like I never shared this information
with my friends at school just because I
don't know I was always embarrassed
about being Korean so there's a little
bit of my foundation now I'm going to
answer some questions from the
asian-american tag
I'm korean-american my parents were both
born in Seoul South Korea and then they
moved to America and then I was born so
I guess I would be 1.5 generation or
second generation my uncle always tells
me of second generation but I always
feel like I am 1.5
I kind of shared this in my background
story but definitely when my classmates
were flipping through the magazine and
talking about Britney Spears I knew
there was something different about that
and also none of my classmates looked
like me we had different eyes we had
different hair colors and yeah I knew
for a fact that I was different but also
when we all started to learn about Asian
culture in history class I remember
people were like Oh what kind of Asian
were you again were you Chinese or
Japanese and when I would answer I'm
Korean no one knew what Korea was and I
was like oh that's so strange like I'm
Korean and I know the language and the
music and everything but I felt kind of
different there and then when we learned
about Korea people would ask me are you
north or south and actually I went back
home and asked my mom like am i north or
in my south korean and my mom answered
that I am South Korean because both my
parents were born in Seoul South Korea
but later I also learned that my grandpa
like one of my grandparents he is from
North Korea and then I got to learn more
about his story and his testimony things
like that
even as a child I was always very proud
to be Korean and I remember trying to
share with my classmates who bola was
but of course I did mention in my
background story where I did want to try
to reject it but I respected my parents
too much to reject my Korean heritage so
I was very proud about it
this definitely changed throughout the
years so in elementary junior high and
high school the stereotype was Asians
are smart so I knew for a fact that I
wasn't born with the brains my brother
is actually really really intelligent
and I just kind of like got the grades
that I needed and it just went like
above and beyond but I definitely knew I
wasn't like smart compared to my brother
but because all of my classmates kept
telling me that Asians are smart
I would work extra hard like I mentioned
before I was the first child in my
family like I was the first born my
parents were both from Korea they went
to college in Korea and they didn't
really like they weren't too strict with
me but I feel like they became strict
with my brother because I would be like
no mom dad Abe has to do this this and
that so my brother always jokes around
saying that I am his second mother but
yeah one of the stereotypes that I did
struggle with was like Asians are smart
but that actually motivated me to take
the classes that I took and get the
grades that I got when I went to college
at UC Berkeley that's when I met the
most Asians so like I mentioned before I
went to a school where I was the only
Asian in the beginning and then I think
I can count like how many Asians
attended my school with my hands like in
elementary school and then it like
obviously grew the Asian community grew
in our neighborhood but in college I
never met so many Korean Americans
Koreans like Asians overall and I didn't
really feel a stereotype because we were
all the same
but then when I moved to Korea there was
another stereotype that I had to deal
with which is being korean-american how
do I explain this kind of situation
people would kind of assume that I had a
lot of money for speaking English but
that was definitely not the case and
then some people would just kind of
point out that like oh I'm being very
ignorant even though I knew Korean so
like I remember like my friend and I we
were eating at this restaurant and like
the ladies right next to us we were like
oh my gosh she's so Curry
she looks Korean but she's not speaking
any Korean
that's like a shameful thing but then
when I was paying for the food I would
speak in like Korean and they were like
whoa
so ho like I always felt like I had to
prove myself that like oh I really try
my best to learn both of the cultures so
yeah yes I can and I'm nowhere where I
want to be because I didn't go to school
here but I can read speak and write
Korean
growing up I learned how to be an adult
a lot quicker than most because my
parents needed help translating
documents and every time they needed to
call like I don't know like an electric
bill company or a gas company I had to
do it with them sitting right next to me
so I remember like in the beginning I
liked doing it but then I also got angry
every time I had to do this but you know
like that kind of got me closer to my
mom because you know she was dealing
with all the finances and things like
that so I think growing up
korean-american like my relationship
with my like parents it was always like
a close one
I am very proud of being korean-american
and I was always proud of being
korean-american I love the food I love
the music I love the films are like you
guys watch Joan Day and this is actually
one of like my biggest goals is to share
Korea in a more realistic view
definitely enjoying best of both worlds
in America there are diners and in Korea
there are pajamas and I identify with
both both has to do with food actually
but you get what I'm trying to say here
so that was my story about growing up
korean-american and of course I answered
the questions that Amy created for the
asian-american tag if you guys identify
with any of this please share your
stories in the comment section below
because I would love to read about it if
you guys enjoyed the sit-down chat
please give this video a thumbs up and
here are the people that I tagged to do
this aegeon american tag i would love to
watch my friends share their experiences
so bug them about it too again thank you
guys so much for watching and I'll see
you guys in the next one bye
[Music]