[Music]
hey guys so today I am going to be doing
the Viette tag it's a bunch of questions
that are about my culture my
relationship to it and I got mostly
these questions from Asia Jackson's
video the Filipino tag and then I just
altered it obviously and then I also
watched a bunch of other Vietnamese tag
videos so here's ten questions that I
put together for you guys the first
question is do you live in Vietnam no I
do not I have never lived in Vietnam I
was raised and lived in America for most
of my life and now I'm living in Canada
when is the last time you were in
Vietnam so yeah I've never been to
Vietnam I am a depending on how you
define it I'm first-generation so my
parents are immigrants from Vietnam and
so I've never been unfortunately but I
would like to go at some point I think
for my first time I'd really like to go
with my family what part of the country
are you from
so my family is from the south my mom is
from Saigon and my dad is from Hanoi
what is your Vietnamese name my
Vietnamese name is an out young people
always try to pronounce it and I think
it's something about the ng that they
just like that sound that they just
can't really get it means precious jewel
so name one of the enemies dish you
enjoy the most and why okay there are a
lot um I'm just gonna need a couple
because for those of you that are
watching that don't know these the next
time you go to get Vietnamese food you
can try these out because I'm sure you
know Fah but maybe you've never tried
these before so boom do is definitely my
favorite noodle dish by far um bun gang
I really like I usually fry it I slice
it thin and then fry it and then eat it
with sugar or soy sauce okay Wow sorry I
had to just look up really quickly what
it was because I know what these things
are by sight and I can describe it to my
mom and she'll know what it is either
order it for me or make it for me but um
yeah it escaped my mind but bang boom
bang boom is my favorite oh my gosh it's
so good and then also bun me so I think
I named like four different things you
can honestly eat them at like different
times of the day you just have like a
whole egg Vietnamese food adventure you
need fun Jack in the more
embryo for lunch banku for dinner and
bun me as a snack boom um ya know my mom
makes amazing bun me I think hopefully
one day I would love to open a
restaurant with her she made some dank
food um I have a spring roll video with
her actually on my channel so you guys
can you go check that out I'll link it
here okay do you eat pho on a regular
basis uh no I do not even when I was
growing up at home I did not eat pho
regularly we do eat it quite a bit but
um it takes a really long time to make
the broth and so I don't know my mom
just wouldn't make it all the time but
we do eat rice every day so named to
Vietnamese household items that best
resembles our culture you can't have a
Vietnamese household without fish sauce
and I know it does not smell great like
if you have this spill on you disgusting
so gross um but it tastes so good and
it's just like such a complex mix of
flavors like I don't know why I'm
discarding fish sauce you guys just go
and try it if you haven't before and
then also I would probably say having a
ton of Buddha's in your house I know
that not all Vietnamese people are
Buddhists but for me growing up not in
Vietnam these are just some of the
things I kind of differentiated my
household from other people's households
yeah there's a lot of like teachings and
stuff that obviously if you guys are
familiar with Buddhism that are very
well integrated into just like your
everyday life and the way that you live
your life is not so much worship and
this one actually is so awesome um my
dad bought this when he was living in
New York in his 20s and he was actually
a candle he's this cute little green wax
Buddha um so I loved him I convinced him
to let me take him with me to Vancouver
and so he lives with me now oh and bonus
artifact four things you have in your
house you have DVDs of body but I it's
like a like a show I don't know how you
describe it it's like a variety show
kind of so there's like a lot of singing
and acting skits and like stuff like
that but it's really big in the
Vietnamese community everyone watches
fairies but I do you know how to speak
Vietnamese if so say a Fraser - okay so
on this topic of language
growing up first-gen there was not a
huge demand for me to retain my language
and I really really wish that there was
because the American Way is to
assimilate into the culture um speak
English it's not really until I got
older that I started to realize like
that is wrong um and I really wish that
I was fluent in Vietnamese because it
was my first language and then once I
started schooling then English quickly
became my dominant language and so my
parents will speak via list to me and I
will respond in English so the phrases
that I do know are all commands hi Babu
hyung come I always say that a lot the
Adam Yauch oh I'm good I don't know why
I would know that your dad let me see
I'm gonna try and say like hi my name is
Nina let's see what other basic
information I got Iago Jojo ah done ah
don khong La Nina um um hi MIMO boy ah
ah oh how God how God deal am ah cun lam
YouTube yeah so that's kind of
embarrassing but that is my proficiency
level I can understand a lot more than I
can speak and I think it's just because
I've practiced listening a lot more than
I have practice speaking and I cannot
read at all honestly like this is really
really sad like I would like one day to
learn this language um and be able to
speak it fluently or as fluently as
possible and I think the only way that I
can do that is to move to Vietnam and be
there for a while so we'll see what is a
stereotype about Vietnamese people so I
would say for Vietnamese women a Hondo
Hondo it's like you work at a nail salon
or you own a nail salon there is a
stereotype that Vietnamese people gamble
a lot and I would say that's like kind
of true
and all our family gatherings there's
always gambling but that's like honestly
the funnest part so like yeah there's a
downside to it but it's also like kind
of true
so my last question is what is your
favorite thing about being gay nummies
and I would say definitely the food we
have amazing food and it's honestly so
diverse like the food from the north is
very different from the south just
because obviously geographically and
just different styles of cooking and I
would also say having like close family
ties I know that this is true for a lot
of Asian cultures I don't know immigrant
cultures in general but I grew up with a
very strong sense of like family first
that was honestly very nice for me to
grow up knowing that and just have that
value yeah and I don't know I think I
really like I didn't really think about
Buddhism all that much growing up but as
I've gotten older side.you realized that
a lot of the things that my parents are
preaching to me are a lot of Buddhist
teachings and that I'm really grateful
for because I've grown up in this
mindset of like gratitude so that's all
the questions that I had for this via
tag feel free to take these questions I
have them posted below and I mostly just
want to make this video because I know
what it's like being Vietnamese being
Asian growing up in America or someplace
where you are different at the end of
the day like that's the reality of it
like a lot of people that I know a lot
of people that I've grown up with have
grown up with this idea that we are
somehow inferior or that we shouldn't
take pride in our culture but our
culture is beautiful just like so many
other ones out there I grew up with this
kind of mentality of combating
mainstream culture and like black is
beautiful black girl magic and that's
very very very much in conversation in
the last couple of years and I feel very
blessed to have been a part of this time
period and even though like I can't
really identify with black girls or
black idols it was still really great
for me to see other people of color
getting some like attention and
spotlight for all their amazing beauty
and talent and it's really interesting
because growing up my idols were always
women of color and right now like I
would say that my biggest idols
especially when it comes to fashion
beauty it's really strong independent
black women it's Rihanna
zendaya Michelle Obama but I would
really love to see Asian Americans
I can look up to that I can identify
with there's certainly a lot of people
making strides in that direction so yeah
I did not mean for this video to get all
political oh that was not my intention
and I don't want to speak controversial
honestly it shouldn't be because this is
my experience and that's all I can speak
from and I know for a fact that there
are other young people out there whether
or not you're Vietnamese um but that
feels strange in America in whatever way
whether it be race gender sexuality
whatever it is um I know that there are
people that feel estranged but just know
like if anything from that you take from
this video just know that you deserve to
be here you deserve to be an American
you deserve to be a Canadian whatever it
is that you identify as you don't need
somebody else to tell you that's who you
are
I was literally told when I was eight
years old that this girl would not be my
partner because I was not American and I
believed it until I was I think in like
fifth or sixth grade
something like it so my teacher was like
no girl you American um and so that's
really really damaging especially do
sense of self and I don't want people to
grow up with this idea of like
self-hatred or that you can't be proud
of your culture and I really hope that
this was insightful um but I hope that
you have a lovely day and I will talk to
you guys soon bye
[Music]
Oh