hey guys so I am filming my first ever
Q&A slash gets no me video I figured it
was kind of fitting it just because I am
back in this room where it all started
so I do have my pen because I have my
little notebook not little but I have my
notebook where I wrote down a couple of
questions and then on my phone I have
some questions that I screenshotted from
my Instagram Q&A like I just posted a
photo and I was like hey I'm going home
for those of you that want to ask me any
questions please feel free to do so so
for the future you need to communicate
with me through there because I actually
am very responsive through Instagram
more so than I am through YouTube just
because I am on that app a lot more so
yeah follow me on there for future like
Q&A type things
I don't know so these are just a couple
of ones that have gotten kind of
repetitively throughout my videos and so
my name is Nina when my first started my
youtube channel I was like I need a cool
name for my channel so somehow I came up
with usually suspect I have a no idea
what that is supposed to mean also my
dad just are drilling downstairs oh ah I
think I was going off of like usual
suspect I think it's supposed to me I
don't know I was just looking at puns or
something and I came back to it after a
couple years and I was like that means
nothing to me
I want a channel that resembles Who I am
and so I settled for needs and needs a
spin my nickname for the longest time so
I am really happy with the name that I
settled with it is very simple to the
point I'm gonna ask my dad to stop
drilling okay where was I sorry I just
had to ask my dad to just put a pause on
the drilling for about an hour just so I
can finish filming yeah so that is my
full name my full name is veena quinn I
do have a middle name but you guys don't
need to know that um I am at 21 years
old finally legal everywhere in the
world it is wonderful I am majoring in
sociology minoring in critical studies
in sexuality at University of British
Columbia I've got my question a lot it
is very nice I think just to know that
like people do care about what I'm
studying so I am fully Vietnamese both
my parents are fully Vietnamese I do
have some Chinese up in there
somewhere I have like maybe I think it's
like Cambodian I have some Cambodian but
like very small amount I was born in
Toronto we moved to San Francisco when I
was very young and I was raised in San
Francisco here not in this house
actually in an apartment in the
Tenderloin and I have lived here up
until now I am in Vancouver that's where
I spend most my time
I am only home about 20 days out of the
entire year and after that who knows so
I get this question a lot and I figured
that it's probably because some of you
out there want to start your own
channels which I highly recommend you do
but I have a let's see it is sorry I'm
just reading it right now um it is a
Canon Rebel t5i the lens that I'm using
is just the one that came with the Canon
I don't actually know that is if I'm
reading it off the lens right now it
says Canon zoom lens EFS 1855 millimeter
and a bunch of random numbers I don't
know if that's relevant to anyone but
yeah so that is the camera that I am
using that is all like the base
questions that I kind of get throughout
my channel and moving on to my Instagram
Q&A thank you so much for everyone that
did ask me questions I didn't get a
whole ton but I kind of anticipated that
because I am not actually sure how many
people on my Instagram actually watched
my YouTube videos but I do appreciate
everyone that did asking questions thank
you so the first one came from calm
juice box and she said hi this is a
question for your Q&A video how and why
did you end up going to Canada for
college also videos are awesome thanks
Thank You Colin juice box so I ended up
going to Canada for a couple of reasons
but for me personally I am dual citizen
so that means I am both Canadian and
American so having dual citizenship
means that going to school in Canada I
pay domestic which is dope for those
guys that are live in America you know
that college is expensive so when it
came down to it it was really financial
it was either I go to University of
British Columbia or I go to Occidental I
got the most aid from Occidental but I
also like just
the domestic rate in Canada was just it
kind of equaled out to be about the same
as about 20,000 I want to say per year
and that's still pretty extensive but a
lot cheaper than a lot of other schools
that I applied to because I applied to a
lot of private universities and I also I
never had a first-choice school but I
was the most excited to get an
acceptance letter from UBC like I
remember coming in the mail and I was so
excited and looking back um when I was
trying to make my decision that is kind
of what indicated me that I want to go
there that was just my gut telling me
that UBC was the place for me so yeah
that is how I ended up going there for
college okay next question is from Tara
fro Nina I love your channel thank you a
question for your Q & A what is your
favorite movie of all time okay so since
I've got this question I've thought
about this a lot and for some reason
this has been the most like frustrating
question for me to answer because
honestly I don't know I enjoy a lot of
genres I love animated movies I love
comedies rom-coms
action what-have-you so based on movies
that I come back to over and over and
over again that's the thing there isn't
one I'm not I'm not really big on
rewatching movies so that's that's kind
of a hard indicator but I definitely do
watch them where I'm like Sam that was
great so let me think um a I'm Shannon
named a couple for you guys so I really
enjoy Kill Bill
I enjoy the first one more than the
second one really hope that there's
going to be a third one but I really
really really enjoy the Kill Bill series
Cloudy with a Chance of Meatballs let's
just mix it up a little bit um when this
movie came out it was my favorite I've
watched it so many times
hood winked I know that now watching
animation it is so boot but when that
movie came out oh my god I watched it so
so so many times
Oh on that same thread Monsters Inc
all-time faves University oh my god that
movie was so funny loved it Shrek okay
um
yeah so that's like all animated I do
watch some other like you know like more
meta really artsy films and make me seem
a lot cooler um can't pick up any so I'm
just sick of those animated ones so
thank you Tara for that question you
really got me going on Allen
the next one I got from Emily and
Ygritte so she asked what do you use for
your skin so thank you for that question
actually do get that kind of a lot
I am very basic I have I used to be that
kind of person that was like toner like
scrub face wash mask like all of that
and I really enjoy that like I love
doing like a whole routine for my face
let's be honest I don't really need all
of that and so all use is Cetaphil and a
moisturizer the moisturizer that I'm
using right now is skin to shangri-la
from a lush but prior to that it was
like a your snow moisturizer and that
was pretty good too it's just obviously
really really expensive and I'm not
working for you or anymore so um can't
afford that so yeah that is what I use
for my face at the moment but watch out
for a video at some point soon because I
will be making one with all the products
that I do use including scrubs and stuff
like that ok so next question that I
received is from Genevieve Smith Oh 3
she asked how do you stay organized and
manage time and what is your favorite
thing to do to pass time so I have tried
so many methods over the years I use
written planners like paper planners I
don't have mine now because I am back
home on vacation but I've used numerous
different planners and those work pretty
well except I end up writing everything
in there like my to do things my events
that I have to go to meetings have to go
to meal plans and so it ends up getting
really really messy but I do recommend
writing stuff down somewhere so whether
it be in a planner or notebook I can
never remember everything that I have to
do off top of my head and when I'm not
using a planner or anything then I do
tend to double booked people which is
really really bad her
second question was what is your
favorite thing to do to pass time and
see honest it is making YouTube videos I
don't have a lot of free time I have
school I have work and I have a social
life like I came home from all my finals
and I was like yes I finally have time
to just knock some stuff over I finally
have time just relax and do stuff for me
and so I went straight to editing videos
and it doesn't feel like work even
though it is so a much work that is my
favorite thing to do kind of as sad as
it is it's just more work so yeah thank
you for your questions Genevieve the
last question that I got from my
Instagram DNA is from Ryan shoutouts
Ryan you guys have seen him in my a week
in my life if you haven't seen that
already check it out I am really proud
with how that turned out
he is the one that was dancing a lot the
person that is not me dancing a lot he
asked how do you think being a youtuber
has changed and will change your life
this is actually a really good question
because honestly like this is all very
timely I'm about to hit 10,000
subscribers which is unreal I did not
think that I would get here in this
short amount of time when I started I
had about a hundred two hundred
subscribers and that was after I was
making uhm Beauty videos and I felt like
when I was making those videos I wasn't
really expressing myself in the way that
I wanted to I was kind of just miming it
and doing the motions that other people
do on YouTube and just kind of I was
another face out there there wasn't
anything that I was really showing you
that was me and I keep saying like over
the Pat like over the past couple years
I kept saying I'm gonna go back to it
I'm gonna keep doing YouTube again I'm
like I really enjoyed doing it whatever
and I do I really really love doing this
but I was never super proud of the work
that I put out and that is just because
I wasn't really being myself I was being
a version that I thought you guys wanted
to see like somebody that you guys
wanted to see
and so YouTube has given me a place to
be creative and to really be myself I
like there are no words to describe how
amazing that's been because YouTube has
given me this outlet and I know that so
many other youtubers say this but really
like I don't I don't think until you are
in this position until you're putting
out content and then having it received
well you can really really understand
what that feels like and I didn't come
to YouTube for acceptance that's not why
I'm here I am here so that I can put out
content that I am proud of and that are
helpful for you guys I don't want to put
out anything that's generic which is
what I was doing before I want to put
out stuff that really comes from the
bottom of my heart and I want to talk to
you guys I want to share with you my
life so that in some way it can help you
either by brightening up your day or
giving you like advice that you never
really thought of or providing some
other kind of outlook or worldview that
is why I am on YouTube and that is how
it's changed my life so guys that is it
that is the end of my get to know me QA
what-have-you thank you so much for
everyone that asks me questions for
those of you guys that did want to know
anything else about me I will probably
make another Q&A in sometime I hope that
you guys have a wonderful new year and I
hope that 2017 is good to all of us I
know we all deserve a good year but you
know what you are a stronger better
kinder person because of everything that
has happened to you so don't forget that
don't ever think of failure as failure
just think of it as a learning
opportunity and you will be fine
you will be fine no matter what you do
so I hope that 2017 is good to you and I
will see you very very very