hello you guys what's up we are back
today with another video and today is
actually a Valentine's Day which is why
I look kind of decent for once you're
probably watching this video a day after
Valentine's Day because I am the
freaking master procrastinator and I do
not film and edit things until the very
last minute but in my full defense this
is actually the fourth time that I
filmed this video the first time my mic
wasn't on and so there was no audio the
second time I look like an actual
freaking potato the third time okay so I
have filmed all the cumin haze I
attempted to film this Q&A like two
three weeks ago
yeah and 20/20 has just been such a
great year but my headspace is like in a
completely different space now and so my
headspace in a completely different
space now is that even something you can
say I am just in a completely different
headspace now and so watching my own
video from two weeks ago really made me
cringe so hard that means we're growing
right so I'm back today I asked you guys
again I'm sorry for the 12-time if you
guys had questions for me but I'm gonna
jump right into these by the way if you
don't already follow me on Instagram you
should go follow me there as well as odd
my tik-tok because they post content on
there a lot more often than once a week
so I'll see you there some of these are
a little juicy so how much money do you
make as a nurse so if you want to know
how much money someone makes you can
just school their job title and also
what city they live in and it'll give
you a pretty good idea of how much money
they make I do live in the Bay Area or
near the Bay Area so if you look at that
you'll get a pretty good idea of how
much money I make I can tell you that
when I started out as a new grad I
worked in Los Angeles and I made I think
it was like 46 dollars an hour but that
number quickly went up after my sixth
month and then also my one-year mark how
did you graduate debt-free so I was
extremely lucky to graduate college
without any debt which means I don't
have any student loans or anything to
pay off which is really really nice I
can just focus on saving for my
retirement
saving for my house and you know those
kinds of goals but the reason that I was
able to graduate debt-free was because
when I was in high school I was a pretty
ambitious high schooler I was pretty on
top of all my stuff and I applied to so
many scholarships every scholarship that
I was eligible to apply for I basically
applied for the application for
scholarships is pretty similar it's
always like some kind of essay slash
personal statement slash cover letter in
addition to your resume and then maybe
likes a supplemental essays but I
basically applied for a bunch of
scholarships I obviously didn't get all
of them but the ones that I did get
really did add up I also did receive
scholarships from UCLA so that was
extremely helpful in terms of cost of
living my parents were very very amazing
I'm very grateful that they helped me
pay for paying friend 12 is in college I
never lived on campus because living on
campus if you didn't already know it's
extremely expensive I want to say it's
like 15k a year at UCLA ended up living
off campus I lived in a triple for all
three years I was at UCLA and my rent
was anywhere from six hundred seven
hundred dollars a month and that's
living with two other girls in the same
room so just keep that in mind but we
were also in Westwood which is kind of a
very nice bougie part of the life and
then in terms of actual like living
expenses so like food or buying clothes
or like going shopping and buying things
that I wanted I have always worked
pretty much since it was legal for me to
work even before it was legal for me to
work as a kid I was like selling pencils
to my classmates I was dog sitting for
other people and when I turned 16 I
started working at a bakery so I was a
barista and also was like a cashier also
worked in some labs and then when I went
to college I also continued to work
part-time and so all that money is my
money to spend and I've never had to ask
my parents for money you think I've been
really wise with my monetary decisions
because all the money is like money that
a super a hard earned to me
so for example my first ever job I made
$8 an hour and so it really put into
perspective like hey if I'm gonna buy
this $40.00 thing I have to work five
hours is that really worth it for me to
purchase item
do you plan on always being a nurse the
great thing about nursing is that it is
such a flexible career there are so many
things that you can do with it you can
work in the hospital you can work in the
clinic you can do you can work remotely
you can work with insurance companies
the opportunities are really endless you
can also do so many things to advance
your career
I will definitely always a hundred
percent be working as a nurse in some
capacity or another it just might look a
little bit different than it did before
are you actually happy or is it just a
front that you put up I actually get
this question quite frequently because I
think I look pretty positive online and
if you meet me in person you'll realize
that I'm pretty pretty similar I'm a
little bit more sarcastic I'm a little
bit more savage in person but otherwise
my personality is pretty similar I will
say that depending on who I'm hanging
out with I definitely match their energy
level so if you're like a super outgoing
happy person then I'll match you on that
energy level and if you're like quiet
and more reserved then I'm also going to
act like that and I'll say that I have
been happier in this last month in 2020
a that I have been in a very very very
long time
so and I've been going to the gym every
day like Who am I 2020 new year new me
how do you balance your career in
nursing and on YouTube this is a great
question I think you know there is
always time to do the things that you're
really passionate about right you make
time for the things that matter and for
me making content is something that
makes me so so happy and I love sharing
my journey with you guys and so that's
something that's always a priority for
me in terms of how I actually block out
my time I have a very wonderful Google
Calendar that's pretty loose I don't
always pull my own schedule that I make
but it is really nice because I plan out
like hey I'm working Tuesday Thursday
Saturday which means I can film on
Wednesday and then do editing on Friday
or whatever it is I do
kind of have to plan it out in advance
especially because my schedule can be a
little bit more unpredictable tell us a
fun fact about you that we would not
know fun fact not really like fun person
oh I cannot I repeat I cannot in public
comment down below if you are the same
way oh my god I have to poop like in my
house like on my toilet like you know in
the comfort of my home when I'm like
traveling I have a hard time pooping so
I think in the last like two years
working as a nurse I have pooped at work
once because I really couldn't hold it
but otherwise otherwise I'm like
literally cannot what are your
insecurities huh I think my biggest
insecurity is like my personality I'm
like a very introverted person and I can
put on a front for a couple of hours for
like 3-4 hours but beyond that oh my god
I'm like an introvert and so I like to
stay at home I'm a homebody and I just
like to I really mean my lone time and
the people that I really love and are
close with I could spend forever with
them but everyone else it's like super
exhausting and draining for me to hang
out with people so I do wish I was a
little bit better at that now we're
getting into the relationship tea I got
a question asking me why don't you ever
share stuff about your relationships so
if you follow me on Instagram I'm gonna
Instagram for like 3 years now and I
very ever rarely share anything about my
personal life and especially not about
my relationships I don't know I think
I've just always felt like it's not
really my information to share like not
everybody wants to be put on blast or be
in the public eye I I'm always scared
because you never know how things can
turn out or what things will happen and
so I don't want to put any information
out there and then have it turn out to
be some scandalous info if you guys know
what I mean
but I also feel like my relationships
are a really big part of my life and
make me who I am and it explains a lot
of the like you know the changes that I
go through and the emotion
that I feel and so I am I am going to
start sharing a lot more information
with you guys about what's going on
because it's just such a big part of my
life
so we'll start right now in this video
I'm going to answer a couple questions
about relationships that I have never
answered before so okay well well so
we'll start slowly how many
relationships have you been in some of
you guys think I have never been in a
relationship but the answer is that I
have been in two relationships they are
both really long relationships one was
five years and the other one three years
so there's that some juicy tea for you
how old were you when you had your first
romantic relationship so I'm going to
not consider a middle school love
because I don't think that really counts
but my first like actual boyfriend was
when I was a freshman in high school and
I dated him for five years so yeah all
the way into college into my second year
of college what are some deal-breakers
for you interesting question it's really
funny because I think the type of person
that I've liked has always been really
similar and I'm like oh I don't have a
type but they all kind of end up being
kind of the same I think it's really
unattractive to me when people don't
work hard for their goals or they're not
ambitious and don't have like a next set
of goals for me at least I am constantly
thinking about like how can I be a
better person how can I give more what
is the next thing I should be working on
and it's really hard for me when the
person that I am in a relationship with
or were to be in a relationship with
isn't also like that like they need to
like also have the same mindset if that
makes sense most was just like not a
huge fan of like facial hair I don't
know personal preference
were you a popular girl in high school
Hey look no one from my high school is
watching this so I definitely like
peaked in middle school middle school
was when I felt like a very very cool
person like all the boys liked me
I was like this very extroverted person
who was like friends with everyone I
said hi to everyone and then when I got
to high school I think that was so
stressed trying to apply for college
that I had zero energy to pretend to be
this like extroverted person that I
actually wasn't and so when I got to
high school um pretty much like the same
couple of people I definitely spent a
lot of my brunches and lunches just in
the hospital trying to catch up on
homework and studying I was just really
nervous that I was not gonna get into
college at all and so all of my time and
energy was focused towards that how has
it been adjusting to your new jobs thank
you for asking it's been really really
amazing um I definitely had I think when
you like first make that switch the
first like you know one month two months
are pretty rough but now that I'm past
that phase I am really really happy to
be doing the jobs that I am doing and
contributing in the ways that I can be
contributing 2020 I've been really
conscious about making decisions that
make me happy and that are in my own
best interest and not what like other
people want me to do or what other
people expect me to do and I have just
never been happier my heart is really so
full I'm really really happy thank you
so so much for a hundred K on YouTube I
honestly I cried I was like I can't
believe right here I hit 100k on YouTube
at 100k on tik-tok within like 24 hours
of each other and I was so so happy my
heart is so full I constantly tell you
guys this but I literally have like two
friends and so you guys are such a
blessing and I'm so lucky to have a
community of friends like you guys so
thank you so much for subscribing for
watching my video for hanging out with
me every week it really does mean a lot
to me thank you for 100k I couldn't have
done it without you and I'm so so
excited for what the future is going to
bring us but I think that's the end of
this video if you like this video please
please please give this video a big
thumbs up and don't forget to hit that
button and turn on that notification
bellow so that you don't miss my weekly
uploads and yeah I'll talk to you guys
next week bye it's been seven hundred
degrees in here since you came in and
now it's starting to spin you'll make me
feel kind of bad
good everything it does
[Music]
you run your ending right