hey I'm a geek a
so I have taken a
23andme
DNA test recently and
today I am going
to open it and find
out the results
basically I've wanted
to do one of these
DNA tests for so
long like years and
years and years before
they were popular
I wanted to do one
and then a few years
ago they became really
popular and like
every youtuber out
there was doing a DNA
test but I was living
in Japan and they
don't really ship to
Japan but now that
I'm back in Canada I
can actually do one
of these tests and
yeah so I saw an
advertisement that
they were on sale it
was like a 50% sale
and I was like yo
now is my chance I can
save you know 100
in something dollars
because it's 50%
off right now and
yeah maybe to 2 to 3
weeks ago I mailed
it off and I got an
email yesterday the
day before um that
my results have come
in and I can you
know check out my
results being a
traveler and coming
from a country like
Canada no matter what
you look like you
kind of get the
question like what are
you really like what's
your background
what's your ethnicity
what goes on there
and the best answer
I could give is
generic white girl I
don't really know
like what kind of
white girl I am and
when people ask
like oh what's your
background and you
just say generic
white girl um it's a little
disappointing and it's a little
lackluster and people
are like oh okay
like you don't have
a better answer you
don't know what kind
of white girl you
are ya know I actually
don't I feel like
it's probably a common
thing if you're
from a country like
Canada that is based
off of immigration
and you're clearly
not native you don't
really know what
your background is
when you're you know
a 5th 6th generation
born and raised
Canadian like me we
can't really like
pinpoint the specific
person or people who
emigrated to Canada
that information has
just kind of been
lost over the generations
in my case and
like my predictions
and what I think
this is gonna say
based on the very
little bit of
information I know I'm
definitely Irish and
that is the only
person that we can
specifically put to
another country that's
not Canada is my
great-grandmother so my mother's
mother's mother
immigrated from Ireland
and besides that we
can't pinpoint a
specific person so
the rest of its kind
of just furies based
off of surnames or
little tidbits of
information that has
trickled down there
the generations so
I'm definitely Irish
and also on my
mom's side I have
heard some Scottish
potentially and some
German potentially
on my dad's side
we are definitely
Scottish even though
we can't pinpoint
the person that
emigrated we do still
know our family crest and my
grandmother's maiden
name is still very
Scottish and my surname
um so the name
that's been passed
down through the
mails to me that is
very very English
sounding so we're
assuming it's English
that's what I mean
like we're just kind
of making assumptions
off of surnames um
so yeah I guess today
we're gonna find
out for sure so when
it comes to the
actual results what
I am predicting is
that I am at least
75% British Irish
around there if I
am less than 75%
British Irish I will
be a bit surprised
just because of what I said when
our assumptions the
little bits we do
know I'm assuming
I'm mostly Scottish
and Irish a little
bit of English in
there so that's why
I'm thinking 75% at
least British Irish
and then the rest
would be you know
German other Europeans
that kind of gets
mixed up in there so
I'm gonna go on my
computer and login I
have my computer right
here so um I will
film my reaction let's go I am
hello okay so it
sounds like my first
thing he had the
ancestry composition
I'm only 59% British
Irish okay okay
it's very blue so I'm
assuming it's very
European so I am 99.2%
European and of
that Northwestern
European is 97.3% cool
um so fifty-nine
percent is British
Irish which is less
than I was expecting
I was thinking a
little more I just
clicked on the British
Irish section and
it said the United
Kingdom has 165
administrative regions
and we found the
strongest evidence
your ancestry in the
following 10 regions
one being Glasgow
City which makes
sense I know I am
Scottish and then
Greater London Belfast
okay what is this the
Highlands that's
what I was kind
of expecting I as
expecting like
Scottish and then the
Highlands because
um my grandmother's
maiden name I said
it's very Irish and
it's Mackay and one I
looked at some map
someone put the map
of the UK together
or like Scottish
names Mackay is very
common in the highlands
traditionally I
don't know it was
like a random map I
saw him some random
website I don't know
if there's any
accuracy oh but that's
cool so it's for
some reason London
but the rest of its
like northern I
sorry northern England
and Scotland and
then there's Ireland
my likely matches
in Ireland are Dublin
which is a place
my great grandmother
is from is Dublin
but also quark okay
that's cool I like
how they break that
down a little bit
but let's go back and
look at the other
parts of my ancestry
so 18% French and
German and then Oh
Scandinavian capital
region of dent so
mostly Danish I guess
two point one percent
Danish okay I'm
cool with that
and then 18.2% broadly
north western
european moving down
a little bit more i
have southern european
which is only
0.5% spanish and
portuguese okay and
then 0.5% broadly
Western Asia and North
African and then 0.3% unassigned
interesting
interesting here your
ancestry timeline how
many generations
ago was your most
recent ancestor for
each population so
because I'm so very
um British Irish yep
one generation ago
this is like are you
most likely had a
parent grandparent or a great
grandparent who was
100% British and
Irish absolutely yeah
um like I said my
great-grandmother was
absolutely Irish
and I'm pretty sure
she married someone
who was Scottish I
think that's where
the Scottish came in
on my mum's side so
that would mean my
grandmother would
fall under British
and Irish 100% and I
think on my mom's bad
side is where the
German came in which
would make sense
that two to four
generations ago someone
was 100% French and
German it all makes
sense these stories
and myths that have
been passed down in
my family totally
makes sense there's
very few surprises
here
the Spanish and
Portuguese is a little
bit more surprising
I wasn't expecting
Spanish Spanish and
Italian are actually
what I am asked if
I am most like are
you Spanish are you
Italian that's what
they assume my
ancestry is I'm like
pretty sure and
British and Irish
Scandinavians also
kind of strange
I've never heard of
anyone on either
side my family being
Scandinavian cool
okay coca-cola so I
guess about to my
ancestry um yeah not
really surprised at
all I guess I was kind
of assuming there
would be more British
and Irish and less
German but overall are not that
surprised
yeah good on my
family for having an
accurate myths passed
down I guess and I
do like that how in
a under the British
and Irish like
Subsection like the two
main regions that pop
up are Glasgow and
Dublin which would
make a lot of sense
being Scottish and
Irish went through
what I assumed I
was I was you know
mostly Scottish a lot
Irish and then a
little bit of German
cool maternal
haplogroup h19 the
maternal line okay um
so I guess they can
trace the maternal
line the common ancestor of the
haplogroup H likely
lived in the Middle
East less than 18,000
years ago during
the last great cold
period of the Ice
Age some of her
descendants spread into
Europe which is probably why I'm
European
haplogroup H and
the Royal lines of
Europe am i royalty
that'd be cool find
out I'm like royalty
from this because
it's a dominant because it is so
dominant in the general European
population okay so
we're gonna move on
to the health traits
the reason I went
with the 23andme is
that they have the
Wellness and
traits which I think
are just really
interesting so before
I end this video
I'm gonna kind of go
through and see if
there's any weirdness
so alcohol flush
reaction unlikely to
flush I do not get
read living in Japan
and drinking with
like my Japanese
co-workers that was
always like a joke
because the one like
boss guy that I worked
with he but has
half a beer and
turn bright red he
looked like a tomato
and I wouldn't and
they're like a red
face and white jeans
yep I don't I don't
flush caffeine I do
consume more caffeine
less likely to be
a deep sleeper
interesting cuz like I
met well I guess I
don't know if I'm a
deep sleeper but I
am a heavy sleeper
like you can't wake
me up bad genetic
weight average lactose
intolerance I am
likely tolerant um
yeah I don't think I
have too many problems
with lactose I do
a problem with like
Greek yogurt that's
the only thing that
seems to give me
problems but muscle
composition common
in power athletes okay
let's go back and
see so that was the
Wellness part and if
we go into the traipse
genetics behind
my appearance why do
people not assume I
am generic white girl
ability to match
musical pitch I
don't have musical
talent at all less
likely than average
to have bunions I
have real I really
messed up feet so
they're not bunions
but like I've really
weird feet that's
why I usually keep
them covered I'm not
a sandals person cheek
dimples likely no
dimples yeah not
really I just have fat
cheeks
there's no dimples there
I haven't higher
odds of disliking
cilantro I don't
really care about
cilantro
I don't care if
it's in or out no
question true um
more likely to get
dandruff yes thank you
detached earlobes
don't think my earlobes
are detached I
don't know what that
means exactly I
color is likely brown
or hazel I have
like a hazel and green
eye yeah if you
have heights less
likely than average to
be afraid of heights
ooh I don't know
about that one
like I don't let the
fear of it stop me
but I have a little
bit afraid of
heights more likely
do have a fear of
public speaking when
I was a kid yes I'm
having to do speeches
was an awful awful
time for me Oh finger
length ratio Mike
Lee ring finger
longer wait what does
that mean longer
than what my ring
finger than index
finger my ring finger
is longer does that
make sense is that
what we're talking
about yes likely ring
finger longer they're
almost the same
but I think my ring
finger is especially
on my left hand
my ring finger is
definitely longer um
less likely to have
flat feet
that's very true I
have a huge super
height art in my
foot gives me some
problems hair texture
likely straight or
wavy my hair is
naturally wavy it's
definitely not
straight but it's not
curly it's it's wavy
less likely to have
thick hair I have a
lot of hair but yeah
it's pretty thin um
about 50/50 chance
of reverb hello our
chocolate ice cream
it depends on my mood
depends on my mood
light or dark hair
likely light I
definitely have dark
hair my mom has
naturally blonde
hair my brother has
blond hair and when
I was born my mom
was really
helping could have
like this cute little
blonde baby and
well I didn't have
enough hair until I
was like four as a
bald child but no I
definitely got my
duds dark brown hair
red hair Oh likely
no red hair interesting
cuz like my hair
is definitely brown
but in certain
lights it gets a
little bit of a red
tint and when I talked about my
great-grandmother from Ireland
apparently she had
like bright bright
red hair light skin
wow I could have
never guessed that
I had lighter skin
totally not what I was
expecting what do
you mean I don't
have darks again so
glad a DNA test could
tell me I of light
skin likely to prefer
salty again it
really depends on
my mood there are
times when I like super
crave salty food
chips especially like
that's what I miss
from Japan is like
fried lotus root
chips those were
amazing they're super
salty and crunchy
and amazing okay so
next what's the oats
do we have likely
second toe longer yes
I have a very long
second toe I pick
things up with my feet
that's why I say I
don't show my feet
they're weird-looking
um likely at least
a little unibrow I
tweeze my eyebrows
like it's no one's business
like bees because
take a good like hour
to get in check I
should really like if
I had money to go get
my eyebrows done
professionally I
would because it's a
lot of meat wake up
time likely to wake
up around 8:40 a.m.
that is really
specific I'm gonna
click on this one why
is that so specific
I mean it's not
wrong like now that
I don't have like a
full-time job right
now and I'm kind of
just like doing my
thing online that's
the natural time I
kind of wake up if I
don't set an alarm
huh interesting
why do they say
this our biological
sleep rhythm effective
habla okay so
apparently I'm a
morning person I
wouldn't say I'm a
morning person but I
am the most productive
in the morning
like if I get up early
and I like just
get done
I am super productive
in the day but I
think I'm naturally
a very like night
owl kind of person but I guess
genetically I'm more
inclined to being a
morning person cool
cool cool I don't
think there's anything
else here okay
there we go I guess
for the other health
stuff they like go
through disclaimers
me like we're not
diagnosing you with
anything
cool it looks like
I'm not I'm not a
carrier for any of
those let's check the
other what's the other one
Health's predisposition
I have an Inc
increased risk of
age-related macular
degeneration its
age-related so it's
probably doesn't
matter yet a blurred
vision vision loss
maybe that's like
what my grandma has
my grandma's losing
her vision um like
her peripheral no
she's losing her
central vision but she
can still see out
the side something
like that I don't know
it's age-related
so I won't have to
worry about it until
I'm like 50 we're
fine celiac disease
increased risk late
onset Alzheimer's
disease slight risk
not not really surprised
us any of that
I need to look up
with this age-related
macular degeneration
is I don't know
what that is but
whatever I'm not really
worried about any
of it um so yeah I
think this is all I
can do for now okay
so um yeah I guess
that is it for this
video there's like
a thing here where
you can like fine
family members or
whatever but I don't
think you need to see
that stuff I don't
think that's relevant
to those video and
those videos
probably long enough
already so um yeah
that's it for this
video if you liked
it give it a thumbs
up and subscribe
because I'll be back
with more videos soon
[Music]