what's up sling schlongs I've tried to
film this video like six times already
so just update you guys a little bit why
I loved you know wasn't feeling very
motivated to make videos and I was
making a lot in the summer but there's a
lot of sponsors and with like fash
fashion brands man you know I'm like I'm
over it conflicted on this subject of
fash fashion but I'm definitely a
thrifty thrifter heart so if there's any
more fashion Tings
probably will be thrifted one so yeah
also people and Germany just like art
not I don't know I don't want to make a
big assumption but if you bought the
Bauhaus that I've met people who are a
bit older they're not like they don't
understand social media they don't
understand why it's happening and I just
feel like judged and attacked because
you don't think no I'm not attacked by
anyone but it's just not something that
I like tell people that I have what's
your Instagram let's hear you this that
like a fatty Chandler like mom I just
need to figure out my relationship with
social media and how I want to use it
thing with YouTube I don't really I
don't know it's weird like I started
seeing someone and they're definitely
gonna watch this video cuz he's like oh
my god you says they may have YouTube
and then he's like watches it okay
there's just like a lot of things but I
wanna I'm seeing guys with because like
I love you guys [ __ ] you know what I
mean okay this is just gonna be really
rambling video none of its gonna make
any sense but okay so like I've been
traveling a little bit here and dere and
usually before I go into a city I'm like
hey I'm gonna be in Paris for this many
days or in Berlin and it's been the most
enchanting magical experience or someone
messages me and is like yo let's like
hit up a cafe together and I'm like oh
my god I didn't know anyone in this city
like five minutes ago guys watch my
videos and you're real people who have
lives in like live in cities and [ __ ]
you know like it's just a wild it's been
amazing I've met some super dope ash
people and it's incredible like I feel
in real life especially on Erasmus first
month you're like partying with everyone
getting crunk as hell and then you
realize you're like most of these people
like I don't connect with any of you we
don't really have similar hobbies of
course I don't want to say I didn't make
any bomb friends because I did there's
so many amazing people also in second
semester that I like finally got around
to meeting and then they're just all
[ __ ] left
um but yeah like it's crazy that I
didn't do anything well I made videos
but I just like everyone that I've met
is so kind hearted and lovely freaking
real people just like I relate to and
it's [ __ ] amazing I can just trust
your judgement that if you like me and
think we'll be friends then we'll be
friends and like so far worked a hundred
percent of the time because I've
genuinely loved every single person that
I've met in Paris Leon Berlin Lisbon but
also in couchsurfing a lot which is a
complete different experience I'd rather
just like I don't know you guys don't
really on couchsurfing but I wish like I
could just go surf and hang out with you
guys instead because no I don't know
couchsurfing is an interesting thing I
recommend it I think it's a very unique
way to meet people that you wouldn't
otherwise me and like you have to have
conversations with them for a long time
because you're like living in their
house so like you really get to know
someone and they could be a lot older
than you they could just be really
different like one guy was like he
literally said he thought white men were
genetically more attractive
and I was like really because you're
[ __ ] 30 and balding and your face
looks frumpy and sad and you're like
complaining about how you can't find a
girlfriend in dirt dirt Dutch land halt
Netherlands um and he basically like has
only dated people in places where he has
an advantage as a foreigner so like in
Newark say you're like in Tokyo because
apparently like all girls there but for
white guys which I'm like okay whatever
like you're sad um but like I wasn't
even like mad at him I just felt really
sad for him because like that's [ __ ]
sad and also a lot of people have been
asking about sub and how he's doing he's
doing great he's just the [ __ ]
go I love him forever seriously like
he's one of my favorite people in this
entire universe and we did break up in
October and it was really flipping hard
for me I didn't see it coming it was
like a big punch or like a brick thrown
in my face maybe like acid I don't know
but you know I think it was really good
for me because I was able to like step
back and see the relationship and maybe
it wasn't really working because we
don't want the same thing in the future
I don't know I still love him to death
and I saw him last month when I went to
Portugal to visit him and it was so nice
to hang out and just be my complete 100
percent gross self and like fart freely
and just be disgusting and be accepted
and not judged best feeling ever
that's like a real true friend I just
think we're always gonna be BFFs I would
take a freaking bullet or two or three
or four or five or a million for this
kid and yeah like sometimes I'm so sad
about it and some
they cry and like that's okay that's
just bugging emotions man and I think
it's like natural human senses and if
you're not sad that maybe you're just
dead I am seeing someone now who's
really wonderful and I didn't really
expect or anticipate or want to be in a
relationship again so soon but it kind
of just happened and I just decided like
you should can't control life and what
happens and when you meet people so you
just have to take it as it is and I
think it would have been a really big
shame if I was like no I don't want to
get to know you because blah you know so
yeah that's my current situation and
like yeah I'm going next week to Greece
for three weeks to meet my dad I said I
my sister just gonna be so [ __ ] late
um I hope it's gonna be let's also be
stressful because I'm like grown up an
only child and like planning a vacation
for people one [ __ ] a seven-year-old
who's they now I can do surprises just
like every single grocery trip it's
rough and tough and tumble okay but I'm
gonna make it through this and it's
gonna be beautiful it's gonna be really
[ __ ] hot but I'm [ __ ] hot too so
am i psychotic Thank You her maybe um
maybe this is just video where I leave
for six months and then you watch me
again and you're like oh my god Leah
you've gone [ __ ] insane maybe I have
but it oh you know caveman is sweet Oh
also I really want to make a recap video
of this entire year because I've been
filming taking film photos taking no I
haven't really been taking any Instagram
or like okay do you know why because
look at my [ __ ] phone look how do you
see how shatter can you see how
shattered it is like
I don't know if you can see this but
this from afar maybe it looks like an
iPhone or something if you really go
back a far but this is a samsung galaxy
s5 I remember when this came out in
grade 11 and one guy my class had it and
was like dipping it into water and now I
have it in 2018 when everyone else has
like an iPhone 300 so that's fine
whatever
I think I might just force myself to buy
a proper phone because this one's really
cracked so slow like I don't realize how
bad my phone is until I use other
people's phones and I'm like yours
reacts instantly when you click it like
what the [ __ ] but yeah what was I saying
oh yeah one make a recap video and I
stopped using my bullet journal um in
March February yeah and I've been using
like small little journals instead which
have been really fun and cassettes mom
gave me this like jeez not lost Chris
last last Christmas and I never use it
but sorry doing travel plans in it and
then it just hurt becoming like a
notebook with ideas and journaling and
like when I went to Portugal the first
time to see sub sister it was just so
fun and she's like such an amazing human
being so [ __ ] hilarious she's so
funny I love her maybe even more than
that don't worry I saw that umm but yeah
we just made like random little plans of
things we could do in the future and
she's like just very spontaneous wants
to live life as well so it was really
invigorating to hang out with her and I
have like cute photos with my friends
this is Abdullah
he's from first year I mean first
semester he's from Jordan but he's a
rocky and he's just like such a
sweetheart I love him to death I went to
visit him in cold cuz he's doing his
architecture in tradition like there's
so many great people that I want to like
share everything with you guys because I
love you guys so much and I wish I could
meet everyone because I'd be so bummed
because so far like people have met I've
been
like I would be roommates with them
that's how much I like them as people
I could cohabit with them that's crazy
right mm-hmm
these I've been using like little
moleskin books and it's using them for
class and lists and also like putting
the piggies in there this is a little
picky of my well QP boy and in yeah yeah
man
it's wild oh [ __ ] okay so I went to a
music festival the other day off today
Friday just for one night called melt
and it was insane it's your life sig so
we like took the train over and we were
just there for one night but I saw the
internet which is Steve Lacey I'll
[ __ ] love him and Cali you cheese
she's she said looks angelic human being
I've ever seen my life and she's like so
just perfect and her dancing is like oh
my god and I love her style and
everything and shy of the creator I
liked him before because I really liked
his new album but I wasn't like crazy
about him but watching him perform was
wild he's like just an amazing performer
so much energy I was losing my [ __ ] I
was so crazy and the thing is artists
here that our popular are different from
North America like European North
American music taste is very different
because I was like front and center for
all three of these baby angels and the
ones that were really popular it was
like Florence and the machines that day
Friday and I feel like back home I don't
know more people would be crazy for
Tyler and there's like some people
sitting at the very center front who
were there like waiting for Florence so
they were like standing through the
entire Tyler that creative thing there's
this like to satalia couple they're
older like 40s maybe and 30s I don't
know I'm really bad at guessing white
people aging um and like they were just
not having they were not happy they were
like crossed arms my friend who's with
me she's like my parents are Italian her
I don't know if she understands some
Italian she's like I'm pretty sure like
yelling like racial slurs and just being
super offensive and yeah now I really
want to go to Thailand the creator
concert like purely Tyler at the Creator
concert I don't want any phones and the
machines after it she's a sweet baby
angel as well but I just want like happy
love Tyler vibes the whole concert I'm
gonna peace out Girl Scouts and I'll see
you another time because I will make
another video like I didn't quit YouTube
okay I just took a hiatus to like live
life and boom Shakalaka okay bye my
tongue helps so bad right now do you see
that my dad was like send me photos of
your tongue Lia and I was like okay and
then no we were skyping we chat video II
cuz that's the hot [ __ ] guys get on that
we chat oh my gosh
I also discovered Chinese rap music so
that was pretty crazy like higher
brothers we chat song their entire thing
is like I don't open WeChat to see your
[ __ ] I really relate to that because
all my family members who have WeChat
and trying to send me like you know
Facebook news articles but like people
DM that stuff into our family group
chats and I'm like I don't open WeChat
to see your [ __ ] stupid article about
how pickles are gonna kill us like just
an example
I don't think Chinese people care about
pickles but you know what I mean like I
was like man I really lead to your songs
and also they have a song about 7-eleven
and it's like ironically like jazz mmm
music video 5 like sensual belly
the lyrics are just hilarious I showed
seven he was like laughing cuz it was
just four dunks when they translate it
but I don't know I think a Mandarin
sounds like pretty sweet and higher
brothers you should check them out and
Frank Ocean I like just discovered how
amazing he was a few months ago so yeah
guys um that
I have for today let me know what you
think and like what type of videos you
guys want cuz this was like a [ __ ]
train wreck and a half so yeah so yeah
guys I'm just gonna like live life and
smoke my USB now absolutely this is my
roommate they need to give it to her
when she comes back cuz I've had it for
like all semester and forgot about it
and also lost it in the library and then
found it again I am such a shitty person
Oh anyways I'm gonna go now to some
ramblings [ __ ] okey bye and love you
guys