welcome back to my channel as you can
tell by the setup I'm going to be doing
another chit chat garetty's with me
video um today's video is actually gonna
be different
in my last chit chat get ready with me
video someone suggested I the user named
Emily says I'd be interested to hear
about your experiences I was a Korean
American like did you have any identity
issues and stuff and also what were
things you used to be insecure about
when you're younger but grew out of
which I think was a pretty good topic to
talk about because um I mean I could go
extensively I'm gonna get started all
the comments are all the products I use
will be in the description box this
could go either way good or bad because
you guys know I have a lot of to
say about this I am a first generation
Korean American my parents immigrated
here the 80s that being said my first
language was actually Korean everyone in
my household spoke Korean so on that was
my first language well I grew up in a
very Korean heavily populated city and I
was like only surrounded by Koreans like
I was born and where there's a lot of
Korean people I went to church in k-town
so I was there every single Sunday just
surrounded by Koreans Koreans all around
me I went to a Korean daycare /
preschool that was at a Korean Church
around where I lived so I was just
surrounded by Koreans all throughout my
entire childhood
so as I was growing up like all I really
knew even though I was born in America
I was only surrounded by Korean people a
lot of us just spoke Korean so I wasn't
really surrounded by many other like a
diverse range as a kid that all changed
when I entered preschool I had a enroll
in a you know public school so it was a
I wasn't the only Korean person there
there was like a lot of other different
races and I was like the first kind of
culture shock for me because I was just
surrounded by Korean people and I was
like when I realized I'm a minority like
so since I was like the only I was
extremely shy like I'm already a pretty
shy person as it is but since I was I
was like the only Asian person in the
class I was just like extremely shy
didn't talk at all ice
spoke English and I could I understand
what I understood what everyone was
saying to me but I just was like just
chose to be mute that's a kid like I did
I just didn't want to talk to anyone
because I was so extremely shy but
eventually like during preschool I
started hanging out with or I started
talking to other people like all his
friends so I had like a little group
when I was in preschool it was like me
this white girl that's Hispanic girl and
another Hispanic girl and I was like
only Asian one so we were like friends
but then that's when I moved to a
different city which didn't have a lot
of Korean people at the time I think now
it's like more Korean people but I
thought time it was like mostly white
people Hispanic people so I was like the
only Asian kid in the class this this is
like first grade this is when I first
experienced like racism and this is when
I started to lose my fluency in Korean
because like this this is when the
school started making me speaking
English more rather than Korean so yeah
my first hand it racist experience
wasn't first grade like as I said I was
sheltered my entire life not knowing a
lot of different races I didn't know
anything about like I didn't know much
about other races like I didn't know
anything about like the racist
terminology being made fun of for who I
am
or I didn't make fun of other people for
who they were so like the first thing
that people said to me was like Lily
Hong - that's my last name Lily Hong
Kong change Hong ding dong Ling long
Tintin King Kong ping pong like people
were just making fun of my last name and
I was like what's so funny about my last
name is like it just seemed normal
who's like I mean a lot of other Asian
people we have like really short last
names like that so for me I was like it
didn't really hurt me it just annoyed me
like I was like pretty Savage I was a
kid too like I was just like the
like it's not funny I don't get it and
then like other times yeah dad these
kids were nasty like they're you know
like doing the whole eye thing like
making fun of how small my eyes were but
it's like like my eyes weren't even that
small or they would say I eat dog which
I didn't understand at that time because
like even though I grew up in a family
none of us ate dog so I like I wasn't
even told about dog meat so I was just
like why would I eat a dog what the hell
like what are you people talking about
like how is that making fun of me what
never done it so like that stuff never
hurt me but it is just like weird that
all these kids like knew all the racist
like who the taught them all
this like their parents like my
parents never taught me I know any of
this stuff so I never understood like
where this was coming from yeah kids are
so shitty
but yeah so like this the teasing like
it just went on the my entire life even
though like I never really reacted I was
just like okay they would just still
continue to like make fun of me for who
I was like my name's and and like
they found out about my Korean name cuz
like my mom she dropped me off at school
and she was like bird nah I think I like
my dad I don't know what my parents drop
me off and they're like have a good day
hon BR and then like one of the kids is
like honey or when she called you hon BR
or whatever she called you and I was
like oh that's my Korean name and then
that girl went on and told everyone like
Oh Lily has a different name first of
all not none of her business
like she shouldn't be telling everyone
that so then people like found out by my
name they all like it started to turn
into a game how do you spell Lily's
other names they try to butcher my name
so they would be like honey you'll hunt
by you'll like I don't understand what
was this whole fascination with like who
I was like just people just need to shut
up and mind their business like I minded
not my own business as a kid I don't
understand why people had to like butt
into my business
I'm such an angry kid huh so like that
the teasing and stuff like went on for a
long time like I said followed me all
throughout elementary school so it kind
of like the the Bowling's all the
teasing it started to get to my head
around maybe fourth grade fifth grade
cuz you know that's when you're in
that's starting to get into that stage
where you just don't understand things
well anyways so then I started to like
believe what they're saying like maybe
maybe my culture is weird as I remember
this one time I think it was like third
grade third grade or second grade came
to school like this is Halloween and
people were like dressing up for it and
I remember the other the previous
Halloween days like first grade second
grade I didn't really have a costume
everyone else showed up in costumes and
I'll just say always going on there like
it's Halloween we all dressed up so then
I wanted to participate I told my
parents like well I want to participate
this year and like I would see people
dressing up as princesses and stuff so I
had my humble my Korean my traditional
dress as a kid so I was like oh I'll
wear this because I always thought I
look so cute in it even as a kid I'm
starting to tear up oh oh oh I might
actually cry like if you guys follow me
on Twitter I posted like pictures of me
because my sister posted pictures of me
crying during Coco this might happen in
today's video oh oh that's such a
crybaby when it comes to this oh
so anyways I decided to go show up to
school in my thumb book and then people
like on me so hard for wearing this
oh god like I was made fun of for what I
wore I was like why are you people
making fun of me
oh like my makeup is ruined now oh
this is gonna be the worst and get
ready with me video ever because my
makeup is fix my concealer on today so
these kids like on me for
wearing like my traditional dress like
that part probably hurt me the most as a
kid because I thought I look so cute but
then people like made fun of me so
that's what I think I like started to
try to assimilate try to fit in to the
culture that's when I started to like
reject my culture or try to hide who I
was and try to fit into who they were I
might just have to wear glasses today
because my makeup is just gonna be
up so then like I would watch a
whole bunch of TV so I watched like a
bunch of Disney Channel and stuff and
I'd always hear talk about like oh mom
make me meatloaf make me leftovers and I
was just like what the is meatloaf
what the is leftovers so I'd this
is when I tell my mom hey can you make
me meatloaf and leftovers cuz in my
family we didn't have leftovers cuz we
finish our plate so my mom's just
feeling the meatloaf what the
is leftovers but she tried which I
appreciate I also like one and my mom to
enroll me into like softball because all
the white girls in my classes would talk
about being in softball and I just feel
like what the is softball never
heard of this and before my life
so I wanted to fit in I asked my mom to
enroll me but that didn't work out
because I wasn't athletic at all as a
kid so that didn't last feeling left out
as a kid
school made me really you know kind of
upset but every I still be going to
church every Sunday where I'd be
surrounded by people like because it was
a Korean church I'd be surrounded by
people more like me so that's when I
felt you know the safest oh yeah that's
like the only time I felt happy this was
also the time when I started to realize
how I'm dramatic and how scandalous
Korean churches were because my parents
were pretty big and like they had a high
suspicion at church so like once there's
like a scandal that happens at church
like or like a small dispute this church
splits in half people leave people stay
like it just goes crazy my family were
always the ones to leave because like
they've worked there so we'd always have
to jump around different churches like
what like it was it was kind of annoying
as a kid because I would set this like
moving cities where you settle down make
friends and all of a sudden you have to
leave because like some goes down
this happened probably like six times in
my childhood where I had a where I made
friends and then we had to leave because
all this so that kind of made me
hate I just had just started to develop
some animosity towards the Korean
churches which has followed me since now
say I'm feeling left out of at school
follow me all throughout elementary
school but like this is the time like
around 6:00 or 5th grade was the time
when YouTube started becoming big this
was when a Higa remember him I
don't know why his name is digger first
of all or nigahiga I guess that's how
you pronounce day I'm sorry he's like
the number one most popular youtuber and
like I think a lot at that time it was
like mostly Asian people who kind of
dominated Michelle Phan loves Beauty
nigahiga kept jumbo it was all like
Asian people who were popular online and
everyone watched them so that's I
started to like you know feel a little
bit better about being Asian like having
some sort of Asian pride I was seeing
others do so well online I went to a
different middle school from everyone
else in my elementary school like I went
to a special one I forgot to mention I
was in they enrolled me into the ESL
program because I never spoke at school
so they assumed that I couldn't speak
English even though
fluent so they made me enroll into the
ESL program and that this is what I like
started to stop speaking Korean and then
I started losing my fluency so I kind of
have like animosity towards my school
for making me do that anyway so then I
go to middle school like a special
Middle School where they have like an IV
program so it's like it's harder I guess
I don't know since I started this middle
school I there are a lot more agent more
Asian people at this school because you
know I was like this of course they're
few more Asian people at this school
so I'll surrounded by more people like
me like Asians became the cool kids for
the first time in my life I was still
like getting teased by my non Asian
friends at school like still making fun
of my eyes I wore glasses at a young age
and then I decided at contacts in middle
school and then I remember what my
friend at that time told me it's like oh
are your contacts little slits to fit
into your eye and I was like the
how dare you say that to me I started to
develop a thick skin at this time cuz I
just like I really just didn't care like
I mean of course I care cuz it's like I
like how the could you say that but
it didn't hurt me
he just annoyed me so I stopped speaking
Korean around this time I only spoke
Korean to like my Korean friends parents
or my Ida needs to be Korean to my own
parents I only spoke Korean to maybe my
grandma so around middle school was when
a kpop I guess started becoming more
globalized this was one I think so no
she did G or maybe that wasn't in
elementary school for me it was I have
6th grade or seventh grade when she
became popular I know sorry sorry my
Super Junior was big and middle school
for me and like 2 p.m. again and again
remember that so yeah that stuff
became popular and that became more
people who are non Korean started to
find out what kpop was which was kind of
like at that time kind of exciting for
me because a like a little bit of my
culture was getting spread out and we're
learning more about it which I thought
was really cool so I could like connect
to these people more like I had no idea
what the was gonna happen with all
this also linked I remember Korean
dramas are getting bigger to like put
the nom de Boys Over Flowers was huge
Christian pure hahaha so yeah I really
liked it that people were acknowledging
my culture a little bit middle school
was
do you sit for me like I didn't really
have to do with a lot of bullying or
stuff because like most of my friends
were Asian because there are more Asian
kids at this school but then once I was
getting used to being part of the
in-crowd my family decided to move and
we moved to an even wider city like
super white at that point I was so done
because of like I already told you guys
about how I had a move Church church to
church to a different Church and stuff
all the time because of like all the
scandals and stuff so this was like my
first time moving to a different place
having to adjust to a completely
different new school with different
people once I looked like I was actually
trying to fit in fit in at a different
place where there was like no one like
me or barely anyone like me so I was
like kind of angry this was when I
started to become like the emo kid like
I had the sushi hair and stuff like if
you ask my friends now who I met in
middle school when I moved they'll tell
you how like different I was
compared to now like they all know I
hated them when I moved because it was
just like I hate I just hated like
having to adjust again but it's funny
because like once I moved to that city
the school assigned me cuz I moved in
the middle of eighth grade that school
assigned to me like someone to show me
around and it was like the only Kurt
like one Korean girl in my school and I
don't know if they did that on purpose
or ever yeah so like I had to restart
everything all over again I absolutely
hated that school like I really didn't I
hated it
like this was when I start to dish a lot
because I was just like so done with
everyone also like at this school Asians
were like at the bottom of like the
social pyramid everyone like just
on Asians so much even at this
school they're like Asian boys who made
fun of Asians because they wanted to fit
in with the white kids and which I
thought was like so how pathetic but
then I actually started to become like
that kind of person later on so this was
a when my denial for my culture started
coming back when people would talk
about being Asians I just feel like yeah
yeah that's true just cuz I was just
like so done at that point which of
course I regret entirely now this is
when I started to be like I would never
date an Asian guy because like I was
just I was just really like denying my
culture heavily it is so hot in here
like I cringe looking back at how I
acted before
how I just thought it was cool to hate
on my own my own culture alright I
didn't want people to hate me so I just
like wanted to fit in
cuz I was new moving on to high school I
think this was like the first time kpop
like really became globalized I mean
it's nothing compared to now but a lot
more people were getting into it like
this is what I think Korea brew started
to become prevalent in my life I already
told you guys about my whole high school
experience in a previous video I told
you how like guys Asian guys came up to
me because this was like people started
to fetishize me for being Korean which
was gross just because of the whole like
globalization of kpop at this time like
I didn't realize it until later on that
some people just wanted to be my friend
because I was Korean and once I figured
that out I just dropped those people I
just got really mad because it's like
really people are just using me for who
I like my race rather than it's like my
personality yeah this is a really
different part of my life compared to
how I grew up
people sign to be more interested in in
Korean culture but it wasn't exactly
Korean culture it was just the
entertainment side of like Korea like
kpop and Korean dramas this is like all
people were knew about Korea at that
time so then people just assumed what
they see on TV or whatever is my life
it's like no it's not
my life isn't a Korean drama
like none of that is true but
people just start to assume because
that's all they really knew this is when
I kind of like started developing a
hatred for anyone who like mentioned my
race it just kind of triggered me
whenever people brought up my race I was
always just skeptical about people so I
kind of just wanted to deny my culture I
didn't want to date a Korean guy at this
point even though I did like in freshman
year but like after that I was just like
no I want a non-asian guy because Asians
aren't cool
that never happened though but it's just
cringy to see how I was as a person back
in the day after high school I kind of
like grew up started to feel a bit more
confident in Who I am and more
appreciation for my culture like even
though I don't speak Korean that well
like I mean I still speak it but not as
well as I used to but I still understand
it like fully I was still aware of like
Korean
like all the going down like I
can't escape from it who I am I don't
know what the that noise is out
there so holy
haha I told you people sorry to
fetishize me this is like even worse now
at this point after high school like
guys just wanting to get to know me
because I was Korean they wanted a
Korean girlfriend so badly cuz like they
assume we all look like k-pop stars
which I don't understand so I grew up
after high school I guess the gardener's
are out to there so then now it's like
not people are becoming more interested
in Korea so that stuff kind of bothers
me now because those thing people who
made fun of me at in elementary school
for being Korean are now like totally
like kpop fetishizes and stuff and like
I get it people change but it's just
like really you bullied me all my life
for who I was but now you're trying to
you're trying to like go after that my
culture now I'm just dumbfounded by that
now when non Korean people tell me about
they're learning Korean or like they
love Korea for the culture I'm always
like oh really like what about the
culture do you like half the time it's
either tape blown up eighty percent of
the time is cuz they watch a lot of
Korean dramas or listen to a lot of kpop
and the other 20% of time they don't get
me a straight-up answer like they don't
give me a good enough answer they're
just like really you just like the
culture for the superficial side of it
rather than the history behind of Korea
all my life only probably three people
have given me good at good enough
answers to why they're interested in
Korea because most of the time is
because of kpop and this is why I like
angers me so much to see people taking
advantage of my culture making videos
about Korea like making videos about
Korea even though they never lived in
Korea or they don't even speak the
language I mean there are definitely
youtubers out there who have lived in
Korea who have good input on it and
actually like learn the language there
are people who make like full videos
about Korea who don't even like bothered
about living in Korea who don't even
bother to learn the language which kind
of just makes me irritate it a bit like
how are you going to talk about the
culture when you don't even under
not what these people are talking about
this kind of turned into a really angry
video I don't know oh my my emotions
were all over the place like I was
crying I was laughing and now at this
point I'm just angry
I'm not saying only Koreans experienced
this of course I'm pretty sure lots of
different races experienced this like I
grew up around weeaboos now I'm just
surrounded by Korea boos I just think
it's disgusting how people take
advantage or like they look at Asian
culture as a whole and make like a
mockery out of it like I'm sure they do
that to other different races as well
but I just see it so much in a Japanese
and Korean culture especially Korean
culture now and it's just weird seeing
how my guys I said I grew up getting
on for being Korean and now
people are just like worshiping my feet
because of who I am it's like maybe as a
kid I would have liked this but now that
I've grown up I'm like no this is not
what I wanted at all but every single
time I go back to Korea or whenever I
see my my grandpa in Korea who doesn't
live here with us he always has to put
my ass on blast about not being fluent
in Korean he already always like scolds
my parents for not teaching me Korean
even though like he doesn't hear he
doesn't know that Korean was my first
language and there's no really any use
for me to speak Korean here like yeah
it'd be helpful for me now but like when
I was growing up like you have to
understand all this that happened
to me so I was like I hate it how he
doesn't understand about that like I
wanted to fit in so badly that you know
the consequences was forgetting who I
was it's like not only my grandpa but a
lot of other Koreans from Korea feel
this way they're like they have like
hatred towards Korean Americans who
don't speak Korean that well because
they're like well you're Korean first
not American but it's like you have to
understand you know we don't get much
usage out of it so I just wish they
would understand that so it's like I get
on for being American I get it
on for being Korean I don't know that
everything's so confusing for me at this
point in the end I'm still proud of my
culture I'm proud of Who I am even
though like sometimes the I talk a
lot about Korea of how light the whole
hierarchical system it has and how and
how homogeneous it is like despite all
that I'm still proud to be Korean I'm
proud of how far we've come
started off as a third world country now
we're flourishing so incredible
that now people just are really
interested even though like of course I
hate the fact that there's a bunch of
Korean booze out there I mean it's great
that people know more about us because
they're just always gonna be shitty
people along the way who make a mockery
out of your culture but of course there
are other people who actually fascinated
by it and respect it so oh I'm finally
done with my makeup I'm gonna go fix my
hair and then I'll be back
as always my bangs are a mess god I hate
my hair so much I need a haircut anyways
that is pretty much it for this video I
feel like I'm gonna offend a lot of
people through this video but honestly
it just really is my opinion and
standpoint on everything growing up as a
Korean American no hard feelings for
anyone I really hope you guys don't take
this the wrong way but feel free to
share your experiences growing up you
don't have to be Korean or American or
whatever to grow up feeling a bit you
know bullied as a kid for who you were
and whatever we all probably share the
same experiences similar experiences
growing up where we have like cultured
cultural differences and whatnot
I mean all minorities probably feel the
same way share them in the comments
below if you have any other questions
concerns or suggestions for future
videos leave them in the COTS below as
well if you want to see more of me you
can subscribe to this channel follow me
on Twitter Tumblr Instagram my blog and
everywhere else wall being the link in
the description box below so yeah I hope
you guys enjoy this video and I'll see
you guys next time
bye
[Music]