happy Asian Pacific American Heritage
Month hi everyone its Katrina and thank
you so much for cooking so the month of
May is Asian Pacific American Heritage
Month and for this month I really wanted
to make a video talking a little bit
more about my culture and my experience
growing up as an asian-american you
might be familiar with the phrase a
picture's worth a thousand words and so
that's kind of my idea for this video I
wanted to share short anecdotes through
photos so let's go first photo is a
picture of me and my mentee Martin and I
want to talk a little bit about my
Chinese name and what I'm wearing here
so my Chinese name is yet shower in
Mandarin and I believe the name could be
translated to skillful child and in Chiu
Chow it's pronounced yep Chi Yi in
Hokkien it's yep Kali and in Cantonese
its EEP Howie so nobody really calls me
that because everybody my family just
calls me now or Nana which is a
shortened version of Katrina but yeah
that is that's my Chinese name and then
too I'm wearing a cheap how here which
is the traditional like Chinese dress
for women and this was my first time
wearing a cheap how it's actually my
roommate's
but I was M seen for a Lunar New Year
event and she let me borrow it and I
just felt so so beautiful in it and I
remember just thinking to myself that I
really wanted to wear one for my wedding
so that is still on the agenda I hope I
can find a really nice one yeah thank
you Darcy
so the second photo here is a photo of
me and my preschool class that is me in
the front center and I use this photo to
talk a little bit about the community
that surrounded me growing up I'm so
I've said this in multiple videos before
but from the get-go the community that I
went to school with the community that I
lived around were filled with a lot of
people who look like me so even though I
was a minority
I didn't often feel like one growing up
because there were so many people around
me that had similar backgrounds similar
family histories spoke similar languages
at home ate the same food and so I never
felt like I was really embarrassed of my
culture because so many people around me
also had
in culture and I think because of that I
was able to develop a very strong sense
of cultural pride and belonging and
self-worth and this wasn't something I
realized until I got much older I
actually took a class this past fall and
we learned about colonial education and
the effect that it has on minority
students in America and across the world
and I did a whole paper on the benefits
of ethnic enclaves for minority students
especially in America and how having
these ethnic enclaves not only helped
foster the sense of belonging and
confidence and self-worth in these
students but it also has benefits
towards their academic performance right
social performance and how they view
themselves in comparison to their peers
it made me think a lot about my own
experience growing up but also as an
educator how can I make sure that these
spaces are created in the schools so
that all students feel the sense of
belonging so this next picture here is a
picture of me coming home from Chinese
school and this is the award that I got
and a couple of trophies that my sister
and I accumulated throughout the years
so I'm gonna try to speak this in
Mandarin
well the bastard child Oh run well the
mama chef Liu jiren a common thoughts
idea and true Shonda
tae-hyun and come on shout shout sure
sure sure
Joel one puto mwah kasha company oh come
on yeah don't what
so heat almond Lehi who a young hot dog
Union workin watch it yeah I can be out
here Bianca shouted homemaker Chon Wang
Wei Xiao Zhang Manchus yeah woman's
shirt a boudoir Sunni an old woman hunt
ow yeah sorry we asked our parents at we
can quit and they said yes but in
retrospect I'm really regretful that I
quit because I feel like I could have
gotten a lot better but tical junghwa
Joan 1e or Santa ap I'm sorry boy yo G
wake ing Joshua what I don't want
I'm not that good as you can tell but
yeah so that's that's me Chinese school
everybody hated it but we're very
grateful in retrospect so the next photo
I have here is a picture of me and my
family on Chinese New Year / Lunar New
Year and this is the typical food that
we have there so I'm gonna try to speak
this one inch each other we are going
east side of Beekmantown ku Lima I like
on the night yep Pink's easy work are
fixing on qu Baba hoping yeah hold on
Kiku mom you ping like guitar combo yeah
Oh No pingzhi seat yeah
hey Joe what Stephanie want your hair
job yeah
see I'll do ba ba cockeyed but what deci
you seem see your tribe oh damn Go
Go okay
tae-young your mom said oh oh hi thorn
and Java chigga chung no yeah ChaCha cat
um yeah I number lime I like your heart
cool what my life that sing knee cry
lock because you have young boy ha
tick-tock Jojo why mommy rap I am bow oh
yeah I'm bow Oh uncle I'm I like ah
watch it
granny see how what JC okay nom nom
watch E support quarters you are like
Jim Georgie phenom some quagga quagga
came hello knocking hollow knock yahoo
hair hi yeah go dad um job satya matcha
me god king Chiquito hacia tomboy like
he ha ha ha
Yanis Chinese New Year and also my Chevy
Chucho so for the next photo I'm just
gonna put a bunch of food photos here so
for my family both Vietnamese and
Chinese food are very much a part of our
everyday lives and culture and I'm so
glad because I freaking love both
Vietnamese and Chinese food I'm just
gonna show a bunch of pictures here so
this is my grandparents and bun Hawaii
and this is over here chocolate that my
aunt
and I really love bet Moy which is just
white porridge it's like my favorite
comfort food when I come home I just
like all the like little preserved food
that we eat with it including let me
show you this is pork some brought from
California all the way to Massachusetts
this is like what I sprinkle on top of
porridge I also really love Dallas
Eliahu which is like this canned
preserved fish with salty black beans
and it doesn't sound good and it doesn't
look that good but it is so bum I love
it
a lot of people who bring you know
ethnic foods to school sometimes they
have this traumatizing experience where
everybody makes fun of them and I did
have an experience like that but it
wasn't as traumatising because I was a
lot older so in high school I remember
that I would bring food and one dish
that I brought was Dubai Tokyo which is
this ground pork and ginger and I loved
it is super good and I brought it with
rice and I didn't get to eat it in time
during lunch so I have to bring it to my
fifth period class and I remember it was
like open a jar I didn't start eating
yet but my teacher who by the way like
I'm not mad at him or anything I'm his
friend like we're friends on social
media he's a really cool and nice guy
but I think what he did was a little
insensitive so that day he was like oh
my god hoorah fish into my classroom
smells so bad and then he looked at me
it was you wasn't it what is that do not
bring that into my classroom ever again
and I was a little bit mortified just
sitting in the front like oh my gosh
okay I didn't take it like oh my gosh
I'm so embarrassed of what I'm eating
and I'm never gonna bring this to school
again more so just like I'm not gonna
bring this into his classroom again this
stuff is good and it smells good it's
not even fish to begin with do you
understand that I think certain smells
can be a little bit off-putting or
foreign to people but I don't think and
I would not suggest you call out
anybody's food like that like I think
young people um is so distasteful yeah I
wouldn't do it so the next photos are
pictures of me and my sister and this is
when I was about like nine ten eleven
and this is really when my hair started
to kind of get crinkle
and frizzy and wavy towards the front
parts of my hair and growing up when I
was very young my hair was very straight
and all of a sudden as I got a little
bit older my hair started getting very
frizzy and it was a really difficult
transition for me because all my friends
my sister my family they had straight
hair very silky straight like that Asian
hair that I just really wanted and I
remember just it was so hard to like
look at myself in the mirror everyday
and just have this like fringe ball I
couldn't have a cute thing that
everybody had because the shorter that
my hair went like the crazier it would
get when I got my hands on a
straightener like that was my baby and I
wouldn't never go to school without
training my hair it is still something
that like if I were to do one thing to
make myself feel better and look better
in my own eyes like I straighten my hair
so these next photos are gonna be of my
family and I just want to talk a little
bit about the struggle that I've had and
still have when trying to balance
between the filial piety of Asian
culture and the individualism of
American culture I'm constantly like
faced with trying to balance these two
and this has definitely rang true when
I'm making these bigger decisions like
where to go to school I'm for certain
and that a huge huge huge reason why I
chose UCI over UC Davis was because it
was closer to my family and that's why
making that decision to even move across
the country to come to Harvard was such
a difficult decision and even in terms
of like who I'm dating I think whether
or not like my family approves or gets
along with them is such a huge factor
and it's not always been like the
easiest but I do think that that is
something huge that I consider and I
think along the lines of that something
that you know me my cousin's my sister
and also the older generation are trying
to navigate is this balance between
being more open-minded to the other
generation and not just kind of butting
heads time after time and trying to be
more understanding about where we're
coming from as this generation and where
they're coming from knowing that
everybody in our family is very
sensitive but just trying to be open and
understanding I think is is this ongoing
struggle and journey
I'm happy to say that I think there's
been a lot of improvement but I think
there's always gonna be more learning
that we all can do so these next photos
I want to put are going to be me my
sister in our very kpop fangirl phase in
high school and I just want to talk
about comments that I've got throughout
the year saying oh you look Korean wow
you look just like Korean girl just like
a Japanese girl and my relatives or
friends or acquaintances they're always
saying this as a compliment and it
wasn't until I got older that I realized
how problematic it was that people are
saying oh you look Korean or Japanese as
a compliment rather than saying hey you
look good a lot of times when my
relatives say it before I was just kind
of like thumbs up give you a little
sticker but more so I think I'm trying
to say like no I look like a Chinese
girl I look like a Chinese Merrit girl
but I want to look like a Chinese
American girl for these next photos I
want to share a little bit about my
experience as an asian-american stepping
outside of my bubble of my hometown and
of me in college as an undergrad and me
in grad school here in Massachusetts so
in undergrad I worked a lot with
international students and they
primarily came from China and so I
started to identify myself and others
would identify me as an ABC or an
American born Chinese or a domestic
student that would come out a lot
because I would be in a lot of mentoring
program where we would mentor
international students and I felt like
it was a great position and advantage
point for me because I was able to
navigate and kind of switch coat switch
a little bit and understand those
cultures the Chinese culture and also
the American culture so I felt I felt
really good about my identity there so
now coming to Harvard Massachusetts it's
really the first time where I'm
experiencing not being a part of the
majority in terms of what I look like
and for the first time I'm in classes
where it's very visible that I am one of
only few Asians and I have struggled a
lot with where my voice fits in in what
often seems like this racial binary and
this is something I touched upon on my
presentation video as well and I was
talking about this with my friend the
other day who is also Asian American
that sometimes in these spaces like for
the first time where we're talking about
Asian Americans
in educational space we have conflicting
feelings because on the one hand it's
great to like whoa we're finally talking
about the group I belong to it but at
the same time whenever asian-americans
are brought up it's not in a good light
right it's talking about the model
minority myth or stereotypes or the
Chinese Exclusion Act or covin 19 and
all the discrimination and so it's just
this kind of like conflicting feeling
we're like yay we're finally being
talked about and then like oh god
everything is really shitty so there's
there's those kind of feelings that
arise so the last picture I have is this
picture of me and Ryan going to see the
farewell and fall and I want to use this
to talk a little bit about Asian
representation in media but recently my
friend and I were talking about this
increase in Asian representation in the
media and how exciting it was to see
things like never have I ever
James conveniens fresh-off-the-boat
crazy rich Asians and how problematic it
is that people are looking to these
shows to represent the entire group that
they're depicting I think an example of
this is when people were getting mad at
crazy rich Asians because it was not
depicting Chinese people in what they
saw as accurate right they were saying
not everybody is rich like this this is
just a very small set but that movie was
never looking to represent all Chinese
people but I think it's because there's
not a lot of Chinese people in the media
we look to these couple of movies that
we can get to see oh is this gonna tell
my story correctly like we look to see a
reflection of ourselves and in some ways
it is and it's great but in many ways
when we feel like oh they got it wrong
it becomes this like tension because we
get so concerned about how people are
gonna perceive our group whereas we
never look at friends the TV show or
like nothing's really coming to my mind
except head amant at our Will & Grace or
Everybody Loves Raymond I'm even though
I didn't really watch those shows no one
really looking to them and say but
that's not really how my family and my
friend group is because there's so many
white families and friends depicted on
television but there's not a lot of
Indian Americans so people are gonna
look to never have ever to see well how
of a job they do did they exaggerate
these stereotypes a little bit too much
but in the end like I'm really excited
to see these shows but I think that it's
something that needs to be talked about
that these shows are not trying to be
representative of every single Asian
American family out there
so that's all for this video I hope you
all found it either to be enjoyable
relatable interesting or learn something
new if you can relate to anything
comment down below or just say hello I
want to wish everybody a happy Asian
Pacific American Heritage Month and I'll
see you in my next video bye
[Music]