[Music]
hi everyone its Katrina and welcome back
to my channel so today I have another
Q&A video for you all about a year ago I
did a Q&A video and answer some of your
questions about like the college
application process my thoughts about
going to Harvard and all these pre grad
school feels and I thought it'd be cool
to do another Q&A video now that I'm
more than halfway through my program and
then do a final one after I graduate and
create a little series to just track how
I feel and what are my thoughts
throughout this journey so I want to
give a huge huge thank you to everyone
who left a question or multiple
questions and I'm gonna try my best to
get through a bunch of them and actually
outline this video because I didn't want
to keep rambling on and on so the first
question is which school are you in so
I'm currently in the Harvard Graduate
School of Education teacher education
program or Thep and I'm in the history
cohort and I'm currently doing my
student teaching and I'm teaching AP US
history question number two how did you
decide on what to study and which
program to pick for grad school so I
went in to UC Irvine knowing that I
wanted to go into the education field
and I've always been thinking about
being a teacher when I first got
admitted to UCI there wasn't an
education major available so I chose
psychology and social behavior because
that seemed like the closest thing and
then once the education major opened up
during my second year I decided to pick
up both of them so I graduated with a
double major as I was considering grad
schools I knew I wanted to continue in
the education field but I started
thinking about counseling maybe a little
part of me thought about research for
time teaching but I eventually committed
to teaching and I knew that I wanted to
do a combo program I knew I wanted to
get my masters and teaching credential
at the same time so I was only looking
at grad schools that offered the
master's degree and the teaching
credential I ended up applying to four
different programs I applied to
Harvard's program UCLA UC Davis's and
Stanford's and I was just about to
submit my application for UC Irvine but
then I got into Davis and I realized
that I wanted to go to Davis more than
UCI so I decided to save myself the
application fee and I didn't end up
to UC Irvine for the results just to be
transparent and you all I got into to
school so I got into Harvard and I got
into UC Davis and on the same day that I
got admitted into Harvard I got
wait-listed to UCLA so for me like the
top two were Harvard in UCLA my family
really wanted me to go to UCLA since it
was close to home I really enjoyed the
people that I met and the interview I
had with UC Davis but I ended up going
with my number one choice which was
Harvard and I eventually got rejected
from UCLA like months after I said yes
to Harvard so yeah those were overall my
results Stanford net zero chance so the
next question is did you consider a PhD
instead of a masters and what factors
that you consider slash help you weight
your decision for me it was pretty clear
that I wanted to do a master's a
professor once told me that a good sign
that you're ready for the PhD path or
that PhD path is the right one for you
is if there is a question that just
keeps you up at night that sparks a fire
within you that you just really feel the
need to dive deeper into and research
and for me there wasn't a question that
did that for me and honestly when I was
involved in research and during my
senior year and a little bit post-grad
it was kind of dreadful like I don't
know every time I would have to bright
those papers I just did not really enjoy
it and so I couldn't imagine doing that
for four to five years but I'm not
closed off to the idea like I think I
just wanted to get into the classroom
first and then if you know after years
if I noticed things or a question pops
up then maybe that will be the time to
go research more and get a PhD but for
now I think that a master's was really
the clear decision for me I'm sending my
AB soon for online grad school and how
was your flow different from undergrad
congratulations on almost submitting and
good luck there were some big
differences between undergrad and grad
school for me for undergrad I felt like
I was always playing it very safe in
that I had a pretty hard like I'm gonna
take 12 academic units like three
classes a quarter and then let myself
fill up on extracurriculars in undergrad
I flew solo for the most part I did not
really consult with like friends or you
know peers to take classes I would just
take whatever I needed
I would go to class I didn't really
study with others didn't really like no
people in my classes my academics were
very important and my extracurriculars
were also very important to me so I
definitely prioritize both those things
and I felt like I had a pretty
well-rounded schedule for grad school is
really different because I really
realized that I'm capable of a lot more
than I previously thought I was before
you know as the child teenager undergrad
I just felt like I was constantly
limiting myself and saying like okay
this is your you know zone of proximal
development this is where you can
succeed if you go any more than that
it's just gonna be too much for you
right and you're not gonna succeed and
the reason why you're doing well is
because you're kind of finding that
comfort zone and putting yourself in
there in grad school I really couldn't
stay in that comfort zone because there
was just not enough time and I usually
took 12 units right as I said in grad
school fall semester I took 24 units it
was a completely like new intense
schedule for me but I did it I conquered
it I was able to get straight A's and
for the first time I relied on other
people a lot of my friends were in my
classes we had cohort mates and it was
just really nice to see familiar faces
in class and a made class just so much
more enjoyable as I'm sitting with my
friends and for the first time I had a
reading group so we would split up the
readings and we would each take turns
taking our notes and that helped
commenced me I I loved the Technic
Studies reading group and I felt like I
didn't need a sit in front you know
before I was like oh I always succeed
because I sit in the front
I buy my textbooks I take notes on paper
and I had such a different routine in
grad school I'm constantly taking notes
on the computer just to save paper and
it's more efficient and quick and just
to have things in one space I'm not
really sitting in the front although I
think it would be better for my own
focus and engagement sometimes I just
don't even think I have the time or
energy or capacity to be getting
involved in like on campus involvement
so I'm here to you know finish the
program take my classes do my student
teaching but I'm not as concerned about
getting involved which I do regret
because I feel like I only have three
more months of the resources that are
available to me and I just don't think I
even made like a little dense thing what
is offer here so there's just not enough
time and another thing I don't know this
fits within flow but I think that it's
nice because in grad school I see a
clear relation between what I'm learning
in either my classes or workshops or
student teaching to my future career so
I feel like I'm walking into these
spaces looking for things that I can
pool and take away with me to use in the
future where as an undergrad I felt like
there was just a variety of different
things that I was learning and not
everything was directly related to what
I would be doing
I think grad school I'm like reframing
the way that I'm walking into these
spaces so it's really cool to just see
what I can get out of these things next
question is how do you manage to keep
your coolness at an all time high all
the time
Thank You Philip you too so the next
question is by Karen and it is can you
bring me back a Harvard Shot cup tada
oops price tag that uh-oh
good cash did I you're welcome next
question is I'm going to why is s or
Yonsei international summer school this
summer and I watch your Yonsei video
thank you how rigorous for the classes
during my summer I young say I took two
classes I took developmental psychology
which was a major class for me and then
contemporary Korean culture which was a
GE and they weren't too rigorous but one
thing I do want to point out is that
they were inconsistent in their
structure and the way they were taught
because the two professors were from
very different parts of the world so my
psychology professor was from California
so her teaching style the way her class
was run was very familiar to what I was
used to whereas my Korean contemporary
culture professor was from Korea but he
is currently a professor at a university
in Singapore so I'm not exactly sure if
the classes are very different but I
felt like the way he ran his class was a
little bit different than I was used to
so I felt like I had a slightly harder
time in that class and I was going to
office hours a lot more I would probably
recommend taking two courses instead of
three if you still want to you know have
some fun while you're there and not be
too into studying so even with those two
classes I really spent my weekdays
studying and then I
myself have fun and go out on the
weekends I hope you have a good time at
Yonsei have fun so the next question is
how do you know if you're doing
something that you're most passionate
about I really like this question and it
got me thinking because I actually
didn't really know how to answer it for
me if I get really excited thinking or
talking about something it's usually a
good sign that I'm passionate about it
and if it consumes my mind as I'm doing
random things like you know getting
ready to sleep or showering or walking
to school and just these ideas pop up
and I get really excited about it
that's how I know that this is something
that I'm passionate about for example
sometimes as I'm showering I'll think of
like lesson plan ideas for school and
and I get really excited and I had to
tell Ryan right away um when I'm
planning my family parties and the games
like those are the things that I would
stay up late thinking about a doing u2
idea sometimes I would just be like
walking and I think about a an idea and
I get really excited or I think about a
brand that I want to ask to collaborate
with and I get really excited I feel
like because I don't like staying up
late if I'm staying up late to do
something that is not like due or an
assignment that's usually a good sign
that I'm passionate about it because I
don't like staying up late to do things
so yeah and maybe you'll be different
for other people but that's just how I
kind of think about things that I'm
passionate about so the next question is
what was the scariest part about moving
so far away I feel like for me many of
the things that would have been scary
like being alone here moving to a new
place not knowing anyone being in a
possibly rocky long-distance
relationship all of that we're not scary
because Ryan came with me so huge huge
huge thank you to Ryan I always tell him
that's what I was an ugly heart huge
thank you to Ryan for coming with me I
really feel like because he came with me
so many of the things that would have
been scary and concerning for me and my
family were alleviated so now when I
think about the scariest thing is
probably being far away from my family
and not being able to immediately be
there if something happens and to just
not always be in the loop of what's
going on because the only way I'll know
what's going on is if someone decides
texts or call me so I don't find out as
fast as I would if I were there and I
just feel like because of that I get
worried what if something happens like
it's gonna take us a while to get there
and it's gonna cost money and
stuff like that so I think that's
probably been the most concerning thing
for me next question is how is the class
culture like at Harvard and did you
experience any culture shock so I have a
lot of notes for this question I feel
like at the education school people that
I've met I'm really nice and they're
very open to helping and engaging with
one another and I've noticed and
appreciated how much people are willing
to share in class and how much we learn
from each other even in classes where it
doesn't seem like you might have a
connection with you know the topic or
the material I've really appreciated how
much I've been able to connect my own
experiences in my own story with what
we're learning about and it that really
just enriches like the learning
experience and makes it so much more
powerful I feel like we derive most of
our learning from each other and the
text rather than our professor just
telling us what's going on because
rarely did I have professors just
lecturing I only had one class where it
was like an undergrad course so there
was like a mix of undergrad and grad
school students and it wasn't in the
education school where the professor
would be lecturing the whole time and
that brought me back to undergrad vibes
but in the grad school like we're
constantly getting up doing activities
group discussions breakout groups to the
point where I remember like in one of
our classes we would have to get up
multiple times during those three hour
classes
and we were really tired from like being
at our school sites the whole day so we
were just like please stop making us get
up like just lecture for three hours you
just in our classes we're definitely
forced to discuss more and to
participate and share our ideas and it
made me feel really anxious because I
felt like my ideas were so I don't know
like basic compared to my peers and I
felt like I didn't really have so much
to add to our conversations so that was
definitely a source of anxiety but it
was really nice to see like some of my
friends and peers felt the same way and
that we were able to be vulnerable and
open to admitting that yeah like this is
how we feel although you think that like
some people would be like hey like what
you said I was really grand you know
like it feels so good when you're saying
something and people like snapped
because in grad school like people snap
a lot when they agree with what you say
and let me tell you the validation the
good feeling that comes when you hear
like you say something and then is in
the back crap
so thank you to everyone who has told me
that they appreciate something that I've
said in class or that they've snapped
for me because it really takes like a
lot for me to be able to share and I
just really appreciate like the external
validation oh as for culture shock I
definitely experienced a positive
culture shock with just the different
demographics of students peers that I
have here with me for those of you don't
know I come from a part of LA that is
very how to say like monolithic it's
like an ethnic Enclave where everybody
kind of comes from the same background
right most of the people that I grew up
with our families where Chinese or
Vietnamese and our parents were from
Vietnam and they escaped the Vietnam War
they came as refugees and that's kind of
like the narrative that every family all
my friends have so for me like that was
what I was used to and coming here like
I'm working with students and peers from
so many different parts of the world and
from the different parts of the US as
well so my students like I have so many
students from the West Indies Cape Verde
Jamaica Ethiopia Eritrea Somalia Algeria
Morocco Bangladesh just so many
different places and when I first saw
the roster of our students there were so
many names and I just never heard of
before and that just really was kind of
like culture shock to me because like I
was just used to the names like Brandon
Kevin Ryan Brian
those kind of things back home so seeing
these different names was really amazing
to me and even in my cohort where often
the United States but were from such
different parts of the United States so
it's really cool to see what was
different in our experiences growing up
what was the same in our schooling
experience isn't just to learn from each
other there I think of all the things
that I've gained I feel like that is the
number one thing that I'm grateful for
for being able to go to Harvard and live
in Cambridge is to work with such a
diverse group of people I don't I don't
know if I would have another opportunity
to live outside of that specific part of
LA that I'm from and so I just feel
really grateful to have this opportunity
to be able to live here and experience
such a different part of America so I
guess kind of related to that a huge
fear that I've had going into teaching
coming to
however was how am I gonna connect to
students or friends if I don't know
anything about where they're coming from
and I mean this was definitely a flaw in
my own mentality that I was so fixated
on potential differences right like well
I don't know so much about this
ethnicity or this part of the world or
this language and I felt like that would
be a huge disadvantage for me working
with a group of students who I wasn't
familiar with their culture and
background but I realized that there are
so many more similarities and the
differences are a great opportunity to
learn from each other because whereas I
thought that oh everybody knows my
narrative because I come from a place
where everyone has such a similar
background story it was the common you
know the common narrative for me but
coming to this place and sharing my
story I'm so shocked to see how
surprised people are and my family had
this kind of journey and for so many of
them they had no idea about like the
boat people and stuff like that so it's
been a really great opportunity to share
my story my family's story and to learn
about others family stories as well this
question hi if you also feel very
disappointed when you study for this
test but then you get a very bad score
and you lose all motivation in your body
and end up soaking if you have
experienced this how do you cope up so
when I read this I immediately thought
to two instances one was right after my
stats midterm in my senior year of
college and another was right after my
health psychology midterm also in my
senior year of college I just felt so so
so discouraged and disappointed because
I did feel like I studied so hard and I
felt like I was confident and then I
came out of there feeling so shitty to
the point where I was crying right so I
think my advice would be to one sit in
those negative sad disappointed emotions
and to cry if you need to cry to do
whatever you need to do to let those
feelings out to is to you know maybe
still soak but as you're sulking reflect
on what you could have done differently
maybe and come up with an action plan to
bounce back so I just think like it's
normal to feel so upset when you've
studied so hard and you felt confident
walking in and the result is just
completely opposite but just try not to
beat yourself up over and to be sad but
also find a way to cheer yourself up
that day that day
to that health psychology midterm I
actually came home and filmed a video
because I knew that that would make me
feel better so out of that day came my
study tips video so you know that
there's something that would make you
feel better whether it's turning our
music eating something I would treat
yourself to that right because you did
work hard and then after that come up
with an action plan of what you can do
better next time so the next question is
how do you feel about going back home so
I definitely feel mixed feelings about
going back home I feel like on the one
hand I'm really excited to be back with
my family my friends to be able to see
them more often on the other hand I feel
like I fear that I'm gonna be this like
post grad slump but like I was after
undergrad where I'm just gonna feel so
unproductive and unmotivated and lazy
there's something just about home that
makes me feel that type of way sometimes
so I feel like I'm excited to you know
start my real career get a job and do
all that and then at the same time I
know that I'm going to miss being a
student here despite how stressful it is
sometimes just the independence just the
routine living with Ryan looking forward
and not looking forward to it I don't
know a lot of feelings so the last
question is who is your favorite
Australian cousin that's a toughy I'm
gonna have to go with definitely not
Darren's
just kidding you're all right you're all
right mate so that wraps up this Q&A
video I hope you all enjoyed it as much
as I did I really love answering your
questions and hearing from you all and I
want to thank you all for making it to
the end I know this is a long video but
I really really appreciate you all for
supporting me and following me
throughout my journey and I wish you all
the best on your own journey too yeah so
please leave a comment if you'd like to
I would love to read anything you all
have to say and I hope to see you all in
my next Q&A video after I graduate
[Music]