[Music]
hi guys welcome back it's so annoying
let's do that again I don't know how to
start this hey guys welcome back to my
channel
that's much better for today's video I
am going to be doing a question and
answer video I had you guys ask me
questions last night on my Instagram if
you guys don't follow me on Instagram
yet my Instagram name is a right here
but yeah I had you guys ask you some
questions that you want answers to on my
Instagram last night so this video is
going to be answering all of those
questions so without further ado first
question is what is my skincare routine
um well I don't have a skincare routine
I know that sounds bad this skincare
routine that I have had doesn't consist
of a whole lot I use a just like a mild
cleanser I believe it's from clean and
clear it's like the yellow and purple
bottle just a really mild cleanser but
still like gets all of that gunk off my
face I usually do I wash my face like
double I wash my face like every night
obviously when I'm taking a shower I
wash it once rinse and then wash it
again and rinse because there's still so
much makeup on my face usually at the
end of the day um I don't go like full
glam makeup look every single day
because homegirl and got no time for
that but when I do take off my makeup I
find that like just rinsing one time
isn't enough but you do have to be
careful because some of the cleansers
are really really harsh on the skin I've
used a couple wide used one from like
Neutrogena which was super good and like
cleansed in my skin really well but it
was so drying that I had to stop using
it and I also had a reaction to it so
that was just a bad experience but yeah
I don't really have a skincare routine I
just use like a mild cleanser I get
facials every now and then and then I
also will like spot treat my skin
whenever like my skin just recently has
not been well at all I hardly have any
makeup on today and I'm also so pale
okay let's just talk about that for a
second I literally look like a ghost
okay but yeah I do spot treat my skin
where I have breakouts I use the Mario
Badescu which is like the most popular I
feel like spot treatment
it's from Ulta at $17 it's in a little
tiny little pink bottle I use that
overnight if I ever have any like skin
breakouts that are coming through or
that I
you want to get rid of in a timely
manner so yes that is my skincare
routine okay next question is what
message would you give to a new makeup
artist coming into the industry that's a
good question
my message to a new makeup artist would
probably have to be trying it as much
practice as you can I know just from
like when I started I started working on
all my really good friends and I thought
like wow I'm so good at this like this
is honestly fire right now if I go back
now and I look at those pictures and I'm
like why did anybody let me touch their
face ever like why but I think my advice
would just to be get as much would be
just to get what did I say would be just
to get as much practice as you can
because practice really does make
perfect I know that's such a cheesy line
but the more practice you have the more
experience you have working on multiple
faces multiple skin tones multiple skin
types like all of that really helps you
in the long run because I mean if you're
a makeup artist and you want to like be
doing you know weddings or parties or
events or whatever it is you're more
than likely gonna be working on so many
different faces and so many different
types of women that you know they're not
all one person is the same obviously so
I think just my biggest thing if you're
just starting out or you want to like
become a makeup artist is to get as much
practice as you can even though you're
probably gonna suck when you first start
that's totally fine because everybody
does I did I've always been into makeup
I've always been into beauty but when I
started doing makeup on other people I
was like what the hell am i doing like I
had no clue what I was doing and I just
had to learn from like experience so
game is not just an experience as you
can okay next question is what is your
favorite place to buy clothes honestly
honestly forever21 I know that's like so
basic and I feel like everybody shops
there but they had really cute clothes
for me I'm not really super
materialistic like I don't I don't know
mean that in a bad way I just mean like
I don't necessarily need like brand-name
stuff like I don't I'm just not that
kind of person I love just finding cute
affordable clothes where it doesn't like
break the bank you know ii mean and i am
one of the people i love shopping like
shopping could be a full-time job for me
because i do it so often but i feel like
i want to be able to buy new clothes
often and not feel like well i'm
spending three hundred and fifty dollars
every time i go to the mall every time i
go shop
you know and I feel like forever 21 has
really really really cute stuff at a
really good price point so I usually buy
all of my clothes there I also do a lot
of shopping at Ross and Marshalls and TJ
Maxx stores like that and I feel like I
feel like they have like a bat you know
what I mean they were like oh you shop
at Ross like this yeah I do got my Ross
because they have a really cute stuff
and most the time I'm wearing stuff on
camera or like in a video or whatever
and you guys like oh my gosh where'd you
get that and I'm like Ross so they just
have really good stuff and also at a
very good price line in my opinion but
my I think my all-time favorite store is
forever 21 next question what is the
most important thing that you look for
on a client before doing their makeup um
that's a good one I think the one thing
that I look at like first and foremost
is their skin type because most the time
like if they have like dry skin I like
to prep the skin I always start with eye
makeup so no matter who I'm working on I
always do their eyes first because I
like to avoid like fall out if I'm doing
like a dark look or whatever but I
always look at the person's skin because
if they have dry skin I like to prep it
before so I'll put a moisturizer let
that kind of sink and soak in I'll put a
primer let that kind of like work its
way work itself in there and then by the
time I get to their face their face like
prepped and primed and ready to go if
that makes sense so I think definitely
looking at the person's skin is the
first thing that I do okay this person
asked what is your eyebrow routine your
yours always look amazing
so I actually get a lot of questions
about my eyebrows and I don't know if
I've said this on my channel before or
not but I used to have and let's just
okay we can just like I think you can
same I know I have a hat on but I used
to have a unibrow when I was little yes
I know I'm just letting it all out right
now also if you look on my Instagram
page I think it's kind of a bit farther
down but I did this whole post about
like my eyebrow transformation 30 years
they were so hideous like I had full
really really really full eyebrows and
then I plucked them and cut them and
trimmed them and they were lines I
basically did everything that you're not
supposed to do to my own eyebrows and I
thought they looked so good I just
didn't want to have a unibrow anymore so
I just tried everything I possibly could
to get rid of them but now they have
obviously grown back and they're not
lying face but I get them to get the
shape of my eyebrows I did threading so
I got I went to like one of those little
threading places and got the shape and
they I feel like the threading places
like shape them really well I don't I
couldn't tell you the name of the place
I went to is out of my bird now I pretty
much keep them up on my own every now
and then I will get them waxed just like
really get a nice cleaning but for the
most part I use those little like tinkle
twinkle razor things I think they're
called tinkle tinkle that sounds weird
but I'm pretty sure they're called
tinkle razors and they're just like they
kind of like will clean up your eyebrows
like your eyebrow hairs and stuff and
then I just pluck the ones that are like
too hard to get with that but um yeah I
just I have a really the girl who does
my eyebrows her name is Olivia I will
leave her contact information in the
description box below but she does a
really good job she's a really good job
shaping them and just like filling them
in and like making them like the shape
that I want
so I mean definitely having a good eye
brow specialist
is good but um as far as filling them in
I usually just use like a pencil I will
fill in like the sparse areas and then
I'll go in with a powder and just like
fill in with a powder so that's what I
do okay next question is how long have
you been doing makeup I have been doing
makeup um I started in January of 2015
so just over three years I've been
working on bridal parties and I'm pretty
sure for just over two years um I wanted
to try and get as much experience as I
could before I like went full-on in to
like doing Bridal parties and we a
wedding makeup and stuff like that
because that was like a huge step for me
but yeah I've been doing makeup since
January 2015
is when I like started my journey that's
when I was like this is what I want to
do this is what I'm gonna do and then I
went for it okay next question is um oh
wait she has three what is your favorite
store to shop at um oh my gosh I love
forever 21 like I said I really really
love that but I also love I love Hobby
Lobby and I love I love like Marshalls
and t.j.maxx because they just have
everything but I also obviously love
Target I'm just such a target girl I'm a
target a holic that's I just made that
up what tips do you have for ladies who
want to start freelancing
that's a good question um I think if I
had tips my first tip would be to save
your money because makeup is so
expensive and especially if you want to
have like a kit and you want to like be
working on other people makeup is a not
cheap I can't even tell you how many
many many dollars I've spent on makeup
and stuff like that because you have to
take into consideration you have to get
different colors you have to get
different you know like foundation
shades concealer shades you have to get
bunch of different palettes and you know
you try to get I mean you try to get as
many things as you can to be like as a
versatile as you can possibly be because
you're gonna be working on so many
different people so my first tip would
probably be to save your money because
it's expensive and it's a very it's a
very expensive hobby turned into which
can turn into a job if that's what
you're wanting to go for so definitely
save your money and also like I said
earlier get as much experience as you
can my biggest thing is people sometimes
ask me this they're like how much should
I start charging like I'm just starting
out ah don't charge them anything
because if you don't know what you're
doing I feel like that's kind of not
fair for you to be like charging at the
same time I understand that makeup costs
money but when I first started
freelancing I would have people bring me
all of their own products and like the
problem with that sometimes too is
people don't have the right stuff like
maybe they don't have the right color
maybe I don't have that shade for their
like skin tone it happens but if you're
trying to like just get the experience
of working with different products and
different people and different faces I
would say have them don't charge them
first of all but then I would say to you
know have used their stuff instead of
like buying a crap ton of stuff and like
not really maybe not knowing at what to
do with it yet sorry there was something
floating right here but I would say use
the clients products use the stuff that
they have so then they that way they can
learn to use like what they have so they
don't have to say it you don't have to
tell them like okay here's what you need
go out and spend $500 on like all this
stuff because you know it's expensive so
that's how II what I would say is I I
didn't charge people when I first
started because I just didn't I didn't
know what I was doing you know so I
wanted to just get that experience
before I was like okay fork it over you
know that I mean just I mean things to
think about
alrighty the next question is I love the
week to makeup how did you how did you
get inspired to start doing makeup for
others thank you I got started doing
makeup like I said in
about 300 just over three years ago and
I was actually in the Target aisle and I
was just like I was I had to buy like
new makeup and stuff because that was
the one I bought all my stuff at oh my
god my gosh yeah sorry that's when I
bought all my makeup at the drugstore
like just at Target and I was standing
in the aisle and I thought you know I
think it'd be really fun to just like
buy new stuff like I'm just gonna throw
everything I have and I'm just gonna
start over like I'm just gonna buy new
product and just like try it out and see
how I like it and all that stuff just
kind of experiment with new things and
so I went home and I like was trying on
all this makeup and I thought wow this
is like so much fun like finding new
stuff and like figuring out like new
ways to do things and like new products
to use and I think that's kind of what
like made me feel like I kind of want to
start doing this like on regular basis
like if I started working on people and
like I knew that I was gonna I knew that
I was gonna have to figure out like
different ways to do things and I loved
like learning I feel like that's what I
love the most about makeup is because
it's just it's never one thing it's
always changing it's always like
something new it's always planets always
exciting and there's always so much to
learn like I feel like I just never
stopped learning in this industry like
which is so cool and I think I think
that's probably what started like what
made me want to start doing people
makeup on other people is just the fact
that I wanted to like learn more about
how to do stuff and I obviously love
makeup I love applying it on people on
myself I love doing videos and some like
that I think I wanted to just find out
you know how how I could better myself
and how I could better the skill and the
skills that you that I need to do makeup
so I think that's probably why okay next
question is how did you first get into
freelancing what are some tips you've
learned along the way regarding
freelancing and being prepared for
clients I feel like some tips that I've
learned is to really plan ahead I feel
like once I have like a wedding coming
up I'm like that whole week I'm like
okay do I have this do I have this I
have this do I have this drive enough
lashes do I have enough mascara do i
havnt hope you know like you just always
are trying to like go over everything in
your head um but I definitely would say
like being prepared and if you're not
like an organized person like start
trying to be organized because once you
go out and you're freelancing and people
are relying on you for something I was
like big is like getting them ready for
their wedding or getting them ready for
prom we're getting ready for formal or
whatever it may be it's like a lot of
pressure and it can be
pressure and when I first started I was
always like Oh am i doing it right like
am i okay like you know I was trying to
like I haven't I always second-guessing
myself but I think some tips I'm like I
kind of mentioned earlier is to like
save your money if you want to do
freelancing it costs a lot of money as
like a startup thing because you need so
much product and you need so many like
so many things of everything like you
just need multiples it's like you're
buying the stuff in bulk it's literally
like I have I can't even tell you how
many foundation tubes I have in these
drawers like it's ridiculous
but you just have to really be prepared
with for like how much money you're
gonna spend if this is something that
you want to get into it's not cheap the
more experience you get the more you can
obviously like you can start charging
people you can I and I wouldn't like I
think when I first started I charge like
oh my gosh like 35 or 40 dollars like
and that was like the base like this is
you know you can have me do whatever you
want and like now obviously years later
my prices have changed but you have to
you have to be really realistic when you
first start out in my opinion because
you can't be like okay day one I'm gonna
be a makeup artist today and I'm gonna
charge $125 like you just doesn't work
like that because people are not gonna
like people are not gonna pay that but I
think yeah those are probably my two
biggest tips another tip that I really
have is to take pictures of your work
because I think that's how I mean that
is how like I came to be like where I'm
at now it's through Instagram and people
you know some of my friends are always
like why do you take in scams seriously
like you're so dumb and I'm like um
because that's my job it's literally my
job that's how I make money and it's
like through Instagram I'm not like
literally through Instagram but because
I post pictures of clients and like you
know whatever I'm doing you know people
really get to know you through social
media they really get to see your work
like firsthand so I think that's
definitely like if you want to like take
this thing seriously you want to be a
freelance makeup artist I'd create a cat
create an account create your own like
personal Beauty account like I I
wouldn't I don't know I have mixed
feelings about like linking it to like
your main account like if you're just
like posting about I here no longer you
know on a Tuesday like I think if people
are gonna want to like see your work
work like you should have something
separate that's what I kind of did when
I first started like I just had my
makeup page I didn't have like another
Instagram and now like I
kind of like I kind of mix things every
now and then but I have like my 1 for
like here is my work makeup here is my
work Instagram and then I have another
one where it's like here's my Tuesday
but definitely utilizing social media
was so big and so important for me and
really really helped me tremendously and
getting my name out there and having
other people see my work and having you
know that's that's just how I built up I
wouldn't say it clientele because it's
not necessarily like I don't have too
many repeat clients just because like
you really don't get your makeup done
for like a wedding like multiple times I
mean maybe you do but like I mean think
about if you're a bridal party like how
many how many weddings are you really
and you didn't mean like you just don't
know like it's not like hair or you have
to get it done like every three months I
think it was kind of a little bit
different but like I did get my name out
there and people started knowing me more
because of social media so I would
definitely say to utilize social media
as well okay just a few more questions
here um I have a question about spray
tans I really get them so I never know
what's the best way to prep your skin
for them what do you suggest okay so I
get spray tans very regularly what I do
is I make sure to exfoliate my skin too
how do I say this the two days before I
get my spray tan so like typically I get
my spray tans on Thursday so I'll make
sure to exfoliate my skin in the shower
on Tuesday and on Wednesday night and
then I usually just shave like the night
before so I'll exploit my skin and
everything on Tuesday and then I will
exfoliate and shave also on Wednesday
that's like the best way I got that's
how it works for me isolating your skin
and like obviously shaving is just gonna
make everything go on smoother I'm not
like a skincare expert so I really don't
know like the technical terms for
everything but I do know that exfoliant
really helps this the tan to like stick
to your skin better and I exfoliate too
primarily because I have a tan on from
like before like I already have a little
bit of like tan like I can usually
always see it like on my arms right here
I don't know if like you can really see
it but like you see that gets white
right here and then it's like dark it's
because that's like it's a tan so I
tried like exploit my skin so that this
that new tan will stay on and to also
get rid of the old tan so that's what I
suggest I mean the next question is what
are your favorite nude lipsticks
actually
last question my favorite nude lipsticks
let me grab them okay my my number one
favorite nude lipstick is this one right
here and this is from Tarte and I will
show you up close what it looks like
this is called rum punch and I feel like
it looks so good on everybody and I just
love lipsticks like that you know so
this is what it looks like and I will
swatch it for you okay so this is what
rum punch looks like I think it's just
like a really pretty pinky nude but like
not too pink not too nude you know I'm
saying like I just don't like lipsticks
that are too pink and I don't like them
to live six oh six lipsticks are too
like browny nude I also love cream Cup
from Mac this is more of like a very
pinky nude can you even see that okay
well yeah this is creme Cup I love to
put like a lip liner like whirl or I
don't even know which other ones that I
have but I usually use whirl and then I
will like align them with the world and
then put cream Cup on top of it and then
I also love anasazi a Beverly Hills pure
Hollywood that's a really really good
one alright so that is all the questions
I hope you guys really enjoyed this Q&A
video if you guys liked this kind of
video let me know thank you guys so much
for watching I hope you guys really
enjoyed it and we'll see you next time
bye
you
[Music]