hey guys today I will be talking about
growing up Asian American grown up
Filipino American one of my favorite
youtubers Amy Lee aka vagabond youth
created this tag the series of questions
that anyone can answer
I watched her video I watched Jenna's
video it's very interesting to see the
different experiences that she has
versus what I have or what some other
Asian American has I'm gonna go through
these questions talk about my experience
my upbringing and I hope you enjoy
I identify as filipino-american
both my parents immigrated here to
America my dad first arrived in
California my mom in New Jersey and so
being born in America I therefore in
first generation American
so I think my first memory of being a
minority or a different ethnicity as
others in my community growing up I
think it was first grade we were playing
recess we were outside the playground
chasing each other playing Thai then I'm
over on the other side doing gymnastics
with some of the other girls because
that's what I was into and I did a split
and this boy saw me do that and he looks
at me points at me and says really loud
to everyone else the playground the
oldest Chinese girl just did a split and
in my head I was like I'm not Chinese
what and at that age when I would tell
kids that I was Filipino or my parents
were from the Philippines they almost
didn't believe me because I didn't know
it was a country it was easy for people
to pinpoint you as Chinese because when
they don't care to ask what your
ethnicity is they automatically assume
you're Chinese and yes he was a kid he
didn't know at the time but it did
offend me and I remember another time
when I was in Washington DC and this is
when I was pretty young as well I was
with my family visiting from California
and we were there to see the Cherry
Blossom
you know just walk around the city and I
remember we were leaving the parking lot
and going towards this park area by the
river catching this crosswalk and there
was a tour bus right next to us and the
man driving the tour bus who called out
the window to us mining our own business
and he goes Nihao at the time I did not
know that meant hello in Chinese I
didn't know that so I was confused
because I thought he was saying meow
like a like a cat
thinking about this question the first
thing that comes to mind was in
elementary school and it was lunchtime I
used to pack my lunch whatever was left
over for dinner whatever my mom just
packed me I just took my lunchbox from
the table and went to school she likes
to cook traditional Filipino food and I
eat it I like it but as a kid bringing
that type of food to school especially
in elementary school people are going to
smell that the aroma of Asian food just
lingers and in elementary school I hated
the attention the attention that I got
from when I brought food like that
pretend this is my lunch box and it
opens like this I would always have my
lunch box closed and if I wanted a bit
of something to eat I would just stick
my hand slightly like this grab what I
needed and took it out I remember coming
home and refusing to pack my lunch I
didn't want that people would see what
you have for lunch and go you know what
is that and after they say a comment
like that you don't want to eat it even
if it is your favorite dish at home I
think after that instance I just would
buy my lunch I would tell my mom to give
me lunch money even though I didn't
really enjoy the school lunches but that
kept up for a long time of me just buy
my lunch never packing food and I think
that was the first instance of when I
rejected my heritage because of the food
because people saw the food that I
brought to school and didn't like what
they received and so I as a child who
wanted to fit in saw this as a bad thing
I wanted my parents to cook more
American food I wanted my parents to
pack me sandwiches like normal kids
parents would for a long time I was not
proud of who I was because of the
repercussions I got from that my parents
being from the Philippines they had a
pretty thick accent with my friends
growing up would talk to them I would
get nervous because I didn't want them
to make fun of my parents for not
speaking properly or clearly and school
I never brought friends home one because
yeah I was embarrassed by my parents I
was embarrassed by the scent of my home
because I remember one time someone came
into my house and they told me it
smelled like spices I didn't take that
as a good thing I was like oh my
goodness
my house smells like spices I need it
for breeze this place up or something I
just never brought anyone here to hang
out and I barely had people sleep over
because when it was time for dinner my
mom would make her traditional Filipino
food I would like it but I would get
nervous that the people that I brought
to my house would be super picky not
like it would make fun of the food and
so me being so on edge never wanted
anyone to come to my house ever it was
like I was just hiding all of it hiding
everything now I think growing up I'm
definitely more proud to be Filipino my
American I have a background that's
unlike most people's I have a better
understanding for immigrants in America
and what they go through you know
watching my parents hearing their
stories especially my dad hearing him
talk about how he was every job ever
when he first came here he was a janitor
he got stuck in an elevator because he
didn't know how elevators work he went
to nursery school for his associates
started working as a nurse took more
online classes got his bachelor's in
nursing and he went to school as an
engineer in the Philippines he's a smart
man and he worked so hard for what he
has and what he's provided for me and my
siblings I just did not understand
rather I didn't even know about or cared
to know about but now I'm more proud of
where I came from more proud of what my
parents have done to provide for a
better life for me
I own a me video and Jen ends video they
talk about the model minority men which
is something that I think all Asians
struggle with you are put in this high
regard because you are Asian that you
have to be smart especially in math and
science
my parents growing up wanted me to be in
the medical field they wanted me to be a
nurse just like them but I'm just not
good with math and science plus I didn't
want to be a nurse or in the medical
field and I think also running up Asian
we are expected to excel in whatever we
do when you have your report card in
high school and even in college and you
get a B that's like unacceptable
we are just put on this higher standard
because of the race that we were born
into and that can be super super
detrimental another stereotype I
struggle with is the passive Asian woman
I think for me I'm very out there I like
to be bold but I have my own thoughts I
have my own opinions and I own feelings
and it's really difficult for me to want
to even play this passive role another
thing I struggle with that goes along
with people outside of your race and
it's identifying you as another
ethnicity is the fact that we all look
the same now I grew up and a small beach
town in South Jersey and there's a very
very very small Filipino community in
South Jersey so a lot of my mom's
friends at work are Filipino because
there's a small community of Filipinos
people think that we're all related it's
kind of just difficult because other
people think that because you're from
one country that you know everyone in
that country and that's just not true
so the national language in the
Philippines is called Tagalog and the
Spanish rule in the Philippines for over
300 years many words in Tagalog are very
very similar or the same as the Spanish
language and because I was learning
Spanish this past semester I was able to
understand bits and pieces a little bit
better in Tagalog than prior to learning
Spanish
that being said I still don't know
Tagalog and it's kind of difficult
because when I went to the Philippines
about 3 summers ago with my mom we went
to the place where she grew up so I've
cousins their aunts their grandparents
their great aunts whatever me being the
one who didn't speak Tagalog it was very
difficult to communicate with my family
members they knew a little bit of
English and they would speak to me but
it wouldn't be a full in-depth
conversation I'd probably be like one
question or two and then they'd go back
turn us someone else and start talking
Tagalog and while we were there my
cousins who have been learning English
in school didn't want to talk to me for
the longest time we were only there for
two weeks and they kinda were just
avoiding me especially in the beginning
because I think they were just
embarrassed to speak English and to
practice their English with me so I
think it's just being my mom and I there
and me not having the support of my
other siblings I didn't talk a lot
dirty' not sure and it seems funny but
it's very hard when you want to
communicate with your relatives
especially those from another country
you want to hear what it's like you want
to hear their experience their stories
but when they don't want to talk to you
or even try talking to you it's very
hard
so along with the language barrier I
think there's also language barrier with
my parents now they'd been in America
for years they speak to God look at home
to each other and sometimes when they're
telling stories to each other they tell
it in Tagalog and sometimes I'm curious
and I want to know what they're saying
so I go mom what did you say and
sometimes she registers that I'm asking
me for asking her what she said so she
repeats in to God look I said no in
English and I feel because there is that
language barrier you're not fully
communicating and I think for me
learning that communication is very
important it's just difficult when your
parent just prefer to speak in Tagalog
but you were never taught that you were
never brought up speaking to God their
reasoning behind it was that they didn't
want us to have the accent that they had
grown up here and they didn't want our
accent learning Tagalog to interfere
with us learning English in addition
growing up in an Asian household you
don't really have a strong communication
in the first place a lot of Asian people
are more enclosed into themselves so I
don't have those deep conversations with
my parents also not realizing what
they've been through
coming here growing up in the
Philippines raising us here in America
it's all different growing up American
in an Asian household and when your
relationship with your parents do not
align with the relationship of your
friends with their parents you kind of
started getting upset and questioning
things why aren't we that close because
of language barriers maybe because of
the fact that Asians are a lot of the
times to themselves
now I am 20 years old I've definitely I
think since coming to college I've
wanted to explore that side of me more I
am nowhere near where I want to be with
my heritage now but I'm working on it
I'm growing on it and I recognize now
that it is something to be super proud
of what I want is to see in general more
Asian Americans being represented
because we are freaking awesome let me
just tell you that I get the best of
both worlds all the food you could ever
imagine and I have this strong
background being Filipino and the rich
history
like I said the food you got egg rolls
and you got hamburgers my favorite thing
about being asian-american is also the
pride I feel like there is that pride to
be both Filipino and American can be
Filipino in a competition in the UK and
your face will be on the Filipino
channel because that's how much pride
they have for their people whether you
were born in the Philippines or not and
just some closing remarks closing
thoughts on me talking about growing up
Asian American in honor of Asian Pacific
Heritage Month I not only wanted to do
this before talk about being a Filipino
American I wanted to also just in
general celebrate me celebrate how far
I've come in this journey of this
feeling of rejecting everything that I
am because I was born American I grew up
in America there may be some disconnect
from me and the Philippines just because
I wasn't born there doesn't mean I
shouldn't feel the pride and show the
support that I have for this country
where my ancestors my parents everyone
before me grew up was raised I hope you
enjoyed that you learned a little bit
about me I will put Amy's and Jenn's
video down below go check that out you
all have very different yet at points
very similar experiences and maybe this
is just a topic you've never thought
about and this isn't an ad or anything
but I just want to end with this one
statement that there is a movie coming
out it looks really good I watched the
trailer it's called crazy rich Asians
it's an entire cast of Asians and it
looks like a very good rom-com I think
it comes out in August that information
will also be in the description below
but but thanks so much for watching if
you enjoyed this please give it a thumbs
up let me know what you thought down in
the comments if you wanted to answer
some of these questions concerning your
background your ethnicity please do so
I'll read it I'll comment or just make
an entire video with these questions
with your experience thanks so much for
watching and I hope to see you all in
the next
you
[Music]