freshly brewed vanilla caramel black tea
I don't even want to put this welcome to
the first installment of here's the tea
my vlogs do a really good job of
highlighting the ups and hiding the pits
and the Falls of college and life in
general recently I watched Timmy
Lovato's documentary it's free on
YouTube if you haven't watched it and I
totally recommend one of the first line
she says in her documentary is in order
to be happy you have to speak your truth
and I really took that to heart because
I'm one of those people who really wants
to speak their truth and I had this
platform that you're watching me on
currently where I have the opportunity
to showcase my life as a temple student
and to show you what an average day
average weekend whatever is like for me
and from all the people that I've met on
campus and just commenting on my videos
a lot of people tell me that I'm one of
the reasons why they came to Temple or
they chose temple and that to me is very
overwhelming sometimes like I would say
thank you I would say that's so sweet of
you but when I actually had the chance
to sit down and think about that and
actually process that people watch my
videos to see if they would like it here
and you don't see an everyday life of a
student when you go on a tour to college
which is one of the factors why I wanted
to make this channel why I wanted to
start vlogging in college but the main
reason why I wanted to start vlogging is
just reminisce because College like
everyone says goes by super fast and I'm
almost halfway done college like that's
mind-blowing to me but these vlogs are
always showing what's good because I
want to look back in like five ten years
from now after I graduate
maybe what I even have kids and I'm like
wow I was a weird child I was a wild
teen it's great that I enjoyed this and
I'm vlogging because I like it
and I'm continuing vlogging because I
like it but I think something that will
be beneficial to not only me mentally
but to other people looking to come to
Temple or just go to college in general
or just seeing the transition from high
school to leaving your hometown and
going to a different state I think
something that will be beneficial is if
I started serious like this and I became
a bit more vulnerable with you and
talked about more serious issues and
maybe even just serious global issues
and just issues in general because as a
college student I found that people
become more aware and I love temple
because it is such an open environment
everyone's so friendly
and it's a sense of community when
you're there and you feel the need to
take action and participate because this
is your life and as a college student I
think we have to be woke about issues
like that and so I want to talk about it
but I want to be more open and I feel
like I think about this in all the
videos that I make I want to be more
open be more vulnerable I want to give
you insight on me I feel like I have a
lot to say but I never think I have the
right words to say them so hopefully
when I go back to edit videos like this
then it makes sense that I am saying
what I want to say and saying it clearly
and effectively I brought this idea up
to a few people and they seem to like it
a few months ago I was interviewed by
this girl for a class project she
contacted me asking me to get
interviewed about she's first which is
one of the organizations I'm involved
with on campus I met with her at the
Student Center and we chatted we had a
really nice conversation and she started
asking me questions about she's the
first then she started asking me
questions about my YouTube channel and
one of the questions she asked was
something along the lines of if I'm
going to use my platform on YouTube to
be an activist and to take action and to
just have a discussion about issues that
matter and I've always had this video
idea in my head a few months ago as well
I came up with this series title here's
the tea and I think it fits because
there's a lot that I have gone through
that I would like to talk about but but
I'm too afraid to do that
it's because I'm afraid of being
vulnerable but I am the type of person
to challenge myself and that kind of
includes being more open because I think
it's not a sign of weakness I think it's
more of a sign that you know who you are
and you're willing to share that with
the rest of the world even though like I
don't even know how many people are
gonna watch this but for me I think it's
beneficial selfishly because I need to
release the inner thoughts in my head
some way shape or form and sometimes we
do that through journaling sometimes I
do that through talking to myself but
those two things by itself alone do not
satisfy my need to just say all this
information and to let people know about
all this information that's in my head
cuz I have a lot to say and a lot of
that is not shown in vlogs because my
vlogs are mostly live like what I'm
doing I tell you what I'm doing then and
then now a lot of it's not what's in my
head and a lot of things are in my head
and so it has resulted in the birth of
this series which I'm really excited to
start I feel like this was more of like
an intro video I have a lot
if more more specific topics to indulge
myself in and just talk about also I
really wish I had a cuter mug at home
this is just a plain simple dark brown
bug all my cute ones are in my door and
back attempt oh this is just sad
so sad side note before I go let me know
what kind of topics you want me to talk
about I know I have my own issues that I
want to touch on but if there's anything
that college related or if there's
anything I don't know you can think of
that you think I would do a good job
talking about please let me know in the
comments below
cool
[Music]