hi everyone um my name is diana
and welcome to my channel if you are new
uh so to start off um i
will be talking about uh what it was
like to grow up as a venus canadian here
and my experiences and observations
uh will vary from different
uh vietnamese canadians like of course
there are similarities and commonalities
um but here are some of the things that
i like to share
so to start off i am a first generation
canadia a vietnamese canadian
so meaning that my parents are
immigrants to canada
um my mother is from
the central vietnam and she came here
when she was approximately 26 years old
and my father came here when he was
in his early 30s they met in
toronto uh and then prior to
relocating and they got married um and
then relocated to
edmonton um so one of the
most common uh questions that i receive
is if i am able to speak
uh read and or write um it read in
vietnamese
and i would say this answer is yes um
it's just that the diff my proficiency
and comprehension level
like i can comprehend 100 um
so in regards to speaking i can speak
fluently
um like i understand fluently
reading i'm i would say an intermediate
level
and uh for writing it's still very basic
and i wish that i could
write better so that's the skill that i
want to
improve over um
the course of my lifetime um
[Music]
so i would say like the alphabet uh the
vegans alphabet is really
similar like the characters are really
similar to the western alphabet
um it's just a couple are different uh
we use a lot of
accents in the in the in
the sentence structure um
like and then i would say like the
reason being like why
the vietnamese alphabet is kind of
that uses kind of like western uh
characters is because uh the french
colonization
um so like before like the characters
used to be kind of like almost like
uh like chinese or japanese characters
as well like a long time ago
um so like even when we speak some words
um sound the same in
in french so for example the word
yogurt if you listen to the
pronunciation of yogurt in french
the pronunciation of yogurt and
vietnamese
it sounds almost exactly the same it's
just the pronounce or
the spelling of course is different
um so my vietnamese name
is yim mi um
so that means in english grace um and
then oftentimes what i also get
is if i'm able to translate my friends
names into
vietnamese and it's really difficult to
do so unless
um unless uh
like you were born or given a vietnamese
name
um i would and then also
in vietnamese cuisine like vietnamese
culture and heritage there
is a lot like a diverse like amount of
food like a lot of food
my top like i would say top three or
four i would say
is um bun sale
so that's kind of like a vietnamese
crepe
slash pancake it has like a
mung bean exterior and then it has
lettuce tomatoes
shrimp in it and sometimes bean sprouts
as well
and then people dip it in fish sauce and
it's really good
uh my second one uh would be bun me
so that's like a vietnamese like um
submarine
uh so they use like like a freshly baked
uh baguette
and then they have cilantro cucumbers
pickled carrots jalapenos and a cold cut
meat and then they also have like a pork
pate
and then um like a mayo
that's uh kind of mixed
or beaten like um egg yolks egg yolks
um and then also my favorite drink is
um cafe soda which is the vietnamese
iced coffee and it's
it comes out of like a like a french
press uh
machine almost and it's with condensed
milk or poured over ice and it's really
refreshing
in the summertime um
so also like one thing in the vietnamese
household that you'll always find
is fish sauce uh fish sauce is like
used in almost every savory dish that we
have in
vietnamese culture and it's really uh
like it tastes really delicious but
if it spills on you it's like i'll make
you stink the whole day
um it's so delicious though and then um
let's see uh in vietnamese culture we
also have like
if you enter vietnamese household like
you'll find like a lot of buddhas as
well
um we have like shrines and stuff where
um for elders that have passed away
and we also have buddhas there as well
at like in her home
um oh and i also forgot to mention about
like vietnamese language um in the
vietnamese language there is
um i'll say a couple dialects in there
um so like from south
uh central and north like there will be
different dialects
like you could really tell like if
you're like from outside
uh like if you're a westerner you can
really
recognize it or notice the difference
um and then um
because like when you're from the north
of vietnam like the accent from the
dialect is
thicker um and then also like certain
words like
of course like there'll be different
work uh different
um different words for the same thing
depending on the region that you're from
but like vietnamese people can
understand which dialect
and they can recognize which part of the
country that you're from so it's really
interesting it's not like
like um it's not that we can't
understand each other like all the
dialects have the same language
like we use like a common language it's
um
uh like i wouldn't say it's
like 100 different it's
varied um
and then uh so my experience growing up
it was
i would say it was fairly good um my
parents provided
like with us with all the necessary
things that we needed
and um i would say like
um growing up there's like a culture
clash
um a little bit uh so because like
i'm raised in a western society a
western culture
you could really say that
when i come home like my parents will
say oh you're so
uh you're so may or that means like
you're too westernized
um and then but when i'm with my friends
like they view me as
being vietnamese or being asian uh which
i am
but like um sometimes like if you don't
have a strong sense of self
it can really make you confused about
who you are
as a person and your identity like or am
i canadian
or in my vietnamese um so i like at the
end of the day
i feel like if you're from a different
culture if you're from a different
ethnic background
it's really important to uh take pride
in your culture because
that's that in reality that's who you
are
and you should not be ashamed um
because i feel like so a lot of people
that have dreaming cultures they
sometimes feel ashamed
and you shouldn't um
and then um i feel like also
like um a lot of times like when you're
first generation
like of any ethnicity or culture
sometimes
you when you're young you kind of want
to assimilate
[Music]
into western society and you lose your
language and
you feel that you should have to only
speak english
and to only follow um
like western culture i feel like in a
sense that's kind of
wrong and because then that way you lose
also your identity as well
um a sense of who you are and your you
lose your heritage and your culture
um like i mean you have to respect other
people's culture too but
don't try to become what you're not is
what i'm trying to say
um and then
um because like i really like growing up
i realized that was wrong too
and um like now i'm so
i'm so proud to be vietnamese i'm really
proud of
my heritage i'm really proud that i'm
able to
kind of uh read write and i'm able to
communicate to members of my culture
that aren't
able to speak english and i
am really proud that i am able to like
recognize different dishes
of my culture um in a pre like it's the
small things that you appreciate
um some of the vietnamese stereotypes
that we get from our culture
is that we either um
own or work at a meal salon which is
kind of
um which is kind of funny um
and then another stereotype that we get
a lot
is that we like to gamble
um so another
thing about vietnamese culture is that
the food
is so diverse um so one of the main
like or one of the popular dishes that
western society
um recognizes is uh
so that's uh spelled as p-h-o um and
there's
obviously some accents to that as well
um
so that's kind of like a vietnamese um
rice noodle soup
uh with like a beef broth um you can eat
it with a poison sauce
and also like a spicy um
spicy sauce as well a sriracha sauce
um i'm sure you guys know what that is
um and then
also for traditional wear or traditional
dress
in vietnamese culture is the it's ow
so it's spelt a o
d a i um and of course there are accents
to that as well
um so i have one um just speaking of
it um so this one i
bought when i went to vietnam with my
family
so traditionally like you like people
wear this
um like i like i would say it depends
also on the region because
the region of vietnam like different
regions of vietnam will have different
styles of aoi
so depending if you work on the farm as
a rice farmer
or if you're in central vietnam and also
your social class so
the beating and everything can be
different so this one i bought
um about eight nine years ago or
ten years ago like that's been that's
was the last time i was in vietnam
so yeah so it goes like this and it has
kind of like a slit
in the leg right here
so that's a slit and then um you would
wear like kind of like a silk
silk pants underneath uh just depending
um on the shade
or on the color of like the the actual
dress itself you would wear matching
silk pants underneath
okay and then depending on how formal
you are and how formal like
a formal the place that you're attending
or where you're going
you can wear like a headpiece as well
so that's how it looks
okay
and then um so like normally in
vietnamese weddings as well like
like the traditional wedding dress i
would say is white
or sorry red with the white pants
underneath
and some like really elaborate uh gold
design so it's really beautiful
um like and then our dress is similar
like
to chinese culture as well so like the
traditions like
we have it's kind of like a mix because
we had we're called we were calling that
like the country itself was colonized by
the french
um and then another thing i'd like to
mention is
um like the last time i visited
vietnam was with my family in 2010
um we went there for about two two weeks
almost
and it was like an amazing experience
um i believe i was about 14 or 15 at the
time
uh 15 16 yeah around that age
and um it was i would say
like a culture shock like even though i
am a vietnamese
descent and a vietnamese heritage
i still grew up in a western society in
a western culture
so like like going there like i was able
to of course like
speak it uh with like the individuals
there
the people there and i was able to
connect with my like my own
like culture and that aspect but like
the way of living in the standard living
was
completely different like the way
everything is structured
the infrastructure like one of my
favorite things about visiting vietnam
was
um of course like the street food
that was like amazing and like the
beaches
it was also amazing as well like like it
can't compare to here
like obviously here is like a lot more
cleaner
and things are a lot more like i would
say efficient
in the way that things are operating but
the culture
there the vibe it's really energetic
really fun um like and i'm sure
things have changed right now like the
technology in regards to technology
um like even maybe cleanliness has
changed a lot as well
um so like definitely i like to go back
and visit it
at the country um and
um yeah so like
i feel like now like i feel like i have
a lot of more
confidence in the way that i approach
things being vietnamese than canadian
like be having a strong sense of
identity and individuality um
like one of the main things that
vietnamese people have or like
asian countries i had is having strong
strong family ties so like being more of
a like
collect country while here like in
canada it's
more individualistic um
so like we have like as a vietnamese
person i have like
like um like
this mindset of having gratitude is a
lot stronger
so you're really grateful for what your
parents have done to you
you're really like you're really close
to your fam family ties
and you always try to grow together as a
unit um
and um like when i was like like this is
like kind of almost like a con almost
but like a common pro at the same time
um is like that we try to please and
seek approval
of our parents a lot and sometimes that
can
like um can i
i wouldn't say uh really
uh like like of course like everybody is
like their own ident like their own
individual a person but
sometimes a person coming from an asian
household we try to please
our parents a lot and we try to make
them happy we seek
their approval a lot and sometimes our
own identity can get lost
so that's kind of also a cultural clash
as well because um
being like being even though i'm
vietnamese canadian i'm not truly a
vietnamese like i'm
i'm still vietnamese but like like
like there's a mindset and the values
are diff really different because
being vietnamese canadian sometimes
you go after your passions and stuff
like that while if you were true like
uh full-blown vietnamese living in
vietnam
you would follow like the family
traditions like if a
family has a family business like you
you carry that on for generations and
generations while here it's more
individualistic
um so
like at the end of the day it's
important to embrace who you are
um as a vietnamese canadian well i try
to
embrace my culture culture and heritage
as much as i can into my daily lives
um but at the same time i have to
also uh respect my own values and how i
grew up as well as
a canadian um so there's like it's like
a lot of compromise
in respect to that like pleasing my
parents as well as pleasing my own
desires of what i want in life my own
passions
um yeah so thank you for
watching that's all i have for today and
i hope to see you next time
thank you