are you pregnant oh my god
relationship status you're in my
business
yeah don't do that
[Music]
hey y'all welcome to my channel it's
finally here you guys have been asking
me for so
long to drop a youtube video on my
channel that i've been have made for
like what two years
now well the wait is
over and i'm gonna be dropping videos we
gonna find a program but
i'm let y'all know i'm here and i'm here
to stay
and we gonna go
what and we're gonna go
head first with this okay i can promise
y'all there's gonna be so much more to
come so much girl
talks so many vlogs so many get ready
with me
so many hauls just a whole bunch of
stuff anything y'all want to see i'm
down to record
and post for y'all this video is going
to be a q a
get to know me i'm answering the
questions that i normally probably
wouldn't answer
on live or in the dms or in the comments
section
so this is your guys's opportunity to
really get the team to get into
it to get to know joe and i outside of
blazing so here i have
31 questions that you guys
asked me out of like hundreds of
questions
but i just feel like these are the ones
that will help y'all get to know me the
best
and maybe in the next video i'll answer
like the other
questions that has to do with like my
personal life and my relationship
life but this one i just wanted to give
y'all
an opportunity to know jonah and not
malaysian
let's get into this video right now
so the first question is how old are you
what's your sign and when is your
birthday
so i just turned 22 years old my
birthday is september 15
1998 and i am a
virgo no cocky [ __ ] i feel like burgers
is the best sign
like if i wasn't even a virgo i would
still say virgos is the best sign
because what like beyonce's a virgo
queen of b
is a virgo
okay question number two
are you still in school and what school
do you go to i am currently enrolled as
a senior at ucla this is my
last year thank god
um yeah so i'm still in school i'm doing
it online because of rona
but i just want to walk the stage
honestly i don't care where i'm doing
school from just as long as i get to
walk that stage in june
and do my little this little cross
stitch i'm good
question number three any advice for
high schoolers or college advice
um let me think back to when i was in
high school because that
was a really long time ago i graduated
in 2016
but i personally did not take high
school serious at all
um freshman year i had straight a's i
was like
real good kids sophomore and junior
definitely worked hard and they kept
my butt senior year i picked up
the slack and my grades was good just
like freshman year
but i feel like colleges really look at
your
sophomore and junior year grades not so
much your freshman or your senior year
um and that's where like i got that
and so with the grades that i had in my
overall gpa i just knew i wasn't going
to be able to go to like berkeley or
ucla
all the top schools that i would hope to
have went to
so i chose the route of going to a
junior college for two years
i went to de anza community college i
play basketball for them too
but i went to danza community college
for two years and then i reapplied to
colleges
after the two years and i ended up
getting into ucla
high school advice i would definitely
say
take your grades seriously like
if you don't want to go to a jc for two
years and you want to go straight
out of high school take high school
seriously
but also make time for your social life
so you have to find a balance between
your social life and your school life
um me i was more of just like social
life so
i was an athlete i was just you know
wanted to
play ball and all that
but i went to an all asian school so it
was a lot of pressure on the students
that went there because
not stereotyping not trying to be racist
or nothing but
asians are known to take schooling more
serious you know so i would definitely
say
do work hard but
find a balance again between schoolwork
and your social life because you have to
have both there you can't just have a
school life and no social life whereas
you're gonna go crazy advice for
college college my first two years
of community college was so fun because
i don't know when i went to college
i was expecting it to be a heavy
workload i'm gonna be stressed out it's
gonna be so many classes so much
going on because i was playing
basketball too so i was like there's no
way i'm gonna be able to juggle this
but i did really well my first two years
of college while i was still playing
ball um i made so many new friends like
all the athletes were in the same class
so y'all can imagine just a whole
classroom full of
football players basketball players
baseball players soccer players like
it was lit okay
but that was good because you're
surrounded by people who
know what you're going through what
you're experiencing having a juggle
okay i got a game this day but i got a
midterm and final this day too like you
know
we were all like in cahoots with
each other like supporting each other
through the whole
class and that was really good
advice for college so when i got to ucla
i really didn't
make friends like i was making at a jc
like
it was a whole different ballgame for me
a new environment i'm
originally from the bay area so i moved
down to southern california
la to go to school and i knew nobody
there i knew one girl that's from
vallejo california which is like
30 minutes from me um and she was going
to you see she got into ucla as well
and that was like the only person i was
kind of hanging out with we had so many
classes together
like that destiny if you ever watch
this shout out to you because girl you
helped me a lot
but that was the only person that i
really know uh when we would go to
parties i'd just go with destiny and her
friends like i never
made friends outside of destiny except
for one and her name was cheyenne
cheyenne if you ever watch this i miss
you and i love you
we fell off on some like weak [ __ ]
but girl come
and those two people really helped me my
daily routine considered me like going
to class coming back to my dorm
studying i would step out
every now and then to like do laundry or
go grab something from the cafe but most
of the time like
i was door dashing through my jar my
parents were
paying thousands of dollars for like the
food
slash meal program and i was not
utilizing it
i had so many swipes left like when i
left ucla
and came back home because of corona i
had so many swipes left
it was bad oh and another tip
or not tip but college advice
save your money while you are in school
that is so
important like i wouldn't say i depended
on my parents a lot while i was in
school because i was still making my own
money
but it's really important to save save
save that money like if you have parents
that are going to support you and pay
for your schooling and your books and
all that be appreciated because i
know a lot of people whose parents are
more so like oh no
like you're making money you go pay for
your books and college books is like 200
of 150 a book
so save your money if you can question
number four how did i get into ucla
i kind of talked about this already but
i got into ucla
after doing two years at a community
college in my city
um i had really good grades i worked
really really hard
um utilize your college counselors my
counselor louise
she helped me so
much like i didn't know how to apply for
colleges i'm thinking i'm gonna have to
write
so many essays so many you
know about means and why i should get
accepted and it's not i didn't have to
do
none of that it was simply just like
filling out paperwork
boo boom but touching your parents
income you know whatever it is
boop send it off and she really really
helped me because i ended up being
um i ended up being behind on some
credits
which caused me to stay like an extra
two quarters at the answer
so i ended up really being there for
three years two and a half three years
taking the last quarter off then
transferring that following square
so she helped me get back on track you
know i changed my major
i think what two times originally no
three
times originally i was a um
kinesiology major then i switched to a
psychology major then i
finally went to sociology
and i really love it um so yeah
utilize your college counselors they
really help
what's my dream career i originally
wanted to be a lawyer have my own law
firm
law firm i originally wanted to study
criminal law
or business law because that's really
this is always where the money is
criminal law i say that because i like
to watch first 48 csi
beyond scare strength all of that like i
could really sit there and watch it
all day so i've been going back and
forth between those
two divisions of law
but now being who i am with this big
following on social media i want to see
where i can go
with instagram whether that be modeling
or working with bigger businesses or
boutiques or
even youtube you know it's no telling
where i go with this youtube stuff if i
really keep adding like i plan to
okay we're not going to be slaving
getting that bag we finna get that bag
doing what we love to do and i love
taking pictures for you i love talking
to y'all
so do i want kids if so how many
yes i want kids i want five kids
i want more boys than girls um i just
love
boy i didn't just could see myself as a
boy mom
it was weird because before like i got
older i always
said no i want girls like you know
everybody's like i don't know i want
girls i want to be able to do her hair
no because i know how i am and having
more than one me is going to stress me
out
i want to be a boy mom but of course i
want like one or two daughters
question number seven do you speak any
other languages other than
english yes i speak mandarin mandarin
was actually my first
language my mom is from taiwan my dad is
from chicago
growing up i didn't learn english until
i started grade school so
here i am this little mixed baby didn't
know in liquor english
and was just speaking mandarin i was
often the translator between like
because my great-grandma raised me and
she didn't know english so
the only way for me to talk to her was
to speak mandarin
so i didn't start learning english until
i started
maybe kindergarten first grade question
number eight
what is your nationality like i said my
mom is from taiwan my dad is from
chicago
i am therefore chinese and black
hence blasian you know the only one
don't play with her
she's not one of them number nine what
do you look for in a boyfriend
this is like hard because if y'all look
at my track
record with the dudes that i have dated
y'all are gonna be like
there's no way like this like but no
like
i like a gentleman i like somebody who
asked me about my dad who's not just oh
for themselves i like somebody
who's selfless who who
acts as my protector who genuinely loves
me for me
not just trying to be around because of
who i am or what i have to offer or what
i got or what i could
get for them or the position i could put
them in i just want somebody who loves
me
for joe and i and not blazing
to say the least i could go on and on
forever about this but we're just gonna
keep it short and sweet
what's your favorite color my favorite
color is pink
not the hot pink not the bright pink the
baby
soft pink like the very light blush pink
question 11 what is your favorite
designer brand
i am a designer junkie like
i love expensive stuff um
i love gucci i really am so in love with
chanel
i like prada um
versace is cool davinci is cool
um i'm trying to think offlight is cool
but
i think my favorite brand really is
chanel
like them sneakers yeah
what question 12 how do you save money
this is hard because i spend so
much money like
it's done but what i
used to do is before i started getting
that
big bag what i used to do was when i
would get paid
i would put half of my check
in my savings and then like half of my
check it was
to spend so it might not be half it
might be
majority of my check went to my savings
and i would keep like 100 or
hundred dollars for me to spend and i
did that every paycheck and i wasn't
really spending then
so like if you have two hundred dollars
and say your checkings and then your
next check you put it under two hundred
dollars it starts stacking nothing sorry
is so money so you got some money in
your checkings
but you also got some money in your
savings you got to do it like that
and if you can't buy something let's say
five times over don't buy it once and
this doesn't go for like
your dream house or a car that you want
or whatever
this goes for like the materialistic
designer things the
the non-essential
things question number 13 where are you
from i kind of answered this already but
i am from the bay area
california yeah that way
question number 14 what is your real
name my real name is jonai
j-o-n-a-i a lot of people pronounce it
like joe nae
or joanie no joe nye
question number 15 how do you keep your
skin looking so clear and glowing
um i every morning i wake up
and i wash my face with hot water first
then i grab
like my sarah v survey
however you want to say it it's like the
green bottle green and white bottle
facial cleanser rub it put it on my face
rub it rub rub it rinse it off and wipe
it with a face
towel then i take like
i have some face oil serum and i just
put a few droplets on my face and i just
rub it in
and that's really it um other than that
i eat a lot of fruits i like
i eat a lot of fruits i drink a lot of
water
when when you make healthier life
decisions and life choices you start to
look better you glow better
you glow different this that [ __ ]
glow period very
very inferior okay
yeah don't play question number 16 how
did i gain
followers um
so it's a long story but i'm gonna cut
it short for y'all
so i was basically in a relationship for
five years with my first boyfriend ever
when we broke up i literally started
just taking pictures on instagram
and i started blowing up like 40k
50k and then
y'all might know i
talked to a rapper by the name of
nba young boy for a little
minute for for a while actually it's
just
i had to keep it on the low low because
i don't do all that media stuff
but i talked to the rapper and be a
young boy and from there it just like
boom like took off question number 17.
how did i meet
nelly
i met bryson on instagram
before he really was in le like
he was in italy but he wasn't nowhere
like how he
is now question number 18 how tall am i
i am for
my
real short question number 19 what are
your goals in life i kind of answered
this already but
i want to get married i want to have a
family i want to have my own business i
just want to be
rich like rich in health and rich in
wealth just overall rich i want
just so many things for myself for my
family for those around me
who love me genuinely and
i just want i just want to be happy
doing what i love
to do question number 20 relationship
status
you're in my business yeah don't do that
i am currently talking to somebody
y'all might know y'all might not
um but he goes by the name
of double r gmk
he is from florida
y'all might have seen us on the shade
room or whatever it is
but that is my birthday
question number 21 was who is the new
man in your life i just answered that
with the other question
question number 22 how did you meet jmk
so
it's weird how god works because
i'm not even going to say his real name
because then he's going to be so upset
with me
but i he see me like
a while ago before i was really big how
i am now
on instagram but at that time he was in
a relationship i think at that time i
was
too um but he was like i've been pichu
like i've been told my bros like she is
so
fun like i want her this isn't that
and it was like one day i was on the
explorer page or
somebody i follow i guess had reposted a
picture of him
and g9 and i had sent it to my friend me
and i was like girl like he is so
cute like you know not even knowing that
she knew him or went to high school with
him
but i had dmd her the picture i'm like
girl he's so cute she was like
oh that's whoopi whoa like i went to
high school with him i'm like
shut up she was like no you want me to
dm him for you
and me being who i am i was like yeah
i'm not gonna dm him like
i'm not gonna get left on scene or i'm
not even gonna give
somebody an opportunity to be like oh
y'all i guess we'll dm me like look what
but
no so she dm'd him
and long story short he dm me like
what's up and i just went from there
question number 23
are you pregnant really [ __ ]
no i'm not no i'm not
question number 24 what's your major how
many degrees will you have would you
graduate
um my major i am a sociology major and i
will have two degrees when i graduate in
the spring
um i will have my associate's degree and
a bachelor's degree in
sociology 25 long-term and short-term
goals i kind of already answered that so
i'm not even going to say it again
26 how many tattoos do you have a most
painful tattoo
in piercing so i have one
two three four
five six six tattoos
my most painful tattoo was my back
i thought like my bones were breaking it
hurt so bad
piercings i have about 24 and
majority of them are in my ears i don't
know if y'all can see
but they're in my ears and then here
my belly my lip
right there my most painful piercing was
definitely my
my nipples my nipples hurt so bad like
it felt like somebody chewed my nipple
off
question number 27 what is next for me
i'm dropping my clothing line my
sweat suit brand t-shirts all of that i
have dropped like some sneak peeks on my
instagram
if you haven't seen them go check them
out they're in my highlights under ceo
but those are coming like end of this
month soon
like real soon um
again this youtube that i just started
that's next for me as
well and i have a lash business that i
just launched
um underscore blatant wigs on instagram
go cut you some lashes these are from my
lash line in the style hot girl
but yeah it's a lot of things coming
from me
from me fourth quarter gotta finish this
year strong
2021 is definitely gonna be my year i'm
going up
and that's just day question number 28
how do you feel about the hate that you
receive regarding your love life
i honestly do not care because at the
end of the day i'm probably not going to
meet
half of y'all let alone a handful of
y'all so
i don't let what other people say affect
me and how i feel about myself or how i
view myself and those who truly
know me and love me and are around me on
a daily basis
on a daily basis don't care what
somebody who doesn't know me has to say
like they know the real me y'all don't
know the real me
y'all only know what is out there on the
media y'all don't know the real story
behind
all the tea that you see or any of this
so i don't really let
the hay get to me i don't read comments
on instagram i simply go on there
post my pictures work and get off like i
don't sit up there and scroll
through the shade room or scroll through
my post looking at people talking about
oh this is you you're a weird like what
you can't tell me i'm ugly because i
know i'm not ugly
and your boyfriend doesn't think i'm
ugly either so
stop the cat no kizzy
but in all seriousness serious mess
i don't let any of that faze me i don't
let it bother me
because at the end of the day it doesn't
stop a bag
over here like me and mine we straight
worry about you and yours sleeping on
that air mattress with roaches in your
house
question 29 what is your favorite thing
about yourself
i think my favorite thing about myself
is
i have multiple things my personality
one
i'm just super outgoing i'm funny i'm
chill like i don't really take nothing
serious
i don't really let anything bother me
and then i would have to say like
the tough skin that i have developed
over time i've never
always i've never always had
tough skin like i do now but being
placed in the position that i am
in today that
god has placed me in it has taught me
to brush things off to not listen to the
haters
to not let somebody's opinion or how
they feel about me
affect me because at the end of the day
one monkey don't stop the show the show
must go on
perry question number 30 how did you get
famous i kind of already answered this
already
but we're not going to go into too much
detail on that
just now like
and question number 31 what do i do for
fun i like to go shopping i like to
travel i'm traveling a lot all the time
whether it be
do you stand and stay at chloe's house
or my hearing me or
you know whatever and i'm so blessed to
be able to get up and go when i want to
go
um a lot of people aren't fortunate
fortunate enough to get up from their
job and go
travel the world and do what they want
to do for two weeks three weeks a month
so for me to be able to do that i'm so
thankful and i'm so grateful
but what i like to do for fun i like to
go shopping i like to travel
i like to netflix and chill i'm not
really a go out party type person
like that anymore but don't get me wrong
i'll still turn up
every now and then i'll still turn up
but it turned down a little bit a little
bit just this much
but yeah like i like to have a good time
i like to go out for drinks
just chill like i like
i don't know it's like i'm calm like you
know
thank you guys for tuning in to my first
youtube video
if you like this video thumbs up it
like comment subscribe and turn on your
notifications so you know when
the next video is dropping because i'm
about to hit y'all with like
i must hit y'all with videos like this
like
out of nowhere y'all gonna be like whoa
whoa whoa she dropped another video oh
my god oh my god okay
go stop it yeah that's the end of my q a
i hope you all i hope this helped you
guys
get to know me a little more get to know
joe and i a little more outside ablation
like i said
and let me know what video y'all would
like to see
from me next bye y'all
[Music]