hi children my name is cameron cao
welcome back to my channel
and if you're new here consider
subscribing watch my other videos and we
can have a fun time together
well except for it now this is kind of
serious or this is very serious
um to me this topic is extremely
hard to talk about because with the
current political climate
and everything that's going on right now
i personally feel
very heartbroken to see
all the hate and stigma against
you know just asians in general and it's
just really heartbreaking to see that
and i thought because even if i have
just
like my channel is like extremely tiny
like not even 100 subscribers but
if i just can at least get out a small
like
word or something
that can spread the message and hope we
can come to a mutual understanding
and work to become better in the future
i hope i can do that
i just think that with all the things
like
last year with black lives matter and
then now everything that's going on with
in the asian community
i think it's really important that we as
people of color poc should at least
learn also have a mutual understanding
of each other's pain and struggles and
not go against each other or
try to compare each other when we all
have
our own different struggles and everyone
has their own experiences to tell and
stuff like that
i just hope that this video will be able
to at least if you
or someone you know has these types of
opinions or negative opinions or stigmas
against other races and
people of color maybe this video will
help you at least understand our point
of view
and stuff like that i personally can't
also deny i have my own stigmas against
other races and stuff like that growing
up in an asian family obviously they're
going to be stereotypes that your
parents always tell you
i think most asian kids growing up with
like you know
uh parents that are immigrants that came
from around the vietnam war korean war
stuff like that
can understand this like with you know
my mom is always telling me oh
don't go near mexicans or don't go near
indian stuff like that when it's really
just
people just living their lives and of
course there's a bad seed in every
single race
it's not like it's because you're white
doesn't automatically make you a white
supremacist
or something like that it's just with
the type of stigma it's really hard for
people to break it since it's such a
generalized thing
and stereotype among other people and i
hope i'm
i hope i make sense because i've never
been that much of a person to speak out
on certain issues i'm more of a person
who like
does things quietly like for me i during
black lives matter i never really posted
anything on my instagram never really
spread too much of awareness
i did things more quietly like i would
just donate secretly or
would uh sign petitions and stuff like
that or have conversations with people
but i never went out of my way to do
anything like that which i
severely regret and i wish i did more
considering now what's happening with
asians i
now generally understand that i should
have done more
now that i see my people my own
community suffering
and that's hard i really understand and
i hope people can also come to that
realization
i get though some people don't want to
post things because you know
political things sometimes people i know
a lot of people have ruined their
relationships
over political topics and stuff like
that and it's just
with that type of climate it's really
hard to like really speak out about it
because you're afraid of the judgment
you're gonna get
because you can't please anybody or you
can't please everybody
you're either going to please one party
and lose once person or you're going to
praise that person and then end up
losing a whole other
group of people so i'm just going to
begin off with my personal experiences
if that is okay
i this day before i'm vietnamese
american i was
born in june 2004 or june 13
2004 and i was raised here in southern
california and if you didn't know
southern california or specifically the
oc area
has a large vietnamese population i was
lucky enough to grow up in that area
of oc where there's a lot of asians and
vietnamese people i went to an
elementary school that
had mainly only asian kids so i never
really growing up
felt like different or felt really like
discriminated in that aspect since when
i was a little kid
all my classmates were basically
vietnamese if you look through my
yearbook
i'll even post like a little thing of my
yearbook and block out everyone's names
it's like just
or try and try and try and transfer if
you know what i mean
so for me it's always just like oh you
just that's
that's how it's always been there's a
bunch of asians everywhere i didn't
really think that america was mainly
white people because in the community i
grew up with
it was mainly asian people so for me i
never understood
the concept of america as a white
country because i was like oh all the
classmates
are asian so everyone else every other
school must have more asians too
it wasn't until i reached middle school
and then i found out differently but
in elementary school i lived pretty you
know normally
i am all my classmates are asian so we
never really had to feel anything weird
about how we brought our lunch to school
and stuff like that
i know sadly this isn't the case for a
lot of people
growing up here but i was i'm i honestly
think i'm very grateful
that i had that you know chance to grow
up and live with other vietnamese kids
as we could speak our language without
having to be like mocked or anything
like that
we could share our food and not really
give any like weird like
oh what's that i was like oh you're
eating fa oh i
something like that you know so it's
never been really too much of a big
issue for me
so as a kid i was like oh life is great
and even we had like a couple white kids
couple black kids in my classes
or hispanics for the most part they
became asian washed so it's kind of like
the opposite effect surprisingly enough
but
that wasn't until i went to middle
school i really started to
realize more about racial indifference
and stuff like that
because for me i've noticed that for the
asian kids in my class i know
i personally don't say it but i do know
that plenty of asian kids
have said the n word and stuff like that
starting middle school because at the
time
we didn't really have that many black
people around we didn't really know the
connotations of what it meant
or stuff like that so for the most part
people my age
we found it funny we were 11 to 13 year
old 13 years old we didn't really know
any better we just thought it was funny
we heard it in rap songs stuff like that
and i'm not trying to justify it i'm
just saying as
children we didn't really know any
better since we didn't grow up around
those types of people
leading to us thinking it was okay along
with sometimes
majority part asian parents do say it
too which is why i must also
for us we assume it is okay so at the
time
most of us whenever i heard it i was
like
i never really understood the any racial
implication behind that
it wasn't until though i actually faced
my own sort of discrimination
i was walking around um
uh the beach area hb and uh
when i was walking around there i saw a
group of white kids they looked at me my
brother
and then they started making oh ching
chong and did this
and then me and my brother for me though
they were making it towards my brother
since i
do not have those kinds of eyes or i
don't have
the tip i don't i don't have the
i don't have you know my eyes are bigger
than a normal asian so i've never really
gotten that type of like feeling where
they did this and stuff like that
it was but it was targeted towards my
brother and my brother felt really bad
because of it and
that's when i kind of realized that
isn't okay you're not asian
but the same time though for a while it
was really normalized for me because
you know i think most immigrant parents
or
most kids living with immigrant parents
know that their parents
have like some type of gratitude towards
um white people in a sense where my mom
is always like
oh they let us into our country we owe
them a lot of things
so they have that you know
you know white savior type of thing
which is why i'm assuming some
white people have that type of complex
because of stuff like that
which i can understand from my mom's
point of view
how it's like to escape from a war-torn
country
to go to america where
here they where they finally get
somewhere else to go
so in turn they feel grateful for that
and i can understand that at the same
time though
it's kind of made it normalized in a way
how
how white people treat us is justified
because that they let us into the
country in the first place
which i think isn't right
on the santander i also think asian
mockery is very
deeply rooted in us like in our heads
where we justify it and we think it's
okay because we think it's funny
asians to each other we go ching chong
and stuff like that to each other
so for the most part when i heard a
white person initially before
say it i was okay with it it wasn't
until i had actually felt
bad about it then i realized it was
wrong
i i used to have somebody i used to know
their family was vietnamese but they
grew up in a white community
and for the most part i remember his
family
would tell me that they rejected or they
decided not to teach
their kids vietnamese because they think
they didn't need it and that
they tried i don't know in a way i can't
really say it because it's not my family
not
but to me it was like very they're
rejecting their own culture
and stuff like that and i realized in a
way it's deeply rooted that
some asian people reject their own
culture in order to fit in with this
country and how it is
and how people here discriminate so
heavily against asians leading to some
people rejecting their own culture
like i remember i told him or i told
this friend of mine
before he i told them oh chipman which
is um
vietnamese for happy new year and they
told me
please don't say that to me and i was
like why he's like
i don't like hearing it and i was like
okay but that's kind of odd but whatever
but for at the time i thought it was
just really odd how someone who was
vietnamese
doesn't like hearing their own language
and i kind of just realized slowly over
time
i see i've met other people exactly like
them
that reject their own cultural innocence
in order to fit in better with
white people and stuff like that and in
turn it makes me feel really sad because
it's very hard to live in a country
where
people are going to hate you just
because of the way you were born
something we can't change no matter how
whitewashed you are
no matter how much you try to act like a
white person or try to reject your
culture
in the end no matter what it's your it's
it's you
you're always going to be asian and even
if they try to deny it
it's just sad because either way in a
way we're never going to be accepted no
matter how hard we try
until they understand our point of view
because
change is extremely hard some people
have their own prejudices and it's just
sad to see that people have to reject
themselves to think that so they're
able to fit in with the
with how this country's built all the
systematic racism and how
it's trickled down to people in my age
and stuff like that
into denying their own culture which is
really upsetting
i also when i was this is actually most
recent i was
walking around the beach with my younger
brother and
you know we were walking with our dogs
and stuff like that and then
some white kid came up and this is
another example of how like
racism is somewhat normalized in
people's minds is or
how it in a way it's like it's just like
going off of the
last example of my friend or one of my
friends
or used to be my whatever but
he this white kid came up to us and he
was like oh can i pick your dog and he's
he was with two asian friends he had two
asian friends with him and it was just
one of this one little white kid
and he was like and we're like oh okay
sure pet our dog i don't care
and he pets the dog and then after that
he starts like grabbing its belly
and like grabbing her why did i call it
i'm so sorry
um i started grabbing cookies belly and
like
rubbing it and then feeling
her fat and stuff like that and me and
my brother were really uncomfortable and
he was like
wow you really find her up are you going
to eat her for a new year
and then me and my brother we looked at
each other and we're like
what the and the two asian kids
with us were also looking at us and
we're like
and they're like
and i was like in my head i didn't i was
like
why aren't you saying something how are
you friends with this kid and then
they just didn't say anything and they
looked super uncomfortable and in a way
they kind of looked us in like i was
like we're sorry
but like they didn't say it but you
could tell they felt uncomfortable
with it too and the little white kid was
like laughing haha
and we all kind of just like
until after that and it just it's really
weird it's really gross how
in a way kids they can't stand up to
themselves because
white people have you know power in a
way
in this country and it's really sad to
see and hear that
the more i got older the more i realized
how
hard it is for asian people to get
certain opportunities
in life due to us being asian like
asians are kind of just categorized to
oh
doctors lawyers doctors lawyers of
pharmacists anything math related yada
yada and i'll admit
personally i do like to be an engineer i
do like math
of course of course i can like whatever
i want but
it's just weird how in a way it's all
every single asian is either
chopped up into that category it's okay
for them to go into that cairo but
anything else out of that spectrum
is for some reason 10 times more
difficult for any asian person to get
into
like for me i know i said i wanted to do
engineering but at the same time my true
passion does
rely in art film
animation and stuff like that but what
the other day i was having a
conversation with my mom and
she was like cameron
i'm sorry to say this to you but you're
asian
and even worse you're an asian girl
so do you think you're really going to
make it to hollywood without having to
get your hands dirty
and i was thinking to myself i was like
you know
she's right in a way that i can't do the
things i want to do because
i don't get the privileges that white
people get
because they are white i can't get the
automatic
respect that white people have because
i'm asian and worse yet an asian girl
and i can't prove to myself
or i can't prove to other people
specifically
my own worth without having to do
certain things in order to get that
approval
i have to work 10 times harder than most
other people
and it sucks it really sucks
because it sucks that i'm not going to
get the same opportunity
that white kids have because i'm asian
i'm not going to get the same
chances and even so even if i work so
hard
bias exists like if i if anything some
people will just choose the white person
automatically just because they're like
oh
they're white it's only after a couple
it's
even bts the number one best-selling
artist in the world right now
can't even get a grammy for best
performance
which no offense to lady gagarin and
granddaddy they're great but
bts wholly deserved that award
but you know hollywood in the music
industry
uses asians for clout they
throw in a couple little splurges of
diversity
diversity and then when they get all the
views and stuff
yank it out the weekend
bts um
khalid and stuff like that it wasn't
even until last year that
an asian movie won an oscar an
international movie won an oscar
parasite and it's opened the doors a lot
i won't say that there's been progress
but it's so
it's surprised it's off it's it's just
it's unbelievable that it's taken this
long
for anyone to get this to make a step
forward
and to change and to
diversify and for other things other
than
american hollywood made movies to win an
oscar
and even this year stephen yin got
nominated for his role in menari
and minari is an excellent film i highly
recommend it it does
also talk a lot about you know
raising kids in america when you're an
immigrant and stuff like that and i
really think it's a good
it's a good watch but
with all this stuff it's horrendous that
has taken this long
even crazy rich asians i think it was
like one of the first movies
in the past i don't know how long
hollywood's
been going on to have an all asian cast
and that was like
two three years ago and this year with
disney finally having one of their first
um animated asian
uh properties since mulan
to get a live action movie i mean i like
an animated movie i mix that up with the
live action mulan and even the live
action mulan
technically isn't even culturally
or accurate to chinese culture
which is just it's disappointing
with a company as big and
has so many resources to make a decent
film just like a decent it didn't have
to be like
they could they have so many resources
they have so many things they could do
to
at least make it historically accurate
make it accurate
make it make sense but no all that money
all the money they have
that they made awful during the pandemic
and they can't even get
a certain set or a certain dress right
it just blows my mind and it's
so it's so disheartening in a way for
asians to try and have dreams outside of
the
things that were already grouped into to
branch out and to
speak our name or and to speak anything
outside of that small bubble that we're
in
but that's just personally what i want
in a way
i want to do certain things but i know
for a fact as an asian
woman it's going to be extremely
difficult
there's also the thing of how asians
nowadays or asian girls are very
sexualized
i see how people talk about bts or just
k-pop idols in general
or how people or guys try to categorize
all
asian girls into like aha so kawaii
it's just so it's so disgusting in a way
that
we are just grouped into that just
because of our race which i've said that
a million times but it is it truly is
i see white girls trying to mimic asian
behaviors
asian fashion eat our food
try to use asian aesthetics hello kitty
rilakkuma
i don't know whatever they use to
make themselves like kawaii
and quirky or whatever whatever
that is and don't even
give a f behind they don't give a
they don't give a behind any of the
people behind that
they use it for an aesthetic and after
that they dip
they don't care about what's happening
to us for the most part i've seen many
white creators on instagram
on youtube who use asian aesthetics
asian
even guys who wear like japanese kanji
kanji katakana whatever shirts like that
and
they don't say anything they're just
like oh it looks cool
and it just it's just gross that you
just think our culture is just an
aesthetic for you to wear
to eat food enjoy yourselves but not
even care about the people behind it in
the meaning behind it
you use our stuff for your aesthetics
and to make yourself look better
only to then not even give when
something is actually happening to the
community behind it
it's disgusting to see things we were
originally mocked for our eyes our
slanted eyes our
our face just i don't know everything
about asians before that were mocked
you look on places like king tik tok i
hate tik tok i'm just going to say that
right i hate tik tok
you take stuff like that you go on to
sorry
you got the apps like tick tock and you
just see people be like
it's just so stupid like why you
like they'll go and use japanese sounds
japanese this japanese that or korean
stuff
and they just turn it into her own
little trend aesthetic and they're just
like oh my god this is so cute
and then once it's all over they're just
like okay
next because they just want to act
quirky or some like that and i just
think it's so stupid they make it a
trend
when originally if anybody or any asian
for that matter was into anime
kpop s j rock
stuff like that before we were all
mocked for it we were called
weird everything that asians used to do
were considered
weird creepy foreign
and now it's a trend for you all
to enjoy and be like oh my god this is
actually
so cute and then after that you don't
even give
behind the history behind that or just
anything like that you just use it for a
trend in which in a way
i know some people can make the argument
that oh we're grateful it's spreading
asian culture
but they don't even know what's behind
it they don't know
the meaning of it they don't know what
they're saying they don't even research
or do anything about it they just use it
for a trend because they see it they see
other people do it and they're like okay
i'll do it too
get the views get the likes and then
move on
and i'm sick and tired of it
if for me i see white creators using
drinking matcha
eating sushi buying hello kitty or
whatever
i at least want you to at least say that
say that
stop asian hate just even post a small
thing just a small thing
even i see the anime community in kpop
community right now they don't
say that much about it either which is
super disappointing for me because i'm
in both fandoms
i'm part of the anime community and kpop
community and it's so
disappointing to see that no one has
said anything
and it just makes me disappoint cause
like
the people that are behind the things
that you love and enjoy
are getting beat up on the street old
people just minding their own business
just walking around
just doing just living their life
they're just getting beat up for no
reason
for the sole purpose that they just for
our skin like
it's just it's sad that
our parents had to work so hard to get
into this country only for their kids to
suffer
the consequences of systematic racism
and for them to say that it is okay
because
we should be grateful that we're even
allowed here in the first place
i uh the other day i had an argument
with my mom and dad
about how they were like cameron you're
being too sensitive over this you're
playing the race card
you shouldn't you should be grateful but
you need to know that racism will always
be there
and that you can never change anything
and i'm like yeah
i get it i get that racism is always
going to be a thing it's never going to
completely
100 go away there's always going to be
some type of bias
or stereotype i understand that but it
doesn't hurt
to make change it doesn't hurt to say
something
staying silent is being complicit
staying silent about it is basically
saying
or just accepting that we deserve it is
not okay
and like i asked i was like i mean my
father
he was like you know i was discriminated
against
by viet people i was like what does that
have to do with anything it's white
people discovering asian people and if
you're described by asian people that's
not
because you're do he's he's like he's
like but i'm beating me and i got to
scream my feet
i was like sure i was like yeah and
people it doesn't matter the whole
purpose of this whole
stop asian hate is so that asians
don't have to get beat up on the street
because of our race
if it's asians against asian then that's
a whole different
that's a whole different type of thing
and it's just it's just
really sad it's really heartbreaking
the other day my younger brother came up
to me he's like like cameron
is it fair that because i'm asian
i'm never going to accomplish my dreams
of doing anything
because we were born this way and i told
him
i didn't know what to tell him i didn't
really know what to tell him
she was like cameron did we do anything
on our raw in our past lives to be born
in this body and i was like no ben
we didn't do anything wrong we were born
this way
and that's how it is then so be it we
have to stay strong we have to
stay hold face in this in this time of
hate and stuff like that especially with
kobit and things getting worse
i think it's really important that we
have to stay strong
and i really love that
our community has gotten a lot stronger
because we all been able to stay
together during this entire experience
and really hold our own together and
stay strong
as a community and it's really good to
see that but
hearing my brother saying that he
doesn't think he can ever accomplish a
dream because he's not white makes me
really disappointed
because sometimes i believe that too
that i won't be able to accomplish
anything i want to do because i am not
white either
there are times where i think most asian
kids can agree with this that we were
born
or we were sometimes wish we were born
white
or like a white male so that you know we
could just go somewhere and cheat up the
place and then
you know get away with it because we
just had a bad day you know
you know it's just yeah
it's just not really that fair
i just it's just heartbreaking to see
old people minding their own business
almost get their life taken away
or seeing people do get their life taken
away just because
of racism and stereotypes
or stuff like that and
just or see people just use our culture
for their aesthetics
only to not care about the people behind
it and
as an asian person myself it's just
really heartbreaking to see that because
i wish that
you know things were different i wish
things would have to be this way but
that's how it is and yeah
i don't really know how to end this i
just
it's just very disappointing it's really
disappointing
i really hope that there's one day going
to be changed
there are there's change happening now
but
is it enough i really hope that people
will be able to come to understanding
that
we never did anything i
most asian people aren't doing anything
wrong
most of us are just living our lives
trying to make ends meet
trying to just enjoy each other have fun
we're just like you everybody's the same
everybody wants to have fun everybody
wants to be loved everybody wants to be
accepted
and we are no different
i just hope that because of all this
that there will be things put in place
and that the victims of asian hate
will get the justice they all deserve
because i am proud to be vietnamese
i am proud that i am asian even in times
where i wish i wasn't
in the end i am proud of our culture i
am proud to
be able to have have a whole community
of people who
all are this all share this like culture
and background
and be able to relate to the people
behind everything
i'm just happy to be vietnamese i'm
happy to be asian
it's just it's always it's always been
something i'm proud of
even if i have glimpses and thoughts of
things suggesting otherwise it's really
just
in the end i'm proud of our community
that we are able to stay so strong
during this time
and i hope that you all continue to be
strong
and spread awareness
and to and to continue
to educate yourselves your friends your
family
and one day we'll hope to accomplish
change i'll be leaving some links down
below
for um mental health for asian
communities um
go fund me for the victims of the
shootings and some
recent attacks on asian amer asian
elderly
um and other charities down below
if you have the money please donate if
you have the time go read a bunch of
articles
um i'll link some good videos i've
watched on this matter as well
and i hope you guys will have a nice day
sorry this video isn't really exactly
the most
fun and it's really disheartening
but i think it's really important for us
to be aware of the topic of
where it's happening and really make us
strive to be better
thank you for watching goodbye