from thank you so much for joining me
today for another video so today I'm
bringing you a slightly different kind
of video a tag video of course I was
tagged by the wonderful and beautiful
Jean Rossi if you guys don't know who
she is I'll link her channel in the
description below so basically she's a
very gorgeous fellow makeup enthusiast
and I follow her on Instagram and yeah I
guess she tagged me in this video so
Jane if you are watching my name to him
thank you for tagging me I'm very
excited to do this tag and I certainly
really enjoyed watching your tag Jean so
thank you for tagging me girly and real
quick if you are new and this is the
first video you're stumbling upon on my
channel I am so glad you're here
welcome I'm sure you'll get to know me a
little bit better through this video for
obvious reasons because I'll be
answering questions about myself and my
channel and if you like what you see I
invite you to join the breath of beauty
family because we really are a good
bunch here alright let's get on with the
tag okay so I have the questions here on
my phone so I apologize if I'm looking
down but that is what I'm looking at
right here so the first question is what
inspired you to start making videos so I
had made other channels in the past and
made other videos in the past but they
quickly flopped because I didn't really
have the grit behind you know what it
takes to make videos and consistently
create content finally this year I
decided to make videos now I have faced
a lot of opposition from my family
regarding making videos for some reason
they were just really against it so
that's another reason why I didn't
really keep up making YouTube videos but
when I became a working adult an
independent adult that can make her own
decisions and like live her own life
without feeling obligated to obey other
people who because of financial
dependency for example I decided hey
I've always wanted to make videos
relating to beauty
I really fell in love with beauty like
middle school souls pretty young age and
it just was so interested and I really
really wanted to create my own beauty
content so April of this year I finally
decided to make videos and the
inspiration just comes from me loving to
create content I'm a creator and also my
love of beauty products and all things
related to beauty
not just outer beauty but inner beauty
as well okay second question is how long
have you been on YouTube and have you
had other channels I kind of already
touched on this and the first question
yes I've had other channels and this
current channel I've had since April so
I'm not very long a little over six
months I'd say it's pretty young so I'm
still really proud of it I'm honestly
pretty surprised at myself for keeping
it up all this time I'm kind of and
notorious for being really passionate
about something and then like really
getting sick of it soon after but this
has stuck and I have the perseverance so
far in creating content every week and I
don't plan to stop anytime soon and I've
been loving it it's been so great
getting to know some of the guys and
like creating a lot of friends that are
really interested in makeup just as I am
so it's been really awesome okay so
question number three where do you see
yourself and your YouTube channel in
five years you know I've never really
been good at like long term planning and
I consider five years down the line long
term planning and I honestly don't
really see a point and trying to plan
out your life personally because I know
most of its not gonna happen and I'm
just gonna let God do whatever he wants
to do to guide me through out though I
guess next 5 10 20 30 years of my life
and so I don't really make it a point of
like planning everything but if I'm just
daydreaming and five years I'll be 30 so
hopefully I don't know I
might be having thoughts about having a
child like a kid I might be having
another dollar which I was all excited
about like I really want another dog and
in five years I don't know um in terms
of my youtube channel I have no idea
honestly um I have made a commitment to
myself when I started this channel that
I would keep doing what I'm doing for
three years at least and you guys that's
actually a pretty long time for me
because like I said I get sick of things
super super fast and this is really
different like I'm really passionate
about it and I'm really trying to keep
it up and just keep the passion going
and persevere through the hard times or
like the slumps and I've been really
enjoying it so far it's been quite a
ride already so um I know I'm gonna keep
it up for at least three years and if I
keep it up for five years that'd be so
awesome and maybe even more than five
years who knows right who knows what
youtube is gonna be like in five years
but um I don't really have like a
subscriber number and mine or or video
views of mine cuz that's not we leave
that important to me what really matters
to me is that through my videos and
through my channel
somebody will really be able to see that
they are beautiful like that if I'm able
to make one person feel like they are
really truly beautiful then what more
can I think yeah I honestly feel like
yeah if I'm able to be a positive
influence on a number of people in five
years that's all I would want honestly
question number four what message are
you trying to get across with your
videos so I guess I touched on this one
too
but the biggest and most important
message that I'm trying to get across
through my videos is that you the viewer
are truly magnificent beautiful and
wonderful
that is the number one message that I
want you the viewer to hear from me and
now I say this because I'm a Christian
and that is the most integral part of my
life that is my life and I think the
most important thing is for people to
see themselves as how God sees them and
that's loved beautiful wonderful
accepted amazing a work of art like
that's how I won't be able to view
themselves and that's the most important
message that I want to get across to you
guys through my videos and that's why at
the end of every single one of my videos
I will tell you that you guys are
beautiful you're wonderful and I'm so
grateful that you guys are my friends
because that's truly how I feel
and I hope you guys really know that
that's really sincerely from my heart is
I feel like you guys are really
beautiful and you're amazing humans each
and every one of you are unique each and
every one of you are loved each and
every one of you are awesome and that's
what I want to get across otherwise
another message I want to get across is
that I really love beauty I just want to
share my thoughts on certain products
and I just want to talk about makeup
with fellow Beauty enthusiasts and if I
get to help any beginners along the way
that's awesome you know so that's that
question number five is do people from
school find your channel
I don't think so I'm I'm pretty small
still so I don't think people from
school find me I guess if they're like
friends and they see me like I suggested
on their Instagram feed or something and
they follow me and that's how they find
out about my channel I can't really do
anything about that but I do kind of
like to keep my channel a little private
when it comes to my friends like only
like a handful of my close friends know
about my channel otherwise like I don't
go around broadcasting and telling
people I have a youtube channel cuz it's
like so precious and then still mine and
like I don't really feel like going
around telling everybody that I do this
so yeah question number six is what does
your username mean and so I think it's
pretty straightforward my username is
breath of beauty and when I was first
starting out you know creating this
channel I kind of envisioned that this
channel my my videos would be a place
where you guys can come and just take a
breath of beauty right like taking a
breath of fresh air you just take a
breath of beauty and I guess that's just
really resonated with me and I really
liked how it sounded and just kind of
sounds like refreshing and revitalizing
you know your passion for makeup or
revitalizing your passion for making
creative looks or stepping out of your
comfort zone or even just taking a
breath of beauty to know and be reminded
that you are beautiful because you need
reminders like let's be honest we're all
humans and we have negative thoughts
that more often than not creep into your
minds and that makes us feel like we're
not beautiful or makes us feel like
we're not worthy but if you have
reminders telling you the truth
which is that you're beautiful it can be
incredibly helpful so you're taking this
breadth of this revitalizing passion for
makeup as well as you're taking a like a
freshening reset breath to let yourself
be reminded that you're
beautiful does that make sense just feel
like I'm just being so abstract but it
makes sense in my mind okay number seven
is favorite small youtuber now I I don't
really know if I have like a favorite
small youtuber yet because I've only
just started watching like the smaller
youtubers I guess I've been watching
like the og youtubers since I was in the
middle school and I've kind of like
stuck with people that I found and they
just end up growing like humongous and
they just end up being huge but I guess
they were small youtubers when I started
watching them so yeah currently I do not
have them but I'm sure I'll have one
soon okay so that's all of the questions
that I had I hope you guys were able to
get to know me a little better through
this tag and I I really did enjoy
talking about just my channel and my
purpose here on YouTube it's just really
important as well as super fun to talk
about the purpose of your channel you
know so I really really enjoyed this I
hope you guys did too again if you're
new and you're still here I'm super glad
you stuck around I do encourage you
again to join the breadth of beauty
family if you haven't already and if you
do join don't forget to click on the
notification bell to make sure you don't
miss out on any of my future videos
because the YouTube world is huge let's
be honest and it's kind of hard to find
people so that's the way for you to come
back to me cuz I would love to see you
again also feel free to follow me on
Twitter Instagram and snapchat if you're
at all curious about what I'm up to on a
day-to-day basis and it's just like a
more casual platform for me to just let
you guys know what I'm up to so go do
that okay you guys know what's coming
and for those of you that are new you're
gonna find out with all of that said
remember you guys you are
amazing beautiful wonderful and
marvelous no matter what anybody else
tries to tell you and remember that I am
always rooting for you and I'm so
grateful that we are friends alright
guys thank you guys again so much for
watching and I'll hopefully see you in
my next one bye
[Music]