[Music]
what is up or let me some motives I hope
you guys are doing well I'm so happy to
be back on you know yield to it's been a
minute I haven't posted I feel like in
like three months or so and I am
honestly going to come up to this video
until you guys like what's been going on
I haven't been posting a lot on you know
my Instagram haven't been posting much
on my personal Facebook or like YouTube
has been a minute because I've been you
know working for a college that requires
me to basically I would say use social
media as a tool and by the time I get
off home I better time I get off I don't
want to do anything I don't want to post
on my youtube nothing I don't want to I
don't know I've just had a little bit I
just had a little bit of issues with
like balancing things that's why I've
been just off my Facebook and everything
was just like my Instagram I you two
just like prioritizing working and then
getting off we get spending time with my
family my husband my kid and you know
now I feel like I'm having a little bit
now I'm just in this level of I'm gonna
get back to my stuff because I do miss
being creative with you guys I've missed
editing videos I missed recording I miss
having a voice a little bit I'm not
gonna lie it kind of sucks in a way that
I've noticed that I've just not recorded
anything what's going on this is like my
outlet also a big deal is is that I've
been diagnosed with ADHD and I'm so
happy that I finally got diagnosed
because with those months that I took my
social media break from my social media
is because I just could not handle all
the things that I'm trying to do like I
do YouTube videos I have an online shop
as you guys know ADA unveiled and I also
have I also work full time I'm a mommy
the Navy's always gonna have to take
care of my son and I didn't know what it
was that I was you know all my life I've
been asked like do you have ADHD because
I do struggle in focusing I struggle and
some other obvious like signs I do
struggle with so there is a thing such
as like adult ADHD and I wanted to get
checked because I've been asked this all
my life like my friend's parents would
be like hey do you have any AGG and I
would totally be in denial like no I
would ask my mom and my mom would tell
me I don't have anything obviously she's
my mom you know so now that I am 25 26 I
felt the need that you know I'm gonna
get checked just in case I spoke to a
doctor and um he agreed he agreed that I
definitely have some some signs there
that I have ADHD so when you have video
to do you can't focus and I have so much
to do in my life that it was just eating
me up like laundry wouldn't be done in a
minute um in the sense of like I
wouldn't wash it but I would never I
would never fold a cuz I couldn't I
couldn't I just couldn't stand still to
fold it I had to move around often I
started like little mini projects that I
never ends I would get simple things
like my keys I would forget my wallet
just I would just be everywhere and
being an entrepreneur working full time
and also trying to be a present mom and
wife is just so much but I feel like
there's a way that I can do this that I
can go ahead and still pursue my
creativity supposedly ADHD people have
are really good with being creative and
I definitely see that as y'all know I am
creative I love it
I've been really just frustrated when it
comes to time management I'm not good at
it and I'm trying to get my life
together with that but since I did say
that I do start mini projects and I
never end them I do have some videos
that are pre-recorded so I'm gonna go
ahead and upload those but it's just
like I never end them I never I record
them but I don't edit knowing that I
have to have a youtube video up or
whatever the case is I choose not to and
that's like something that ADHD people
have that they just procrastinate and
that's like my issue as well so I am not
taking any medications at all because I
have any HD I'm trying
to see if I can just time manage better
I spoke to a doctor the doctor told me
since you don't want to take medication
like at all
etc try these methods and he gave me a
few I want to say like right now what's
working for me is the hourly hourly
agenda that I have but um I feel like I
have to master this down as a person in
general like to feel sane I'm so glad
that I literally do not feel crazy for
wandering about have ADHD and I'm glad
that I got checked
I feel like Latinos and you know we're
just really hard on mental health like
this is something that we don't look
into enough and maybe not even as a
Latino as people in general we like we
don't we don't go and get ourselves
checked for mental health and I feel
like if you feel you might have an issue
like focusing or depression or I don't
know suicidal thoughts get help like
please so I just want to come in here
with a new fresh fresh of breath air
breath fresh I just want to come in
clean slate I just want to come in and
just start posting like I used to
I am prioritizing my youtube again I'm
taking care of back I'm again I'm taking
my baby back and making something out of
it again I will go ahead and see you
guys stay tuned and I'll see y'all soon
[Music]