[Music]
let me someone is what is up welcome
back to my channel if you're new what's
up what's up don't forget to subscribe
and if you're an oldie so today I wanted
into a video called the Latino tag and I
don't know what better target to first
start off I am a super proud to be
latina and I feel like a lot of people
really look into these videos cuz you
know it's something that we can all
relate to you know old fan so I got my
questions from Monica style Muse she has
Dominican like me better I don't want to
eat that you're silly being blanquita
and I thought I would be awesome you
know because she's after latina and I'm
like super pale so I think it's really
nice you know to show the two sides of
our islands so this is the first this is
the first question where are you from so
your girl is American I was born in New
York City but literally like two months
after I was born I moved to Dominican
Republic and some time ago I was raised
there for like I want to say eight nine
years and then I moved back to the
States
usually you're born in like rabbuka
americana and they here like move to New
York again your papers or whatever so
usually that's how it happens but I
think this whole opposite just which is
really nice my childhood was so poppin
it's so different
going up on an island compared to going
up here in the States when you're a
little that's for sure
do you speak Spanish do I speak Spanish
Claud okay y'all espanol
it's my hair let me be mini yo ma
Spanish is my first language and even
now I mess up my words sometimes I think
in Spanish but my English just sometimes
messes up you know it's bilingual
problems what what's your favorites are
making this literally like this is so
hard I can't even I love food and my
favorite Dominican dish I want to say
it's like a mango mango is the bad
I love is plantain smashed
right and then you can have Wilfredo
fried fried eggs or you can have Scilab
you frito and then if you want to hear
with the three bangs I think it's like
salami Weibull and fried cheese oh my
gosh so much I can eat that in the
morning in the afternoon I can hear it
at night I can eat it literally whatever
and I'll be happy it's so good oh my
gosh what's the next question is what's
your favorite is I'm gonna get dessert
yo the Dominican dessert I love arroz
con leche I think that's like Hispanic
though cuz you see them like in a Cubano
the Puerto Ricans have it like in the
restaurant but I don't know when I was
that's I don't know made it because the
Caribbean is all like one big thing to
me and I love I wish what I would say
why I mean I don't say y'all I shouldn't
it
I love each other compensate yes so your
parents our grandparents have plastic
over there so fast
no they don't but that's a thing that's
a thing for sure but no my godmother
doesn't have but she does have instead
of plastic she's like okay did she now
has a folder like it blends in with the
sofa so it looks like it's part of the
sofa what item in your household
explains where you're from oh my gosh so
this doesn't get any more intimate again
I'm gonna put a clip in I have here a
casitas colonial like these are little
houses and you buy them in the island or
whatever and they're handmade and as you
guys I don't know if you guys knew but
Dominican Republic is the oldest country
in the West hemisphere it's actually the
first island that Christopher Columbus
discovered and that's what he discovered
the worst atmosphere
which is crazy because we have his
castle and all that stuff and it's a
little mean boat and it's pretty funny I
don't know I I don't think a lot of
people know that but
you're welcome so since you know their
colonial houses this just represents
well from basically like la zona
colonial is the caches the color yarn is
a colonial houses who is your favorite
melon ghetto
so this is the problem this is where it
gets crazy for me I don't really listen
to anything like that
oh okay so if I would say actually
before I even look at food I need dough
and that's like pretty good API and not
even merengue love hula neato Pula neato
oh my god everything bad 90s memories
because I grew up in the 90s on the
island so literally all the parties
everywhere you went the stream move
might not have a soul bobbing way where
would I need oh I'm sure
[Music]
okay so that's my favorite and then I
think the last question I think the last
question was who's your favorite bachata
singer I'm gonna go ahead and say of
course
let's just say it Romeo Santos
you're literally over the summer I went
to Santo Domingo because my father is
out there my family my brothers everyone
lives out there so of course I go visit
my fans so um when I went it was also
nah cuz you guys know when I'm gonna get
input her again and then it was Romeo
Santos hot tub and like she was late so
after seeing how lit I don't know how
those gets there's no way anyone can
happen cuz like Ramos house was that guy
alright so that's basically it I just
got I just got the questions from her
from my all Monica Scott wheels because
I love her and she'd be reppin on her
first Dominicans it's really nice to see
you know a lot of shades from my islands
she's moromete I wanna navy denim Bonita
and I think it's so cool that you know
you two can see the different sides of
us Dominicans because I'm super you know
hey I want to say I'm not super dark I
want to say I have yellow tone I tan
easily I don't know if I'm olive I'm
gonna color I am but you know Mon Monica
is black she's a Latina so it's really
nice you know that you too can show you
guys their friend Dominicans different
colors because we are so unique and so
different in that Island so yeah don't
forget to go ahead and give this video a
thumbs up subscribe if you don't mind me
posting all school YouTube videos give
this video thumbs
okay okay all right love you
[Music]
[Applause]