[Music]
hey guys what's up boy let me some
mortise if you guys are new here don't
forget to go ahead and subscribe and hit
the bell for notifications and if you
are returning sub us ah I'm so happy to
be back
literally I feel so good to like set in
front of my camera and record for you
guys because I've been at my a for
almost like two months and um yeah I'm
just gonna give you guys a quick update
on my life before I just start bombing
y'all with videos like I say um you know
I don't get paid extremely poppin on
YouTube I mean I can't even lie to you
guys so I got a job but your girl is
official I got an official job a big
girl job after graduation good we're
gonna make a video about these little
hairs right here I don't know if you
guys remember a video that I posted that
I was losing my hair while it's coming
back and I got a routine that I'm gonna
show you guys that's helping my hair go
but literally like it's like popping out
looks crazy someone it just I get an
amazing job and I'm so happy because
it's actually something that I'm making
a difference so that's really nice um my
makeup got stolen
that's like this huge deal of why I
haven't posted someone broke into my car
and they took my makeup my expensive ass
makeup literally stole another bag that
I had that had clothes in it I was I was
in downtown and someone broke into my
car and took all of my things which is a
huge reason why I haven't posted on
YouTube because I haven't had makeup I
haven't had anything to to come out and
look decent at least I've been it's been
crazy it's been crazy so I have to start
all over how to start super fresh um and
that's sucked because it's expensive as
hell
so by Omega as you guys know so I am
gonna do like a Ulta haul to show you
guys like the makeup that I got because
I
to start fresh and um yeah was it really
all motivated me to post any videos on
top of the fact that I've been really
busy that's like a big deal for me
I know some of you guys are I don't know
if you guys are gonna be like well they
have eat enough sylvain but I love to
have my makeup on from my video ha um
you guys know I love a phase B it's
quite simple so yeah that really sucked
I lost a lot of expensive things my fave
my favorite perfumes and even my
drugstore makeup they stole everything
girl literally had no mercy on me which
which really sucked so that was that um
yeah but I have so much content
I got a Deva Katta I had a lot of curly
hair videos coming I am so excited for
that I'm also gonna make more videos in
espanol but I mean gente que el español
because a lot of you guys want me to
make more Spanish videos and I'm okay
with that
I think I'm fine my boy is walking my
husband's back from deployment that's
another big deal - I haven't told y'all
my hubby is back from deployment oh oh
and your girl now has an online shop oh
my gosh I haven't told you guys so I
think like oh I think last time in the
video I said that I was making it but
now I like have it and I've been with
the shop for a few months now so it's
going really well
but going really well with it I have a
lot of brand reps that are beautiful
anyways I'm gonna go ahead and look and
uh below so you guys can see it I love
it I love my online shop it's called ADA
on Belgium so follow me on Instagram yes
girl and just keep a lookout for my
content leave any requests in the
comments so I can hook you up with some
videos you know I'm saying but I'm so
happy to be back I really missed you
guys I love you guys so much and thank
you so much for being patient and
messaging me and making sure that I'm
alive and I'm alive and well so I'm like
I just wanted to hop on here real quick
and show my face and say that I'm back
and I'll go ahead and keep you guys
updated I have so many videos coming up
and um yeah so stay tuned
[Music]
you