*groans*
ah!
my microphones stand!
hi it's annabelle
it's nice to see you again, i can't wait to catch up through this q&a
um-- *stutters* *some gibberish*
thank you to everybody who submitted questions.
also in the description, you can jump to specific questions or come back to them.
i think the easiest thing to start off with- many people are excited to learn about bambi and prairie how they're doing.
i expected that prairie would be very standoffish, i said give her a week.
i think it really only took her four days? we were at lilith's for the first week
when i had to organize my storage unit but i don't want to explain all of that process too in detail because the vlog is coming out next week
show not tell, right?
good news is after we settled into this new york space- three days or so, they were already playing, chasing each other,
grooming each other, and i think like the only step left is for them to cuddle.
i was a little bit worried whether or not they would feel disappointed or cabin fever from
being in this studio apartment,
bambi's been living in a two-bedroom--
two-story house for a year
and even my sister's *apartment*
is bigger. it's a huge downgrade but, i do keep in mind  just what i feel would be healthy.
i almost got another studio apartment with no view
right off the bat, i just had a bad feeling about that place. my sister was just like "this jeopardizes cat vitality" or something like that
maybe i can take them out on walks again but from experience,
neither of them liked it very much. i don't think that the space is actually too small for the three of us here
because like they're two tiny cats and i make sure that there's plenty of perching spots for them whether it be like all over this couch,
they have their own couch, they have the  castle, the table top and the bed
and they love to switch out their resting spots,
and they kind of have like this routine. maybe i'll do a day in the life of prairie and bambi one day.
on to me: what am i most excited about living in new york?
explore more of the city of course
and to make new friends.
i've been really anxious all my life when it comes to making friends
and i have a really.... great set of friends
how do i say that lol
we're not like in a big group or anything i have really strong one-on-one bonds
but now that i'm an adult and self-employed it's just a lot harder to meet people right ?
one of the reasons why i wanted to move here is the culture
and the arts scene and like maybe i could get  a studio residency and just be more hands-on
yeah in terms of that living in new york...
...um..eating
..and exploring cool- oh you know what haha
..clubbing, i've never gone to a club or like even a party
where i'm like *wooo*
my sister has a lot more expertise than me so,
luckily she doesn't live far,
just a train ride, she's gonna come over and in the uh... occasional nights where i don't sleep before 10.
so i have to figure out how i'm going to-
did i always know i was gonna come to new york?
no there were maybe two or three times i was like hoping i can come to new york and even making plans or looking at apartments
but it never even solidified
in the back of my mind i just sort of..
if this dream was a balloon i just kind of let it go and watched it flow far away in the sky i was like, it's okay,
it doesn't have to be my life
i'm proud of myself for being here.
i'm never bored.
when i was reading the book flow they were kind of saying you don't want to be in a state of either boredom or anxiety,
you want to find flow.
i'm always on the anxiety side but occasionally, i do find that nice  flow and i enjoy my day when i plan it out nicely.
do i miss home? i've not been here long enough to feel homesick
i really enjoy the independence. i'm sure as time goes on i will begin to miss my family but now that i'm not in school, i....
...okay i've been having extreme brain farts i don't know what happened here i meant to say, now that i'm out of school
my schedule doesn't have to work around  going home only on holiday breaks which is nice
do i miss home?
it definitely gets quiet sometimes at night,
i kind of just get myself in a mood to really enjoy the evening and like
take it slow and stuff- i can make videos about this if you're interested.. in terms of just being homesick in general,
i moved around so much growing up i never feel attached to any one place. i used to be a lot more attached to objects which
has changed recently
but like i think what i have the hardest time letting go of are like 'memories of a time where things were once like this'
and they would never be like that again.
my yeye, which is my.. wait what- paternal grandfather and i had a really close relationship and he's
he passed away from cancer a long time ago
i had some of the most happiest memories um of my life
so i still ruminate on a lot of those memories it's like equal parts
sorrow and joy
so here in new york do i feel free or released?
the main difference is being able to do things by my own schedule,
cooking my own meals, right like my grandma's not there to take care of me but at the same time i won't feel the pressure
and the guilt to say, i need to eat dinner an hour later, like organize my time without needing to explain myself has definitely
saved some mental energy but at the same time
it was never too bad because living in my family house
it was really comfortable.
the only huge difference is like the first time i went grocery shopping
i was just like what the F--
living at home for a year has like screwed me over because i completely forgot my meal plan,
it's been a long time since i've shopped for myself.
i definitely don't think i'm gonna stay in new york forever,
the way i eventually want to live my life maybe have like a little store or a cafe and have like a nice quiet home with my family
and i can't afford anywhere like near new york city i just don't think that's realistic here.
the worst parts of living alone?
having to face the crises all by yourself. at  school, you know those nights where the cats would catch this mouse?
maybe one was missing its head or  whatever? you know- you have to pick it up yourself!
so i've been paying for my own bills since i  moved out of my college dorms. the only main things i rely on my mom for is phone
like we're still on a family phone plan.
other responsibilities that i'm going to look into that i haven't previously done is like renters insurance, cat health insurance
we don't have dental insurance so i'm going to have to go like... i have a cavity *cries*
poopy parts of being an adult of course but inevitable.
probably gonna have to spend 300 on that cavity..
lilith doesn't live so far from me she's in rhode island still and she's gonna take the train in next week and i'm gonna see her,
so i'm excited. it kind of reminds me of the gilmore girls intro song
*all you have to do is call my name  and i'll be there on the next train*
~where you lead
i will follow~
anywhere that you tell me to
i can go and visit hair and a train anytime
so in terms of my current job uncertainty what the hell i'm doing, how many jobs am i juggling,
so the main thing i'm doing is youtube full-time and my shop
i would say i spend equal energy on both of those and then i run my patreon. i have like a little bit over 400 amazing patrons
that have stuck with me even though i've been the most unproductive ass in the last three months
in the beginning i was like overworking myself i don't know like just needing to prove something to myself i think
do i fear the uncertainty of this self-employment? yes
yes...every day
every waking moment??
you know i haven't been as active on youtube- i appreciate when people say  they miss me on youtube
because i'm just like.. it makes me realize that i used to be a lot more productive so
as soon as i cover all my bases like make a nice spreadsheet of my financials, i want to make enough for savings, then we can talk about um like what do you call it like expendable income..
it's worth it for me. yes i can be saving like thousands of dollars by living at home
but like not only is being in the suburbs just..
too.. it's like drying me out.
full on spongebob in the spongebob movie.
bird needs to leave the nest as one of my friends put it
and a viewer asked me a sort of personal question about if they should go into engineering because
it ensures their livelihood in the future because if they instead major in their passion, which is literature
like maybe they would be unemployed and struggling
i guess my advice would be ask yourself could you imagine yourself being happy doing engineering?
if you had to go into work five days a week probably for decades, doing this field- could you actually be happy with it
because if you're pretty content and you can get a stable livelihood then you can definitely take classes or go back to school
for your passion but, if you just if you cannot like go on living like that which is kind of how i feel about why i needed to pursue art
full-time even if it means like a life of uncertainty, like to me..
that rigor is really worth it. but also if you want to get a degree in literature and you feel like you might not immediately find a job
related to your field, that's so normal.
even people who graduate with stem backgrounds might end up somewhere not even in remotely related to their actual major
if i were to get a stem job?? well i am very passionate about biology,
i've always enjoyed biology.
i used to think i would be great as a nurse i realize i'm kind of faint when it comes to thinking about like surgery or like injuries
so i actually don't think i would be great..
dream job? okay would be some sort of biologist and i get to go in the field to research marine biology or just ecosystems in general,
i've seen organizations that do rescue and animal rehabilitation or is that like a veterinarian field? or a mix of both?
some of you might know that toby ran away  last month and that was really unexpected and
totally messed up my shop operations because i kind of just shut down for a few months-- *for a few days*
*weep*
and during those days one of the things i did was watch our planet on netflix and i've always loved animal documentaries
and i really liked that one too
i just never got the chance [to watch]. there were some scary parts like seeing an imbalanced ecosystem, way too many of like this
one species and how that affects other species it was super insightful and quite inspiring at the end
hmm..okay
so how am i really?
i thought i would be a lot more concise when answering this question but, in general i'm doing..
uh... like... i'm.......
i just realized how much work i have to do on myself and it's cool. my mental health has been so bad for so long
i didn't even notice
when you're not really thinking about it and you have coping mechanisms that act as crutches for you to be able to be
high functioning at the things that you need to get by with..
there's no more pretending-- admitting to myself hey i actually don't feel okay at all  about this, why do i think that?
and unpacking it. i found pretty cool books that have been helpful,
podcasts, but finally i i'm going back to therapy.
yesterday i signed up for it. i'm trying a service i haven't done before,
so i'm still waiting to get matched to a specific counselor and start the session. i just hope that all around,
my mental state will improve and that could impact my productivity,
how do you really expect anyone to be thriving with the year that we've had?
so i give myself a break in terms of that but like also
hey, how can i make the best with what i'm given ?
that's sort of what i'm trying to do right now.
so i've been having a long art block for a long time!
and yes i question my abilities, "am i doing enough?"
am i as good as i think? or i just question that all the time.
one of the ways to calm down a little bit is to get off social media.
when you're on the explore page sometimes you find so many inspiring people and that fires you up and you want to paint!
but other times it totally over stimulates me and i just get into this paralyzed like huhhh i can't do anything!
just a few decades ago we weren't exposed to so many hundreds and thousands of different people living different lives
so in our head we kind of compartmentalize all of these internet strangers always thinking that other people are
doing and being more productive than us,
that they're struggling less, thriving way more than us, and that we're falling behind.. seeing my peers,
sometimes i love seeing their illustrations sometimes it just makes me question myself feel like i'm getting nowhere.
i DO feel like right now i'm nowhere,
like as in i don't really know where i want to go my life??
because in college i have this huge dream that was shattered.
..like i became really disillusioned
i started school wanting to do textiles for fashion and i wanted to do fashion because i was just one person and that person
just doesn't exist anymore like i'm not that person anymore
so it does make me question like do i want to even work for a fashion company ? because the person who wanted to work
for a fashion company thought that her life was going to be like this..
i really want to work on illustration because see if i didn't do fashion and if i never pursued that career i would want to do
storytelling.. probably animation or write  graphic novels.
my muse currently, they're my cats
i'm freaking catcreature, i live with two of the most charming little things
and i've been sketching my cats a lot and i'm-- prepare to see a lot of cat paintings! because i'm just like hey. i have an artist block.
what do i do. i'm just gonna paint my cat like there's no tomorrow
and maybe one day i will expand my visual  vocabulary.
do i want to continue doing textiles, yes!
even if i don't want to do it on like a  corporate level,
freaking textiles is like the most magical thing ever.
if you learn the craft of textiles, whether it be weaving crocheting knitting,
dyeing, i would never regret having learned what i have learned and the appreciation for textiles
i love it. i have a knitting machine i purchased from a friend that i haven't started using
so expect some knitting struggles from me.
sometimes to calm myself i think about
me as a 60 year old as an 80 year old,
i'll probably be making art that speaks to me a lot more,
time is just such a gift. every day is such a gift your health, your body is a gift. don't forget that don't let the fast-paced world,
the consumer, capitalist world convince you that you're never enough or you'll never get there.
not feeling as rushed and knowing like i have the time to get there someday even if it takes me decades,
given that i will be blessed with a long life
i hope to live into three digits-- given that the world is still around
and not  burned to the ground by that time,
what will my art be then? so in that sense i'm not so worried about where i'm going and how many skills i will obtain
because every day is just a new opportunity
to improve those skills, to learn more.
lastly the miscellaneous stuff!
has my style changed?
i'm kind of at this blank canvas point in my life where- you know my hair's grown out now, it's all natural
the funniest thing is that i kind of miss  having damaged dyed hair
because when it was kind of dry and crispy it had some texture.. i need some volume. you realize that my head is extra small
when i was in middle school i had an inside joke with a guy who i called bigfoot.
right before puberty his feet started growing faster than the rest of his body
so i called him bigfoot every time i saw him he called me small head
we'll be like bigfoot! small head~
so i'm excited i think i'm reinventing myself, definitely want to make a glow up video,
i really enjoy watching those, as well as transformation videos, i still haven't transformed myself into my high school self..
i saw uh some footage and i was like- i was sexy when i was a minor?? look at me now.
i like your hair!
i quite enjoy how my dark hair looks.
the last time i had long black hair was when i was 15
so it's been a long time.
i might as well try.
try to see if i can grow it out and..
before, i had a lot of it thinned out due to the trendy layer cut at the time, everyone was getting their tips thinned out so
i want to see how nice and thick my hair might look like. hopefully it won't be too flat and maybe i can even donate my hair
if i could resist myself from dyeing it..
we'll see.
lastly i just want to talk about music for one hot second
what's my favorite song of the moment?
okay so in the last couple months,
i really fell in love with joji.
sad songs about love...
yeah. i i really enjoyed joji's albums,
i can't remember the name of it was it..
broadcast? like the album name..  i like nectar, i have that one
slow dancing in the dark, which is the most famous track.
i also love clairo a lot.
immunity is wonderful but her ep,
uh- favorite song from her is hello? that song just makes me wanna go like:
play the song to me dancing just now.
what was my favorite song from lana del rey's new album?
i actually just listened to it for the first time  this morning.
i didn't like it as much as i thought it would. however, i find that all lana songs i have to listen to it a lot and it will grow on me
and then i'll become obsessed with it like exactly a year and a half after the release date. a lot of the songs seem super similar
whereas i feel like in her previous albums they all had their own story
whereas this one was like the whole album  was a continuous song in a way with different chapters..
so my favorite song as of now is probably 'not all those who wander lost' or 'yosemite'
and again this is gonna change
because from norman fcking rockwell, my favorite song was cherry- wait.
was bartender, and then now...
it's probably mariner's apartment complex for sure.
those are all the questions for today,
it's getting hot and i don't shave my pits.
i had fun catching up with you. thank you for keeping me company! i feel a lot better because with this last week,
i've just been...
with everything that's going on in current events,
i want to talk about a fundraiser that i'm doing.
the link is right there in the description and  just by announcing it on instagram in the last day we've raised 1500$ which is incredible
i made this nice painting of bambi sleeping,
need a little bit of peace and calm.. one winner is gonna be drawn in a week. it's open worldwide the shipping is included
so in order to enter, it's five dollars minimum to purchase an entry ticket
or you can share it on a social platform i think
for one free entry and the drawing would be generated on better world the organization
100% of profits are going to be donated to the asian american pacific islander community relief fund
so i hope that doing this video would notify some people who don't follow me on instagram.
also if you are not interested in getting this painting because you just don't like it
you can also donate to other organizations  and gofundmes of members of the AAPI community, so you don't have to actually
use my fundraiser but i just wanted to let you know that's happening
and yeah i'll see you pretty soon. next week is gonna be the moving vlog. until then take care goodbye!
bambi doesn't normally chill over here by the toaster,
i just put him there because i almost filmed the video with that backdrop
this cat tree.. *grunts*
belongs..*big lift* over here.