hi everyone it's melissa here and today
we are going to be going over
my past month's budget and how i go
about budgeting
so i've never really been great at
holding myself accountable
and actually keeping track of my money i
used to overspend a lot and it hasn't
been until this past year where i've
actually
got control of my money again and that
is all because of budgeting
budgeting has really helped me keep
track of my money and also
get control of my money again budgeting
is really helpful like i said
for keeping track of your money but also
just getting to know your money and your
money habits
like i said i used to be a spender but
now that i've been budgeting i
really kept control of my spending and
have really
spent on things that i really wanted
instead of things that i didn't really
need
budgeting helps keep yourself in check
it helps you gain control of your money
and it also keeps you from getting
yourself into more debt because
you're keeping track of where your money
is going and you're also not
overspending which is really helpful
so i'm going to teach you guys how to
set up your budget but also
how i do my budget and what my past
month budget looked like so i like to
budget on a monthly basis
i find that this is really helpful some
people budget on a weekly
some people budget every like quarter
whatever you're more comfortable with do
that
but i tend to do monthly because it
gives me an overview of how much i spent
what my bills were and just how much i
made for that month
so when i budget i tend to do right at
the end of the month so usually on the
last day of the month
or the beginning of the next month so
when it comes to
setting up your budget i'll leave a
template in the description box down
below
for you guys to download i tend to use
google sheets
i used to use microsoft excel but i
found it really helpful
to just be able to go online wherever i
was and look at my budget
i like using google sheets because it
allows me to
put in simple addition and subtraction
formulas to my budget sheet
some people don't like using a document
other people like using
apps so there are plenty of apps such as
mint that help people budget without
inputting the numbers
but i really like to sit down at the end
of the month and calculate the numbers
myself because it gives me
that idea of how i'm spending and i also
come face to face with the numbers i'll
leave other templates down below in case
you don't like mine
or you don't find it very intuitive for
you to me my budget is very simple
to me but you may not find it helpful so
i'll leave those
resources down below as well in case in
case you are a different type of person
so like i said i break down my budget
into five different sections i have
my income my bills loans spending
and my totals so for income i have three
lines under that
i have my work other and depop so
work right now as most of you know i am
currently furloughed
so my work is not work it's actually
the unemployment benefits that i'm
receiving so i'll put that
under my work income for other this is
typically
like money that i get from people then
mowing me paypaling me
apple cashing me whatever they may owe
me or
if they wanted to give me something what
have you i'll put that under other
so for depop i do make money every month
from depop
i don't make a lot but it is enough for
like spending
and just like buying coffees every now
and then
getting gas things like that so i'll put
depop there
and then i also have a line for my total
income
just to add up the first three lines and
that's basically
the total income that i get for that
month for my bill section these are my
recurring bills so my phone bill
credit card bills this also includes any
type of subscription so that includes
adobe creative studios and i also have a
line for aggressive payments in case i
do want to aggressively pay off my
credit cards
i have a line for that because every
month i pay the same
amount but if i want to take off more
i'll put that in as well
the next section is my loan section i
like to keep my loans separate from
my bills because i do like to
aggressively pay off my student loans i
don't want to be
in student loan debt forever so i have a
separate section for that
it just allows me to see how much i'm
spending
on my loans compared to like my bills
and my spending habits
for my spending i have three lines i
have food
shopping and miscellaneous under
miscellaneous that is usually where i
put
what i spent on for gas as well as any
like one-time payments that i have
so for example my squarespace account i
just pay it
annually so i'll put that under the
miscellaneous section because it's not
really
shopping and it's not food at all and
then my next section
is my total section so in each previous
section that i have like i mentioned for
my income i have a total income line i
do that for each section so i have
the total bills i pay total loans and
total spending and then for my total
section
i add up all my expenses so that
includes my bills
loans and my spending i take the totals
from
each of those sections and that is in my
total expenses and then my total income
is the same line that i take
from the total income section underneath
that i have my net total so
this is how much i've saved or how much
money i've
i have left over so for my budget for
this past month
i will be putting it in percentages i'm
not really comfortable
with sharing the exact numbers but i
feel like percentages is more helpful
for those of you that are trying to
emulate a budget
that will help you aggressively save so
out of my total income i spent 15
of my income towards bills i spent
around 10
of my income towards my loans and i
spent
around 22 of my income towards spending
so in total i spent about 47 of my
income and i
save 53 of my income
i know not everyone can do this but i've
been aggressively saving
so in my emergency savings video
i mentioned how important it is to build
a budget it's definitely the first way
for you to get started on saving
aggressively and making sure you have
enough money in your bank
in case of any expenses so i've already
saved up to a fully funded savings
account but now i am currently
aggressively saving
for another goal which is moving out as
some of you may know i am currently
living at home
and i plan on moving out of the state
and probably out of the country with
juan and so
we are just saving up and making sure we
have enough
to easily transition into our next stop
in life so we're really excited for that
but it
does come with a lot of discipline so
that is why
i am saving a lot of my money for a move
just in case anything happens in case i
don't get a job right away
things like that so that is one of my
more closer goals
that i have with my finances some of my
other goals
include paying off my credit card debt
and also
paying off some of my student loans i
have a lot of student loans
like i mentioned before but they're all
broken up into smaller more manageable
loans
so i have a couple loans that are almost
done
so i do plan on paying those off as well
i also mentioned this in my emergency
savings video
but right now i am currently paying the
minimum
and also interest so that way i'm taking
away the principal total and also taking
away the interest that is occurring on
any of my bills whether it be my credit
card debt or
my loans so those are some of the
reasons why i'm saving
50 of my income because i want to have
a robust savings account but also once i
reach that goal i want to be able to
know that i'll be able to pay off
my credit cards and my loans it's up to
you how you
want to set up your savings maybe you
want to aggressively
pay off your debt for me you can't
get your money back when you pay off
your debt so
it's really important to have that
emergency savings fund before you start
aggressively
paying off your debt other aspects to my
budget
that i really like highly recommend but
you don't have to do it
it's definitely the extra mile when it
comes to budgeting
but that is doing an assets tracker and
a debt tracker
so with excel and google sheets you can
add sheets to your document so the first
sheet
that i have is my budget sheet but then
the next two sheets i have
an assets tracker and a debt tracker at
the end of every month
for my assets i line up all of my
banking accounts in my stocks see how
much assets i have
for my debt i do the same thing but with
my debt
so for my debt tracker i have a section
for my credit card debt
and a section for my loan debt and then
i have a line for total debt i like to
do this because
i want to see the overall debt that i'm
making towards my debt
because you can pay your debt month to
month but you might not be making any
sort of debt to it
you might be paying the minimum payment
but you're not taking off that interest
which may be just as much as the
minimum payment that you're making so
it's really important to keep track of
all your debt so you know that you're
making a dent
and you're closer to that sort of
financial freedom
that you have from your debt i also like
tracking my assets because i like to
know
whether or not i'm saving enough and i
like to know if i'm making incremental
steps towards those goals that i have
such as saving
for moving out and just being able to
manage my money better
so it's been nice i've made a lot of
improvements like i said
about a year ago i wasn't overspender
but that's when i started budgeting and
taking control of my money
since the beginning of this calendar
year i've
improved a lot and i'm very proud of
myself
so the beginning of the calendar year i
had about
four thousand dollars in assets and now
i have nearly twelve thousand dollars in
assets
it may be a lot to some people may not
be a lot to others but
to me that's such a huge improvement
that's eight thousand dollars within
eight months so at that rate i'm saving
about 900 to a thousand dollars a month
which is
really nice also with my debt i made
tremendous
dents towards my credit card debt i
started off with nearly eight thousand
dollars in credit card debt and now i'm
almost down to five thousand
and i definitely made dents in my
student loan debts as well especially
since
they're doing a freeze on student loan
repayments for federal loans
i've been able to focus on the private
loans that i took out
for my schooling so my tesla and my
wristlet which are state-based
so connecticut and rhode island so i
like having the asset tracker in the
debt tracker because
i want to make sure that my assets are
going up while my debt is going down
and yeah that's basically how i set up
my budget and how i do my budget every
month
if you have any questions or concerns
please feel free to comment down below
feel free to reach out to me on any of
my social media accounts
if you like this video give it a thumbs
up let me know if you want to see
any more videos like this and i'll see
you guys in the next video
[Music]
bye