hello friends
what is up you guys welcome back to my
channel
we are in the guest room today we've
never been here before i wanted to sit
here
have a little bit of like a makeup
therapy with you guys
talk about life try new makeup products
talk about really comfortable loungewear
that i'm wearing right now
also can we talk about the new hair your
girl is quite obsessed
i love it she's pretty she's different
she's healthy and i love her i might go
this week and get a haircut
you guys see how like it's just kind of
like sitting there which i love this
hairstyle because then i can do waves i
can curl it
it's easy to do different hairstyles
like today tied it up
however i kind of want to add long
layers so i have more
of a bounce and more personality in my
hair i don't know you guys should
comment down below and let me know what
you think
but i love it so far another thing i've
been loving is what i'm wearing right
now
this is a new loungewear from third love
if you guys follow me on instagram then
you know that your girl is in love with
third love third love has a really
comfortable
underwear bras and now they just came
out with loungewear which
i'm very very very obsessed they sent
over this
i'm wearing the set right now and it's
so so freaking cute
but isn't this so cute we have this top
here
i'm gonna wear this or try it on a
little bit later i haven't tried this
one on yet
but look at these shorts that go with it
we
love comfortable loungewear because we
are homebodies and
that's what we're all about this is like
nothing new i've been
literally obsessed with this and
honestly i've been using it more before
makeup because i feel like it sits
really nicely
on uh underneath makeup for my skin care
if you guys watch my vlogs then you know
like i've been using something different
for skin care
today we're just getting ready for the
day i wanted to put
a very light natural face on just to
look put together
i'm very excited because we're getting
new
furniture this afternoon so we're not
doing anything
crazy with the makeup no lashes nothing
like that tomorrow i'm going to get my
eyebrows clean
so we are going to hydrate hydrate
hydrate i've been so
dry lately so we just want to hydrate
the skin before we go in with primer
i'm very excited for this this is the
new benefit hydrate primer
i'm actually so excited for this primer
right here
hopefully it's really hydrating like it
says and i'm so excited for today's
video because
today's video is in partnership with
third love
which if you guys have been following me
on instagram then
you know you know i've been loving third
love and i'm so grateful to be working
with them because let me tell you
i mentioned them in a previous vlog by
the way so some of you might already
know
third love is a place that you can go
and get really
good quality comfortable bras underwear
and now they have loungewear which is
really exciting but
i hate brawls i'm gonna be honest with
you i hate brows and
whenever i do wear a bra it has to be
extremely comfortable i'm all about
support i'm all about comfort and i'm
all about coverage and i'm all about
quality because bras are very expensive
these days and you want to invest in one
that's going to last you for a very long
time
and something that makes you happy
something that makes you want to wear it
something that feels like you're not
wearing a bra and that's exactly what
third love is
they are probably one of the best bras
that i've ever had and i love them
dearly if you are somebody like me who's
looking for a good bra
third love is the way to go i want to
show you guys my bra that i'm wearing
right now
um first of all this loungewear from
them is so cute i love this color
but you guys look at this bra so i
shared this in a previous video but
i think this is so funny let me just
take this off can we just admire
how cute this bra is so what i love
about it first of all
is the coverage i love love love the
coverage i love the support for the
girls
and it's high quality you can see the
wires right here for the support but
these are not going to poke through in a
few years because this is really high
quality
i definitely had other ones before where
i didn't really invest in them or they
weren't
made well and eventually the wires here
would poke through
and then bruise like the middle of my
chest here leave me a comment
and let me know if you've had one of
those third love doesn't do that
they have really really really high
quality bras
i also love how comfortable the straps
are they just sit really nicely
in on my skin they're not like in my
skin
where they're causing prints or making
me feel uncomfortable
i also love the double layer for this
design so we have the bottom here and
then we have
this comfortable uh see-through material
on top
this is definitely the one bra that i
would recommend to you guys
you can wear this under a t-shirt you
can wear it under a nice blouse it's
very versatile
it's good to have in your closet one of
the main things
that makes me love third love so much is
just go on their website
you'll see it i love their website
because every time i go on it i feel
like
i'm able to wear those things and it's
all about
different shapes and different sizes
it's for everybody
it's diversity and it makes me feel like
i'm a part of something that's super
powerful and
i feel like i can be myself and i love
third love because
i said this in a previous vlog but in
and 2019 i gained a lot of weight
and i was going through a lot of
self-conscious
so it's really hard for me to talk right
now about this in 2018 and 2019 i gained
a lot of weight
and i was very self-conscious about my
body and
i was very uncomfortable my own skin i
would photoshop my instagram photos
i hated looking at myself on camera and
i feel like that's a big part of
also why i didn't vlog as much because
not only do you notice the gateway in
yourself
but then you're on the internet and the
internet sometimes can be such a crappy
place
and you're reminded all the time how
much weight you've gained or how fat you
are or how ugly you are
and it starts affecting your mental
health and
that's also part of the reason like i
said why i just hated looking at myself
on screen
and i would have to tell you third love
reached out to me at the end of 2018
and it was kind of just like this new
chapter
i felt like you know what i love the
body that i am
in and i'm so happy like why am i
letting
other people's opinion of me affect me i
can't control that the only thing that i
can control
is how i react to things and that's been
something that has really helped me get
through
finding myself again and loving my body
and so
whenever i go on the third love website
i guess it's kind of nostalgic
it brings me back to that time of when
truly everything started to change
like it's okay to
not look like others like don't compare
yourself to others like it's okay
like this is flappy like flappy wacky
right here like it's just
okay to be yourself like i like who
cares like i have
a stomach like i have a waist but look i
also have a stomach
like this is belly jelly right here it's
okay to be yourself and i feel like
it has felt so good in 20
sorry i'm gonna get emotional like it
has felt so good in 20
20 21 to like feel myself and be myself
and i wish that i could go back and like
tell that girl in 2018 that
it's okay to love your body and it's
okay to not look like everybody else
that you see on the internet
i i just like i want to put this out
there because i want to set an example
for
young girls and young boys that are
watching out there because i feel like
the generation under ours is just so
social media obsessed which is a bad and
good thing
and having being someone with an
influence and having a platform i
want them to know that you are beautiful
and you do whatever makes you happy and
you don't need to look a certain way or
act a certain way
all you have to be is unapologetically
yourself
and it's it's it's taken a very long
time
for me to get to where i am i feel like
i am entering that chapter like i'm
turning 28 this year
and for the first time in my life i
truly can say like
i just don't care what other people
think of me like i know who i
am i finally realize my truth
and i love me i love my body for the way
it is and
if one day i want to change something
about myself
like i will choose to because it's my
body and i tried so hard for so long
to change people's opinions about me
and it's like that's their opinion you
know i feel like
people are like mirrors whatever they
reflect
is what they're feeling on the inside so
all of these mean comments and all these
super awful cruel
vicious people on the internet i hope
they're okay and that's all that i can
that's all that you can do because you
can't control other people but like i
said you can control
how you react to things and how you feel
and
i've taken some time to work on myself
to love my body again and
she's here and she's here to stay and
she's got flappy this is flappy wappy
it's definitely still been a journey
there are some days when i'm just like
you know
we're not feeling ourselves today and
then some some days i'm just like i'm
fine
so nothing's perfect no one's perfect
there are on and off days you know
anyways i just felt like that was the
right time to express that and
i hope you guys know where i'm coming
from but i do want to share
a few more bras from third love i want
to show you guys that they have so many
variety
this is another favorite of mine i love
this everything is just
high high high quality like these bras
are going to last you
i love this one i'm all about comfort
i'm in t-shirts and hoodies and crew
necks half the time you guys watch my
vlogs you know i'm a homebody like i
wear sweats out in public
i love love love comfort i love that
there's gonna be so much variety for the
loungewear and it's so
comfortable like i can live in the set
like when you guys watch my vlog you
will know
but i love these and then i also have
another one this is how much i love it i
have a backup bra
and then we also have this really sexy
black one i love this
how sexy is this pattern design right
here
and then i want to show you guys the
high quality straps
look at how stretchy everything is
and how high quality everything is we
have even like the gold hardware
this is really pretty and then we also
have this lace one
we love a little lace moment i love it
so much and then look at this oh my
goodness and look at all the stretch
this is a close favorite of mine i love
this this would probably be in second
place
i just love how beautiful the designs
are
but they still make it comfortable like
you shouldn't have to choose
between comfort and having a cute-ass
bra you know
like you can have both and that's what i
think it is like i just love everything
about this one this one i've warned
like 10 times already like i love this i
love the color as well they have great
color selections
and i love that this section here
doesn't go super tight on the side of my
uh body because then i have like extra
fat bulging
out i just love this and then we also
have a strapless
bra i'm always down for this sometimes
you wear dresses that require a
strapless bra and then what i love about
the strapless bra here is
they have this kind of texture material
here so it's not
going to move when you guys wear it if
you guys are
unsure of your size they have this
feature on the website called the
fitting room
and you can go on and take a very
detailed test and find out your perfect
size
and don't worry if a bra doesn't fit
they have a 60 day guaranteed so you can
send it back and they'll gladly take it
also if you guys are looking for
half cup sizes third love also has that
most brands have like 30 sizes i believe
third love has 80. so they definitely
have a variety you guys should check
them out i do have a discount code it's
kim tai
and that takes 20 off your first order
but i think i should like start putting
makeup on because
my primer already probably has dried
into my skin
i'm using this foundation today and i'm
honestly
so excited so i was doing my foundation
and i realized that we were not
recording so that's
great we love that so what we don't love
is this foundation
i'm going to be returning this this is
the morphe filter light 8 foundation
yeah not my favorite it's not really
looking good on
my skin and i don't know if maybe it's
not
compatible with a brush but i don't know
i just don't think it's good for dry
skin
because my skin is dry right now not too
sure about this one
i'm just gonna like blend this in and
just like hope that a miracle happens
also with natural lighting i feel like
it's in and out in and out sometimes i'm
going to be brighter and sometimes i'm
going to be a little bit on the darker
side
so i do apologize we're using natural
lighting which personally i love because
i feel like you guys can really see the
products
and it just feels more casual like i
feel like we're really hanging out you
know
honestly i'm very very very sad about
that foundation i really wanted it to
to work but it's okay
thank god i can return things right
i am using this new bronzer which i'm
very excited about i hope this one works
i like light bronzer you guys
nothing too much especially when i'm not
wearing a full face of makeup
we love a light bronzer
i was like honestly sitting here talking
to
my best friend brooke the other day and
i was just telling her i was like i feel
like
people should just stop commenting on
other people's bodies and i'm not
talking about like commenting on
instagram or like youtube
i feel like just commenting on other
people's bodies in general
because you feel you like don't know i'm
honestly just ranting right now because
i feel like we're just hanging out and
and doing makeup together but what i was
saying is like i feel like you just
don't know what people are going through
like you just don't you don't know if
someone's like low-key
not feeling their body in some way i
know when i was
gaining weight i was going through a lot
of like mental things in my head
and it was really hard you know i don't
know if you guys can relate i definitely
have said this before and i feel like a
lot of people
have said oh my god that's like the same
thing in my culture
i feel like in the asian culture they
like have no filter
like growing up even when i was like at
my skinniest
i would have like aunts and cousins come
to parties and be like oh
like you look like you gained some
weight or oh my god like they would like
pinch your arm or whatever not like in a
vicious way
it's kind of like a teasing way but that
really effs up someone's mental health
like growing up i was like 115 pounds
120 pounds
and whenever i looked in the mirror i
was like i feel fine
i look fine i would always oh my god i
would always google
like what is that thing called be bmi
i think it's like body mass index or
something and if you type in your weight
and your height
if you're over a certain number you're
like consider
like under medical terms like overweight
and then
if you're in between a certain spectrum
you're considered
normal or something like that something
like that i don't know i learned it
i think in health class but i would like
always like this is so bad i would
always type in my weight
and my height and it would say normal
but then i would see like these
relatives and they would be like oh you
look
fat and that mentally really destroyed
me
and then as the years like as the years
went on
when i was gaining weight it just got
worse and worse it's like hey
like you know you're gaining weight like
maybe you know and it's like
i know that like when it comes to family
in the in like the vietnamese culture
it's not coming from like a bullying
aspect
it's coming from like a good place i
don't know how to explain it it's like
really hard to explain
body image issues in the vietnamese
culture it's it's super hard to explain
it i don't even know where to start
because i don't want you guys to think
that like my family is super mean to me
that's not the case i love my family and
they love me so much but
that's like the one thing i would change
and i always tell carlos this i'm like
when we have kids
like i don't care if it's a boy or a
girl like that [ __ ] is not gonna fly
with me like i don't want any of that
unnecessary comments
not saying that i want my child to grow
up thinking he or she is completely
perfect
that's not the case the case is i don't
want my child growing up
thinking that they need to look a
certain way or need to be at a certain
weight or they're not considered
beautiful if they're
in this weight uh range or that weight
range you know
i don't know it's just like i feel like
we should just stop commenting on
people's bodies in general because
someone could yeah be losing weight or
for example like someone could be skinny
or in your eyes skinny and you can be
like oh like
you look like you lost some weight or
and they didn't do anything new and they
could be like oh like was i fat
like it it it makes people especially
people that already have
self-image issues like i did like it it
like
[ __ ] with you like it messes with your
head i just feel like we should just
stop in general
i don't know it's just and i feel like
social media doesn't help because i feel
like
in 2017 when i was really really really
indulged in social media
i wanted so badly to look like the girls
that i saw online and the only way to do
that was obviously to photoshop
like i have to facetune the [ __ ] out of
my body i wanted to look like those
girls i
in my mind in 2017 was like if i
look like them i'll get more likes i'll
be more likable people will like me
and it's just so unhealthy like so
freaking unhealthy
and it took a very long time for me to
realize that it took me a long time
to finally this year sit down and be
like
i love flappy waffy and i love belly
jelly you know i just we're
all so beautiful in our own ways and
sometimes it takes
everybody like a different amount of
time to realize it but once you get
there
and once you realize how [ __ ]
beautiful you are it's like the
best feeling ever like i honestly have
gotten to the point in my life where i
just don't care
like i just do not care what people
think of me i'm happy
with who i am and i can do what i want
to my body it's
my body it's my temple and i'm gonna
take care of it like that's my mindset
i just want ah i i so badly wanna go
back to like
18 year old kim and like 25 year old kim
and just be like hey like you're fine
the way you
are like ugh it's just i don't know it's
it's something that by the way love this
bronzer uh
i don't know it's just something i've
thought about and i just i want
i want you guys to be sitting at home
watching this video
and realizing that too but i also don't
expect people
to wake up the next day loving their
self and yeah yeah yeah you know like
it's a journey and it's it's gonna take
a while but i just want you to know that
you're gonna get there
and you have to take baby steps and you
have to take care of your
temple and protect it from all of the
all of the bad energy out there it's
truly a mirror it's like
it's truly how people what what energy
people put out into the world is you is
truly a reflection of how they feel
about themselves and what the hell is
going on in their life
it truly is it's all about energy and
you got to surround yourself with really
good people
really good energy as well um i also
want to try this bronzer
oh my god this bronzer smells like
cookies i freaking love it
we're just gonna bronze it up today huh
why not i cannot explain to you
how good this feels this is a butter
bronzer
by physicians formula
do you guys see how like i'm bare i'm
just like i'm not really contouring i'm
just warming up my face
it doesn't look different but i see it
oh we love and we smell so good all of a
sudden
oh i love a natural face it's me but
better you know
oh it's getting bright out oh she's
getting bright outside
ugh this is like the downfall of filming
with natural lighting it's like
the lighting is not consistent like it
was just kind of dark and now it's super
bright out
but i feel like you can see makeup a
little bit better
i really want you guys to comment down
below and like let me know your thoughts
on everything i just i love social media
but the internet can be such a shitty
place and
that's coming from somebody that does
social media for a living
you guys don't see the comments that i
get like it's
super insane how crazy people can be
i also think it's just so wild
that people can be so mean behind a
keyboard like i
i just i i can't do it like but
however i must admit at one point
i was that troll though at one point
when i was 18 i hated my life
hated hated hated my life i was honestly
i don't use this word lightly i was
depressed
when i was 18 i hated my life i was
depressed had
major self-image issues was going
through
a really rough mental state no one knew
because when you grow up in the
vietnamese household ain't nobody got
time for mental health and it's the
shittiest thing in the world like
i actually can't wait to raise kids
because i'm so excited
to focus on things that were not focused
for me growing up and i feel like i had
to learn
on my own i feel like lightning just
went down again i
was very comfortable behind a keyboard
because one i didn't have
any friends i had just moved to
california had no friends and i was
trying
so hard to be somebody that i wasn't
online
i would like say things i would talk
about other people online it was
straight up shitty like i was such a
shitty person
like i look back now and i was like damn
let me be your friend kim tai like let
me help you
get out of the hole that you're in and i
just feel like
i was always like reaching i was always
like reaching for someone to help me
and it sucks but i didn't really like i
didn't really
have a friend at the time like brooke
and i weren't talking brook had moved to
florida for college i was in california
i had no friends in california people
that i met in class like you're not
gonna find your bff
i really had no one and i was so
fascinated
kind of like painting this false
personality online
um so i know like i know why people do
the things that they do online because i
once was there like i
once was a reflection of what i was
feeling
like i released negative energy and
that's all that i got in return and it
wasn't until
i reached a point where i was like okay
hold up
i'm a shitty person and i'm doing shitty
things and i need to change that around
and switch things around like i would be
like oh my god like i hate
i hate girls that wear colored eyes like
who the [ __ ] do you think you are like
oh my god i was
i'm like honestly embarrassed to talk
about 18 year old me that was
literally oh my god i'm turning 28 this
year that was that's
10 years ago that is crazy to me um 10
10 years ago i was a very very crappy
person i will be the first to admit
but thank god i grew from it like thank
goodness
in the 10 years i grew up i hope people
grow up in 10 years to be honest
like you're supposed to be growing up
and i feel like that's another thing too
i started youtube when i was 21 i had
just recently turned
21 years old and that's when i started
youtube and
i feel like people forget that you
grow up in seven years like you go
through life things
you go through obstacles in life and you
go through hardship and you have
you have your ups and downs a person is
gonna change you know
i feel like i've changed so much in
seven years i mean a lot has changed in
the past year
getting engaged having this house like
maybe having a kid in the next year or
two so it's
it's just crazy i feel like my mind has
mature and like
when you reach that point where you just
feel so namaste with your life
you look back and you just want to help
your younger self like what would you
guys say to your younger self if you
could
what would you tell your younger self
that is like a really good question of
the day
so like comment down below and be like
what were you going through at a certain
time and what would you tell
your younger self if i could i would
just go back to
18 year old me i mean i still made
mistakes though like i still made
mistakes when i was like 22
23 24 25 like you know what but that's
part of life
you live and you learn and you're gonna
make mistakes and you're gonna grow out
of them and
and that's life and that's the beauty of
it that's how you become the person that
you're becoming
i'm gonna wear my favorite blush this is
milani luminoso
it is literally my favorite thing in the
world
did they change the packaging milani
changed the packaging
luminoso never used to look like this
oh my goodness oh oh this brush is
very very hard
and that ladies and gents is why i love
luminoso it is the most beautiful blush
with this can we just
can we just look at it okay no luminoso
luminoso do you see that glow from
within
i'm not even trying y'all like look at
this okay no luminoso
and then luminoso
oh milani luminoso is my favorite
i have backups of it i love it so much
we're also going to go in with a little
bit of highlight today i know
you guys it's been a long time um is
this one not opened
oh wow can thai i thought i opened this
you guys
i used to use this religiously i need to
get my nails done
i got my nails done and then i like
chopped them off because they were too
long so i need to fix them there we go
okay i'm gonna just dab a little bit
and blend it in with the blush because
i don't really have a full face i just
i'm all about the skin to be honest
whenever
whenever i'm doing makeup this is like
an everyday look
i love sitting here and just chatting
with you guys this video might be like
super long but just talking about third
love and how much they
appreciate body positivity and
different body types and shapes and
stuff just
just spark that in me i don't know it's
just you know and it's something that
i'm working on too
like loving your body is not an everyday
thing
like you don't wake up every day loving
your body and i totally get that because
i have days where i'm just like nope
today is not the day
but tomorrow could be there's always the
tomorrow could be you know
i'm gonna go in with my favorite
lipstick as a lipstick color today
we are doing mac cosmetic velvet teddy
there she is the velvet teddy
oh my gosh it is the most beautiful
everyday color i used to wear this all
the time in college
like 2014 kim used to love this color
and can we just appreciate the focus on
this camera it's like the prettiest
lipstick ever
it matches my lips perfectly it's such a
good everyday
oh yeah
you guys have to go and buy velvet teddy
velvet teddy is so good
oh my god i love this glow look at that
can we just add a little bit more blush
in my world in my world not your world
in my world
i'm just kidding in my world there is
never a such thing as too much blush
we love her we accept her
she's amazing
sometimes i get excited and i put it all
over
oh oh yes i'm gonna spray my face today
because
it's feeling dry this is the fenty
beauty uh what i do
makeup refreshing spray it's actually
called what it do
oh my god i love the mist you guys see
that nope you guys don't see that
oh it smells expensive i love it
honestly
i'm all about the easy peasy also
i oh sorry for all the hair that's kind
of gross i got this brush
at the dollar tree
you guys it is such a good brush
oh there we go so yeah i got this brush
at the dollar tree the other week
it is such a
good brush let me tell you oh my god
i want to go back and get more
oh oh yes hair
oh i want to show you guys my lounge
wear that i'm wearing today isn't this
so
freaking cute okay this is from sorry
had a wedgie this is from third love
i'm wearing black underwear so don't
mind it
it's like a full set so it comes with
this crew neck
and then you can also get the bottoms
here as well the shorts are so
comfortable
i love it so much oh my god
it's such a cute set you guys should
definitely check out their love
use my discount code you get 20 off your
first purchase
i will link all this down below but this
is my favorite i'm gonna wear it today
well hey you guys thank you so much for
hanging out with me and having a little
chit chat
i am gonna go on with my day i'm very
excited we have new furniture today
which is
very very very exciting oh my god i love
this brush
who knew a dollar could be so amazing
do not forget to check out third love
down below i will list the link
to everything please please please use
my discount code 20
off on your first purchase use it and
get my favorite bra
i will list my favorite bra down below
for you guys it is going to change your
life it is the most comfortable thing in
the world
just trust me okay i will see you guys
in the next video
thank you for having a heart to heart
with me it feels so good to have someone
to talk to i mean this is why i started
youtube in 2014.
thank you so much for uh spending your
time with me
and being my friend i'm so grateful that
i have
people all over the world to talk to and
that's the reason why i started youtube
in the first place
i just love not only sharing my life
with you guys but
knowing that you guys are truly the most
amazing friends in the world like
i appreciate you i'm grateful for you
and
i love you so much i will see you guys
in the next video
goodbye