hi guys welcome back
to my channel today
I'm going to be doing
a update on my
ancestry DNA results
so if you don't
know or if you're
new to my channel I
did an ancestry DNA
test two years ago
and recently it was
updated I think they
did the update maybe
like a month ago or
a few months ago
so because of the
updates my results
changed dramatically
I would say if you
don't know the
results that I had the
last time I would
suggest to click on
the insert DNA video
that I have on my
channel and just to
watch that one all
the way through so
you are up to date
so if you look on
that video I was so
excited I was so so
so excited about my
ancestry DNA results
and I don't know the
results that I have
now they're not
they're still kind of
the same not they're
different they're
different there are
some similarities
but there's a lot
of things that are
completely different
than what I had the
first time around the
first time around
I was super excited
about my results but
it's just I'm just
gonna show you and
tell you how like
what my results were
this time this time
around my results
overall is said
that I'm 87 percent
African 12 percent
European and then 1%
Native American so
yeah I mean if that's
those overall change
it it did change a
little bit you like
unless European
where African that
my first results so
let me just so on
the thing it says
there's an updated
estimate and right
off the bat it says
that I am 41 percent
Cameroon and Congo
which is it's great
because I did really
love how high my
percentage of Cameroonian
it was before
but it's completely
different from from
my history and not DNA results
that I did I took the
first time around
the first time around
they said I was majority
gunning and now
they're saying I'm
a journey majority
Cameroon Congo and
then got my night my
gun and results are
only ten percent so
okay let me just
read it off first of
all it says 41 percent
Cameroon Congo 19
percent Benina toggle
10 percent Ghana
9% Mali you have the
four I mean you
have the eight percent
great brain all
my last results it
says that it was four
percent so increased
by four I also have
Nigeria six percent
Sweden two percent
Africa's sausage
hunter-gatherers that
same design the same
two percent and I
have the same Native
American in 1
percent
I have Italy as 1
percent Ireland and
Scotland as my
president so this is
really is just so
different from my last
results please because
as you can see
some results increased
like my Ivory
Coast and Ghana that
decreased by 23%
the Cameroon Congo
that increased by set
like by 19% and I
need to talk about
increased by 16 percent
and then as you
scroll down it says
that these items are
no longer in my
estimate at all so
there's no African
Africa sent something
doesn't man - there's
no Senegal there's
no Finland and
more therus Russia
there's no European
Jewish and there's
no more of like these
other things and
[Music]
and this is they
said that update is
because they got you
know more DNA their
DNA is a lot better
a lot stronger they
have a lot more samples
so this is why
the the update
happened but it's also
really really
frustrating and kind of
kind of like damn
okay because when you
first get those DNA
results I mean like
as a black person
in America and you
kinda are like oh
okay Dan like this
like what I am even
though I know that
it's just like I said
on my other video
is just just like a
well educated guess
as to me so and it was
just sort of kind
of disappointing
innocence that I feel
like if it changed a
little bit then I
would have been alright
but it changed
so much it was such
a drastic change
that I was just I
kind of I was like
okay like what like
so everything that
you told me was a lie
so you lied to me
and this is why I
have trust issues but
no it's just really
interesting to me
how things can dose
those DNA like that
change so dramatically
and reason why
I'm doing this video
because I'm very
much interested in
how you guys did did
you get an update for
your ancestry DNA
results was that
as traumatic as a
change that I had
and if I'm being
honest these results
make a lot more
sense than my last
results if I'm being
completely honest
like cuz I was really
trying hard to think
like how my Russian
how am i from Finland
how like way like
European Jewish
like happy like who
house beds like I was
really trying to
make the connections
but it does make
more sense for me
to be for these
results great Brendan
that makes it
slavery okay the other
ones I was kind
of out struggling to make the
connections and a
lot of you in the
comments
y'all are also kind
of struggling to
make the connections
y'all were like oh
well maybe this
time he maybe just
happened maybe that
happened I was like
maybe but yeah this
was just really an
eye-opener for me I
but like I said in
the last video this
doesn't change how I
didn't
as myself I'm still
a black American
every day in my life
so in all honesty
like don't take these
these sort of dnh has
so hard like I say
today is just an
estimate I guess the
man don't take it to heart
it doesn't really I
mean I'm not gonna
say it doesn't really
mean anything it
means a little bit
of some Sun but if
they make him a space
like this I don't
know but yes thank you
guys for watching
this video do I
feel like I've been
swindled do I feel
like I got the bang
for my buck for my
money I'm gonna say
yeah I do kind of
feel like I've been
swindled a little bit
I thought that I
was something or they
made it out so I
can be something even
they they did say
estimate so I can't
be then I'll make it
say estimate but these
estimates are so
they were off they
were off so I do kind
of feel like I've been
swindled a little
bit but at the end
of the day you know
it's all good fine
I'm just as happy to
be 41% Cameroonian
then I was to be what
was like 30% getting
in the last time if
you liked this video
give it a thumbs up
be sure to like share
with your friends
and family members
who are thinking
about my ancestry you
naked or any other
ancestry kids just
let them know that
this is not this is
not real it's a bit
falsified and that
they should you know
really think about
this before they put
a lot of stock into
these results I will
see you guys in