hey y'all welcome
back to my channel so
today i wanted to
do a get to know me
tag because
we made it to 10 000
subscribers if you
haven't subscribed
yet click subscribe
button to join the family
i've been doing youtube
for about like
three years
maybe a little bit
more than that so i
really love that our
little family is
growing and i'm like
i'm just so excited
because like even
though this is a smaller channel
we are really growing
like we're getting
our rings we're going to college
we're getting married
all this sort of
stuff so i'm just
excited and because of
this i want you guys
to get to know a
little bit more about
me and for me to
get to know a little
bit more about
y'all
i'll just link the
questions that i'm
answering in this video in the
description
box down below so you
guys should answer
the questions along with me
first question is
what is your name my
name is marquisha
i know my channel
name is misfit mari
but
my real name is
marquisha i get that
from my dad his name
is marquise so my
name is marquisha
so you can call me
mari you can call me
quisha but don't
call me marikrisha
because that is not
my name so yeah
that's where i got
the name of my channel
miss fit mari
from how old are you
i am 25 years old
i'm about to be 26
i know like i'm so
old it's kind of
crazy
usually when people
find out how old i
am they're like what
you're 26 i'm like
yeah i'm like i'm
pretty old
i think it's because
i'm like super
skinny and i'm so short so
i just look like i
should be like in
high school or something
where are you from i
was born in chicago
illinois but now i
live in indiana and
i've grown up in
indiana my pretty much
my entire life since i was eight
a lot of people when
i tell them i'm
from indiana they're
like indiana
where is that what do
you have there and
i'm just like you know
we got cornfields and
stuff that's fun
and they're like wow
i didn't even know
black people existed
in indiana i'm like
yeah we barely exist here
what is your sign
i am technically
a virgo but i
believe in the cups
signs so a cup sign
is like when you're
born at the end or at
the very beginning
of each sign
cycle so i was born
on the 21st of
september so that's like
basically the end
of virgo season and
almost the beginning
of libra so i you
know i feel like i
represent both signs
technically i'm a
virgo but i believe
that i'm a virgo libra cuss
my moon sign is aries
and my rising sign
is sagittarius
are you an extrovert
or an introvert so
i am an introvert i'm a very
introverted person
i've been like this
since
before i can even
remember i've always
been an introvert
when people talk to
me i'm super shy
even when i get to
know someone like i'm
more of a listener
than a talker which
is funny because
i have a youtube
channel but
when people meet me
in person they're
like oh you're so
quiet like you don't
really say much
i'm like yeah like
i'm just surviving
what's my favorite
song at the moment
okay i listen to a
lot of different
music but i think
that my favorite song
right now is the pop
smoke song and it's
like
how does the song go oh
okay it's shiny my little body
that's my little boo
thing and shorty
got the fatty
shall i be catching
mood swings that's
my favorite song
what is on your bucket
list so i have a
lot of things on my
bucket list i made
it like a couple years
ago and that includes
like learning how
to surf and visiting
like a volcano but
one thing that's on
my bucket list that
i really want to do
is to get married to
a stranger in vegas
so
i have this scene in
my head where like
i go to vegas i
meet this stranger
just random person we click
me and this person
click soul mates um
we get super super drunk
and he's like you
know what we should
get married and i'm
like you know what
we should get married
and then elvis
marries us in vegas and
that that is on my bucket list
favorite youtubers
okay my favorite
youtubers
are travel channels
i also like vlog
channels and a little
bit of beauty but
i like watching a lot of smaller
youtubers
so i like watching
like just doing me
i like lydia ginga
even though she's not
a smaller channel
she's pretty big i
like watching her
i like watching of
course the ogs like
raven elise
and jayla corian and
all those people
like i like watching
their channels
um who else who else
like but i usually
like watching a lot
of smaller youtube
channels just
because i'm a small
channel too
and i feel like smaller
channels are a
lot more
real in a sense so
i'll put a list of
like the smaller
channels that i watch
here too so you guys
can like check them
out as well
what is your most
i don't even know why
i put this on here
one of my most
embarrassing moments was
when
i was in middle school
so i was on the
bus
and i had like my
backpack and i i
forget like what i was
doing my backpack
i think i had to
like check something
like check homework or something
so i didn't close my
backpack like all
the way i thought i
did but i didn't
so as i was like
getting off the bus
like my backpack
flew open and all my
papers and stuff like
were everywhere and
this was like right
in front of the middle school
at my middle school
like all the like
the cool kids and
stuff would like hang
out
in front of the
school before school
starts
so you can only imagine
a middle school
me
with my glasses and
my little ponytail
in the bang like all
my papers like flew
everywhere i was like i was so
embarrassed but
people were really
really nice they were like
and they helped me
get up all my papers
because it was a lot of papers
so like literally like
i think like five
people helped me get up
get my papers up but it was so
embarrassing it was
so embarrassing
what do you want to
do with your life
isn't that the big
question like what do
you want to do with your life
i think overall like
if i could live the
life that i want to live
i would probably travel
like 24 7 like i
love
traveling so much
like it's crazy
so i would travel all
the freaking time
and i would get paid for it
a lot of people want
to get settled down
get married have
kids but that's not
really my goal my goal
is to travel like
if i could travel
forever for the rest
of my life that
would be the best thing
to me what's the
next place on your
travel list
so i really want
to visit an asian
country i want to go to
japan like japan has
been on my wish
list ever since i was
in middle school
so i really want
to go to an asian
country next like
i've been to european
countries within south
african countries
south american countries
i really really
want to go to an asian country
so so badly what is
your biggest fear
so my biggest fear
is probably like my
biggest fear
isn't death i know a
lot of people say
their biggest fear
is like it's death
dying
um but i'm not
scared of death just
because i know it's gonna come
no matter what so
you can't really do
anything about death
so i think it's
dying without living
the life that i
want to live
or dying without
doing all the things
that i want to do
or dying without
living
to like my highest potential
if that makes sense
so there's a lot of
things that i want to
do i want to see i
want to experience so if i die
without doing those
things like that's
probably the biggest
one of the biggest
fear
that i have what are
your pet peeves
so i would say the
biggest pet peeve of
mine are
like people who are
constantly negative
i understand that
you know life isn't
all rainbows and
unicorn sunshine
poop and throw up
whenever i speak to
someone and they
always have something
negative to say
then that like is a
really really like
big pet peeve of mine
like yo like come
on now like
life you know kind
of sucks sometimes
but life is also really
beautiful people
who are very rude
i don't like that like
that is a big pet
peeve of mine like
why like why are you
being so rude to this
person or why are
you like
like so angry all the
time when do you
want to have kids and
how many kids do
you want
um i don't
so i don't think i
want to have any kids
the thought of having kids just
kind of freaks me out
i think that if i
do have kids it won't
be until i'm like
45 or 50 and then
like i'll probably
adopt
and the kids that i
adopt will probably
be teenagers
the thought of like
taking care of a
baby
all the time it doesn't
it doesn't sit well
with my spirit so if
anybody wants my eggs
like you can have
them they're up for
sale what do you look for in a
relationship
so this is a good
question um usually
i'm like i'm a serial
dater so i usually
date like a lot of people
but i don't really get into
relationships often at all
because i believe
that dating is for
dating and it's to
get to know a person
and then when you're
in a relationship
that means that you
look at this person
as a viable partner
so for me i only get
into a relationship
when i see the other
person
as like a potential
husband one of the
biggest things that
i look for like
in a partner is
like being someone
trustworthy
someone who is very
nice and very very
generous
someone who's really
attentive because
you know i'm not gonna
lie like i like
i like attention and
just someone who's
like what i can
depend on like very
very dependable and
someone who's fun like
i want to have fun
like i want to do
things i want to go
places i want to
have fun
also financial stability
is a really big
thing for me
so someone who's
financially stable like
come on now but
thank you guys for
watching
uh remember to post
like your answers to
some of these questions
in the comment section
below yeah so
hopefully you guys
learned a little bit
more about me
um and i will see
you guys in my next
video
bye