if I won the lottery
right now how would
I spend it
[Music]
hey everyone so I
wanted to do a quick
get to know me tag
I've been posting a
lot of videos but I
feel like you guys
don't really know me
and who I am so um
yeah I'm gonna do
this tag and I have
the questions on my
phone so I'll be
looking down at that
but let's get into
it a one when were
you born so I was
born September 4th
1995 I'm 23 years old
and I have the same
birthday as Beyonce
which is cool in theory but she
definitely still a
little bit of my
shine um - where are
you from and are
you proud of it
so I'm from Las Vegas
Nevada I was born
here I was raised
here I'm and I lived
here currently however
I went to college
in Virginia and I
interned in Seattle
and so I had those
two experiences
outside of Las Vegas
am i proud of it
yes because like
everywhere I go and I
tell people I'm from
Las Vegas they're
like oh my gosh
that's so cool I'm so
jealous blah blah
blah but personally I
would have wished
to be like born
somewhere else like
maybe the south or
New York it just
seems like a little
more diverse and more
exciting and I can
see myself moving
to one of those
locations and when was
the last time you
cried so this is
funny I'm 23 but I'm
still a crybaby I
still cry when I get
my feelings hurt I
don't know why I
can't help it but
last time I cried was
my sister spoiled
the show this is us
for me and they're
just really annoyed
me I was like how
dare you spoil it and
it was more of a
build-up because I feel
like my mom and my
sister like their
goal in life is to
spoil shows for me
like they'll try and
be sneaky about it
like oh I'm not
spoiling the story but
this happened and so
I was just really
upset I really like
that show so that
was the last time I
cried but that was
actually like a week
ago so it's been a
while since I cried it's not
I cried yesterday do
you have kids if no
how many do you want
so no I do not have
any kids I would say
I want two kids one
boy one girl um I
definitely would
want at least two so
they could have like
that like sibling
bond like I feel
like that bond is
unmatched like you
don't have that bond
with anyone else so
I would say the two
kids but the most I
would have is four
like if I was like
in a crazy situation
where I decided to
have a ton of kids it
would be maxed out at
four um what's the
first thing you notice
about people so I
noticed two things I
noticed their smile
and then I noticed
their overall like
aura and their energy
like I noticed
that they have
negative energy or
positive energy if
they seemed like a
friendly person or
you know a confident
person or insecure person
I just noticed their
energy that's like
really something that
I'm drawn to but
other than that would
be their smile if
they smile at me um
I noticed that what
is your zodiac sign
and do you believe
in astrology so my
son sign is Virgo
September 4th but
my moon sign is
Capricorn do I believe
in astrology so I
want to say no right
like the right
answers no I don't
believe in astrology
however I do kind of believe in
astrology because
there are a few signs
that I get along with
really well and a
few signs that I
don't get along with
really well so I
mean I think it's
interesting to look
into but I don't
think it's like an
end-all be-all like
definitely not
discounting a person
based on their sign
but I do normally
ask people when I
meet them like what's
your sign and it
will remind me about
them so order like
remind me of other
people like them do
I have any siblings
so yes I have two
sisters I'm one older
sister who is 34 and
a younger sister
who is 20 about to
be 21 she thinks
she's grown
she's not how tall are you
I am five five
what's your favorite
drink so it's the
same alcoholic or
non-alcoholic so
non-alcoholic is water
I don't drink anything
but water like
occasionally I'll
drink a sweet tea or
lemonade but I
pretty much strictly
drink water and
alcoholic I would say a
creme vodka or like
the old me like back
in the day it would be like an
Incredible Hulk which
is Hennessy and
Hpnotiq so but now
in the stage of my
life I'm a creme vodka
Queen like that's
all I drink
so Crane vodka and
water it was pretty
much all I drink
I also like mimosas
so cran Baca water
and mimosas um what
would you name your
children so I I don't
know why but I
really love the name
Olivia like I mean
also scandal Olivia
Pope but I love the
name Olivia like I
totally want to name
my daughter Olivia
like nickname Molly
nickname live like
so I'll probably end
up naming my daughter Olivia
but we'll see um and
then as far as like
a son's name I
really like the name
David because I
King David it's my
favorite character
in the Bible so like
I don't know I like
the name David but I
don't know if it would
be like a middle
name or first name um those are
basically the only
two names I thought
about who are some
of your favorite
youtubers so my favorite
youtuber is DDG
and it's funny because
I don't know DDG
I feel like his
audience is like all
these young kids
in like elementary
middle and high school
and I'm like this
grunt wente three
year old woman loving
DDG but I love his
energy I love that he
look double and triple uploads
I love how like raw
and real he is like
you don't see that with a lot of
youtubers like DDG
is like the realest
youtuber out there
I love his grind I
listened to his music
when he's like go watch
this video or go
stream my music a go
stream it on repeat
like I'm a big DDG
supporter I love him
I'm I also love fly
with Stella because
I wanted to be a flight
attendant but on
top of that I just
love her personality
I love Jay McCrory on
Aliya Jay briefing
at least TV Shane
Dawson I love Shane
Dawson he's a freaking
genius like his
series he just has
people like binge
watching and I'm
like addicted I've
always loved Shane
like even when he did
his conspiracy there
I'm in way before
it's like when he was
like Jenny Craig
B's or should I say
like Jimmy Smith
Bay's blank I don't
know I love Shane
Dawson but yeah uh
what phone do you
have I have the iPhone
XS in gold I just
got it I'm loving it
what's the farthest
you've been from home
I would say either
Paris France or Spain
Barcelona Spain
I'm not sure which
is actually five I
have to live on the
mat but I'll just
say Europe um I went
to here at this
March and that's the
farthest that I've
been away from home
if I could live
anywhere where would
it be I would love
to live in New York
City I'm either
Manhattan or Brooklyn
really any of the
borough's as long
as I was like in a
comfortable space
um I'm definitely a
city girl and it's
definitely like my
dream to move to New
York City so um I'm
planning on doing
that like hopefully
next year that's my
plan I plan to move
to New York City
next year and I love
New York City I
don't see me living
there like for the
rest of my life but I
do see spending like
a little bit of
time there like I have
to check that off
my bucket list living
in New York City
um what are some of
your favorite TV
shows why said this
is us I love that
show
insecure love a big
brother like I'm a
the biggest Big Brother fan ever
freaking love big
brother um those are
the main show I don't
really watch a ton
of TV I'm more on you too
all my free time I
like dear white
people on Netflix um
yeah and I like the
new LeBron show the
shop he had Drake on
it so it's like
you gotta love it
my favorite movie
um is Black Panther
what is your favorite
book my favorite
book is the Bible have
you ever been out
of the country yes I
just mentioned that
so I've been to
Europe I've been to
London Barcelona and
Paris and then I've
also been to the
Dominican Republic my
favorite place is
definitely the dr like
freakin love the dr
i could just move
there and live there permanently
um london you'd be
number two really
reminds me of new york
i need how much i
love new york um then barcelona
I mean Barcelona was
amazing as well it
was like the highlight
of my European
vacation and then
laughs would be Paris
Paris was beautiful
literally the most
beautiful place I've
ever been like the
Eiffel Tower is
breathtaking but I
really didn't like
the culture and I
mean I don't speak French
I tried I learned
like a little bit of
French to get around
but I don't know
Paris would be at the
bottom of my list
places I want to go
Italy Mexia I want
to go to pretty much
like all the major
cities in Italy
Toronto Canada um I
would think those
are the two biggest
like international
trips on my radar for
now can I sing no I
cannot sing everyone
literally always
asked me like can I
sing and the answer
is no I'm a horrible
singer I did not get
that trait passed
down to me do you
have any allergies so
when I was a kid um
I had a really bad
allergic reaction
to an avocado so
basically they told
me I was allergic to
avocados welcome only
like anything with
avocado in it and so
I basically spent
my whole life up until
like avoiding avocados avoiding
guacamole Mexican
food is my favorite
food so you know
that's hard right like
all the time I go to
Mexican restaurants
and they're like um
walk and I'm like
nope
can't have it so earlier
this year I was
just like you know
what like I'm older
now
like I'm not a kid
but I want to try
cuacamole like let's
see what happens
still I like to Cafe
Rio and I got like
a guacamole on the
side and I was just
gonna eat a little
bit and see my
reaction but it was
so good that I
literally like ate
way more than I
should have and I was
nervous like I'm
better go to laugh
at all like I'm back
I'm about to take
like 20 benadryl
luckily nothing
happened so I'm just
like okay baby my
theory is right so I
just kept slowly
eating guacamole
now welcome Ali's
like my favorite food
I totally see the
hype I love guacamole
yes I want Waka moly
on my bowl I will
pay the extra $2 I
think it's cuz I've
been deprived all
these years um what
kind of car do you drive
I Drive a Ford Focus
I'm nothing crazy
but I feel like it matches my
personality on a scale
of 1 to 10 with
10 being the highest
one being the
lowest what would you
rate your driving
skills I would rate
me like a three
people always say I'm
a horrible driver
you're like my friends
are always like
okay I'll Drive like
cuz they don't want
to be in the car with
me but I feel like
over time especially
with me commuting
for work I've really
become a better
driver but I'm still
not gonna write
myself that high
like you still might
not want to
in the car with me
um what did you do
for your last birthday
so I didn't do
anything too crazy
um so my birthday I
was born on Labor
Day so my birthday
falls on Labor Day
weekend every year so
this year I didn't do
anything too crazy
I'm going to Orlando
Labor Day weekend
um and then on my
actual like the day
before my birthday
I went to this
restaurant with my
friends we actually
seen Shaq there which
is crazy and like
I didn't ask for a
picture cuz I was
like I didn't want a
fangirl and like my
friends weren't
fangirling so I didn't
want to be the only
person like hey can
I get a pic cuz you
know he was enjoying
the meal you know
what I mean like who
wants to jump up and
take a pic when
you're enjoying a
meal but um that's
when I ran my birthday
in and then on
the day of um I went
to happy hour with
all my co-workers and
some of my friends
and they made me
feel really really
special it was amazing
very low-key my
parents also made me
feel special I was
like ten cakes and I
got air pod so it
was a pretty good
birthday very very
little key I mean my
21st I went to New
York City my 22nd I
went to San Diego
yes I went to Orlando
this year but it
wasn't necessarily
like a birthday trip
I was going for something
else so it was
probably one of the
most lucky birthdays
I've had in a while
but I really enjoyed
it
so 24 I'm definitely
gonna make sure I'm
doing something
more on my actual
birthday that's a
little more dramatic
because that's how I
am um but even uh
like 23 I did go to
the dr and august
and that to me was
my birthday trip but
I went like because
of the dates and who
I was going with
like I went with my
family and my sister
she started school
like the middle of
August so she could
not go in September
so that's really the
reason I won't went
to the dr was for my
birthday but it wasn't
necessarily label
that's my birthday
celebration but
either way I'm blessed
I went to the dr
I went to Orlando like
not worried about
it had a group if
I won the lottery
right now
how would I spend it
so this is funny as
we all know the
Powerball or whatever
it's called is well
surpassed a billion
dollars yes I bought
my ticket so one
thing is I only
bought one ticket
because they say like
for me to buy 10
tickets 20 tickets
it does not increase
your chances like it
does but it's such
a small increase that
it's not worth it
like if you're gonna
win you're gonna
win so I always just
buy one ticket for
two dollars because I
also don't believe
in throwing my money
away right but what
would I do if I won
the lottery right
now so first I would
put like about 100
million and like
some type of safe or
trust fund so like
below all of the
money I can like live
off that money for
the rest of my life
and then I would
like give my friends
and family money
like I would give
all my best friends
like a million dollars
to just spin I
would give my parents
like ten million I
would give my sister
like five million
my cousin five
million see how am I
trying to do the math
make sure I'm not
like losing all my
money but a billion
dollars is a lot of
money and the pot
just keeps growing then I would
definitely like stop
working and I would
just travel the world
like I would take
at least three months
to just blow money
they gotta set a
budget I was gonna
budget of like fifty
million dollars I'm
just gonna below fifty
million I'm gonna
be extremely like not
responsible taking
the most lavish
vacation staying in the
penthouse and like
all my friends are
coming with me so
I'm like paying for
all their expenses all
their flights I'm
gonna buy a Lamborghini
I'm gonna buy a
Ferrari I'm gonna buy
a rolls-royce like
I'm gonna buy probably
like a penthouse
in New York City a
house in Beverly
Hills a Houston
Houston um but yeah I
just travel go to Dubai
go to Bali go to
Ghana like Brazil
literally everywhere
like I'm gonna just
blow in the lottery
right now how would
I spend it so this
is funny as
no the Powerball or
whatever it's called
is well surpassed a
billion dollars yes
I bought my ticket
so one thing is I
only bought one ticket
because they say
like for me to buy 10
tickets 20 tickets
it does not increase
your chances like
it does but it's such
a small increase
that it's not worth
it like if you're
gonna win you're gonna
win so I always
just buy one ticket
for $2 because I
also don't believe
in throwing my money
away right
but what would I do
buy one the lottery
right now so first
I would put like
about 100 million and
like some type of
safer trust fund so
like below all of
the money I can like
live off that money
for the rest of my
life and then I would
like give my friends
and family money
like I would give
all my best friends
like a million dollars
to just spin I
would give my parents
like 10 million I
would give my sister
like 5 million my
cousin 5 million um
see how am I trying
to do the math make
sure I'm not like
losing all my money
but a billion
dollars is a lot of
money and the pot
just keeps growing then I would
definitely like stop
working and I would
just travel the world
like I would take
at least 3 months
to just blow money
they haven't set a
budget I've got a
budget of like 50
million dollars I'm
just gonna below 50
million I'm gonna be
extremely like not
responsible taking
the most lavish
vacation staying in the
penthouse and like
all my friends are
coming with me so
I'm like paying for
all their expenses all
their flights I'm
gonna buy a Lamborghini
I'm gonna buy a
Ferrari I'm gonna buy
a Rolls Royce it's
like I'm gonna buy
probably like a
penthouse in New
York City a house in
Beverly Hills a Houston
Houston um but
yeah I just travel
go to Dubai go to
Bali go to Ghana like
Brazil literally
everywhere like I'm
gonna just blow okay
so my camera just died
so I'm just gonna
finish filming this
video on my phone
I'm like I mentioned
I have the iPhone
excess so it's pretty
good quality but
yes I was saying I
will blow be female
like blow 50mm and
then I'm just start
investing my money I
would invest in a
lot of stocks a lot
of cryptocurrency a
lot of different
businesses that are
opening and then I
would create like a
ton of business is
like I want a last
company and I would
love to have a hair
company just anything
beauty related I
could see myself opening
and just having
that as my passion
after I travel for
like three months
um and then the last
question was do you
have a nickname so
my name is Kiera and
my nickname is Kiki
um it's really
annoying with the
Drake song like I've
literally gone by
Kiki my entire life
but this Drake song
is like ruining me
like everywhere I go
I get harassed with
a song and I'm so
over it like no I
don't love you no I'm
not writing um and
then another nickname
I have is K baby
you know when I'm out
you know drinking
alyssum some I'm K
baby but yeah those
those are all the
questions um just
wanted you guys to
get to know me a
little more if you
have any other
questions feel free
to leave them in the
description and I
will comment back and
let you know and
then I'm also please
comment like
subscribe definitely
subscribe trying to
get my subscribers
up but I really
appreciate you for
watching and I hope
you have a great
rest of your day