Hi, everyone welcome back to my channel!
Today I will be filming a Q&A
It's been a while since I filmed one of these
And I received a lot of questions on Instagram
So I'm gonna try my best to answer as many as I can today, so
Let's get started!
I'm actually in LA right now
And Abe is actually here as well
he's actually helping me film this, so
If you hear his voice, it's Abe
I don't make the list anymore
Mainly because I don't want to get disappointed
when I don't fulfill them
but one of the things I wanted to do this year
was to visit a country that I haven't been to
And I already did that
I went to Spain,
and then I'm gonna to Philippines, and
I don't know, I wanna travel as much as I can
before I settle down
but I don't even know when I'm going to settle down
... I don't know
I'm finally going
in the first weekend of May with Christine!
We're going to Boracay
Israel
Eventually, I want to move back to California and
that transition is probably going to take a few years
You don't have to drive
and everything can get delivered to you
everything and anything can get delivered to you
I'm a full time YouTuber and
I also talk on the radio!
Are you not doing Joanday vlogs anymore?
I kinda answered this answer in my video with Charlotte
And I'm taking a break
I am thinking of a way to start Joanday again
I'm still in the process of thinking...
Abe: Uhh... you can just watch my vlogs
ehe Abesfigures!
Abe: There you go! *chuckles*
What is your favourite thing about having all of the Joanday vlogs to look back on
Their memories! And
I documented them and I could go back and watch them and
relive that moment
They're extensions!
I have a video dedicated to my hair extensions so
click up there to watch!
I got a lot of questions about products
so I'm going to answer them all right now
and I'll link it for you guys in the description box!
Currently, I love MAC 'Chilli'
I love Le Labo Santal 33
YesStyle!
Rifle Paper!
Reformation
For skincare I really like Drunk Elephant and
for Make Up I love Hourglass
Currently I'm using 3CE in 'Smoother'
Abe do you wanna just throw them out?
Abe: Oh yeah so the MVP cream..
Centella Blemish Cream...
Abe: The Fire Lotion
What Lotion... the Ph?
Abe: The Birch Sap lotion...
Oh the Birch Sap! Fire? *chuckles*
Abe: And also...
Abe: that Ceramide Cream I've been really into these days..
Oh really??
Abe: And.. um..
Abe: of course the patches! That's like a no-brainer and
Abe: their cleansers are fire too, so
Okay
My personal favourite would have to be the patches
I love the patches and the Snail Essence because
that actually help me fade a lot of my shingles scar on my leg
I know I used it on my leg! *Abe laughs*
But I was like,
"It has to help fade everything on my body"
So I tried it out and I love the Snail Essence
Who are the YouTubers you like to watch?
lmao her laughs <3
Abe is like *pointing at himself*
Um, I really like David Dobrik yeah
Abe: you know like, PewDiePie?
You like PewDiePie
Abe: I love him
I love David Dobrik because he does the vlogs
Abe: Oh yeah
and those are vlogs that I can never do cause
he's just wild. You've watched his vlogs, right?
Abe: This means that you have to do
No! People are gonna get hurt!
Abe do you want to answer this?
Abe: What kind of question is that makes question?
Are you hyped for Endgame?
Did you buy your tickets yet?
Abe: Of course I did!
Who you're going to watch it with?
Abe: Dad *laughs* (LOL)
Are you gonna vlog it??
You should vlog it!
Abe: I might
You might vlog? Watching Endgame with dad?
Abe: Well I might be vlog my dad's reaction like he would insecure
Fun fact!
You can't film in there tho?
Abe: No, but I'm gonna ask him questions
Fun fact I'm gonna see Endgame before Abe
Because it releases in Korea before America!
Um I got a lot of questions about marriage
I don't plan on getting married anytime soon but
if the right person comes into my life
then maybe I'll get married!
What is the best things that happened to you during the past week?
Since I'm in LA I've been meeting up with a lot of my friends and
catching up with them so I guess that has been the biggest highlight
and Abe just got to LA so
He doesn't want to be in the video cause
looks like he just got off the plane
Abe: No seriously.. Like I
It's not a good sight!
Not that he's a good sight! ( LMAO YOU TWO )
Abe: Dude yeah yeah I was about to say that!
Subscribe to Abesfigures!
2002 World Cup!
I really like 'Kick It'
Spiderman, because he's a nerd
but he's also very powerful and
when it comes to superheroes
I really like characters with a brain, so
I love Iron Man, Hulk, Rocket Racoon
and who else who's really smart? Abe?
Abe: Doctor Doom..
Doctor Strange!
This might sound sad to you but
I never been in love, so
I don't know
Abe how do you deal with heartbreak?
He's just cries for a week
Abe: *argues in the back*
Abe.. Abe *chuckles*
Abe is so emotional
It's annoying!
Oh my God!
He does! And he gets over it so quickly
Abe is a serial dater. I've never seen him single.
I've never seen him single! Maybe for like two weeks
And he's like "I'm lonely."
Abe: This is your Q&A!
Roasting Abe!
Oh my gosh, Okay last question
My favourite scene is when Thor has like
the magnificent comeback.
With his new hammer
and he's like... yelling
"Bring me Thanos."
Is it "Bring me Thanos" ?
Abe: Yes
Yeah, I watched that scene like so many times on replay
So good
That's it for today's Q&A
I hope you guys enjoyed watching
If you want to see more of these
Please ask questions in the description, description box?!
In the comment section down below!
And I'll see you guys in the next one!
Bye, have a Joan Day!
( See you soon, Joan )