Hi everyone welcome back to my channel and in today's video
I will be sharing with you guys something that I have been wanting to share on my channel
And it's about my life as a Korean American so
Amy actually tagged me to do the Asian American tag
but I wanted to do it a little differently by sharing with you guys my
Background story first before getting into those details, so I'm gonna start my story now
So if you didn't know I was born and raised in Los Angeles, California
and when I was about three and when my brother was born
our family we moved to South Korea because my
Grandpa was diagnosed with cancer and my parents wanted us to spend time with him
And I remember going to preschool, in Korea
And you know I just grew up like learning how to speak Korean and that's all I knew
But then when I was five I moved back, and then I started attending school
and I was the only Asian in my school so
Obviously I looked very different, and I didn't know the language so I mean as a kid
I'm kind of like very similar to what I am now
I'm very extroverted, and I love meeting new people so I didn't really have a problem with making friends
But of course there was that language barrier, but I don't really remember like traumatic
Experiences like from kindergarten at all so in first grade
That's when I kind of realized that I was different because during reading time
I was always asked to you know come out of the room and then go to another classroom and
Do ESL courses with another teacher and you know that was very helpful for me
But I also hated it because I felt very different from my classmates, and they would always be like oh
It's like 11 o'clock, its time for you to leave the classroom
so that actually motivated me to study harder and
Actually, I'll be going into details of this later
But every time people pointed out that I was different or like a certain stereotype
I would always work extra hard
just so that I would no longer be in ESL and that I could get better grades and things like that so
Yeah in first grade I had to deal with
Feeling different because I would always have to step out of the classroom for those ESL courses
and then I also remember a time when my like classmates they were looking through a magazine and
It was a Britney Spears magazine
and I remember not knowing who she was and my classmates made fun of me for not knowing who she was and
Like I grew up liking kpop
So I'm a very OG kpop fan
like I listened to it back when Fin.K.L was around Baby VOX
GOD, Boa, Jang Nara like those were like
Those are my idols
so for them to hate on me for
Not knowing who Britney Spears was like that was really sad on my end
but I remember like going to like Ralph's and Albertsons just to study the
celebrities because I had no idea who any of them were
so 2nd grade comes around and
A Korean moved to our district, and I was like whoa that's really cool
And I remember teachers
Asking me to come out of the classroom
Just to help her because I knew how to speak both English and Korean now
So I felt really good about doing that because for the first time I felt a sense of worth
Because now people were praising me for
knowing Korean and Korean culture
So I remember for like a whole year the teachers would always let me sit with this girl
And I would always translate for her help her do her work and things like that
but then like later um I realized that she didn't want to do anything Korean anymore so I
kind of felt
How do I explain this
so I remember this girl kind of avoiding me because she just didn't want to practice Korean anymore
And I remember coming back home, and I told my brother
I was like Abe from now on we're gonna only speak English at home
And we started doing that to our parents as well
And I remember my mom feeling so sad afterwards because if you think about it now
if I think about it now my parents both sacrificed their comfortable life in Korea
To move to America for me and my brother and even after we moved
We still came back after
Two years of living in Korea because my parents wanted us to have an education in America
so I felt terrible about that and I also got in trouble for trying to only speak English at home and then after that I
Was like you know what, I'm just gonna embrace Korean and at home it will just be Korean and outside of it
I will just speak English so I always kept it
Like I never shared this information with my friends at school
Just because I don't know I was always embarrassed about being Korean
so there's a little bit of my foundation now
I'm going to answer some questions from the asian-american tag
I'm korean-american
My parents were both born in Seoul South Korea
And then they moved to America and then I was born
So I guess I would be 1.5 generation or second generation my uncle always tells me of second generation
But I always feel like I am 1.5
I kind of shared this in my background story
But definitely when my classmates were flipping through the magazine and talking about Britney Spears
I knew there was something different about that and also none of my classmates looked like me we had different eyes we had different hair colors and
Yeah, I knew for a fact that I was different, but also
When we all started to learn about Asian culture in history class I remember people were like Oh
What kind of Asian were you again were you Chinese or Japanese and when I would answer I'm Korean no one knew
What Korea was and I was like oh
That's so strange like I'm Korean and I know the language and the music and everything
But I felt kind of different there
and then when we learned about Korea people would ask me are you north or south and
actually
I went back home and asked my mom like am I north or in my south korean and my mom
Answered that I am South Korean because both my parents were born in Seoul South Korea, but later
I also learned that my grandpa like one of my grandparents he is from North Korea, and then I got to learn more about
his story and
His testimony things like that
Even as a child
I was always very proud to be Korean and I remember trying to share with my classmates who Boa was
But of course I did mention in my background story where I did want to try to reject it, but I respected my parents
Too much to reject my Korean heritage, so I was very proud about it
This definitely changed throughout the years so
In elementary, junior high and high school the stereotype was
Asians are smart so I knew for a fact that I wasn't born with the brains my brother is actually
really really intelligent
And I just kind of like got the grades that I needed and Abe just went like above and beyond
But I definitely knew I wasn't like smart compared to my brother
But because all of my classmates kept telling me that Asians are smart
I would work extra hard
Like I mentioned before I was the first child in my family
Like I was the first born my parents were both from Korea
They went to college in Korea, and they didn't really like they weren't too strict with me
but I feel like they became strict with my brother because I would be like no mom dad Abe has to do this this and that
so my brother always jokes around saying that I am his second mother
But yeah one of the stereotypes that I did struggle with was like Asians are smart
but that actually motivated me to take the classes that I took and
Get the grades that I got when I went to college at UC Berkeley
That's when I met the most Asians so like I mentioned before
I went to a school where I was the only Asian in the beginning
And then I think I can count like how many Asians attended my school with my hands
Like in elementary school, and then it like obviously grew the Asian community grew in our neighborhood
but in college
I never met so many Korean Americans
Koreans like Asians overall and I didn't really feel a
Stereotype because we were all the same
But then when I moved to Korea there was another stereotype that I had to deal with which is being korean-american
How do I explain this kind of situation?
People would kind of assume that I had a lot of money for speaking English, but that was definitely not the case
And then some people would just kind of point out that like oh, I'm being very ignorant even though
I knew Korean so like I remember like my friend and I we were eating at this restaurant
And like the ladies right next to us. We were like oh my gosh
She's so Korean. She looks Korean, but she's not speaking any Korean
An that's like a shameful thing, but then when I was paying for the food
I would speak in like Korean and they were like whoa
So like I always felt like I had to prove myself that like oh
I really try my best to learn both of the cultures so
Yeah
Yes, I can and I'm nowhere where I want to be because I didn't go to school here
But I can read speak and write Korean
Growing up I
Learned how to be an adult a lot quicker than most because my parents needed help
Translating documents and every time they needed to call like
I don't know like an electric bill company or a gas company
I had to do it with them sitting right next to me so I
Remember like in the beginning. I liked doing it, but then I also got angry every time
I had to do this
But you know like that kind of got me closer to my mom
Because you know she was dealing with all the finances and things like that so I think growing up
Korean-american like my relationship with my like parents. It was always like a close one
I am very proud of being korean-american and I was always proud of being korean-american. I love the food
I love the music
I love the films are like you guys watch Joan Day
And this is actually one of like my biggest goals is to share Korea in a more realistic view
Definitely enjoying best of both worlds
in America there are diners and in Korea there are snack carts and I identify with both
Both has to do with food actually, but you get what I'm trying to say here
So that was my story about growing up
korean-american
and of course I answered the questions that Amy created for the asian-american tag
if you guys
identify with any of this please share your
Stories in the comment section below because I would love to read about it
if you guys enjoyed the sit-down chat
please give this video a thumbs up and
Here are the people that I tagged to do this Asian American tag.
I would love to watch my friends share their experiences
so bug them about it too.
Again, thank you guys so much for watching, and I'll see you guys in the next one
Bye