I would meet people
and they would be
like yo I'm distance
and now what are
you and I'll be like
I'm black and like
ya know but like like
like what are you
and he'll be like I'm
like like no what
are you and that's
when I really started
the question like
oh where am I wrong
because I will see
what's up you guys
it's your girl
Dwight I'm back with
another one um today's
video is gonna be
a little bit different
from you know
what I usually need
to put up on my
channel and I guess
it's a little bit
more serious today today's video
is gonna be on I say
like genetics DNA
heritage culture etc
so um let me gotta
run down so maybe
about a year ago my
principal was sick
and I was will see
her in the hospital
and while I was
there I was telling
her somehow someway
her and her brother
we got on the topic
of culture and stuff
like that and I was
just telling her like
I always wanted to
know where I was
from yada yada yada
so fast forward a
couple weeks later
when she got better
she asked me for my
address and suffered
ah and she was like
I'm gonna send you
again and she sent it
to me and it ended
up being a 23andme
now like I said this
this was a while
ago so I got the
package and I just
never open everyone
in time she send it
sent it I was in the
process of moving
etc etc and after
that that wasn't like
January when she sent it
no January yeah it
was January so it
wasn't even a year
ago almost here
cuz it's it's November
now but yeah I
didn't take it I let it say
say let it sit and
finally a few months
ago I think in September
I finally was
like okay let me go
ahead and let me
take that 23 me and
I'm also glad that I
waited too because
if I would have took
it as soon as she
gave it to me as
possible that I wouldn't
I wouldn't have
God and I was like
as detail you know
our description
of where I'm from
because they just now
you know updated
their system so and
about I registered
my kid i'ma say well
I feel like I'm
kind of like over the place so I
register my kid
around September 16th
you know I do all
that nasty stuff I
spent in the to viral
and around that time
I think you have to
sender like to one
of the Carolinas
around that time I was
like in September
I think that they were
going to flood in
so I'm like years gonna
take me mad long
to get it back but
every day and at all
I'm just trying I'm
like burning up the
timeline so September
16 my kid was
registered I'm looking
at my email right
now September 24th my sample was
received and then
October 2nd my reports
were ready of this
year all these dates
for 2018 so October
2nd 2018 my reports
were ready and I've
watched a ton of
other videos of people
saying oh it took
like four to five weeks
I arrived with a
little time as y'all
can see this was
not a long time at
all for me at least
it was like Nene ready
already so let me
get it a little bit
into the background
right now family
history whatever um
honestly I've never
had the culture or
like whether for
mom talk from my
parents or anyone in
my family I don't
I think that they
care about stuff like
that I think I'm the
only one because
you know they've
never talked about
culture and my mom
she's a little ignant
so I don't think if I
were actually like
your mom do you know
I don't think she
no we just grew up as being
african-american I
was being black and
that's always what
it was you wanna say
everybody my family
or from the Upstate
regions of New York
grew up here most
grew up here most of
the time in my life
and I did live in
Georgia for a very
small portion of my
life but we moved it
is because my mom got
married we do not
have any family down
there or nothing so
I don't have anybody
no ties to Georgia
most of my family
it's an upstate New
York in this region
so yeah that's it
and as for my father
my father know much
about where we came
from he I don't
think he's interested
in culture anyway
he's never you know had that
conversation with me
and I honestly to
me to be completely
honest I never
really thought about
where I was from
and stuff like that
until I got to
college now like I
said I am from New
York but I'm not from
New York City from
those of you who are
not from New York
State I'm from upstate
New York so when
I went to college
it was just like a
culture shock even
though I'm black I
did I do go to a PWI
predominantly white
institution but the
percentage of black
people at my school
is you know pretty
eyes pretty good or
whatever for the
most part for it being
a PWI and upstate
New York um and when
I got there you
know I was meeting
people I left on
campus and I would
meet people and they
would be like yo I'm
dis this and now
what are you and I'll
be like I'm black
and like ya know but
like like like what
are you and I'll be
like I'm like like
no what are you
and that's when I
really started the
question like Oh am
I where am i firm
because I would see
people like it would
be Nigerian it would
be from Ghana I
have a friend who's
I think she's cubed
a lot of Jamaicans
there a lot of
Dominicans at my
school so it's just
like and they are
in those two their
culture and a lot
of people my school
are from New York
City in the downstate
area you know the
five boroughs Browns
Brooklyn Queens blah
blah blah blah so
down there you know
it's very culture
based and New York
City it's completely
different from upstate
New York so once
I got to college I
was just like oh my
god like they got
the only food and I
think oh you know
they go to bed to do
this and on this chicken
a little chicky
the loser cuz I'm
just black like we
don't know like we
don't Jack nothing
else
I just always gonna
have you thinking
about it cuz my first
couple of years at
colleges really showed
me a line open up
my mind to so many
different things so
yeah ever since then
I've been wondering
like damn where am i
from or whatever so
I'm really grateful
that my principal
decided to go ahead
and buy me this kit
because lord knows I
didn't even really
I didn't know party
and I never probably
would have found out
about it if she
didn't buy it for me
so yeah so before
prior to taking this
test I did look up
a few videos and I
noticed that they
gave me percentage
so I kind of like
predicted my own percentages I'm
probably and I was
like I'm probably
like 95 per second
five percent European
because you know
African American says
we come from that
dysphoria um you know
we always have a
little bit of African
in us I mean
European and then
dope guys working in
us um so yeah my
European percentage was
not high at all I did
not get anything
out of American
nothing Asian just
because like we never
had that culture
talking my family
so that was really
just out of the
yes so as far as
what I thought I was
because I got this
mentioned before I
was around a lot
of people from my
school who were African
like from Ghana
Nigeria most of the
people that I'm at
school are from there
so I predicted that
I was probably
either from Ghana
or Nigeria and um
[Music]
that's pretty much
a dad and guess
anywhere else just
because of the
dysphoria and you
know knowing that
history another thing
people from my
school is when I
would just tell them
I'm just black is
like they they they
forgot this whole 400
years in history
just went late for
my mom like they was
like really an old
that I didn't know
where I was from they
didn't mean me I'm
just like yeah my
bad job is really
interrupting but like
I was saying like
they will forget
that you know this
whole point in history
actually took
place and there's
people in America that
are black that don't
know where they
come from in Africa I
haven't message at
my phone right now
from people that I've
talked to that I
know that they like
what do you mean and
it just at that point
it was kind of
getting aggravated
because it's like at
the end of the day
you're in America
it's not like I'm
living in Africa you
know then and I don't
notice you're in
America you should be
well familiar very
familiar with what
occurred here and
what happened I'm
pretty sure everybody
in on the New York
State area is just
they know where they
come from they all
Caribbean nation um
yeah that's another
thing was a lot of it's a lot of
Caribbeans at my
school a lot of that
and if anything in
this video as a
fitting to you I'm
sorry I'm not I don't
know I'm I'm not
trying to be offensive
I'm not trying to
you know come at
anyone
I'm just speaking my
truth so I got my
results back and when
I tell y'all I was
high Chao was high
so let's let's do it
let's do a drumroll
[Music]
for these results
because I actually
sent it to my guy
friend because I was
just so excited so
your girl on Esha
that's me oh Allah I
am ninety point four
percent I'm blacker
than black black black
black black black
black black black black okay
and guess what was
Gus was my highest
percentage guess
what what guess what
was my highest percent
left Nigeria I
was thirty eight point
nine I love yoga
but you girls 38 0.9
percent nigerian so
I'm gonna read the
breakdown after that
I say 16.04 said
coastal West African
six point seven eight
six point seven
percent from the Congo
Congolese I'm not
sure if I'm saying
every correct me in
the comments if
you know you know
they'll crack way
say that a lot of
these I don't know how
to say Senegambia
six point one per
se I know I just
slaughtered that
southern East African
one points one
point four percent African
hunter-gatherer
whatever that means
1.4 percent sort
of knees they're a
point one broadly West
African which was
would you mean that's
why I got over
this today I was
trying to be like
cultural even though
this is a low-key
Jamaican colors
but you know Nigerian
flag is green and
white I try to give
y'all I try to give
a little hint okay
try to give y'all
over here it's green
and white but you
know the yellow had
to do because I
don't have anything
that's green white
and I like Jamaicans
anyway I go on okay
anyways so yeah that
mix up and then you
know 1.6% broadly
southern ease it just
makes up a whole
bunch of things and
broadly subsets
sub-saharan african 4.0
so if i'm ninety
point four percent
African how much my
European how much
seven point eight
percent European I'll
take that and my
highest percentage for
being European was
Burley Northwestern
European three point two percent
British and Irish
one point three
Scandinavian one
point one French and
German 0.9 Burley
European one point for
this next one really
shocked me because
I never heard that
story growing up like
oh you're Native
American you're this
you're that never got
fed any of those
lies but according
to this my genetic
makeup East Asian and
Native American I
am one point three
percent a percentage
is very low but I'm
surprised that it
existed anyway it
says I'm Native
American one percent
that doesn't mean I
don't even excite
me like and I said
drily north and
northern I using a
Native American 0.1%
Burley Chinese and
Southeast Asian 0.1%
so that makes up my
1.3 percent East
Asian and Native
American underside
and unassigned with
0.5 so yeah I was
extremely excited for
you know these results
but what I wanna
do is
you guys are interested
I kind of want
to take the ancestry
DNA one just
because I feel like
that one is a little
bit more accurate just
because they have
a broader arm
I guess genetic pool
to the tech exactly
where you're from
because the videos I
watched prior to me
getting my reports a
lot of people you
know that did this
with 23andme I would
just say that they
were sub-saharan
African that's it was
like three categories
and then they
really got into their
European to say
but I kind of want to
do an ancestry DNA
and I purchased that
with my own money
but I only do it if
you've got a really
interesting and they
cuz I think it's
like seventy eighty
dollars a Irie go up
large areas or I
know if I need to do
any more okay but
yeah I was tight when
I found out that I was
Nigerian like you
know and I'm saying
I was about to go
back to school
[Laughter]
[Music]
let me stop you
copyrighted again I'm
always doing that
um I was extremely
inside I was in DC
last week because it
was my birthday and
I was an uber like
yes I'm Nigerian and
I hope any fellow
Nigerians that happiness
eaters please
don't feel offended
I'm actually very
excited that I come
from that country
and that I know a
little bit more about
myself because if I
have to have kids I
can tell them a
little bit at least
about themselves and
stuff like that so
hmm I think that's
gonna conclude this
video like I said
I was extremely
excited to know that
I'm that black I'm
black I'm black I'm tougher than
Nigerian air
yeah so that's pretty
much it I'm sorry
if I was renting a
little bit in this
video but like I said
I was just super
excited and um hope
to see you guys on
the next one comment
below if y'all
wanna see one from
ancestry DNA okay bye
guys