hey everyone welcome back to my channel
so today I have a pretty unique video I
did my entire face of makeup using
products that I am getting rid of from
my collection I originally saw this a
video I think Laura Lee did it on her
channel I don't think I've seen anyone
else do a video like it but I thought it
was a really interesting idea and I
wanted to do it recently in the past few
weeks I've done a huge declutter of my
makeup I got rid of a gigantic bag of
makeup to get rid of so some of it was
old that I threw out some of it was
pretty lightly used some of it was never
used and some of it was pretty well used
and loved so these are products that I
either wasn't reaching for anymore or
fell out of love with or never loved or
got from boxycharm rip see that I wasn't
really ever gonna use so a lot of the
makeup I did donate I'm gonna be sending
out a huge box soon I think I'm gonna be
sending it to Project Beauty share which
is one of the companies that takes
gently use products because I do have a
lot of those so I'm sending them some
makeup soon I haven't set out the box
yet I'm also going to be giving away a
lot of the makeup to my friends and
family just anyone who wants to take it
but there are some products here that I
have that are not good enough to donate
or that I can't donate like for example
I can't donate lip products that have
been used so stuff like that I can't
donate so I decided to film a full face
of stuff that I'm getting rid of I
actually found a full face of stuff
within the stuff that I was getting rid
of so just a disclaimer not all of these
products are bad products they're just
products that either don't work for me
or I just wasn't using anymore some of
these were products that I did really
love at some point and I just don't use
them anymore but this is how the makeup
turned out I don't think it looks
horrible I think it looks like okay I
really did try to make a very nice
looking makeup like I didn't try to mess
it up on purpose so if you want to see
how I created this look and what
products I will be getting rid of out of
my collection then just keep on watching
I've already moisturized with a little
sample of this glam glow glow starter
make illuminating moisturizer and I've
already primed
off-camera because I don't have a primer
that I'm getting rid of so first
foundation I'm going to be going in if
the Milani conceal imperfect to an one
foundation plus concealer in 0-5 warm
beige so this is very popular on YouTube
over a year ago and people were saying
that it was really amazing and it was
really full coverage and so I picked it
up and I tried it and I didn't love it
because it did make me throughout the
day and any foundation that makes me
Olli unless I really really loved it I
never wear it I think it's a pretty good
shade match for me so it is quite full
coverage you can use it as a concealer
like a spot concealer as well I don't
really ever do that I forgot to what my
Beauty Blender I'll be right back
okay so I'm back with my dirty Beauty
Blender I promise I'm washing all of my
brushes after I filmed this video and
I'm just gonna blend that out so yeah I
do think this is a pretty good shade
match for me and so I did buy it because
it was pretty hyped up at the time and I
just never reached for it because it
made me
oily throughout the day I mean there are
foundations that also get like that they
get oily throughout the day like the
Maybelline better skin and the Too Faced
Born This Way and the Wet n Wild mega
glow whatever that the foundation that
every will have somewhat in wild um but
I love the finish of those so I don't
really mind the fact that I get oily
throughout the day wearing it but I just
didn't love this foundation on me and it
always kind of felt a little too heavy
so now we're gonna get into concealer
and I bought this when I was in London
and I was really excited to use it it is
the collection lasting perfection
ultimate wear concealer but this is way
too light of a shade I don't know why I
thought I was a shade like I bought it
in store and this is in the shade light
I think fair one why did I do that I
think I mut like I must have just
accidentally bought it so it it's way
too light for me so I'm gonna use it
today and I actually mix in a little bit
of the foundation and use s concealer um
and I really it's ridiculous like that's
the reason I'm getting rid of this I
really haven't given it a fair shot
because it's so light like that's
ridiculous
like that is white I can't believe I
bought this like
and I'm annoyed because I really wanted
to try this concealer because I hear
really great things about it okay so now
I'm gonna take some of this foundation
I'm gonna squeeze it on my hand like a
pump and I'm gonna just kind of mix it
in there with that so I'm just gonna
take the bead blender and blend that out
oh my god that looks so light yeah that
looks a little crazy underneath my eyes
which is kind of disappointing because I
really want to try this concealer and
they only sell it in Europe and I'm
gonna set that I think with this
covergirl outlast all-day powder
I hate pressed powders so I don't know
why I buy them I've gotten rid of almost
all of them my collection here it is
yeah it's a finishing powder so you're
not really supposed to it's not really a
foundation powder but I'm just gonna set
that so hopefully that'll darken this up
a little bit this powder I don't think
there's anything wrong with it it's just
that I hate pressed powder and I don't
know why I buy it I I think in my
collection I have like two pressed
powders at the moment and I've barely
ever used those okay so when I set the
concealer with this tinted powder it
looks better
I think this powder actually does a nice
job is setting under the eyes but I
don't know why I hate pressed powder so
much like I always feel it like I'm not
setting my face enough cuz I do like to
use a lot of powder and now I'm gonna
set the rest of my face with this powder
and I just feel my face doesn't feel set
enough but I think my skin actually
looks nice so now let's hop into brows
so here I have this afro eyebrow pencil
and Universal I think it's one of those
like it'll suit any tone um does not
have a spoolie which is kind of annoying
I use this brush this brow product for a
while and it's kind of waxy there's
nothing really wrong with it it's just
not good and I have other brow products
that I like way more I think it's also a
good color for me there we go that's the
brows and then I'm gonna set that with
this brow food clear brow enhancing gel
fix try think where I got this I think I
either got this in a boxy charm or I
gotta act generation beauty which is a
beauty convention and I went in New York
but I feel like this brow gel just
doesn't do anything for me I'm not that
it's bad I just think it doesn't do
anything so I got rid of it
I don't think it's bad I just I just
don't I don't think it's good and I feel
like it doesn't do anything to my brows
like it doesn't it doesn't it doesn't
feel like I have anything in my brows so
I just kind of got rid of it because I
wasn't it didn't do anything okay next
for eyeshadow primer I actually do have
an eyeshadow primer that I'm getting rid
of this is the Catrice prime and fine
brightening eye shadow base intensify
any eyeshadow I don't know why I bought
this I think I bought this at generation
beauty and it was like you can get it
was like five products for twenty
dollars I think I just grabbed this so
first of all it feels really kind of
like oily which is gross uhm and it is
white
cuz it's supposed to like intensify your
eyeshadow that looks a little crazy I
think okay so now for eyeshadow I have
two palettes I have the elf mad format
palette and the crown glam metals
palette so this elf palette I loved for
a really long time as you can see I hit
pan and one of the shades I just never
reach for this anymore so I am getting
rid of it but it's not in good enough
quality to donate because I have used
this shade completely up it's not a bad
palette it's a pretty good palette
actually I'm gonna take this first shade
right here and set the lid with that
it's just the base shade trying to
neutralize some of that white on my lid
right now I think it looks ridiculous I
feel like my eyelids still look really
weird and pale I don't like it I really
don't like that eyeshadow primer this
crown palette I've honestly never used
it but I don't want to donate it because
it broke
I got in boxycharm so twitty shades
broke when I got it so I'm trying to
think what kind of look I'm gonna do I
don't want to do anything too warm so I
think I want to use this shade here that
I've hit pan in right here it's the
fourth one in we're just gonna throw
them in the crease um so yeah more about
this eyeshadow palette I like it but I
think I just have better quality things
and I don't use I don't really do all
matte eyeshadow Lopes I usually have to
use another palette in conjunction with
it and this one just wasn't really
cutting it for me I might take a little
bit of this next shade this one right
here and also throw that in the crease
with the same brush also these
eyeshadows aren't the most pigmented
they're pretty good though they're good
for this is a 10
my palette so it's pretty good for that
but definitely it's not the best quality
palette in the world but it's definitely
it's a good staple especially if you're
a beginner and you want a good neutral
matte palette now I'm gonna take this
same shade right here the darker one
which is right here and I'm gonna take
that and just deepen up the crease in a
more focused way now I think I'm gonna
take this shade right here and the shade
and put it in the outer corner I'm a
little bit concerned or nervous about
these darker shades blending out because
darker eyeshadows can get patchy okay
that blended okay honestly as I'm using
this palette I'm liking it less and less
I think I just used to really like it
before
I was extremely into makeup like I used
it a lot before like when I was more
starting out my eyeshadow just not look
great
actually and I'm gonna go into this
crown palette I as I setting up this in
boxycharm I think I'm gonna go in with
Wild Thing just right here I've never
actually used this palette and I'm gonna
take out my ring finger and put that on
the outer half of my lid umm this
palette is also just not very exciting
to me besides the fact that it broke
I just don't picture myself using it
because these aren't really shades I
would use that much I'm also gonna take
rebel which is this middle shade on my
middle finger and put that on the inner
part of the lid okay color doesn't
really go with this look but it's a nice
color actually I just think this palette
is kind of a weird palette if there's
like it's like these shimmers just like
don't really make sense they're not
vibrant and like nice kind of like dull
shimmers if that makes any sense I don't
really have an eyeliner so I'm just
gonna do regular winged eyeliner with a
liquid eyeliner off-camera and I'll be
back to do the rest of the makeup okay
so now I'm gonna set my eyeliner with
this black shade in the elf palette I
always do that it's like an essential
step for me and then in the upper
waterline I'm going to take this ciate
Wunderland
wonder what notes wonder wand CIT london
wonder wand
Kjell coal liner I think I got this in
if C or boxycharm so it is a gel liner
on one end and then this is weird like
angled brush I guess to blend it out but
I don't know it doesn't really make any
sense to me so this is pretty black
there it is washed right there um this
is some other stuff ignore that um but I
don't think that stays my waterline it
goes on pretty black but it smudges
pretty quickly and then I don't have a
mascara that I'm giving away so I'm
gonna do that off camera and I'll be
back for like bronzer blush and
highlight and that kind of stuff I
almost forgot about fitting shadow on
the lower lash line so I think I'm gonna
take this shade right here and put that
on the lower lash line I feel like since
this is more of like a dark and kind of
smoky eye shadow look I'm gonna make the
lower lash line a little bit more dark
and then I'm gonna blend that out with
the shade that I hit panning okay so the
eye look is done I feel like it's very
okay it's not great I don't love it but
it's there it's on my eyes now for
bronzer this might be a product that is
a little bit surprising to you guys and
this is the Tarte Park a princess
bronzer this is a deluxe sized sample I
had this product in my collection for a
while and I just I never used it I never
loved it it wasn't my favorite thing
ever I know a lot of people love this
bronzer this one does have a little bit
more of a sheen to it and I've tried
using this and I love bronzer and this
one for some reason I never wanted to I
never was reaching for I never wanted to
use it nothing about it like excites me
so it just kind of sat in my collection
never being used and then for blush I
have the Hikari tingle blush this I got
an Ipsy a long time ago this is quite an
old blush as you can see it's extremely
bright and I did keep this in my
collection for a while and I was using
it sometimes I wasn't using it that much
so I decided to get rid of it but I'm
just gonna take with a very light hand I
think it's pretty it's just I never was
reaching for it because it's so bright
and then for highlighter I have this
city color highlight trio I use this a
lot for a really long time I got it in
epsy I'm pretty sure and I just I'm
getting rid of it now because I never
use anymore and I do have highlighters
that I like more than this but it
definitely isn't a bad product by any
means I'm gonna take this middle shade
and this I'm gonna take these two shades
this one's more pinky you can't really
tell I don't think because my camera is
watching it out a little bit there we go
um so this is more pinky this is more
white and I'm gonna mix those two it's
pretty you can definitely see the
highlight I just wasn't reaching for it
and I have so many highlighters that I
didn't need to keep this one okay and
lastly for lips I have this MDM flow
retro liquid lipstick I don't think I've
ever really worn this but I did swatch
it and I probably put it on my lips just
to see the color so I can't donate it
anymore cuz it's not brand new but this
is a liquid lipstick I'm pretty sure I
got an Ipsy and it's just kind of random
and I had colors similar to it it's a
pretty pink color let me put it on now
it's quite pigmented I feel like this
doesn't really go with my look either
it's very bright lip compared to my very
cool toned eye it's a fine product I
don't really like to smell it kind of
smells like plastic but it's drying down
it's getting very sticky which means
it'll probably dry down completely matte
once it's done so I'm gonna wait a few
minutes for this to completely dry down
okay so the liquid lipstick hasn't dried
down completely but I'm just kind of
noticing something as I'm pressing my
lips together and pulling them apart the
product is like lifting from my lips I'm
not sure if you can tell but I keep
going like that and then now there's
like a whole of product on my mouth
which is really weird I'm not sure if
you can see it but it's right that
there's like product missing it's really
weird I don't like that I'm gonna try to
put a little bit more on I don't really
want to layer this I don't like this
liquid lipstick either yeah I'm happy
I'm getting rid of it um yeah I really
don't like it at all okay so this is the
finished makeup look full of products
that I am getting rid of getting out of
my collection I think the makeup ended
okay I actually think it looks better
all put together than it did before
I will do a little close-up now so
here's the face all closed up the
eyebrows look pretty good I think
looks pretty good um the eyeshadow I
think the eyeshadow honestly looks
patchy and didn't blend really well and
this lip is just super weird it's still
kind of sticky I didn't want to wait for
it to dry down completely but I just
don't like it I don't really like the
way it feels um I think my skin feels
kind of heavy
because of the foundation and the powder
so if you liked this video be sure to
give it a thumbs up and subscribe to my
channel I put out new videos every
single week and that's all I have for
you guys thank you so much for watching
and I will see you in my next video bye