hello everyone welcome back to my
channel so today I'm going to be doing
the 50 facts about me tag I'm doing this
video because I feel like when I'm doing
my makeup videos you guys don't get to
know me super well because I'm just
talking about makeup instead of talking
about myself um
so I love actually watching these videos
on YouTube so I decided to do it for you
guys I have 50 facts took me a long time
to think of all them that I can tell you
about me I feel like my lashes are a
little crazy today these are very
dramatic lashes for me you know I don't
usually wear eyelashes this dramatic
alright so I will be keeping track of
the numbers on the screen I have my
computer right here with all of my 50
facts so let's just hop right into it
okay so my full name is Sophia Lee sada
everyone calls me Sophie that like no
one okay there are a few people who call
me Sophia like my dad and like my
grandpa like some of my aunts and uncles
but basically everyone calls me Sophie
like and like all my friends my mom my
brother my dad sometimes but yeah
everyone calls me Sophie also no one
ever knows how to pronounce my last name
it's really easy it's literally how it's
written just say des I was born in New
York City I was born in Manhattan I
moved to New Jersey when I was six years
old my birthday is March 15 1999 and
that makes me a Pisces I don't really
follow like astrological signs and stuff
like that or I don't read my horoscope
but I'm a Pisces and that would make me
18 years old
I have one brother Bennet you probably
know him if you watch my vlogs he's
always in them also I have a dog his
name is Jerry and Jerry is a labradoodle
and I love him very much and he's my
best friend I love him and if you can
put that together it's Ben and Jerry
like the ice cream so my brother and my
dog are Ben and Jerry that was
purposeful I am super close with both of
my parents I'm very happy and like lucky
that money my parents are so close I
have a pretty diverse background
I am half Taiwanese 1/4 Lebon
and a quarter like European /
french-canadian I don't really know I am
right-handed so when I was younger up
until like middle school I was super
into theater I loved I did all the
musicals at school I did some community
theater and I really wanted to be on
Broadway but now I don't really do
theater anymore I actually went to
speeder sleepaway camp for like four
years but now I don't want to do theater
as much I actually want to be a criminal
lawyer when I grow up as of right now
that could change I never know so this
fall I'm going to be a freshman at NYU
I'm going into my first year at college
also I'm this is like random side now
I'm planning on doing like NYU related
videos once I get to school so
eventually keep your eye out for those
so my best friend is lose you probably
have seen her and some videos on my
channel before I love her very much
and she has her own YouTube channel so
go check her out so I actually started
doing makeup when I was in seventh grade
my mom found that we do makeup and it
was it was a whole mess I didn't know
what I was doing I liked her blue
eyeliner a lot it was not a good look
I'm sorry I like blue eyeliner and eye
shadow or like purple and I drew school
like every single day it was so bad but
I didn't really get like really serious
and to makeup until I was in tenth grade
I still wasn't that good but that's
really when I started like building my
collection and just learning a lot more
about how to do my makeup and that kind
of stuff so when I was a freshman in
high school I was super into doing nail
art I mean I wasn't super great at it
but I loved doing it like I would spend
like two hours painting my nails doing
like different things like I painted
cupcakes on my nails I think I did like
little cows on my nails ones I don't
know super into it I don't really do it
anymore and now I just like get my nail
done and I do gel or I just paint my
normal nails but I have a pretty big
nail polish collection also I am 5 foot
5 I'm technically 5 foot 4 and 3/4 but I
just say I'm 5 foot 5 I have broken two
bones before I broke my left wrist when
I was in second grade and I also broke
one of my ankle I don't
literally don't remember which angle
stood my left on my right but I broke
that in 5th grade I also got a
concussion freshman year of high school
and I hit my head on my wall and I got a
like relatively minor concussion I was
out of school for a week but yes I hit
my head on my own bedroom wall and I got
a concussion I have never had braces I
used to have like one of those like
permanent retainers on my bottom teeth
and then on the top
I had this retainer that I never wore so
my teeth just like straightened out on
their own I don't know how that happened
but they did so I got glasses when I was
8 years old and now I just wear contacts
I got contacts in middle school and I
hate wearing my glasses I rarely wear
them I just wear contacts basically
every single day I have a really bad
habit of biting my nails so that's
honestly why I always have nail polish
on my nails because otherwise my nail
pleasure is off I'll bite my nails
end of story I have traveled to 28
different countries I love traveling my
family and I travel everywhere I'm super
lucky to have gone to so many places so
I have four piercings total I have two
in each ear just normal lobe piercings I
don't know I don't have any cartilage
anything like that I have a pretty
severe phobia of throwing up like myself
throwing up anyone else throwing up yeah
it's really bad if it'll be out like
I'll have a full-blown panic attack if
anyone like throws up around me it's
pretty bad my favorite food is pasta I
think I don't know I guess yeah
pasta is definitely my favorite food I
love pasta my favorite drink I kind of
have two favorite drinks I love bubble
tea or boba I guess people in the West
Coast call it boba but basically if
you've never heard of it it's like black
tea with milk with like tapioca bubbles
and I love it I love it so much it's
originally from Taiwan which is where
like part of my family's from you love I
love it and then I also love green tea I
used hot doesn't really matter I love
green tea my favorite color is violet to
purple my favorite snack is salt and
vinegar chips I love salt and vinegar
chips I hate cheese well it's kind of
like like weird like what I do like I
like mozzarella cheese but I also like
pizza
mac and cheese but I will never eat like
normal cheese just like straight up
I won't eat like cheese and sandwiches
or like like cheese and crackers
no no I'll eat like mozzarella cheese
that's basically it and like sometimes
cheddar and grilled cheese - but with
mozzarella cheese and I don't like cream
cheese or cottage cheese or sour cream a
lot of like dairy products there's kind
of grossed me out like I never ate them
when I was younger so what like I don't
like them now and it's like I like my
body has like a physical like aversion
to these foods thinking my favorite
subject in school was history - my
favorite stores to shop at are like
forever 21
Urban Outfitters and like hmm two of my
favorite movies are Forrest Gump and
Mean Girls
I much prefer watching TV over movies
and I have liked I love TV so my
favorite TV shows are like the office
friend's house Grey's Anatomy orange is
the new black how to get away with
murder I don't know I watch a lot of TV
shows I also love to read a lot of the
time like I won't read for a long time
because I'm busy with like school or
stuff but then like once I start reading
like I can't stop like I'll binge read
like four or five books like within a
week it's crazy but I love it to read
like once I get into it I love it but I
hate starting books I also love adult
coloring books like ones with like
mandalas I just love them they're so
relaxing and they're just like fun to do
like even if I'm like watching some TV
or just hanging out in my room I'll
color in my coloring books and I love
them and I just have so many coloring
books I love board games idol playing
like any types of board games my
favorites I like monopoly I love
monopoly I love clue I like taboo
basically any like board game I am down
to play I love it
I much prefer dogs over cats I don't
really like how they kind of freak me
out because I've never had one and I
like I've never had much exposure to
cats so they kind of freak me out but I
love dogs I love dogs so much my
favorite perfume is Elizabeth and James
is nirvana why
I have it right here I love it but I'm
not one of those people that wears like
perfume every single day like
consistently the same perfume cuz I
forget that kind of stuff I love
Christmas it is my favorite holiday I
start listening to Christmas music like
the end of November all throughout until
Christmas I love it I love everything to
do with Christmas
I love seeing family I love giving gifts
I just love I just love decorating the
Christmas tree like making cookies I
love everything I love Christmas I also
love Disney World I love Disney World so
much I go like every single year I
didn't go this year but I love Disney
World love going all all the rides
specifically going in Orlando I believe
into the one I've only been to
Disneyland like once I think but I
picked it Disney well a bunch of times
and I loved it so much and I feel like
I'm gonna be one of those like adults
that like goes up there children and
just hang you out and has a blast I hate
wearing jeans unless they are like super
comfortable and like flexible like I
hate like skinny jeans they're just not
comfortable I need to have comfortable
jeans and usually like when it gets
colder out all I wears leggings like I
swear that's all I wear I dyed my hair
only one time it was in tenth grade and
I got ombre and I was horrible I liked
at the time but it was like it was so
bad it was like ombre from like here
down and it was like like brass yellow
it was not good my hair got too brassy
it was a mess but I thought I looked
cute no that was a big regret I collect
those little pressed pennies like if you
see at all there's a always at like
amusement parks and different
sightseeing stuffs like you put the two
corners and the penny you crank the
crank and you get the penny I collect
those I've like I've so many of them
maybe like tons of booklets of them and
I love them I don't know why I love them
so much though my favorite season is
fall and then I also like winter and
then my third favorite season is summer
and then I hate spring and that is
because I am allergic to pollen and I I
used have really really really bad
pollen allergies and now they're not as
bad but they're still like pretty bad
and I'm also other two figs now we are
act our last fun
about me I am obsessed with organization
and like color coding definite stuff but
at the same time I'm not like super like
I'm not super super super clean because
I need a lot of time to organize a long
time I don't have time so then things
kind of get like a little messy I
wouldn't say I'm a messy person but I'm
not like super clean but like when I get
the chance I love to organize like my
books on my shelf are alphabetized they
love color coding things that kind of
stuff yes I love it all right so those
were 50 facts about me so I hope you
liked learning a little bit more about
me I really liked doing this kind of
like get to know me type of video I'm
thinking of doing more of these kinds of
like tag videos or get to know me videos
in the future so if you like this video
be sure to give it a thumbs up and also
subscribe to my channel I put out new
videos every Wednesday and Saturday and
sometimes Monday so if I thank you guys
so much for watching and I will see you
in my next video bye