[Music]
I can't like it's
illegal for me to say
da right now because
if I say duh
I've been gone for a
minute like that's
like this is very
hurtful to do you guys
like that I'm not
gonna see the dog
today cuz I miss dolly
that's a rock he
does can't stop no
he's gotta keep up
with me you could be
back be back baby
I'm trying to be
consistent at least a
video a week with
my charts like that
because I have a lot
of things on my
plate right now and
I have not found
accurate balance I
don't let y'all know
where I've been
so keep listening it's
a little rambling
because like I'm
nervous I'm actually
very nervous because I
you guys are doing me again I've
forsaken you
so just take a little
time with me and
like my thoughts are
everywhere without
further ado let's
you too you too me
too me too me too
it's been a while
it's been a while I'm
sorry I'm sorry and
I'm going to explain
a bit of why I've
been missing for so
long and why I've
been so inconsistent
because I'm not in
connect I'm not an
inconsistent person
and I'm pretty sure
why I love you guys
subscribe to my
channel is because
I was in consider
little NAT talk now
I'm pretty sure
the reason why you
guys subscribe to my
channel originally is
because I was very
consistent I was
pushing out content
every week but you
know life happens and
that's what it's gonna
be um we're gonna
do a get ready with
me to go nowhere
because kena decide
it's time to snow
and it's snowing so
plans get shagged up
so we're not going anywhere
ok ok so how have
you guys been like
how's life how's it
been treating y'all
um because I'm going
to we're just gonna
do like a random
beat like it nothing
serious just real
simple real basic real
everyday is but we
still gonna slay cuz
you know he does this
ok oh um so guys I
got some new foundation like I'm
actually something laura mercier
I definitely got
these but I haven't
been here so there
need to use and there
still need to meet
it ok we were doing
this together
um I'm rambling
because I'm nervous
McDonald like like
imma start from the
top like the first
week that I missed a
video to be honest it was catch
sleep to be completely
honest when I
make my YouTube videos
I work I'm gonna
have a dog actual
job I work for Home
Video and so it's all
and the nighttime
like everything's in
the night time and
I was just really
exhausted so I took
like a personal break
it's just like it
was only supposed to
be like a week or
two okay and then
like before I even
took the personal
break I was having
like a lot of trouble
with like being
creative like I wasn't
focused you know
I wasn't focused I
was having lack of
creativity I was just
the energy was it
I'd like to there and
like I don't know
why but I think it's
mainly because of
my focus I wasn't
really carefully so
that could have been
definitely why I
know it's also in my
head about a lot of
the things like I
just felt like I
started my channel
give me a teal pause
but I did I didn't
shut it oh this did
you guys see that inter
I'm saying her name
right I think it's
Jade janae Shana or
Jade Shana la gun I
was gonna put her on
yeah I'm just gonna
put her at name on
the screen because
she really did that okay
the like I was just
first thing is that
I felt like I've
been on YouTube for
about two years now
and I didn't have
like a really dope
intro I I don't have
a camera like I'm
still using my phone
like I don't have
like this super amazing
hobby but what
do you say editing
software I'm not
gonna use my NARS
I'm gonna try this
Maybelline one day
I just got it it
looks like so if you
come out shake just
please just ignore it
I was in my head about
a lot of things
those really comparing
myself to a lot
of other people stuff
and then it was
really yeah time
like an impact on my
creativity like I
wasn't focused about
what shine I wanted
to do I was kind of
like doing what was
in or what was the
trend so I had to
really take a step
back and we focus
on remind myself
Cheyenne why on
earth are you doing
YouTube China
why did you start
this YouTube channel
Cheyenne what was your
was the main goal
when you started
this into a check
originally and when I
originally started
it was to help other
girls and not only
help but also create
like a support
system slash community
environment where
we can you know
talk some and like
you know laugh and
talk about relatable
stuff and like be myself
like that's what I
wanted to do and I
felt like a lot of
that was getting lost
in like video I'm doing
right now Beauty
videos like I like
makeup and stuff and
I love beauty I love
hair like more than
anything else but
like I don't wear
makeup every day I'm
not like oh my god
get that new foundation
I'm more like oh
my god I'm going to get that new
skincare product like
I just really had
to take a step back
and remind myself
Cheyenne what are you
doing what is it
that you want to
accomplish what is that
you love about YouTube
I really have to
fall in love with
YouTube again so if I
haven't responded to any of your
comments or anything
it's because I
haven't been on my
own YouTube channel
like I was so disappointed
in myself for
not being consistent
that I wasn't even
on my own channel
like I logged out of
my own nose using
my older weather's
tonight like personal
personal account
not mine that's so
shy account and
that's goes to show
you guys like how
how much I felt bad
because it's like I
came you guys started
getting like
attached to me
whatever and I just
disappeared and
like I thought well
because you guys
don't deserve that
we rock it together
so I should come
here and be like fully
transparent with
you which is what I'm
gonna try and do
this video I want
to be bullying some
things aren't fully
dealt with or
finished so I can't
fully talk about
them yet because I'm
just one of those
people that feel
like sometimes you
can't put all of your
goals and dreams
out there because
but mine is I real
something it's real
so I just feel like
I just can't as yet
and then another
thing it was just like
shine has to take
care of Cheyenne I'm
just like a person
in that leg well I
don't really sleep on
the regular but like
I'll compromise
sleep to do anything
and everything like
it was really about
like self care like
I was really taking
like a self care
moment because there
was also a lot of
other things on my
plate I was working
um I was working and
I also I have like
my own like hair
business now I was
working and I
started my own hair
business I make wigs
guys so if you guys
are interested in a
way my aunt named
my shy not shame any
wish I am so shy
crowd my shy and I
think I'm pretty
don't but what I do
like I make wigs
install wigs if you
live overseas or you
don't live in Canada
I can send the wick
to you well you can
send your hair to me
then I'll send the
week back so I don't
provide Harriet below
it but like yeah I
had to take some time
to focus on that
because and my
life balance is so
important when things
are unbalanced I'm
a whole mess like a
complete wreck and I
don't know what's
going on at all so I
needed to find that
balance and I know
that I needed to find
that balance but I
wasn't focused on
finding that balance
because there was so
many other things
going on that I was
distracted so I
could have found the
balance earlier but
I I did it like I
like life hits you
sometimes like frickin Tom seems
sometimes like at
the same time like
during all that after
like my birthday
vlog I also come back
and like be fully
active on YouTube
but like my spirits
weren't high like I wasn't a
happy-go-lucky you
know positive shine
and like I I'm known
to be or who I
actually am I wasn't
like I just wasn't
in a good mental
space and I really
needed to like I was
focusing on getting
back into a good place
but then it boom
something else I was
going through a
breakup after that
and that was a lot
because I was in a
relationship for a
very long time and
I definitely love
this person a lot
and like you know
things don't work I
was the point think
things happen and
stuff and I was going
through that and like
I was like I was
just emotionally
unstable you see and
say at that point
that makes it seem
crazy but like not
that it just wasn't
for me
and I'm not the
person to come on
YouTube and fake about
how great my life
is when it really
isn't I I just can't
fake smile I can't
fake do anything I
can't fake laugh like
if I do anything
I'd do it because I
want to and my heart
is in it i'ma with all my
hardtack person Mike
and I love you I
love you with all my
heart I hate you I
hate you with all my
heart I think you
that's just who I am
sometimes it's um
that's what like one
of my really bad traits
negative traits cuz
if I don't like it I
don't like you like
if I was just not in
a good space and shy
and had to take
care of shine because
her shine doesn't
take care of shine
who's gonna take care
of her right and I
really feel like a
lot of the time you
talk about like
self-care and our
mental health and
stuff but we really
don't take it
seriously until you're
actually in that
point another update
I'm not in school
at the moment I
took a semester off
school so I haven't
been in school I've
just been working
making wigs and that
basically takes up
my whole entire time
and then I have like
you know I tried to
make time to hang out
with friends and
have like a little
fun time so yeah I
took some time off
school because I
wasn't motivated
like I wanted to I
wasn't motivated about
anything I wasn't
motivated of hope
and you think like
first of all school
and then it was like
YouTube stuff then
it was like okay
Cheyenne you gotta
find like I wanted to
reef all in love
with everything so
while I'm not being
in school I wanted
to spend the time to
fall back in love
with what I was doing
understand why are
you going to school
Cheyenne why is this
important because
you could be making
Mad Money some of
your um without this
thing degree that
they say is gonna
change your life and
it has not changed
my life it just caused
me a whole bunch
of being society um
academia and a whole
bunch of damaged
stress and depression
like that's the AuSable
hasn't done for
me so far so I didn't
really understand
why I was just very
unhappy plus my
school went on strike
for like freaking
4 months like messing
up my vacation
line to think of
everything like such
like monado go back
you're not gonna
disrespect me at way
you ready a tecmo
buck that's not
that's not how life
works I was just
being Cheyenne I'm
learning me but I think
it's been a good
time like I've honestly
understood why
school is important
while not being
school the job right
now that I have is
like I hate it so
much that I would
never want to work
here and actually be
my job so it's important
that I go out
there and I go and get
a degree and then
a master's and what
I want to do so I
can love what I do
for the rest of my
life that is like
the most important
thing to me that I'm
doing what I love
and I'm helping
people period point
blank whatever I'm
doing I'm helping
people that is what
I want to do within
this period I've just
been learning to
be a little bit more
selfish put shine
like first over
things that don't
necessarily matter or
deserve that space
of where shine should
be it's just like
what - I want to do what
- I am loved
what does shine and
want some I think it
was all about me right
now in the place
that I am right now
in my life I feel
like you guys probably think I'm
rambling and I'm
talking about nothing
but this just this
is just where I am
like I don't know
fully where I'm going
I don't fully know
what's happening but
I am doing stuff
that I love and I'm
extremely passionate
about and it's
making me happy and
that's enough for me
right now
like Cheyenne is
Reif falling in love
with Cheyenne to
make I keep talking
myself it's you gotta
think I'm crazy
I'm not dancing swear
like I don't know
it's just so in Blake
y'all I just it's
just life and it's
picked me up it's
tossed me it's taught
me and your girls
still alive we still
be here thriving
kickin pushing and
yeah that's it
there's also another
reason why not in
school but I won't
say that until it's
done and that would
be like a whole
video on my stupidity
period this
discovery period that
I'm going through
there's a lot that
will change and I
will have to accept
because I'm one of
those people that
don't like change
these are times
like to do risky and
fun and dumb things
but just because
like I've never like
it's the high that
it gives me but like
changing my whole
life or like opening
up some new people
and whatnot it's not
really my thing
sadness struggling
with accepting teens
and understanding it
because it's part
of life and I have
to accept it when it
comes my weight whether
I like it or not
um I think I've
learned a lot through
this period so I will
be coming back to
do like a lot of videos
on things that I
learn that basically
what I'm saying
y'all is that your
girl is gonna try to
come back and be
consistent - there's
some hair companies
that are ready to
hand my ass to me
because I'm not going
to come on here not
give me you guys a
video and come into
a sponsored video
that's now I'm we
get into this lease
and can we get into
this like like oh we
get a little shine
here it's getting
nothing we can't fix
Devon this video I
want to say don't
allow anybody or
anything to steal your
joy and life things
happen some things a
lot of things out
of our control and
some things don't
define us or happen
because of who we are
what we have done
something just happened
because of that
so the story is written
that's how it's
supposed to go and it sucks
it's a bi TCH but
like you know we
should pop it nobody gets it
pop it in these streets
you know what we
you know what we do
want to do with a
Duke and like yeah
like I don't know did
you guys miss scene
did you guys I kind
of feel I rambled oh
this full video a
lot done if we understand
tell me you're
gonna do I that's
done til like and
what's been going
on in your lives I
feel like a lot of
you guys I don't I
don't know what's going
on like a lot of
you guys I don't
have your Instagram
snapchat so I don't
really know what's
going on in your
like if you've been
going through the
motions like I've been
going to tell me vent
below let me know
because we can type
this out together
sis we in this together
suits okay like
you got this together
since okay so we
can get it done
together okay Wow boom
it's a girl shy and I am
[Music]