hary one it's me Isabel it's been such a
long time my stomach just growled it's
been a really long time since I filmed
I'm so sorry it was my first year of
college finished and now I am back home
in Taiwan
I just wanted to film this video because
a few days ago or yesterday I was
watching Jenna's video of being
korean-american and this was a tag from
Amy her friend who was doing this in
terms of Asians Pacific American
Heritage Month and I was watching some
videos on BuzzFeed which they also had
other people talking about their
experiences being immigrants or also
like born in America but having to face
like some difficulties and also
successes being Asian so I thought I
would share some of my stories I am
really passionate about it overall
basically what Amy did was she put a
whole tag a few questions I just did her
questions that she provided and just
answered them back on my trusty dusty
laptop that further ado we'll just start
with it um new look
hello I hope you guys enjoy
so I'm Taiwanese American and I am a
second generation immigrant my parents
they left Taiwan to go to America and
they met and they fell in love and I was
born on July 22nd in San Diego and
that's how I came to be
like we were in San Diego and then we
moved to Irvine and then we moved to San
Jose I would have Chinese school and I
would also have temple and these were
things that were usually happening
during my weekends and it was just kind
of weird to connect with other people
and realize that they didn't have
Chinese school or they didn't have
temple to go to during the weekend that
was when I kind of felt like I was
different but I just didn't really know
why I was just like oh maybe that's just
my family likes to do this never really
had that much thought about it what
really made me realize how different I
was is when my family moved to Taiwan
because of my dad's job during that time
I was placed into an International
School in Taiwan I VSH I just started to
notice the difference of like Oh being
Asian our school was literally like a
whole grade was like 57 people and
literally all of them were Asian there
were only probably a few that were not
even in that huge group of people that I
that were like the same ethnicity as me
I felt different I realized like my
experience in Taiwan would be so
different from my friends back in
America like their high school
experiences or like all the movies that
I would watch of like prom we did have
prom but it's like these experiences
were not going to be at like the same as
it would be if I was back in America and
that's when I started to realize the
difference of it or like international
school it's where academia is largely
English based but you will also have
Chinese class you also have Chinese
social studies which that adds on to an
extra two hours so when usually back in
America
I would end class at 247 i'd end class
here at 410 so that was always something
where - I dressed with and also like the
culture was not entirely similar to
being in America
and like having the education there
when I was back
in America I would be like super excited
of being um going to Taiwan because I
was like this is the place where I love
how crowded it I was always really happy
to go to Taiwan I would find my family
like my relatives and my grandma
she cooked amazing food there was only
once I went to back to Taiwan I actually
lived there like lived here permanently
for like eight years
um that's when I started to really like
reject my culture cuz I felt like
everything was so homogenized and there
was a really much diversity not saying
all Asians are the same someone says
that like but in terms of like our
background was pretty much similar in my
high school it was incredibly
competitive there would be days where I
felt like I was living in a bubble
because everyone was kind of striving
for the same things that it just started
to become really like pressuring over
all I really wanted to meet people that
were different from me like they had
different stories they had a different
background as opposed to something so
similar because I felt like that really
just made me focus on like a really
narrow mindset as opposed to have like a
wider mindset I only started to really
like appreciate it was when I came back
from my first year know first semester
from college I go to college in New York
so New York and Taiwan is literally like
halfway across the globe it's just so
far away there is still like some parts
of Taiwanese culture but it's pretty
miniscule compared to coming back here
really just allowed me to miss home and
realize like there are some experiences
that I have that no one is able to
really comprehend and really truly
understand I felt so grateful to have I
felt so grateful to be called the
international student because it really
allowed me to gain this like critical
view point the way of how I saw my life
back in Taiwan and my life during
college
okay so some stereotypes that I managed
to struggle with Asian they're smart
Asians are good at math there's so many
others that I could keep on talking
about but that would just take a really
long time for this pressure like that
was not really spoken but you could
still feel Asians should be doing
something that's more practical
something more science or like stem
based I was never really the person who
was good at that
I would always struggle on the subjects
that we were expected agents were
expected to be good at wanting to do
performing arts that just really made me
different a lot of people would really
judge comments of like oh are you sure
you really want to do performing arts
because it's not like something that's
biological I'm not born where I'm just
naturally good at math and science I get
so tired when people just say that it's
such like it's something that's so
natural it's not how much hard work is
instilled in like the academic system in
Taiwan or like the kind of culture and
like ideals that your parents instill on
to you that's like the stereotype that I
really just struggled with
growing up in this kind of Taiwanese
culture they essentially instilled what
they were taught from their parents to
put on to like me and my brother they
had more of a traditional mindset when
it came to gender norms for example for
being a female I was expected to be prim
and proper not to be too loud like not
focusing is it focusing okay yeah often
it's like what's expected of a son and
what's expected of a daughter and yeah
like the things that they have been
taught at a young age differs from like
the things that I've been taught in
college I've taken like classes and
woman and Gender Studies classes like
those really challenged like the social
norms and like gender norms like
expectations that are given that was
like a huge eye-opener for things that
I've always questioned but was never
really able to put a firm like stance or
belief in a lot of my views that often
or sometimes come in clash with my
parents are because I take the
indoctrinations that they bring to me
and I also take like my outside college
experience analyzing what are the
stances that I believe like what are the
values that I hold true I feel like in
Western like culture they emphasize on
individualism it's that certain sense of
like finding your own self and that
you're the one who's able to create your
own destiny don't know if that really is
truly related but like it's somewhat
correlated yeah
yes I am extremely proud to be telling
these American I think both cultures
Taiwanese and being American like these
really shaped the person that I am
there's this way where I can compare and
contrast and even like fuse together
differing viewpoints I remember I was
talking to my dad came back from my
first semester of college realizing that
being Toni's is something that I'm
really proud of and he said like yeah
the thing is that you'll always be
Taiwanese not American like that's for
sure I stopped him and I said the thing
is that I don't believe that American
means only one thing like being American
is being white instead being American is
being Korean American being Japanese
American his Latin ex American African
American and even immigrants make up
what is American that's my definition
yes you can be both you can be Taiwanese
you can be American there should be this
part where American capsule eights
Taiwanese or like Korean just people who
come to the States and just want to be
here I really identify with it it's kind
of like gratitude that you have because
there's so much more to you your
ethnicity is important but it's not
something that solely defines you our
last question
my favorite thing about being
asian-american is bringing forth a
different perspective when I'm in the
States or when I'm even in Taiwan darío
types are still so prevalent in our
society I can't like tell you how many
times I've like had so many
microaggressions that were directed at
me or like stereotypes that people would
use are you kidding me
I think being a Taiwanese American
really just allows me to be like this
advocate against the stereotype there
wouldn't be this kind of X like belief
that oh I would just breathe in and take
it I want people to understand that
stereotypes are not the way to allow
people to get together instead it just
divides other people it really makes me
uncomfortable when people just reduce my
personality or Who I am as a person to
just something so simple and something
so offensive
I think being Taiwanese American really
allows me to just understand that
there's still so much to that needs to
be done in terms of bringing more
representation when it comes to like TV
shows or movies because there are so
many stereotypes that like you can see
in film the great wall for example and
assume that white people are the ones
that are saving China you would never
really understand or realize that
there's a certain kind of dignity
something that's more magnificent and
the actual true story of something then
an outsider's viewpoint of a country
that's alien that's really just my
favorite thing about being an
asian-american
thank you so much for watching my video
I am incredibly thankful for those who
watched till the end I will put the
questions down below in the description
and you can just write in the comments
of what you feel like it is being an
asian-american you can comment down
below or you can make your own video and
tag me on it I would love to see it hope
you guys really enjoyed this video it
was hard at times to say but it's
something that I'm incredibly happy to
do and I hope you guys enjoy
Asian Pacific American Heritage Month
and have a good day I am an incredibly
awkward being I'm so sorry I'm so so
sorry