are you guys ready for some piping hot
[ __ ] takes
[Music]
preemptively if you'd like to give me a
thumbs up for the amount i'm about to
over share
that would be much appreciated
ordinarily in my almost 10 years of
doing youtube
when i do any sort of q a those of you
following me on instagram will submit
the questions
i will scroll through i will audit for
the ones that seem the most relevant or
topical
timely there's a lot of bias going on in
here
there's a lot of custom selection but
today we're going to
wipe that all away and answer the
questions that i have
strategically avoided over
many many years i haven't even read
through any of these yet so you're gonna
get the raw and real reactions i wanted
no pre-meditation on any of these so
that you guys get
the the genuine [ __ ] only and we're
gonna start with the one that i was
expecting it's top of the pile
why did you and austin break up so it's
been two years
i will say i like definitely snuck the
announcement about the breakup
into a video that didn't really have it
in the title mainly because breakup
videos were like
very popular in that season of youtube
and i felt
really really icky about exploiting my
breakup for views
but right now i am circling the question
so let's just go right
in and just say that listen like we were
together for four years
i completely love that relationship
online with all of you so i totally
understand the curiosity
it like wasn't an amicable breakup so i
didn't feel super comfortable talking
about it online but
he was like my first serious
relationship
we were together for almost four years
and i think just tort it was a really
happy
lovely healthy relationship for most of
it just to clear up like there was no
toxic horrible huge blow up moment where
it ended there was none of that
it was more so just that towards the end
i just kind of like realized that i
convinced myself that i was happy in the
relationship and that
i was fulfilled and i felt good about it
but in reality
um i wasn't and the way i would kind of
put it and explain it to people because
it was really shocking when we broke up
is that our relationship like
a through o
was incredible and we were super
compatible and there was so much good
but there was
p through z where i was like i don't
know if this is just what you sign up
for when you're in relationship
i don't know if these more negative
things i need to just settle for or if
there's somebody out there that
potentially could fulfill
me and compliment me more which i never
expect anybody to
be your everything and be your a to z
that's totally unrealistic but i think
it was a situation where i didn't know
what i didn't know
and i clearly just wasn't happy for a
number of different reasons
i'm not going to say those reasons i
know that everybody would want me to but
it's like there's still another person
in this situation that doesn't get to
share his piece so i think it would just
be like
super immoral and evil to like spill
dirt on somebody else and honestly i
harbor no resentment like we've both
moved on
i wouldn't say we're like friends but i
can certainly text him if there's
something like
pressing and like maybe we'll be friends
in the future so
that's that on that he was my first love
he'll always be my first love
i do not regret it i learned so much
from the relationship i look back on a
lot of fond memories but i am really
happy
i'm not really happy overall because
we're in a pandemic but i'm happy to
be single were you wilder than you let
on in your college vlogs and just chose
to maintain a cleaner image or is what
we saw
pretty much what there was to see
honestly
i wasn't that wild in college like i
definitely
drank but there wasn't any like wild
like i never had a fake id like i was
just this like normie kid pretty much
like
definitely in band there was some like
raunchy kind of stuff going on
and some like not so pg stuff but like i
vlogged at like band parties and stuff
so it's not like i was just
hey i'm always in the library i think my
college vlogs genuinely were like
pretty much an accurate representation
of what was going on which is probably
not the answer that you guys want to
hear but that's
that's my take would you ever have a
public semi-public relationship again
um i think maybe i would let you guys
know that i'm in a relationship or maybe
i would post
bits and pieces but i don't think i
would ever want
to advertise my relationship online
again just because
and i've like had a lot of reckoning
with this i choose to share a lot of my
life online and i would never want to
feel like i was subtly encouraging
or influencing my partner my friends my
loved ones to like
need to be a part of my youtube videos
because it's hard to live your life
publicly online like
you get a lot of criticism you get a lot
of eyes watching you and and while i
make that choice for myself i would
never want to make that choice
for someone else so i think that's kind
of why i wouldn't want to live
my life publicly but then again like
this is single me talking so who knows
what will happen in the future
how's your grieving journey going since
the loss of your best friend
i don't talk about this in most of my
videos just because it is
so so personal i just feel like there's
not a lot of avenues to open up about it
online
i have done so very thoroughly in a
couple of videos because i know how
important it was for me to see others
grieving when i was grieving
and understand like what that looked
like for people to make me feel
less alone and more in community um and
my grief looks very different now it's
it's not
it's more in sort of the restoration
phase where
there are like really random moments i
remember
i was interviewing for my job for a
promotion and
i was prepping the night before and i
had all this work to do and
this presentation to make and for some
reason out of nowhere just like a pang
of grief hit me over her
and i spent that night like really
really intensely
in my feelings and crying and just sort
of
re-mourning that loss because
it's it's never gone i think about her
literally every single day and i
can feel myself already getting
emotional about it it's never too deep
below the surface but it's not at the
surface anymore
if that makes any sense what's up with
your dating life
i have dated around and dated a few
people nothing serious
nothing like i would ever title a
relationship i'm not dating
anymore because my mom is
immunocompromised and so that would be
horribly recklessly irresponsible and i
could never do that to her so
um while i'm super open to it and i
would love
to meet some people and just like
explore that part of my life
i am not currently do you regret posting
your relationship on the internet
yeah like i actually want to answer yes
to this um
i don't regret the relationship very
distinctly
at all what i do regret was like
blasting it online but to give past cats
some grace there was literally no way
my little brain would have been able to
comprehend
like that a relationship can end nobody
ever expects their relationship to end
so when i see people posting their
relationships online in like a very like
in like a very confident way i totally
understand
i don't think i'm alone in feeling this
way i think a lot of youtubers share
these
feelings and i think a lot of youtubers
on their second time around with a
relationship
just get a lot more conscious with what
they share some of them still choose to
share their relationships but they
become a lot more conscious with what
to share i've like unlisted a few of the
videos just that i felt
uncomfortable having still up but like a
number of them still are just because
i'm like
that's a part of my life that happened i
would never try to erase that
or pretend it never happened i'm proud
of that
relationship and like it's definitely
cringe to look back on
yourself and all of the like all the
puppy love and all of that
but um it's something i've like reckoned
with and gotten to a place where i'm
good what are your thoughts on the
recent trend of people leaving
california and relocating to a different
state slash country
something you've recently considered oh
my god guys
maybe i do have a hot take about this
one in that i
feel like a lot of the people leaving
california the graham stefans the joe
rogans the tim ferrisses of the world
it comes from a place of wealth and not
so much
a quality of life thing it comes from
place i think
chiefly what they really like or
predominantly what they mention in those
videos and what i hear from them is like
the taxes are too high or like it's too
hard to maintain my business here
like sort of coming from like a i know
that my money is more valuable
elsewhere versus for me i don't live in
california
to like optimize my wealth my goal in
life is not to accumulate wealth that's
not what i associate success with
it's obviously necessary to pay your
bills and receive health care in this
country like you need to like
have a job to just you know literally
exist
but i am not in the business of like
climbing to billionaire status so
i think the reason i have trouble is
because like a lot of things they
mentioned are like
the unhoused folks that really troubled
them
and i'm like i personally don't view
folks that are unhoused
as a facet of the city as like a quality
of the city like the traffic would be or
like the restaurants would be i'm like
they're people they're not like
something you can just mention
as a characteristic of the city
like like we literally have more empty
houses in this country than
unhoused people i think by a magnitude
of like 1.5 x like if we wanted to and
it's nuanced and it's complicated i know
it's not as easy as this but if we
wanted to
we could house so many of these folks we
just choose not to because there's no
profit in it and there's no
financial incentive to do that and
there's so many other countries where we
don't see
a homelessness crisis because they just
choose to
support their people differently so
that's the t that's the shade that being
said i'm like a california loyalist
i love this place i've always
evangelized it that doesn't mean i won't
criticize it and criticize like policy
choices made in california that doesn't
mean that i'm just like
blasting sunshine on it and saying it's
the best place ever for sure not
but you know i am looking to move to
washington and move to seattle and
experience something outside of
california
um would love to move abroad i would
love to live
in shanghai again i have a lot of
reoccurring
nostalgia for that time in my life and
living there
and i also can really see myself in like
zurich and switzerland i think would be
a really amazing experience
um so yeah it's not to say that you
won't see a leaving california video
from me but it's gonna be a very
different
outlook it's not because i'm like trying
to buy a massive house
you know it's like not from that angle
that i would ever leave it's just
because i myself for my personal growth
would depart but like i really probably
maybe will boomerang back here at some
point um
especially because my family's here have
you ever questioned your sexuality not
sure if it's just the crunchy vibes but
i feel like you might listen to sweater
weather lol
so i think i actually have been seeing
more
um comments about this since i've like
moved
more in the granola direction and
like many of my best friends are sapphic
and i just get along really well with
with my wlw women
um if you had asked me this question
like six months ago i'd be like no i
know for sure that i'm like
only attracted to men this is in
no way coming out video guys and i don't
want to be like yeah i'm like playing
with my sexuality it's more so just like
i feel like the time alone has given a
lot of people in my life
time to like rethink their gender and
the way they
perform their gender and like their
sexuality and a lot of that because
you just have time to spend with
yourself so i'm not trying to like
queerbait or anything i'm just being
open with the fact that i never thought
i would question my sexuality and i'm
in this moment um that's not to say that
like i'm gonna arrive at any sort of
conclusion that's different than the one
i have today
given that you're so anti-capitalist and
anti-hustle culture
why do you continue to work in sales at
a major tech company
why don't you instead work in government
or at a non-profit
given that you're back living with your
family it seems like the perfect time to
work in a less high-paying field
though speaking from experience you can
definitely earn a high wage in public
service
love this question am i a big ass
hypocrite lady
for saying oh my god i hate capitalism
and i hate this economic system that has
really like
hurt so many working-class americans
um and globally hurt so many working
class folks
um got a ton of reckoning and i think a
lot of my thoughts on this topic are
sort of circular
where i think about it and i'm like my
job is definitely
propping up capitalism but when i look
at a job and a lot of my friends and
non-profits
talk about the non-profit industrial
complex where when you work at a
non-profit
it actually is also propping up
capitalism and not to get too much into
like
economic theory or like political theory
because i know that's not really why
people come to my channel
but it's a huge passion of mine and i
felt like i've learned so much about my
political identity and gotten a real
political education
in a way i never did growing up so
that's why i want to talk about it
but nonprofits also do prop up
capitalism because
um when you have a government that
chooses to privatize a lot of social
services
like healthcare um like housing
non-profits oftentimes exist to try to
band-aid those
problems and where the pipes are sort of
leaking and busting open
a non-profit says hey let's use like you
know
money from bill and melinda gates to
help fix this
issue but it's not actually fix you know
addressing the root cause
of the incentives of capitalism and the
reason we don't have those
um problems addressed at the root i
don't know if i explain that whatsoever
but i just know and i've heard from
friends that like
want to do more public service work that
a lot of jobs you still feel like you're
just a cog in the machine and that
you're just propping up this system so
it's not
you we all have to participate in
capitalism i'll never have a job
that's outside of capitalism because
that's like saying you can be a fish
living on land it's like we currently
live in water until we all
as fish get together and decide we want
to
become amphibians and move on to land
like the water is what we got and you
have to live in this world
and maybe some of us can try to swim
closer to
the top of the water and try to see the
other options that are out there
i don't know if this analogy is making
any sense but
i would never criticize somebody for
participating in capitalism
um because that's the situation we have
like we all do that there we are not bad
capitalists because
we're not the people that um are
creating the problems does that make
sense like we're just working class
people
helping the rich get richer not to get
too charged here but at the top like i
literally could talk about forever i
love
um thinking about these sorts of things
so okay tldr
am i going to stay in sales forever no i
am interested in working in different
areas that
more closely align with my values but
will i ever get to a place where i'm
going to tell you guys
yeah i'm just doing like the best work
ever no i've tried to remove
any sort of superiority complex that
like anybody's job is better than
someone else's job
like we are just selling our labor like
getting our
bags that we can pay our bills and
support our families like
i would never criticize somebody for not
doing like ethical work because there
is no ethical consumption under
capitalism
how much do you earn um i feel like i
always have to explain myself and give
you guys the context because
i am trying to be as class conscious as
possible and i know that my life
is so different from the majority of
lives of americans
in large part because of my
intergenerational wealth my
my white privilege i did not earn what i
earned today
based on meritocracy and because i
worked harder for it than somebody else
it is literally so fueled by the
community i was raised the school i was
able to go to
that's just my little two cents my
salary
for my tech job is not fixed because
it's sales so i have a base salary that
i'm guaranteed
every month then that's 50 of my salary
and then 50
so half of my salary is commissioned so
if i close no deals this year which like
who knows i will earn zero dollars of
the
expected commission and if any of my
customers cancel their contracts i
actually owe the company money so
this is literally so subject to change
but as long as i don't go into the
negatives my
base salary is 92 000 which is
so much more than i ever thought i'd be
making out of college that's like
astronomical and then like i said it's
50 so if you do the math
my target earnings would be 185 000.
that's super recent i wasn't
targeted to make that much until this
new role i took
so it's not like i've been making that
amount for the past five years like it
very much was incrementally stepped up
um when i first came out of college i
was not making six figures i think
i was making like 60k so um which is
still
a ton of money like that's an insane
amount of money
um and then youtube it's really not
as much as you would think guys like i
don't have a manager i'm just this like
indie youtuber like i don't have people
that are like sending me pr packages and
like reaching out to brands to partner
with me
so i would say youtube i earn like
around
nine or ten thousand dollars um a year
like i said i'm trying to be class
conscious
it's one thing to say i earned this much
money and it's so much money and that's
crazy and it's another thing to say
what can i do if you all have folks in
your life that are seeking
any sort of like mutual aid type
situation especially black trans folks
if you have any
gofundmes or memos or twitter threads of
folks that need help
like please put those in the comments
that's my
mo's to make sure that i am
redistributing my wealth the way
that i can without you guys even
suggesting anything i'm already doing
that i just want to say i'm not asking
you guys to provide that labor for me
i'm just saying if there's folks that i
don't know about through my own research
into mutual aid
let me know i would love to support um
any of
your causes your local causes and
individual folks rather than
maybe huge non-profits that a lot of
their overhead goes to administration
fees rather than the individual people
that's that on that do you ever have a
tough time feeling like you might have
already peaked
i'm about to graduate college and i'm
definitely starting to feel this
i have already just claimed for myself
that i know i peaked in high school
i have never been as confident had as
high of self-esteem
um felt as bright
and as just on top of my [ __ ]
as i was in high school but i would say
there's no
negative like i don't have a tough time
now feeling like
i am no longer that like incredible and
maybe it's achievement oriented that i
feel like i peaked in high school like
i'm trying less and less to orient my
success and my worth and my value over
what i achieve and what i accomplish
and more just about my fulfillment i was
very fulfilled in high school so even if
i look at that through that angle like i
was still very fulfilled then
but that's not to say that i still can't
be fulfilled today
so i love that i'm constantly growing
and evolving and changing and i'm not
the same person i came onto youtube and
recorded my first video
as you know almost 10 years ago so i
would
almost rather backslide from my peak
than peak and stay that exact same
person forever
that's the thing about peaking is it's a
point in time you're never going to
maintain the peak
so i kind of feel good that like maybe
my progress hasn't always gone up and up
but progress and like growth isn't
always linear
um we've seen that in the past year
that's the way that goes so
what do you want to do youtube full-time
if it paid as well as your current job
this is an answer that i was so
confident about when i had
i did a q a i think january of last year
i'll link it below if you want to
watch that one and see how much my like
ideals and how i present myself and all
of that has changed
but um i was always really feel fearful
of being self-employed
i think because i was so used to having
structure
put upon me i'm so used to being a
lifelong student where i have classes at
these certain times
they tell me these are the mate the
classes required for your major
you know here's what you have to take
you have some freedom but here's pretty
much prescriptively
what you gotta do and then being in a
job it's like here's the job description
here's your role
here's what we're expecting of you and
then you get to decide do you wanna
try to beat those expectations do you
wanna just ride through it
that felt comfortable to me and i think
now i'm looking at it and i'm like i
think it was because i was just buying
into like
the paths that upset you know in front
of me i'm basically recording a [ __ ]
podcast right now with these answers but
i've been talking to a few folks because
i'm like if i were to redo my education
or pursue education again
i wouldn't really want a degree where
they enforce exactly which classes you
have to take
i would want to take classes that i just
find the most interesting and
i'm most curious about and like build my
own
degree per se and just take individual
classes
so i'm becoming more and more like
interested in building my own structure
so that is to say youtube wouldn't ever
have to pay the same
as my tech job for me to want to do it
full time i still
struggle with like it's just so hard to
stay relevant
on youtube and i think i would literally
drive myself cuckoo bonkers
right now when my views dip i'm like oh
that doesn't feel great but it's also
like nobody has to watch my videos
it's just a form of creative expression
for me it's not like
i will literally not be able to pay rent
if my videos flop
but it would be really scary to be in
that position i thought i was going to
answer this question very differently
but now i'm seeing that i still have
kind of the same answer as last year
which is that
i would have a lot of caution around
doing youtube full-time but
i no longer look at people that do it
full-time and think oh my god that's
like so crazy and risky because i've
seen so many folks thrive
when they do it full-time does your
parents pay for your college and do you
feel privileged because of it
yes and yes my parents saved what is it
a 501
k there's a certain fund you can save
tax-free
from the time your child is like
literally conceived i think for college
and my parents prioritized that because
they had tech jobs where they were able
to
pay for that they had enough for three
years of a private education
and that is why i graduated from usc a
year early came in with ap
credits and said to myself i would
rather
have a three year experience at usc and
not be in like
60 to 70k of debt that i would have to
pay because they didn't save for me
then do the four years and have the debt
or go to a different school you know
um i really wanted the usc experience
for myself and i'm genuinely really
happy with the way i
went into that experience but i was only
able to make that decision because of
the
money my parents saved for me and i i've
been i don't think i've always been very
forthcoming about that and i'm trying to
be more and more forthcoming that i know
that my accomplishments are not my own
and that i'm standing on the shoulders
of um my parents where a lot of people
don't have shoulders to stand on feels
like you've changed a lot in the past
year or so how do your parents feel
about that change and has your
relationship with them also changed
i might actually do a video on kind of
like i'm about to turn 25 so maybe like
25 things i've learned before 25
i love those videos um i don't know if
any of you would be interested in that
but
i might just make it for myself you know
to kind of have something to look back
on
and if you want to watch it you can i
just i don't think there's been a year
in my life where i've learned
change developed in positive and
negative ways
more than this year like it's not just
all positive politically like i i
grew up pretty damn aligned with my
parents
and now i've moved um
a little a little little maybe a lot
further away from them
and i'm not the kind of person to like
hide who i am
and like hide what i believe i love to
have conversations i love to
be challenged about what i think and so
i've had a lot of those conversations
with my parents
doesn't result in a lot of like positive
warm and fuzzy feelings i'll just
be completely honest about that um but
it's not like they're
disappointed in me or anything i think
they're glad that i
can make up my own mind in this world
and that i'm not just like
literally following um exactly what
they would have done do you ever wish
you'd made different decisions in the
past and pursued other interests for
your education and career
does anybody ever feel fully confident
in their decisions because i'm just a
lady that's full of self-doubt
and i love and i think it's healthy to
doubt and
question um you know yourself and try to
like grow your self-awareness
if i could imbue 18 year old catherine
with the knowledge i know today
i would make much different decisions
but that's not how life works like the
brain i had at 18
what i learned about the world in my
very small bubble
i made decisions that i was happy with
and i don't regret those decisions
because i know that i did the best with
the information i had at the time
that being said if i were to go back to
school back to school now like
redo education like now i'm a lot more
interested in like political science
um and more like structural work rather
than
learning about like private companies
and that kind of thing would you ever
oh my god this is a wild question wow
would you
seriously date mary someone who is lower
than you socioeconomically
if yes would your parents be upset for
sure
i am no longer classist about who i date
i for sure was like i remember thinking
like i need to date someone that earns a
certain amount because i know i want to
live in the bay area and in order to
afford a house in the bay area you have
to have x dual income to afford this and
afford that
and it was very much like i was planning
out my entire life path
but now i'm less like i need to buy a
house i'm like it would be okay if i had
to rent forever i'm not like
100 nailed down to living in the bay
area so it's not like i need someone
that's
you know working in tech and doing that
whole thing so for sure i would date
someone
um lower than me socioeconomically like
for sure but i will acknowledge that i
didn't always think like that
and would my parents be upset hopefully
not we'll cross that bridge if we ever
get to it
is there a video you regret posting and
what's your favorite video that you've
made
my favorite video that i've made is
actually my transformation into a
granola girl video
i think the way i packaged it with the
title and the thumbnail it didn't
get it didn't seem as appealing because
i'm just i'm just really bad at titles
and thumbnails guys like i'm just
that's the hardest part of youtube for
me so i think i packaged it in the wrong
way but the actual content of the video
i'm so so happy with and i think it's
the best work i've ever done
i think i'm like the most me in that
video and i just think i was able to
channel a ton of creativity in there so
check it out because i think it it is
really different than
what i've made in the past and i like it
um a video i regret posting
is the video i talked about how i saved
50 000
my first year out of college because i
was so
like entitled in that video and i had
such a lack of conception of like the
economic reality of most americans and i
think my
financial advice in that video was very
non-inclusive
i would i actually haven't watched it in
years and years but i just remember
getting a lot of comments about like hey
dude like the only reason you're able to
save is because you didn't have any
student loans
and i wasn't upfront about that so i
think i just approached that video the
wrong way
um i've tried to make my financial
videos in the in
the last couple ones i did much more
inclusive let me know if i've
accomplished that if i still have you
know work to you know
work to go on that on a scale of one to
gay where do you think you
fall is there a scale of one to gay what
happened with your college bf do we hate
him no we don't hate him
okay i just looked through all the
questions and everything else was either
a repeat
or something i've already answered in a
previous video
please leave me a comment with what
surprised you the most or
the biggest hot take of the video in
your opinion you might not agree with
everything i said in this video and i
totally get that i think i gave you guys
a
much bigger window into my world view
than i usually do i might have voiced
some unpopular opinions i totally get
that i'm growing and changing and
shifting and just trying to figure out
who i am in this world and i hope that
you will give me grace that
um i'm just trying my best when i know
better i do better
sometimes i do not know better if
somehow you're watching this video and
you're not subscribed
that red button is so much prettier when
it turns gray
and you just have to click it and
finally if a lot of this was surprising
to you and you felt like you learned a
lot more about me in this video than you
usually do
i feel like my twitter and instagram
fill out a lot more of my life just
because youtube is a very specific
medium to package content in so
if you want to explore any more of my
radical takes
twitter is the vehicle for that
instagram is the vehicle for random
thoughts
and realizations i have thank you so
much for watching
i'll see you all next time and cather
out
[Music]