if I could you imagine
what life would
be like without black
people could you
imagine what life
would be like without
black women hey
guys what's up and
welcome back to my channel
whoo I feel like I'm
so far away from
the camera but it's
like I don't want it
I don't want it
immense cuz I don't I
don't want the
close-up like I don't
need the close-up
so what's up and
welcome back to my channel
just know when I film
videos like this
is because I have ran
out of video ideas
ok ran out of video ideas
it shows the other
video that I want to
film like I saw the
list of videos that
I want to film it just
I can't film them
quite yet because
there's what it's like
missing like pieces
of a puzzle you know
Dean doesn't make any
sense I just also
hate ok this is my
birthday weekend kind
of a fight infection
on my name itself
so we are going to
be doing the black
girl tag the people
even still do ties
here on YouTube I
don't think so but
it's cool you know
we're still gonna
have fun we're still
going to do it but
before we even get
into that if you have
not already make
sure you subscribe
don't forget to give
this video a thumbs
up now let's don't
I don't know I did
that it's not like
it's gonna have a
cool transition or
anything so question
number one
have you heard you
sound like a white
girl no I don't think
anyone has ever
told me that I sound
like a white girl
because I don't know
I feel like I have
a pretty deep voice
and if someone was
on the phone with me
I feel like they'll
be able to tell that
I am black however
when I was in middle
school some of the
friends I used to
hang out with used to
call me Oreo for some
strange reason and
it definitely was not
because I used to
act white I just
think it was because
they was real dirty
and they want the
participating ratchet
get other stuff
and I was not about
that life so I think
that's why they call
me Oreo but not
necessarily because
I act do I just
because I didn't want to do that
stuff that they was
doing but now that
I'm grown I'm all
for it so you know
question number two
are you natural
relaxed or tech slacks
hmm I don't really
know what tech slacks
mean but I am natural
when did you big
chop so I've actually
never got the big
chop I just started
transitioning I want
to say and fall like
2013 I just started
transitioning so yeah
and then over time
I kind of went through
and just like cut
pieces off but I never
officially like
we went to the place
I'm I got my hair
cut off but I honestly
need to because
it is not doing so
well what is the one
thing that you like
about your hair okay
I'm just kidding no
I really do like my
hair um I feel like
I'm learning how to
love it and appreciate
it just because
for the longest
time like I used to
always wear weave in
my head I mean like
I started wearing
weave at a very young
age like a very
very young age so I
think now that I'm
older like I'm
starting to appreciate
it more and I'm
starting to wear it
out more like this
right here even
though technically I
have on a ponytail
this right here is
big for me because I
never used to do this
like when I was in
high school in
college like I never
would've worn my
hair like this so I
think I'm learning
how to appreciate it
more and then honestly
I feel like with
my hair I feel like
if I truly took care
of it like the way
I'm supposed to it
will be just fine
but because I don't
what happens is I
start to take care of
it and then I get
really lazy and I go
back to wigs and stuff
like that and I
kind of like mess it
up all over again
it's like this face
like I keep doing it
but I know for a fact
that if I actually
take care of it and
like put the right
products in it and
like do things that
I'm supposed to do
that my hair will be
just fine but I just
have a problem with
consistency what
don't you like about
your hair every thing I know I
do I like my hair but
what I don't like
about it is um it's
just difficult to
work with like sometimes I get
frustrated when I
see videos on like
natural hair especially
for women with
my textured hair
like you can't do this
you can't do that
you can't do this
you can't I'm like
that what's the point
of having hair
like what is the
point of having hair
you can't touch it
what black celebrity
do people say you
look like okay I have
been told numerous
times and I know
y'all gonna be like
what the cuz I do not see it and
trust me I do not
see it either but I
have been told
numerous times I would
say about like three
or four times in my
life that I look
like Teyana Taylor
which is so weird
because first of all I
think she honest
Taylor is beautiful
like she's gorgeous
so yes that is a
compliment to me but
I do not see it
like I do not think
I look like her at
all like I don't like
we literally look
nothing alike but
I've been told I look
like Teyana Taylor
and I think she is
gorgeous and then
recently someone told
me I look like Nia
Long which I'll also
take but those are
the only two that I
can think of at the
moment um did you go
to a predominately
white or black school
I went to a black
and Hispanic school
okay straight up
black straight up
Hispanic that's it
I could literally
count the amount of
white people that
went to my skin I
know y'all see that
Ash
really Wow okay I
can literally count
the amount of white
people that went to
my school on like one
hand it also had a
bunch of like Asian
people too but if I
had to pick like a
number it was for
sure black Hispanic
mess and they're
like Asian it was
pretty it's pretty
diverse this I mean
despite not having
white people but other
than that it was
pretty diverse what
is your favorite
thing about being black
oh honey I don't
even know I don't it's
just like it just
feels good like I
can't explain it I
feel like if you black then he'd
probably know exactly
what I'm talking
about but it just feels
good like I just
feel like we are the
culture that most
people I try to emulate
and things like
that you don't have
to grew me but
that's just my
personal opinion like
it's like could you
imagine what life
would be like without
black people could
you imagine what
life would be like
without black women
I can't so I don't
know I just love me
and black it's just
it's amazing it's
empowering and just
just to look at like
our history and
like where we are now
and where we are
going like it's just
insane like I just
feel like in my
opinion again like I
know a lot of people
may not agree but I
feel like the black
race or like the
african-american race
is just it's just
progressing like
it's just getting
better and better
and honey you can't
stop us okay you can't
stop us dude they
have your shade at
your local drugstore
yes they do have you
ever dated a white
guy I've never like
dated a white guy
well okay how about
this I was never in
a serious relationship
with a white guy
but I did go on a few
dates with one guy
who was white and you
know it was cool
he was cool or
whatever he was like a
different type of
white guy though for
sure like well then
again what does that
even mean I don't
even know but he was
cool he was cool he
was I you know it is
what it is we never
like to get anywhere
but he was cool have
you ever heard is
that your real hair
if so win yes I've
heard that multiple
times I would say
though I used to hear
that a lot when I was
younger like when
I was in school and
stuff like that
people would act like
is that your real
hair and stuff like
that but I feel like
nowadays I don't hear
it often at all I
should I don't really
hear it at all I
think it's mainly
just because where we
have come like in our
culture wise and
meaning like I just
feel like everyone
knows about weave
and extensions and
stuff like that you
know back in the day
it was kind of like
hush hush like who
she got on the wig
or she got on weed
stuff like that now
everybody do it not
just black people
white women Hispanic
women Asian women
like everyone kind of
has extensions and
stuff like that so I
feel like at this
point it doesn't even
matter because like I
feel like a lot of
people don't even
really where they're
like full hair anymore
or their real
hair or at least like
all of it be their
real hair but so yeah
I used to hear it
a lot when I was younger
like when I was
in school but now that
I'm older I don't
really hear
opting box braids
or twist definitely
twist I look so stupid
with braids in my
head like I cannot
wear braids like to
the back you're not
some girls be having
those like braid
designs and they're so
cute it's like to the
back of their head
they're kind of
like cornrows but
they're like long and
stuff like that I
cannot wear those
hairstyles like I look
so ugly with my hair
like all the way to
the back like right
now you're probably
thinking like your
hair is to the back
now but technically
I got I kind of got
something like in
my face and then
there's also this
hair in the back that
kind of takes away
from it but like
y'all like if I just
like like I look so
bad with my hair
straight to the back so
I can't wear that
side 100% preferred
twist when do you
feel the blackest
around family friends
would say we'd walk
through the blackest
I was saying around
family France hell
I'll 3 hell all 3
like I feel black
around my family
because we all black I
feel black around
my friends because
majority of them is
black I don't know
like it's just who
I am I'm black so
like and then of
course I feel black
around white people
how else am I gonna
feel black you know
so is your best
friend black why did
I read that like
that is your best
friend black so I have
two best friends one
of them is actually
black and the other
one is actually
Asian so you know
call me diversity are
you loud or quiet
I am definitely loud
I was gonna try to
make up an excuse
and explain how I'm
quiet but plenty of
plenty of people
have told me that I'm
loud so I am loud
does your name have
a Isha in it no it
does not
Jalen Janine Jackson is my name
do you drink Starbucks
no I do not do
people ever say you
are ghetto or do
act ghetto no and I
feel like that's a
very I feel like
that's a very dumb
question just because
I've seen people that are not
at ghetto so I don't
really think that
has anything to do
with race I just
think that has to do
with like who you
are as a person and
how you act around
others so can you
dance yes I can dance
I can like I can do
a little jig like
I'm a beat come on
you know I can do my
little jig I can twerk
some but as far
as I can get up there
and be like like
no I can't do any
of that type of
dancing do you eat
chicken yes yes my do
my favorite type
of chicken bow is
Popeyes so and yes
I was a hundred
percent for that
Popeyes chicken salad
do you wear wheat if
so how often yes I
do where we I have
it in my head right
now as much as I
wish this was my
ponytail it is not
and I do wear wigs
and stuff like that
were you always
confident in wearing
your hat short milk
where are you
always confident in
wearing your natural
hair no I was not
and honestly I it
kind of changes there
are moments when I
am very confident
with wearing it and
then there are
moments when I'm not
it really just it
depends on where I'm
going and then just
like how it is in
general like again
like I've actually
take care of my hair
because I've done
it in the past when
I've actually took
taken care of my
natural hair and I
will wear like an
acute like twist out
with like I don't
know it just depends
but no I haven't
always been confident
and wearing it and
I'm still not 100%
confident in wearing
it it's gonna take
some time but I know
that more I wear the
more I learn about
it it'll be all
good what is your
favorite hair brand
ooh that is actually
a difficult question
okay so okay no
boom if we're talking
about in terms of
like weave like
bundles my favorite
hammering is she's
happy hair and I know
I'm gonna get a lot
of crap for that
because I know a
lot of people hate
she's happy hair but
that hair is so
good like you have
no idea I made a wig
and 2017 I still have
that wig today now
I will say I do need
to switch out the
closure because the
closure is balding
but the hair itself is still
like she's happy
hair is really good
hair I love it I know
some people don't
like it but I like it
how deep is it for
you to let someone
see you in your
headscarf it is a big
deal and I don't
think any of the guys
I've ever talked
to in my life have seen me in a
headscarf I'm on
maybe one but it's a
big deal like if you
see me in my bun to
my what does it call my Bonnie
oh you you're close
we're close two more
questions and then
we are going to be
done
what black woman do
you relate to the
most fiction or
nonfiction like Olivia
Pope Oh Laverne Cox
Solange um what
black woman do you
relate to the most
oh who do I relate
to fiction they
definitely don't know
I feel like I feel
like okay so nonfiction
wise I feel like
there was a black
like Celebi that I
would say I relate to
what probably have
to be like Issa Rae
I don't know I just
feel like she keeps
it real and a lot of
the stuff she's like
voicing I feel like
a lot of black women
go through I don't
know like I would say
Issa rate and then
as far as like nonfiction
I don't really relate
to this person but
I'm obsessed with
like annalise keating
which is Viola Davis
character on how to
get away with murder
but to be fair I'm
also obsessed like
Olivia Pope too but I
don't know like I
just liked their
characters I feel
like I feel like
actually you know what
I can't relate to
Anneliese kidding
because on that show
she was like a slight
actually she was
alcoholic at man I'm
not alcoholic boo
and like be rough
y'all straight vodka
does not sound like a bad idea
okay okay last
question okay last
question and we're
doing name four black
classic movies that
you have or haven't
seen okay so my first
classic movie that
I've loved and set it
off oh I love that
movie so much the
second one would ever
have to be poetic justice we
Janet Jackson if Tupac
if his fine stuff
and then as third
one I don't know I
really do like loving basketball
although I've seen
that movie so many
times that if you put
it on the TV right
now I would probably
throw something at
it now there is two
black movies that I
have not seen and
I am so ashamed
I'm so ashamed but
I'm just gonna say
them okay I have not
seen a menace to
society all the way
through like I've
only seen bits and
pieces of it and yeah
so I've never seen
like ministers
society all the
way through and I
actually want to see
that movie but no
one has it like Netflix
doesn't have it
Hulu and I'm not
trying to put any more
viruses on this computer
so I don't know
but mr. society and
then I've never seen
belly I know right
I've never seen belly
in my life I've never
seen it and I want
to but I just haven't
had the chance to
so those are my two
like black movies
that I need to see
that everyone has
like seen and loved
better than that I
think I'm good but
that is going to be
all for this video
I'm not gonna lie I
actually enjoyed
some of this video a
lot more than what I
thought I would so
if you enjoyed it
just as much as I did
then don't forget to
give this video a
thumbs up don't forget
to subscribe and
I'll see you guys soon
you