Germany epsilonc my Jasmine hey
everybody its Jasmine and today I have a
brand new video that I was actually
requested by one of my subscribers her
name Isabella and I was requested to do
a videos talking about me being
Cambodian this topic to me is something
I never thought I would actually address
because I never thought of I guess the
importance of actually vocalizing how I
feel about my own ethnicity about my own
culture and my roots but apparently to
some of you guys it is very interesting
because a lot of the comments that I do
get from other my Watchers viewers you
guys always tell me oh my god I've never
seen a Cambodian youtuber so to me that
is a huge compliment in its own so this
is why I feel confident in talking about
everything that I'm gonna talk about
today hopefully we can learn a little
bit more about each other I do have some
questions that you guys personally asked
me but I'm gonna just start off with a
little bit of an FAQ type of thing
because you guys have pretty much the
same questions so am I born in America
or was I born in Cambodia I was born in
California my parents were born in
Cambodia and unfortunately they endure
the Khmer Rouge which is why they moved
here in the first place
now unfortunately within the war I lost
my two grandfather's and I just never
grew up with them I grew up with
everybody else in my family which I'm so
thankful for but I just wish I had a
grandfather figure to talk to but I know
he's somewhere out there looking down on
me blessing me being like I see you girl
I see you another question that I get
asked not only online but my friends
asked me to do I speak mine
unfortunately I can understand it very
well I could speak like the bare minimum
and as of right now as of like a week
ago I've actually been trying to teach
myself how to speak more and more come I
so right now where I'm at if you want to
see my progress I can count up to 20
pretty confidently
so there's that I am thinking about
doing a whole video like a makeup
tutorial where I speak cry but that is
so scary Chinese maybe later maybe later
have I ever visited Cambodia yes when I
was 16 right now I'm 20 keeps you guys
over now and it was nice it was really
cool I got to see where my parents grew
up I got to see from pain and I it was
just it was just an eye-opening
experience overall and I would
definitely go back but you know it's
just it's all the way across the world
honey so whenever I have time when I
ever have money especially money then I
would be glad to go again so I'm just
gonna go on to my YouTube community tab
where you guys ask me some questions and
I got one from emerald on the moon that
says lol you're like the first one I've
ever seen on YouTube so it would be a
cool video she's talking about this one
but one question would be what do your
parents think about it kind of my
parents are always so not understanding
and strict but yours may not be so
beagle to know now when I told my
parents and I made YouTube videos their
initial reaction I was like okay cool my
parents I feel like are strict to the
point where like I can't hang out with
people but then if it's like something
that I want to do on my own and that's
affecting just me personally I don't
think they really care for example I cut
my hair right I cut my bangs they don't
care I would dye my bangs blue in high
school they didn't care if I asked for a
sleepover they would say no but when I
told them I had a YouTube channel and
when they actually found out and they
found out that has a significant handful
of people who are watching then we were
really proud of me and they were like
wow you're really doing some you
know so it's really cool to see them
actually support what I like doing you
know being a makeup artist like a
freelance makeup artist and seeing them
support me it's very very reassuring
I never thought that I would have a
career or just something that I like
doing that they approve of because Asian
parents in general so strict I was
always the kid who had to get straight
A's and had to do my best in school so
just doing something that I thought was
out of the ordinary is kind of scary but
just knowing that they're okay with it
is a big breath of fresh air
Bianca Lee asked me what it's like to be
a Cambodian youtuber there isn't a very
large Asian beauty guru community so I
think starting out was hard in the sense
of not seeing this role in the community
I agree completely
I noticed it from a very young age even
where I live even in the community that
I live in I am pretty much always the
only Cambodian person and I think that
just being in a community in person
where there's not a lot of Cambodian
people it just put into perspective that
I want to represent Cambodians I don't
know why but I just want to represent
because we are so often overlooked
because we are such a small country and
it's just it's sad to see that we are
depicted as like either gangsters or
either really poor and I just want you
guys know like hey we don't have to fall
into those stereotypes like we can be
like somewhat successful and we can be
somebody with those stereotypes attached
to us but we don't have to fall into
them and another side note even before I
was fully into makeup and all that I
even noticed on those foundation charts
or even in magazines there were rarely
any Asian models and if there was an
asian model they were stark white
there were always like the palest asian
so to me I always felt like oh that
makes me really pale too but no I have a
medium skin tone
I'm an Asian girl color and I want to
see more of that represented whether
they are Cambodian whether whether they
are Thai whether they're allow or than
me and I don't care I want to see the
representation within the brands because
we're often always overlooked Rose like
the flower asked me do you speak
Cambodian and if you do can you give us
a little sample maybe say yes I speak
Cambodian oh I suck at when people tell
me to say a specific sentence because I
get put under pressure if I remember
correctly Jack you'll make my and
knowing my parents I know damn well they
taught me Cambodian before it English
but they started to talk a little bit
more English at home because they wanted
to learn English so that kind of halted
the expansion of my knowledge to speak
my but I can understand it saying Karen
asked me how is your diet mostly
Cambodian or American and what is my
favorite Cambodian meal my diet is
anything Asian anything Asian I love
Asian food whether it's Korean whether
it is Vietnamese whether it's Thai
whether it's Cambodian I love it all I'm
just such a huge foodie they're like oh
a junk food doesn't right it's so
filling it's so warm it's just so so
much like home to me and it just makes
me feel so comforted so any Asian food
will do American food though I don't
really eat all that much American food
to be honest it makes me feel very
bloated and very fat so I'd rather not
you know and then she said what is my
favorite Cambodian meal
I love salami - I love Salama - with
those little lotus roots goodbye you
good bye have a nice day like I would be
all up in there I would literally go in
and just take the limit lotus root
lettuce just take it take it girl yes my
uncle makes amazing Ben chow oh my god
oh my god and obviously just your
typical 'kathy which is
you can't really go wrong with noodles
right so I asked you guys questions on
Instagram and you guys asked me Tania
Sam asked me why do you think there are
so few Cambodians anything more so she's
talking about the YouTube side of things
or like social media I think there's so
few because again we're not represented
and it kind of goes back to the first
question that I had from Emerald it's
because a lot of Asian parents are
strict not a lot of parents are able to
be cool and she'll be like hey that's
the right way to go because you know
there there's a lot of pressure because
my parents and my auntie's and everyone
everybody who's older than me majored in
some type of science biology physiology
what it whatever and I'm like I'm like
the next one down you know and so I I
had a lot of pressure and I can just
probably tell you that it is the
pressure from Cambodian families because
again we are poor country and yes we're
kind of like up-and-coming buy more so
we are pretty poor and I think that when
you are a Cambodian parent you want your
child to succeed and you want them to
make a good choices so that they can
have a lot of money provide for the
family and I think that just in an
outsider's perspective people don't
think that Oh making YouTube videos can
get you by I mean granted like I don't
really get paid off YouTube like most
most of my money is like commission from
affiliate links but even yet I still
like doing it but I think just having
having the mindset of like oh maybe my
parents aren't going to appreciate this
or even accept this is something that
always kind of runs in the back of our
minds and I think that is why there is
so few Jaden knows where they asked me
what was your favorite thing about
Cambodia and do I see myself moving back
while I never move there
first place but I think my favorite
thing about Cambodia was some of the
food definitely wherever you go food is
sometimes hit or miss depending on like
where you go but I remember I think it
was module kadhi and they there's this
restaurant there they had some fresh egg
noodles oh my god I had I dream about it
it was so good and it's just so fresh
like just everything about it like the
scenery and you know some of the people
there are really really nice obviously
my family was really nice to me but just
everything about it it just felt like
home to me
and I know it was really hot and I know
like the traffic there is crazy and
everything just like is it as I guess
civilized as the United States but I
just felt comfortable everything about
it I just felt really comfortable and I
had a great time and I do see myself
visiting again it's just something that
I cherish so much I mean it's my
motherland what do you expect I love it
there Cham Li asked me has anyone
assumed URIs girl everybody assumes my
race nobody ever ever in my life guess
that I was Cambodian I have never came
across anybody none of my friends ever
guessed I was Cambodian everybody in
this town that I live in thinks I'm
Filipino where I work people think I'm
Mexican they also think I'm Indian I
don't look Indian I mean I don't look I
don't even look Mexican and people think
I'm Chinese Japanese Korean people think
I'm Thai but like they think everything
but everything but Cambodian and it's
kind of crazy to me but also not crazy
because again we're just not represented
enough and that's kind of my mission my
mission in life is to represent my
fellow Cambodians you know
and whether be in makeup or whether it
be within my business major I want to
make it known I want to I want to let
people know that we're out here Taryn
asked me what was it like growing up
Cambodian in America any difficulties
and racism growing up in America it
definitely is kind of an eye-opener even
though I haven't you know been in
Cambodia all that much it was definitely
an eye-opener because even at a young
age like I said I kind of noticed that
I'm unrepresented in a lot of
circumstances and I noticed that people
look down on a lot of Asian people and
it's not just Cambodians it's literally
a lot of Asian people and they think
that Oh weird that is becoming like
nurses or just really good at math and
we just hold this stereotype where I
work there is a lot of racism and I've
caught in so many insults throughout my
life you know even at a young age like
people will come up to me and they'll be
like hey are you from China straight up
to my face people people at work would
be like I don't understand what you're
saying I don't speak your ching-chong
language or they would say things out of
pocket and when I'm working they would
say like can you read this it says like
I don't know like I'll just hold up this
because it's right in front of me my
hourglass highlighter it would just be
like can you read this H oh you are etc
etc so I went hit so much racism
throughout my life people think I've
been competent and people think that I
don't know how to speak English people
think that I don't know how to do all
these things regarding English and it's
just frustrating it's frustrating and
you don't know how many times I just try
to keep my cool and to just say you know
what they don't know me they don't know
where it came from and that to me racism
it's its own difficulty I just had a lot
of difficulties growing up
in general that don't pertain to being
Cambodian but that itself is a whole
nother video and I have just gone
through hell and back
basically so just thinking about like me
being bullied and like all the racial
slurs that I've endured it's a lot to
take in because but you never expect
like when you're 12 you never expect
people to come up to you and be like can
you read this because you're Asian it's
it's hard it's hard growing up in that
environment and I still I still get that
today you know it's something that's
never ending so it still like strikes
like a really hard core and yeah I don't
even know if that even makes sense but
it just it just hits me hard it's hard
when people just continuously bully you
and you know just say all these mean
things and they know that they're doing
you you know you can't just you can't
just say like the n-word
to an african-american person and just
be like oh yeah well like that's just
fine like no you know what you're doing
you know exactly what you're doing and
you're doing it to hurt somebody and
you're doing it to perpetuate somebody
you're not doing it just because it's
cool by the way I'm sorry for crying I
had like a really rough day at work
today people were calling me names
anything that's why I'm so upset about
the whole like racism thing it's because
it's so fresh it's so it's so like on
the surface you know and I'm just I'm
still trying to get through it so if you
ever think that calling people names or
saying anything rude to somebody is okay
it's never okay but you know what at the
end of the day I love being Cambodian I
love being underrepresented because it
gives me the space and opportunity to
grow and just show people was right from
wrong and
I am so thankful that I have a platform
where I can share my thoughts genuinely
and openly to you guys because again
it's helping me achieve my dream and
it's helping me spread the word that
like hey you know there's there's more
races and Asia than just Chinese
Japanese and Korean there's so many more
countries out there and I just want
people to know that you know it's okay
to like ask if somebody is a certain
race but you know it's another thing to
just assume and to belittle them because
it's not okay it's not fine I want to
end this video on a positive note and
just talk about the good things about
being Cambodian and you know it is
bittersweet that Cambodians are
underrepresented but it's also a
blessing because you know if your
Cambodian you're watching this we have
the power to make everybody aware that
you know we're here and we're here to
make an impact throughout my life I've
had many friends and I've added them a
lot about me and my culture through food
just through me speaking the very teeny
bit of Cambodian that I know and it's
good to share cultures and I think that
is something I want you guys to take
away from this share your cultures and
be open about it be open taking the
information with a very open mind
everybody is unique in their own way and
we are not what stereotypes claim us to
be so I just want to end this video on a
positive note thank you guys so much for
watching and thank you to everybody who
ask me questions thank you for
recommending this video and I hope this
shed some light onto you guys I'm sorry
I got really emotional I'm just a really
emotional person when it comes to
bullying and when it comes to just
racism so thank you guys so much and I
will see you guys in the next one bye
he saw grass cats
[Music]
[Applause]