hey friends my name is Mel and about a
year ago I made a video called live
after college and tips on dealing with a
struggle so this day it is still in my
most popular videos and I think the
reason why is because a lot of people
can relate to the topic people are still
damning me and messaging me up about
this topic and certain conversation and
sharing their stories and the kind of
struggle that they've been going through
and I feel like it's been super helpful
because we're both kind of getting
through it together and I just feel good
knowing that I wasn't alone and so I'm
hoping other people are feeling the same
way I kind of wanted to make an update
video on my life as of now in the past
year and what I've been kind of going
through to get myself out of the rut I'm
hoping that this video will kind of
inspire others and hopefully help them
in their situation last year as I said
in that previous video I was super
depressed and I wasn't happy with my job
so I made the decision to quit my job
and travel for the summer and kind of
find myself clear my head a little bit
and narrow down what I am truly
passionate about what I really want to
get out of life and how I can go about
achieving it once I was kind of
traveling and exploring and meeting new
people it made me realize what was
important back home and what wasn't big
part of why people don't leave their
jobs that they're unhappy about is
because of money and when I was
traveling I kind of realized that money
is so insignificant in the grander
scheme of things because it gets you by
it's a house over your head and food on
the table but honestly I had a start
from scratch and I feel like I
sacrificed so much and a huge part of it
was money I got back for my trips and I
was faced with okay what am I gonna do
now and I just started going in on
applications I was applying like no
other day after day after day I was
getting rejections I was revising my
resumes and nothing was happening for me
for months I hit a really really dark
place and I was so distraught because I
couldn't figure out where I could go
really felt like everything I worked so
hard for was going down the drain time
was passing and I was just sitting there
it's just stagnant and not knowing what
to do it really really it takes a toll
on the your mental health I feel because
I began to feel so much anxiety and
depression I honestly like there are
times where I wouldn't get out of bed
because I just didn't know like what was
I was like what is the point of me
getting out of bed what is the point of
me doing these things why even you know
why why why I think what got me through
is knowing that I really really trusted
in myself even though I had nothing
basically I mean I moved back home with
my mom I didn't I obviously didn't have
an income I had no experience I felt
like things were just hitting dead and
one after another
what company positive was knowing that I
trusted myself and knowing that I did
have a lot to offer and even though I
didn't necessarily know how to narrow it
down to words or even a job description
I knew that I was capable of doing a lot
of things trusting myself really got me
through and when you're in that kind of
state you spend so much time alone you
think a lot about who you are and you
really break down the core values of
what you believe in nothing humbled me
more than being able to kind of sit
there by myself and really dissect my
values and core beliefs for months when
I was depressed
i sat at home I looked up as many
opportunities as I could I had a small
in my pod for so many things and I I
feel like I had this mindset that made
this certain amount so I had to make
more than what I was making before and I
just knew that it had to be better man
did that knocked me down a couple pegs
because I really had to realize that I
was starting from scratch I was starting
from zero experience education was there
but it wasn't necessarily going to help
me in this situation
I applied to the simplest of things like
I even applied to administrative work I
wasn't even trying to do that
I was applying for other psychology
roles even though I wasn't trying to do
that anymore I just was so desperate
that I needed a job then I stumbled upon
an internship for a fashion / social
media intern it was going to help this
personals personal shopper in her social
media for me the one thing I really have
been working on I guess in the meantime
was blogging blogging taking photograph
doing social media embracing any little
opportunity I could get to have
experience in some way so my social
media experience helped me get that
internship and even though it was unpaid
it was in my mind experience so that I
could you know leverage that on my
resume to hopefully appeal to at least
one other person one employer and
through her I was able to network so
much and I met a lot of people and I was
lucky enough to kind of connect with
them to you and I went to events with
her I filmed things for her and took
photographs and other people would
notice me and say like oh are you a
videographer are you photographer even
though I wasn't I I said that I was yeah
that helps me gain other gigs you know
just faking it till I made it
through them I was able to kind of start
booking gigs photography gigs and just
doing here little videos here and there
that was just kind of the start of what
was to come if I'm starting to value
myself more I feel like other people are
going to value me as well I started
getting emails I started getting gigs I
booked my very first photography gig I
booked my first video gig and from then
I'm still kind of working on that it has
been such a goddamn journey I feel so
happy doing it I feel so so blessed so
I've been working towards that in the
meantime while looking for other jobs I
applied to Yale I applied to start up
then opportunities started to come I
started applying again I continued to
work my ass off I applied to one company
that was looking for an assistant buyer
they just needed someone who had retail
experience working with negotiations
being able to communicate with people
things like that I was thinking okay I
don't know if I have the experience for
it but I'm gonna try anyway
through this whole process and interview
a test another interview and then
another interview or set process it
lasted two whole months the last and
final interview I go along with the
interview is really well and I felt like
it just really clicked for me felt
promising so I wasn't going to put all
my eggs in that basket because I still
wasn't sure but I just I felt prominent
I was patient and then this week I got
the call that I got a job offer oh my
god I had tears streaming down my eyes
it's been a whole year and I've worked
so hard it was finally paying off they
recognized you know what I could offer
to them and they even actually liked
that I had a psychology degree because I
was able to communicate with multiple
people and kind of get an insight on
people with different backgrounds I
guess so
that really helped actually in my
experience in this job position so even
though the job itself has nothing to do
with psychology my degree helps I can't
even tell you how happy i frickin feel
now going from a dark place to finally
getting your first gig your first
opportunity meeting people and then
finally landing that job I could cry
right now I feel really emotional right
now good great to look back at how far
I've come from that person last year who
is so depressed huh I could say it's
been a crazy year I want to show people
that good things can happen and you
don't have to stay in a shitty job you
don't have to stay in it for money you
don't have to stay in it you know
because it's safe I think what pushed me
was getting out of my comfort zone and
being so vulnerable and myself that I
had to do it I'd had to do you know I'm
hoping that sharing my story will
motivate and inspire other people to
chase their passion there are a million
reasons why you shouldn't but I think
just having one really big good reason
why you should is enough to jumpstart
your life in achieving happiness so I
want to share five tips I've come up
with that can hopefully help you find
your passion regardless of how many
people say no and how many people doubt
you my first tip I
is don't limit what you are capable of
don't limit yourself to saying I can't
do this because I don't have the
experience I don't know enough people or
I don't know where to start if you limit
yourself then you're only gonna be
capable of that much believing that you
can do anything in the world I feel like
is enough to any possibility the second
tip is to be willing to sacrifice a lot
so I sacrifice where I was living having
a steady income I sacrificed my ego my
third tip is to don't be afraid to push
yourself out of your comfort zone and
just go for it if you are always gonna
be comfortable you're never gonna know
what is out there you never know what
new things could come you can't find a
solution being in the same place you
found your problem or something that I
don't know if that's the right quote I'm
sorry but my forced tip I have is to
take time to reflect to yourself and
just figure out what you really really
want what you're capable of what you
want to offer what you are willing to
risk and give up for this narrowing down
or just the basic basic core values of
what you really want is gonna help you
so much in the long run because you
realize what is important to you and
what is it the fifth and final tip I
have is just trusting in yourself trust
that you will get out of this if you
know what kind of person you are for
example me I know that I can't be in one
place at once I know that so I know that
I'm not gonna always be in this place I
wasn't gonna be someone who wanted to
stay stagnant and I wasn't gonna let
myself you can't achieve what you want
out of your career out of your life out
of your goal I hope this video helped in
some way for you I know that it was kind
of jumbled and I feel like I can go on
and on and on about this topic you have
support out there and if you don't you
can feel free to message me I understand
that finding your passion is so so
difficult and even more difficult is
trying to pursue it if you're not in
that state thank you so much for
listening and following with my journey
I'll see you guys later bye
you