hey guys my name is Melissa and today I
wanted to share my experience growing up
as an Asian American I'll start off by
just kind of saying that I am Vietnamese
and Chinese I'm three quarters enemies
and one quarter Chinese my dad is full
venes and my mom is half so she speaks
Vietnamese Chinese and English my
parents came to America in the 80s and
they moved to Seattle had my brother and
then had me Vietnamese was my first
language and I obviously spoke it a lot
within my family especially my dad's
family they all spoke Vietnamese with
each other and my grandparents didn't
know English so that's all I knew when I
was growing up up until when I was in
about preschool that's when I started
learning English and I had to speak to
other people obviously I was so shy but
so I learned English through daycare and
then elementary school grade school I
kind of learned how to speak English
really well started to forget Vietnamese
I formed kind of like a language barrier
between my grandparents and me it was
really hard because I thought it wasn't
fair for me to always have to speak
Vietnamese at home or know how to speak
when everyone spoke English my family
also looked down on the fact that I took
English during family parties and things
like that and they're like kind of
shaming me for not knowing my native
language there was a point in my life
when I was young I was really proud to
be Vietnamese I'm an eighth birthday I
wore a traditional Vietnamese dress and
oh yeah for my party I learned how to
read and write in Vietnamese and I still
know to this day I still hold that like
very dear to my heart because of the
things that people said in school they
made fun of me for the things that I ate
or the smells that were coming from my
lunch box sometimes it would be judged
by that and I was embarrassed so I just
chose not to share that part of myself
to the world I knew that I was different
in elementary school when they assumed
that I was really smart and good at math
I personally didn't take it offensive
just because I was good at math and I
was a smart student so I was just like
yeah that's just who I am I
didn't realize that they were kind of
making the general assumptions and
stereotypes because I was Asian I just
thought it was because of who I was I
didn't really experience prejudice until
middle school high school when people
always assumed always exceeded
expectations and education because of my
parents and they assumed that it was
because I was Asian and that they were
really strict on me but in fact I didn't
feel like I had a lot of pressure like
other Asian parents might have put on
their children just because my parents
are always kind of like do your own
thing you know
you know you know what you have and what
your people love and stuff so I never
felt pressure from that I think the most
pressure I receive for meeting high
expectations of like the typical Asian
was from the society that I was growing
up in when I was like in the middle
school I remember I brought my lunch and
I was eating a sandwich head bread Mayo
and then the shreds of pork and it looks
like hair it's kind of like just
shredded up and I just ate that for
lunch all the time is my favorite thing
to eat and I remember my friends are
like oh my god Melissa is eating hair
and almost like it's not here it's my
food but I didn't know what it was
either I didn't even know how to say it
in English and so I was like I don't
know what to call this but I just number
people thinking it was weird or like
sometimes I'd bring stuff that was like
leftovers and people would think it was
stinky so I was just like really
embarrassed and that's kind of like the
first indicators that I knew I was
different than other people I grew up
with a lot of white friends I didn't
really realize that I was only one it
kind of opened my mind she listened to
you you know country music and like pop
music and things like that and I was
really into it
I didn't make the connection that was
Asian an American until I was in like
high school and maybe that's a little
slow paced for someone like me but I
didn't recognize that I was an Asian
living in America I guess I think what
taught me that was when my own cousins
were kind of shaming me for not knowing
Vietnamese and not knowing Chinese and
stuff and I was like okay well I grew up
in a predominantly white community like
what am I supposed to do where am I
supposed to learn that the town I grew
up and barely had any
but I feel like there's also the stigma
especially in high school when I started
hanging out with more Asians they're
like oh you're part of like the Asian
group and stuff and I'm just like so I
just didn't understand it high school
was when I started hanging out with
Asians more I think it was just
naturally because I felt like I
connected to them more and I understood
more about their culture in their
background and they understood me more
and then other people who weren't Asians
would be like oh you're part of the
Asians like okay let me live
I felt like kind of embarrassed still
even at like 17 18 years old and I don't
think I felt really comfortable in my
skin being asian-american and shell I
was in college and I was applying and
you know colleges are like oh we like to
keep our campuses really diverse and I'm
like hey that's a plus for me because
they're gonna want more diversity that's
when I was like okay I kind of have like
a little bit of an upper hand because
I'm Asian and whatever and then I also
was able to kind of be the face of my
college so I went to you to Bothell and
the photographer for the little ads and
stuff like that were going around and
they came across me and they were like
hey do you want to be photographed for
the u-2 bottle like pamphlets and stuff
and I was like sure so I thought it was
really cool that I was able to kind of
represent my college in these little
pamphlets that they're handing out to
new prospective students so I thought
that was really cool and I was like
proud to represent you know a colored
person on a pamphlet in a college when I
first went to Vietnam my very first time
I was 22 I had blonde hair so I know I
stuck out like a sore thumb but when I
was in Vietnam people were automatically
assuming I was American and didn't
understand Vietnamese mind you they're
kind of right I only probably speak
maybe equivalent to like a 3rd grader I
can kind of get by I can kind of order
but I understand pretty well when I went
there I wanted to try my Vietnamese you
know and I feel like they just
automatically seemed I didn't know it
and then when I did speak Vietnamese
they were super surprised and they're
like whoa you speak Vietnamese but your
and I was like yeah I'm Asian American I
can speak a little bit of both I came
home and I realized that like I didn't
really fit anywhere because I'm too
Asian to be American but I'm too
American to be Asian so it was just like
a weird crossbreed and I had kind of
like an identity crisis because I was
like okay why don't you will accept me
anywhere you know I'm 26 now I can have
the best of both worlds I can be
American and I can be Asian and I can be
proud to be both I am proud to be both
I'm trying to really hold on to my roots
and hold on to my culture because it's
really important to me that I'm able to
pass that down to my children in the
future my parents I feel like didn't
understand the culture the American
culture when they came here and so when
I grew up in that culture they were like
why are you like this you know when I
grew up I wasn't able to do this this
and this I didn't have a boyfriend I
didn't get to go out it was just a
really different world going up ahead to
kind of learn for myself like where my
spot was in the world and where I was
able to kind of feel comfortable and
safe and represented going up Asian
American I don't think I'll ever take it
for granted because it kind of formed
and shaped me to be Who I am and I'm
proud of that I'm able to kind of stand
up for myself now where I wasn't before
I wasn't able to identify I guess or
really stand up and be confident in my
Asian as' but I think now that I'm older
I'm able to really embrace the culture
and embrace that I am Vietnamese I am
Chinese I am American I think that's
what is so great about America is that
we are it's a melting pot and even
though there are so many differences in
our country right now I think everyone
should embrace and accept that our
country is made of so many different
backgrounds and it's not ever going to
look like one person want to make that
known thank you so much for watching
and let me know if you guys can relate I
would love to hear you guys this story I
will see you guys later
you