[Music]
hey how are you guys doing I am so so so
expose so excited to share this video
with you guys today I'm always excited
aren't I still excited to ship so it's
such that since I am new to YouTube and
you guys don't know me like that well
besides the products I use on my face
and the clothes that I'm wearing and
lalala like things like that I'm just so
happy to share these little things these
50 things about me I'm gonna do the 50
things about me tag so I'm happy to
share these little things that make me
me so let's get right into this video
because since it is 50 things how am I
going to come up with 50 things about me
yeah that's a lot I have the same
birthday as Kobe Bryant August 23rd not
the same year no Lex I hate us and I am
very proud to have that birthday because
Mamba mentality baby just look it up
mentality I love it that makes me a
Virgo and I am a huge believer in
astrology not like all those every
little day things that you read I got a
magazine no but I do believe there's
some truth to little certain
characteristics for each sign I lie on
the Leo Virgo cusp so I don't know what
that really means but I'm about times 10
my absolute favorite station on pandora
is Sean Paul radio I'm half Panamanian
half Mexican but I was born in Southern
California and I lived in Southern
California my entire life I love LA I'm
super super super into birthdays like I
will not miss your birthday if you're
like my close friend I'll do everything
to make you feel special and I just love
to celebrate people's birthday have just
I'm really into it and including my own
put my first job ever was a sales
associate at PacSun the only time I
broken a bone is these two the ulna and
radius I broke them when I was a
cheerleader in high school I only did
one year of cheer obviously
good I have two tattoos I have one that
says promos when I go this one with my
cousin pinky promise and I have another
one that says karma um yeah I'm 27 years
old I know I look super young I've
always looked super young for my age I
used to get pissed so so heated when
they would pass me the kids menu and I
was in high school I'd be like right I'm
a huge huge foodie I love I just love
food so much I can't even pick which
dish is my favorite I really I can't do
that don't do that to me don't make me
answer that kind of a question Food
Network is always on but I can't cook
for like to say my life I can't get to
say my life I can't I can't do it when I
was super young I wanted to be a taxi
driver or sawgrass Paulo which is like a
snow cone in Panama because I would see
them collect cash money like directly
into their hands and I just I wanted
that money in my hands right my absolute
favorite show is Shark Tank I don't like
being around super negative people I
think because I'm so aware of it it just
bugs the crap out of me like if they're
just constantly like no don't come
around me with that um just makes me
kind of sad for those types of people to
be honest I have a super super super
addictive personality when I get into
something I need to know every little
single detail about it a little bit I'm
a little crazy in that sense I love iced
Americanos like just straight up black
but if I have hot coffee I need to have
like a little bit of almond milk and
cinnamon I have a mega girl crush on
Mila Kunis I'm deathly afraid to hold
newborns I don't know how to hold a baby
you know from here like oh he's so cute
he's so cute but do not pass him over to
me because I am like this paralyzed like
I won't move I'm so scared to hold a
baby I don't know if you guys can
already tell but I am very animated with
my facial expression so I'm like when
I'm surprised on the rise like you know
when I'm mad like you can just see it on
my face I'm very easy to read I love
love love spicy food I know this might
sound a little weird but when my lips
are burning after eating something
that's like a good
for me I love it and my favorite chili
is habanero it hurts me when I see
people yell at anybody in like a service
type of industry I hate it
it irks me so so much I love traveling
the ultimate trip for me would
definitely be Tokyo I just love
everything about that culture and love
Tokyo I love Japan I really really want
to visit so hopefully this year I get to
go
my favorite trip that I have taken is
definitely a tie between Peru and Kenya
hands down my dream wardrobe would be
anything each sailor on I love each
sailor own I used to be made fun of for
being super flat-chested but I actually
really love small boobs so I never
really cared I have the biggest biggest
crush on Aziz Ansari it's not like your
conventional crush but I have a crush on
Aziz Ansari I do
I like candles and incense every single
day like people who come visit me well
it's not like a lot of people but like
when my mom comes and visits me visits
me she's like oh my gosh Amy how could
you be with all these incense and but I
it just makes me so happy I love I love
love love incense and candles Lewis was
the movie that really got me into
fashion I think like I mean I was super
young when I saw it but I was like oh my
god like the way they match up the
clothes with the revolt of closet oh my
gosh I got a ride I don't know I love
fashion after that I used to never cry
for anything like nothing nothing would
make me cry nothing sad would make me
cry and now I cry for anything and
everything oh my gosh if somebody got a
deal on shark tank I'm crying but I
mainly cry if it's something like happy
thank you birth control made me crazy I
love watching documentaries Anthony
Bourdain is my hero my number-one hero I
can put avocado on everything and
anything if it's like a weird mix like
if it's desert or something like that my
theory is if I can't put avocado on it I
can probably put peanut butter on it
love peanut butter love avocado I read a
ton of nonfiction but my favorite book
of all time is the outsiders the only
book I really read more than once love
love love the outsiders I am obsessed
with hanging out with my cousins I have
so many cousins and
all best friends from 18 year old all
the way to 40 years old like we all hang
out and it's amazing I wouldn't change
my family for the world I love them to
pieces I am a huge believer in dream
boards I do one every single year so I'm
going to be doing a new one for 2017 I
have an obsession with clouds oh they're
just so beautiful I thought I wanted to
be a meteorologist actually when I was
younger when I used to work with Katy
Perry years back she used to call me
Little Miss Perfect I am a super
perfectionist especially when it comes
to work I prefer the beach over the pool
I love love love traveling but every
time on the return flight landing into
LAX I have like these butterflies I
don't know I have like a love affair
with LA hocus-pocus is one of my
favorite movies of all time because it
reminds me so much of my sister we used
to reenact the entire movie and I can
still quote it like verbatim I'm pretty
adventurous when it comes to food but I
can't do anything slimy like a little up
I consider myself to be a son child I
just feel super connected to the Sun I
am so not a gym person I hate going to
an enclosed space I'd rather go for a
hike or do Zumba the music just makes me
feel alive
I went to a small Catholic High School
and we had to wear uniform that guy's
like I have to go to a small Catholic
High School and headwear uniform every
day and I actually came to really really
love it I love love love mangoes and I
would probably eat them more if I knew
how to peel and cut them I just I don't
know how to cut them I've YouTubed it
and I just can't seem to get it together
I used to think that I was gonna marry
Adam Brody from The OC Seth Cohen I used
to think I was gonna marry him I really
did when I saw that he married Lee
Leighton Meester my heart dropped I kid
you not my heart sank to my the bottom
of my stomach I'm addicted to vegan
peanut butter ice cream from Van Leeuwen
lewin I don't know how to say the
freaking place but I go there so much
and I am not even vegan I just I love
that ice cream song so much mary-kate
and Ashley are definitely the twins that
inspired me to want to travel the world
all their straight-to-video movies
passport to Paris our lips are sealed
winning London all those movies made me
want to travel and I
thought I was gonna meet like a hot guy
everywhere I went so not the case
delusional delusional
I love reading but I get so excited for
new books so instead of finishing that
book then I'll start the no new book
because I'm so excited and then I'll
read a little bit and then I'll get a
new book and then so I have a lot of
unfinished books it's really bad I'm
trying to be better about that and
trying to finish the books that I start
I love linguistics I love language I
always wish I had better vocabulary I'm
obsessed with vocabulary when I was
younger I would write down all the new
words if I was reading a book or
listening to a song and I loved that
word I would write it down in this like
little journal that I made and define
them and try to use them in sentences I
was kind of a nerd I'm very like turned
on I don't know if turned on is the
right word but I really love people who
can speak eloquently I'm such a fan of
people who can speak eloquently that is
why I like Matt Lauer that is why I like
Colin coward I love listening to people
with I don't know good voices I hate my
voice I'm so lucky being my little voice
is so annoying I think that's how we all
are right everybody hates to hear the
sound of their own voice so those were
the 50 things about me I hope you guys
enjoy I know they're just little like
shallow things but they are those little
things that make me me so I hope you
guys enjoy getting to know me just a
little bit more I want to get to know
you guys more so please leave me a
comment a some interesting fact about
you and I'd love to read to get to know
you guys a little bit better as well so
give this video a like if you did enjoy
it and also please subscribe if you
haven't already I will see you guys in
my next video bye I can touch my nose
with my tongue really attractive right
what else what else what else do I
[Music]