hey guys so today's video I am going to
do eight what was it an edgy sultry look
[Music]
Thank You Viviana for helping me name
this I posted this on Instagram and a
lot of you guys were asking to recreate
this look because I actually didn't film
the video when I did that look I went to
this event for fresh which is super cool
because I was like all about astrology
it's for their zodiac soaps there was a
lot of forecasting up in there like
what's coming in 2018 according to our
signs and everything like that so it was
pretty interesting but anyways you guys
wanted to see that look so I'm here
recreating that look the main like focus
or like what I was kind of basing every
all the colors around were actually this
natasha de Nona crystal topcoat this is
in the shade gray Brown and you guys
helped me choose this as well on
Instagram I had posted like which one
should I get and I actually ended up
getting peach and gray Brown but then my
friend finally wrote back to me saying
like don't get peach it's kind of like a
basic like you can get that in any kind
of palette and so I want to exchange it
and get the nude one because she says
the nude is beautiful so anyways let's
go ahead and get started this is gonna
be very chatty if you can't already tell
I'm feeling very chatty today I don't
know we'll just talk so let's go ahead
and start with my base actually you know
what I did this time around I used it as
a primer spray so now let's go right
into foundation I'm gonna use this one I
use the Double Wear foundation that
night as well because it gives a lot of
coverage at last all day all night so I
like this one for those kind of
occasions so I went ahead and used it it
doesn't have a pump that's the only
bummer about it but it's a good
foundation it's so spreading that all
over I'm taking a bit more I just shake
it onto my finger until I get that and I
just like to do this I love to hear what
you guys want to see from me so
definitely keep sending in your requests
because I mean I always have tons of
ideas it's insane like how many ideas I
have like for fashion especially I'll
take care of those videos but you guys
definitely send me makeup stuff because
I tend to do like I'm like a one-hit
situation with like my natural looks so
there's any like celebrity you want me
to do or anything by any inspiration
that you guys see send it my way or even
like a palette and I really create
something with this I'll definitely do
it I'm sorry I am just like so tired
today so I need my coffee and then I'm
just gonna apply my concealer this is
the glossier concealer when I go to
events I always use like my trusty faves
because it's like not really the time to
like test out stuff you know what I mean
you don't want to like have your I don't
know concealer be all crusty I like to
use things that I love and trust
when I go out occasionally I'll play
around with like obviously eyeshadows
and I'm like whatever about that but the
complexion products have to be things
I'm familiar with just your spot conceal
I'm gonna use this fit me by Maybelline
rather spot conceal then put on more
foundation the less makeup that I have
to wear the better I get really really
Creasy here here like my face just looks
a mess honestly when I wear a lot of
makeup I load my makeup done before for
like past events and stuff like either
at the MAC counter or whatever just like
a makeup artist and their makeup artist
that use a lot of heavy you know
foundations and stuff like that and
literally I just feel like I look better
with like less makeup it looks so crazy
and like you know they're professional
so I'm thinking like I just don't have a
face where it can take a lot of makeup
like I am so mesmerized I love
nikkietutorials she's so good but like
the amount of makeup that she use and
manages for it to look so flawless like
damn she is so talented but I feel like
my I would love for her to do my makeup
just to see if I'm capable of wearing
that much makeup because I honestly feel
like I just don't like my face can't
take it anyways let's continue on I'm
gonna set that with this Laura Mercier
this is the candle glow that sheer
powder that I've been loving lately it's
a nice one to just kind of set
everything while still remaining very
luminous and doesn't that look so dark I
think I because they sent me a bunch of
these and I think I gave away my shame
too by accident but it's fine - this one
it's so sure that it kind of goes if it
makes me a little tan I'm kind of okay
with that so now we're gonna move right
into eyeshadow so I'm gonna take this
huda beauty palette and this is the
color suede and it's literally like a
grey brown as well that's why I wanted
to choose it just because the Natasha
didn't own a crystal topcoat it kind of
goes on sheer like it's exactly what
it's a good top coat you know
it's really pretty isn't it like just by
itself I would do this even and do like
a wing liner but have it be smudgy oh
that would be such a cool like rocker
eye what's nice is because we're gonna
put the top coat it literally beautifies
the eye so you can kind of be messy
about it I kind of sat there and blended
for a bit but I mean honestly you don't
really need to that was just me being
crazy yeah this is a clean brush now do
that and I'm gonna go right into that
suede color again so now I'm gonna take
another brush and I'm gonna take this
color called BAE Beijing and use that to
just kind of highlight the brow bone oh
this is why I should do my eyebrows yeah
we're gonna do my eyebrows now I'm going
to take the colour-pop pencil brush
these guys out really quickly you guys
already know I need to fill in those
gaps that I have so I don't look all
chewed up brush it out again maintaining
the ones in the front
somewhat natural these are so curly
right here
so I didn't use boy bra that night
actually I used this I've been really
liking the ico one for these events that
I've been going to it literally looks
like mascara guys it's like so big
compared to like any of the other brow
gels and stuff that I've tried but this
one gives you like super dimension and
it leaves them kind of glassy so I like
that that's why I like it mainly because
it kind of leaves them glossy and I feel
like that looks very very groomed and
expensive the only bad thing about this
or what I don't like about it is that
it's hard it leaves your eyebrows very
stiff and you feel it when you're
washing your face and stuff so I don't
really love that but I feel like it's
okay for events and stuff like a night
out because you're only out for like
maybe four or five hours or - oh yeah
but it gives you a lot of so those are
my filled in and very groomed to brows
let's finish up this shadow that I was
talking about so I'm gonna take bay and
now we can really get in there I want to
take one of these little guys and go
into that same I'm I just use this
palette for the whole look I'm gonna use
the sandalwood it's like a warm light
orange e Brown and I actually applied
this first so we're gonna go back I
forgot we're gonna go back over it with
the gray Brown that color suede but
first I did this because honestly I
don't really love the way I look with
cool tone colors I feel like I look
really paced the undead I mean it's fun
for a night out though but I still
wanted to add it just a little bit of
warmth where I could and also right in
here and
we'll go over just so that the gray is
actually the main one but this is just
kind of peeking through so I'm grabbing
that suede on a fluffy brush just to
blend and then again for the bottom I
want it to be very very soft like not
too harsh or like a smoky smoky all
right but you know what I did actually
add some black into the mix so I'm gonna
take that baby brush again and this
color here it's just a black it's called
black truffle I just placed it right on
the outer and here with my lash line
just like that and then also right on
top kind of like a liner but more smoked
out
so I'm gonna bronze my face now I'm
gonna use the Estee Lauder and Victoria
Beckham bronzer I'm just going into the
usual bronzing spots I'm just gonna add
a little bit to my nose so what I used
for blush was actually this guy called
Lovejoy and it is a mineralized blush by
Mac looks like this yeah I'm gonna leave
that
I think I went for like ugliest face
while applying blush for sure I just
like of my cheeks I'm very hard to
define to make all kinds of crazy faces
to find them
so then I'm gonna put the highlighter on
I'm gonna use a powder highlighter this
is the laura mercier highlight and one
this was like my ride-or-die for a
really good whole year I'm surprised
that it has not even a dent in it like
I'm literally hard this for like two
years that's crazy okay so I'm gonna
apply that this is the fenty brush how
pretty is this by the way so that's what
I used first and I like using this one
for like photos at night and stuff
because it doesn't photograph crazy it's
like very natural in a way even though
it's not that natural so now I'm gonna
set all of that with the spray again so
jumping back into eyes actually I'm
gonna add just a little bit more of the
black this one's great this is the
three-in-one brush from Aiko and it's so
cool because you literally have every
brush to really help define your eyes
like you can line it and stuff
I forgot I used this one so it really
packs the black in a lot better than
just like the fluffier one that I used
this one why isn't the black that
intense yeah so it has like a little guy
this different one - do you notice I say
little guy for everything
and I'm gonna tight line with this
master Kajal this is from Maybelline
really really good highly recommended I
love me a cush all to tight line
especially you couldn't really get up in
there without tugging or anything like
that
and then for the waterline I used a
beige one because I like to come as B so
now for the inner corner you know that
never goes untouched I'm using the off
tropic by color pop so taking that on a
small little brush I'm just going to hit
that tear duct with it
I love this one because it like works
with both cool tone and warm tone it's
just like the perfect little highlight
especially if you are a little watery
there and it mixes in with like your
actual tears down like you've got such a
good beam sometimes I exaggerate it
sometimes like oh you kind of like
something wide in the center I'm like
yeah I know it's my inner corner
highlight I didn't blend it out because
I wanted it to really pop hmm so now we
get to play around with the top coat I
am so excited about this product so
obsessed you guys it's the perfect like
topper to just complete any look
especially for a night out the reason I
picked it up was because my friend
Melissa who I met on a shoot actually
she did my makeup for the line you know
way so wait transform me into Cher and I
was like Melissa was with color pops the
color pop provided all like the
cosmetics and stuff she literally
murdered my face and all supposed to
like kind of you know imitate the next I
and oh my gosh it was I was so
intimidated she was the one I was like
following her into stories she's so
funny I'll leave her handle here so you
guys can follow her she's hilarious but
she was out at Sephora hunting this down
and I was like what it's like of a big
deal about it and when she revealed like
the swatches I was like ah I need that
in my life
I absolutely need it so picked it up of
course and a lot of other things that
she recommended actually I love her
style of makeup so I liked her
recommendations so you can build it up
so I build it up a lot that night you
could it can be like more sheer or like
packed with glitter so I've built it up
pretty heavily that night and it's still
subtle though like to the touch it
almost feels not exactly like this color
pop shadow but kind of where it almost
feels wet but it's like definitely like
a dry powder so that's what it looks
like I've already gone into the pot
quite a bit if you want your makeup to
make a statement like have it be a look
but like no effort this is definitely
the way to do it and this color is
really really cool I think it looks kind
of like grungy but at the same time like
chic AF it definitely picks up way way
better on your finger I would highly
recommend using your finger so those are
the eyes I'm so obsessed with this
Natasha - no no I want to buy there's
four shades total so I'll show you the
peach one on the next one I'll probably
just end up keeping it now just by the
nude one as well what's the other one oh
bronze of course bronze is gonna look
beautiful as well so I feel like you
really can't go wrong the only thing is
like I wish they were just cheaper I
think they're 30 I'm like I wish they
were like 20 and I wouldn't feel as bad
getting all four of them but anyways so
I'm just gonna use this Marc Jacobs
mascara mascara okay so for lips
actually let me apply I'm gonna use a
liquid lip so I'm gonna apply this this
is from L'Occitane and I like this one
under not sticks because it's very it's
hydrating but it's very thin I love the
thicker like I love a balm calm but
sometimes they're too thick so it really
takes away from like it just transformed
the liquid lip into something else where
this is thinner so it doesn't really
like add too much shine like you know
this looks kind of matte so to continue
this like cool tone
I'm taking point zero this is the color
pop with kathleenlights there's a moment
I was using it a lot like last fall and
I haven't really touched it since but I
thought it was perfect for this look so
then I added a gloss because I felt like
these cool tones make me look kind of
dead so Mike oh no I need like I need a
gloss I can't be like mad and cool tone
like I just look super dead so I took
this one this is by Laura Mercier and
it's called a little rose gold accent I
don't know it has like little tiny
flecks of glitter in here and I just
planted that in the center my last
little finishing touch because I felt
like my face was like looking a little
bit too matte so I took the face gloss
by make so good so I just kind of do
this and then I do that
and it gives you if you guys saw my
November favorites that's what I had on
my cheeks and you guys were like oh my
gosh you look like it's like a natural
glow and week exactly that's what it
gives you it's like a natural glow it
doesn't look like you know - - it looks
just enough and that is the finished
look you guys super easy I told you
[Music]
it for this makeup tutorial I hope you
guys enjoy my god I feel like I need to
go somewhere now this was like strictly
just like a recreation for you guys
usually when I do like my get ready with
me is I'm like literally going somewhere
but this time I think I'm gonna wash
this off and film another video for you
guys because I'm feeling extra energized
like thanks to this coffee oh and
speaking of bumble bits I just wanted to
do a little networking here on YouTube
I was wondering because I know a lot of
you guys want to see more fashion from
me and trust me I like that's like my
baby you guys can tell like how
passionate I am about fashion so I
definitely like I have so many so many
so many ideas for fashion but it's so
hard for me to kind of execute what I
have in my head like my vision as far as
like creativity and like how I want to
display the outfits like I don't want to
just do it on my like blank wall but
it's hard for me to shoot alone so if
anybody lives in like Southern
California and you want to kind of help
me shoot these outfits so I can get
these videos are out for you guys you
can literally like use my camera we can
hang we can have lunch I'm like make a
day out of it go around LA like whatever
I just really want somebody to help me
shoot these lookbook so send me an email
or just the end me and be like hey girl
like I can help you out like it doesn't
even have to be like you know like a
work thing it can just literally be
hanging out having fun and shooting
pretty outfits so slip into my DMS hit
me up in my email anywhere Twitter like
I look at everything always so you guys
know where to find me thank you guys so
much for getting ready with me talking
chatting and I will see you guys all in
my next video bye guys
[Music]