[Music]
hi guys good morning thanks for tuning
in to another vlog
i thought i would vlog today because
it's a super busy day
i think it's going to be super packed so
i'll have more stuff to share with you
guys but anyways
this morning my day started super early
usually i don't have meetings on my
calendar until
like maybe 10-ish but today i actually
had
two meetings back to back i had an eight
to nine am
and then a nine to ten a.m basically as
many of you guys know i work as a
marketing manager and part of my job
is to oversee sustainability so
um we're part of a few
industry groups and within the industry
there's a lot of different
organizations that you can take part of
and they host a lot of different
webinars and updates
so those first two meetings in the
morning because basically it's
global so they have to find a time that
works for
everyone across the world so um i had
one at 8am and then the other one at 9am
and i was just like listening and doing
my makeup so
thankfully i just took the time to get
ready i actually just got a package so
i'm gonna go open that right now
so exciting i just got this box from
skintay
and i've been wanting to try all their
drinks because i love sparkling drinks
and
it has collagen which is a plus plus if
you're over 25 which i
am i'm 25 right now basically your
collagen production starts to decrease
and collagen is essential for healthy
glowing
youthful skin so i'm so excited they
sent this to me let me show you guys
what
what i got so they sent me this box with
a sampler of their green tea grapefruit
white tea ginger
and hibiscus vanilla i think i'm really
excited to try these too but in general
all of them sound so good and then they
sent me a six pack
of the green tea grapefruit which i
think sounds like my favorite flavor
so i'm really excited to try these i'll
probably have one in the afternoon
and i'll let you guys know my first
first take on it i'm sticking these in
the fridge
i'm just gonna stick these three first
so i can try all the flavors
also i love that the packaging is i
think it's like
matte it feels really nice but yeah
i'm excited okay i'm so excited to try
skintay that just made my day because
i love anything sparkling i love drinks
and
i love anything good for my skin gonna
go ahead and hop into my next meeting my
next meeting is a super short like
five minute meeting it's just to touch
base on this one report that we're doing
so um i'm gonna hop into that right now
[Music]
okay i just got done with that one it
was super quick i'm debating if i want
to change now
or maybe a little bit later i just
it's been hard for me to get out of my
little comfy clothes
but i have two back-to-back meetings
right now i have an 11 o'clock
um which i'm discussing something with
someone on the pr team and then my next
one is with
the it's with the it team
so um i have two back-to-back and then i
think i'll finally be able to have time
for lunch so
yeah i'm just i mean my coffee again
this morning
i make coffee every morning i love mine
espresso
all the ice has melted by this point but
i love how nespresso you get this nice
foam
and i added um oatmeal into it so
okay should i change now or later
i'll figure that out okay i'm going to
hop into that meeting now
finally finished my meetings and changed
an outfit
i'm just wearing a graphic tee biker
shorts
um but still at least it's an outfit
i'm gonna grab some lunch right now so
let's
[Music]
when i hit go ground so i moved out here
so that i could actually have a standing
set up
um one of my co-workers inspired me to
start standing more
and i don't have a standing desk so i'm
just standing at this island
in our kitchen um but i wanted to show
you guys
i'm gonna try this i'm so excited
let's see how it tastes
it tastes so good
it literally just tastes like sometimes
at boba places i'll order their
grapefruit green tea
it literally tastes like that but
sparkling
so i spent most of this afternoon
prepping for this one meeting i was
leading
i just got out of that and um for the
rest of the afternoon i have emails to
catch up on
and um what else do i need to do oh
there's a few emails i need to send
um a couple projects i need to move
forward
and i think that should be it for today
okay it's just seven right now but i'm
eating dinner
just leftovers from lunch again but
i was on a call with sandy so small
business tips
love her let me know if you guys follow
her i'll link her below
um she's so sweet she's one of my
favorite people on tick tock
one of my favorite friends that i've met
on tik tok and
um we just chatted about some stuff
and then i met with my intern
and did some more work now i'm eating i
think i'm gonna do a little more work
later
the rest of my evening is just going to
be my normal night routine so
i'm still debating if i want to work out
maybe i will maybe i won't and then i'm
just going to go ahead
and shower read do some master class and
call it a night so i'm extra pooped you
can tell how low energy i am now
versus earlier in the day i'm definitely
pretty dang tired it was a long day
a really busy day um and i still feel
pretty stressed right now so
i'm just gonna hurry and eat i actually
need to film some tick tocks too so i'm
gonna hurry and eat film my tech talks
work out maybe and then um
probably just go back to working um but
yeah thank you guys so much for watching
i hope you guys enjoyed let me know what
you guys liked what you didn't like
and if you want to see more of these and
don't forget to
subscribe and follow me on instagram
tick tock
all that good stuff and i'll catch you
guys in my next one thanks for watching
bye