[Music]
hey everybody
it's lynn for today's video i wanted to
get a little serious and this is going
to be part one
of five of a new series that i am
starting on my channel
that explores and reflects my experience
growing up specifically growing up asian
american
growing up in the philippines growing up
as
a second culture kid growing up as an
immigrant
and growing up with a single mother and
i feel very strongly about these topics
because i as a teacher
know that there are kids all over the
world and kids that i
teach who may experience some of the
things that i have experienced
and as somebody who is
part of our district's middle school
ethnic studies
committee i feel very empowered
in making this series on my channel to
perhaps
share with the world and maybe share
with my kids
the experiences that i have had to go
through
to be who i am today because without
those experiences and without the people
who have supported me throughout
the entire time then i
would not be here today so
today's video is going to primarily talk
about
what it's like growing up asian american
and before
we dive a little bit deeper here are
some details that you should know
i was born in the philippines on july 14
1992 specifically in pasay city
philippines
and i moved to america with my mom when
i was
eight and i actually turned nine here
we ended up moving to daly city
california
my aunt vilma was actually very kind
enough
to let us in her home and my mom and i
shared a one bedroom with
my cousin ie and in the other two rooms
were my aunt and her husband as well as
my cousins i distinctly remember that on
the very first night that we arrived
here that i was crying to my mom
begging her to go back to the
philippines because the reality
just hit me and the reality consisted
of the fact that i'm gonna be going to
school with people that i don't know and
i'm gonna be starting a life
in a place and in a culture that i know
nothing about
and to be fair my mom tried to console
me but at the same time she can't really
do anything about it because
plane tickets are expensive and i just
remember
her consoling me and hugging me and
ensuring me that everything was gonna be
okay this would also be a good time to
let you know that the reason why my mom
and i moved to the us
is because her and my dad decided to get
separated and later on
they got divorced so then fast forward a
couple months
to me going to my very first american
school
in the fifth grade and at first i was
very shy because
i didn't really want to speak out loud
because
i was scared that people would make fun
of me and
it turns out that i was scared for a
reason because when i did
finally open my mouth to speak i had a
very thick filipino
accent and some of the kids
in the class were making fun of me not
only
in the classroom which by the way my
teacher to her credit nipped in the bud
but she couldn't do anything while we
were at recess and
at that time it was one of those really
really bad and traumatic experiences
because i was bullied a lot
not only because of the way that i spoke
but because of the way that i dressed
and because of the way that i presented
myself
but i just remember that there were a
few
girls who were kind enough to
talk to me during recess and i
specifically remember i had one friend
her name was nicole v
and she was one of my first friends here
in america and
she basically taught me the pledge of
allegiance because
back then that was something that we had
to recite
every single day before class started
but despite the fact that i was getting
bullied on
the daily i ended up actually excelling
in my academics because i kept trying
and i didn't have all of these friends
to distract me from my work
i remember my cubby in my little
table used to be the cleanest and the
neatest
and i thought that that was a telltale
sign of who
i would become today in addition to that
i also
read a lot i turned to books
and the characters in those books became
my friends
and i ended up reading a whole bunch of
a series of unfortunate events
matilda i ended up reading a few of the
harry potter books granted i didn't know
that
they were in a series before and i just
remember going to the library which was
about
a two to three block walk away from my
house
and i would get books about witches and
aliens and cookbooks and
goosebumps and a whole plethora of books
because i just wanted
to escape from my reality i actually
didn't tell anybody
about any of the bullying that happened
to me in the fifth grade because i
didn't want to be a burden to my mom
or to my aunt or to my uncle or to
anybody else in my family
because i know that my mom was already
having a hard time because
she literally had to uproot herself and
her daughter
from the philippines travel across
oceans to come to california and to
start a new life
and i can only imagine what that was
like for her
and i remember her telling me this one
thing that
sticks to me to this day and that is
it's better that you are going through
these experiences now as a young person
because then it will make you a stronger
adult
and i completely agree with that now
but back in the day i was like girl you
crazy
i do not want to experience these but
i needed to be strong for her i needed
to show her that i am as resilient
as possible because there were nights
when i would actually hear her crying
herself to sleep
and a lot of the times i would just
pretend
that i didn't hear her because i didn't
want her to think that i could hear her
and that was to this day one of those
experiences that i will never forget and
then after i graduated fifth grade i
went
to middle school sixth grade for about
two months
in daly city before moving to
southern california san diego
specifically chula vista california
where my aunt ended up getting a really
big house
and in that house i shared a room with
my mom
and my cousin i had his own room which
was super fun and i was really happy
that he got that
and in san diego at least at the time
sixth grade was still part of elementary
school
so i pretty much graduated elementary
twice my experience
as a sixth grader and part of seventh
grade in san diego
were the complete 180 of my experience
in daly city granted the school that i
went to
in san diego was brand new
therefore we were the first batch of the
sixth graders to graduate
but despite that in my class
specifically
i had a ton of friends i made a ton of
friends we were all
hanging out together during recess and
during lunch we all had a little lunch
spot
and we were all just really good friends
and
we didn't have any difficulty
hanging out with different people
because everyone
was new and i would really like to give
a shout out to my sixth grade best
friend
andrea she goes by drea now because
she's cool like that
and we are actually still friends today
we've kept in touch in spite of the fact
that i ended up moving back to daly city
and we have remained friends and for a
while there when
she still lived in socal i would visit
her we would watch kpop concerts
together
and we would go to disneyland and just
having her
in my life really made my experience
in san diego so much better and what i
really liked the most about my
experience living in san diego is that
i got to be a part of my favorite
teachers class miss higdon
she to me is one of the reasons why i
became a teacher because
she empowered me she made
me feel like i was accepted and most
importantly
she challenged me and it was actually in
the sixth grade
when i won my very first speech contest
and this is coming from somebody who
couldn't even speak english fluently
or well literally a year a year and a
half
prior and since i won the school-wide
speech contest
i ended up going to the district-wide
competition
and i unfortunately didn't win that one
but i just remember seeing all these
kids from all these different schools
within the district
and them reciting their speeches
and it sounding amazing and
these are the kids who have faced
many challenges the topic of the speech
is what is the most important thing in
your life
and everyone had a plethora of different
answers and i remember this girl who i
think won
second place and her speech was all
about pictures being the most important
thing in her life
because about a month before the speech
writing contest
happened she and her family actually
lost her house to a fire and one of the
first things that her
mom took from their burning house
were pictures and clearly that struck a
chord with me and that
impacted me to this day because i
remember it
so distinctly and it was great and if
you were wondering what my answer was
and
as cliche as it sounds because i am now
an educator and a teacher myself
my answer was school education was the
most important thing in my life and
my reason then and my reason now is
pretty much the same thing and
that is because i value it more than
anything in the world because it is
something that no one else can take away
from me
and it is something that i know i can
work on
to make myself and my life better
so that's really dramatic but clearly i
have picked the right path for me
because to this day
i am a teacher and i have no plans of
changing careers anytime soon or any
time
at all and all of that i want to say
is because miss higdon never gave up on
me
she always made sure that i was doing
what i was supposed to be doing and that
she
challenged me to do better whenever i
felt like giving up
she would always tell me that i can do
it and as a matter of fact it was also
in the sixth grade that i got
a spirit award and the spirit award
is called perseverance and at first
i was actually getting a little salty
because every other one of my friends
were getting the spirit awards at the
end of each month and i didn't
and the very last spirit award was
perseverance
and she said that that was on purpose
because
she knew that at the end of it all that
i would persevere
and then after living in san diego for a
little bit my mom and i
ended up moving back to daly city
because she
actually found a job in san francisco
and we ended up staying at my cousin's
house my atomolec
and she is amazing she and i are still
very close to this day
and i am very close with her two
daughters
kaylee and crystal and they are actually
the ones who
painted those paintings in the back
there
and we have stayed very close all
throughout
and i remember when i moved back to daly
city
i was kind of dreading it because it
wasn't a fun experience the first time
but i thought to myself hey it's going
to be a new school
you're going to be fine and for the most
part it was fun and fine
but then again middle school is or at
least
was full of kids who were catty
and who just wanted to be cool
and i also wanted to be cool like
everyone else
i mean as a middle schooler i think that
was everyone's goal
but i realized too upon
moving back to daly city that i
needed to make some changes about myself
i wanted to be
cool i wanted to reinvent who i was
and if i'm being completely honest with
you it was a complete fail
because despite the fact that i tried to
assimilate
to the usual american societal norms
and the usual american school norms
i was still and i want to
say to this day still not the coolest
person
in the planet and i just remember i was
wearing skechers while everyone else
were wearing their
air force ones and i remember wearing my
clothes
multiple times a week because hello we
had a washer and dryer
you can just wash your clothes but
apparently there is an
unspoken rule in middle school that you
should not be an outfit repeater
and granted now as a teacher in middle
school i feel like that
stuff doesn't exist or if it does it
doesn't exist
that much in 2020 i can honestly say
that kids are not as catty kids
are actually very accepting of others
and
i want to say that a lot of them tend
to stand up for what is right and what
is just
and i want to give credit to the fact
that despite the fact that kids are on
their screens
for hours and hours and hours a day it
is through those screens that they are
able to get
information and that they are able to
see representation of themselves
on social media on tv shows on movies
and i feel like they feel a little bit
more empowered because back in the day
when i was in middle school anything
that i watched on tv
had zero asian representation i was
watching one tree hill dawson's creek
gossip girl
even law order svu these are shows that
only primarily
featured white people and nowadays kids
have people to look up to that are
people of color or that are part of the
lgbtqia plus community or non-binary
and now because the internet exists the
world is their oyster they can be
watching k-pop videos
one day and then watch mukbang videos
another day
and watch vloggers another day
right like all of this are things that
used to not exist
when i was growing up in america and
it was a culture shock for me coming
from the philippines where it was
primarily conservative not necessarily
politically
but more so values wise
and despite the fact that i did have
some negative experiences
in the united states a i didn't let it
deter me
from pursuing the goals that i had and b
it actually liberated me from some of
the more
restricting and conservative ideals and
values
that limited people and that forced
people to conform
when in reality you should be liberated
from all forms of oppression
granted america still perpetuates
oppression
and flat out murders of people of color
especially black people hashtag black
lives matter
but i do want to say that my experience
in america really helped me
decolonize my mind especially
when i ended up going to college at san
francisco state where it was a
requirement
to take ethnic studies classes and i
liked it so much that i only needed two
classes to get a minor
in ethnic studies specifically asian
american studies
but i didn't pursue it because i didn't
want to stay an extra semester i can
honestly say that all of these
experiences
that i had growing up as an asian
american the good
the bad the ugly the valuable the
important
all of these experiences made me who i
am today and in spite of the fact that
there were some negative experiences
i still came out of it alive and kicking
and thriving
and ready to take on the world and now
my life has come full circle because now
as an adult i am an educator i am a
teacher
and i strive every single day to ensure
that i am providing a safe place for my
students to be
who they are and who they truly are on
the inside
and for them to not be afraid to show
who they are
and to share their experiences with me
and with their classmates because at the
end of the day all
everyone wants is to feel a sense of
belonging
and hopefully through this video and the
rest of the videos that are going to be
a part of the series
people are able to see that in spite of
the challenges that life throws you
you're just gonna keep on keeping on
and when they throw lemons at ya don't
make lemonade
grab those lemons and plant a lemon tree
so you can be
fruitful wow i actually just thought of
that idiom myself does that idiom exist
because
if not i'm a genius all right so that
concludes this video i will be sure
to film edit and publish the other parts
of this video series hopefully you guys
enjoyed and learned
something about growing up asian
american
in my experience i hope that you guys
are having a good day
thank you so much for watching you are
awesome stay awesome and i will see you
guys in my next video
bye