ah take a bajillion times I can't I'm so
awkward I just I'm just all over the
place for this video and ice I'm so
sorry
oh hey guys and welcome back to my
channel it has been a long long time and
I apologize as always but of course
school comes first
it is finally summer I'm out of school
and I just came back home from Missouri
so it is all about getting back on track
so by senior year I can continue on um
really quick update this summer I will
be taking a lot of summer classes as
well as working at the same time so of
course everything is still on a Tuesday
Saturday schedule in terms of my blog
but everything else in between it just
kind of is on my own time so there may
be some weeks or some days where I don't
upload on time but please do bear with
me because I do have school and
applications open up in July for my PT
schools so I really have to focus on
that as well
and most importantly my goal for this
year is to get into therapy school so
once the application is opened up in
July I will be busy trying to finish my
applications getting everything together
and then of course if I make through
round one then I go through interviews
and go visit the schools and everything
like that
so yeah it's gonna be really exciting
really busy really stressful so I'm
really hoping this summer I will
actually fulfill my promise of wanting
to be back where I was when I was a
freshman in today's video I will be
doing the Asian American tag as I saw
from Jen M I really really look up to
her and
she is absolutely like perfection in my
eyes on all honesty I really look up to
her and I watched a lot of her videos
and when I saw this tag it like it's
struck like a heart string like it made
my heart throb and to hear her story of
how she grew up as an Asian American
made me want to do this tag as well
number one which ethnicity are you I am
fit amis American both of my parents are
from Vietnam and yeah I like to eat pho
I like to eat rice every day like I love
fish sauce but yes I am Vietnamese
American a lot of people kind of get my
ethnicity mixed up with other Asian
ethnicities but yeah I don't know why
both my parents look very venom ease in
my eye and when you look at me I get I
get I look like I'm Filipino or I look
Chinese or lately people have been
asking if I'm Korea and it's just a
weird thing to see because my family
looks very bitter means in my eyes and I
and I thought I look doing two Me's but
I guess I guess I don't but yeah number
two which generation are you I am
technically first-generation American
Ford but both of my parents did
immigrate here after the war when they
were very young they were about seven or
eight years old when they first came to
America and yeah they grew up in the
American school system they both speak
fluent English and they are also flew in
Vietnamese most of my friends are like
they're like taken aback when they first
meet my parents because they don't have
a Fabi accident they have a normal
American accent somewhat southern
because we're from Texas and they grew
up in Louisiana and
so we say y'all they sometimes say ax
instead of ask I kind of tether in
between there but yeah number three what
was the first experience where you felt
that Democrat of being a minority or
different um my first experience would
have to be middle school long story
short I went to private school from
kindergarten through second grade and
then I went to public school from third
grade through fifth grade and then I
went back to the same private school
throughout the rest of my middle school
life um growing up I didn't really have
a big problem with my ethnicity I didn't
question anything I didn't feel out of
place because I went to school in Plano
and Plano they have a lot of different
ethnicities and a lot of variation for
my regulation I don't remember a lot of
teasing of my ethnicity in my public
school system but once I went back to my
private school that's where things
changed and I didn't understand why
there were a lot of other
asian-americans in that school system a
lot of Vietnamese Americans in that
system or not system in that school and
so for me to be singled out most of the
time and teased was so bizarre to me I
felt very out casted in middle school I
felt that I had to change myself or act
in a certain way or change the way I or
change my personality based on who I was
talking to just so they wouldn't tease
me I really wanted to fit in with those
kids
I remember going into the school and I
just remember being teased a lot and
great when we when I first rejoined this
private school it was very hard
transition for me I was the nerdy kid I
was the one with the transition glasses
when everyone had contacts already I was
the kid that more like a headband and
had I didn't have layers my hair was too
here and look like Dora my hair was
thick and I didn't wear clear mascara or
like clear eyebrow gel we weren't
allowed to wear makeup or any nail
polish other than clear so but I never
wore any of that I didn't get my
eyebrows waxed I didn't shave yet I was
it was a very awkward time for me but
this was the time where the bullying
really affected me and my personality it
really bothered me I felt like I was the
only one being bullied because no one
else was being teased for being Asian I
had a lot of people and a lot of people
but I had some people come up to me and
like they would do this when I'm talking
or they would tease me and I would just
say something normal or what I thought
was normal and they would they would
mock me and do this and like pull their
eyes back and it used to make me feel so
frustrated because I wasn't the only
Asian there but they didn't tease them
as much as me they always teased me and
I think it was because I was also the
new girl or the new girl number four
were you always proud of your heritage
or was there a time where you rejected
it um I was never ashamed of being Asian
I was more embarrassed of my facial
features and more embarrassed of like my
physical attributes not necessarily my
culture I was just more embarrassed
about what I looked like in middle
school than any
than anything else number five what are
some stereotypes that you struggle with
um I don't really struggle with a ton of
stereotypes I did when I was younger but
the one stereotype that I struggle with
to this day even is the stereotype that
Asians are smart because they're agents
or you're smart because you're Asian
or you got your good grade because
you're Asian that stereotype bothers the
crap out of me um it was introduced to
me when I was in I think it was
introduced to me in elementary school
but I didn't really think much of it at
that time but it really did bother me in
middle school because it was constantly
thrown at me I think it really bothered
me because we were in private school we
were expected to be the best that we
could be we were given the privilege to
attend a private school where our
academia is supposed to be higher than
that of normal education and we were
aware of that Hill but if I was just
five points higher than this one kid or
another kid they were like oh well you
got five points higher because you're
Asian you're supposed you're smart
because you're Asian we all have to work
really hard but you don't have to work
hard because you're Asian it really made
me frustrated because it disregarded all
of the effort that I put into school and
all the effort I put into studying and
doing the best that I could do but it
still it bothered me but I didn't
retaliate I didn't say anything I just
said oh well you got a really good grade
too or you know like oh well she got a
better grade than me and she's not Asian
like I would say things like that to try
and be polite to not you know feed into
that stereotype and I never bragged
about my grades I would tell them if
they asked me
because I was honest the time when it
really bothered me was when they or was
one the kid or the group of people would
come after like my family from it I
remember this one instance and like
after-school program I don't know how
this conversation came up but it like
really made me ain't this one kid and he
probably I think he was like one of the
couple of kids that like relentlessly
kind of went after me for being Asian I
remember we were talking about stuff and
all of a sudden there was like he had
like an outburst he like got in my face
and he pointed his finger at me and he
was saying stuff like oh you don't
understand what it takes to be like to
be able to go to school or whatever to
afford things I think it was like that
he basically accused me of not knowing
or not understanding what it's like to
work hard and he told me he was like
your parents are doctors even though
they're not but your whole family is are
doctors because you're Asian things are
easy for you because you're Asian at
this point in my life I had heard
stories about my parents immigration and
it really broke my heart like to hear
all of their struggles to come to
America after the war and basically
escaping from the war it really it just
really bothered me that that he would
say all those things not realizing all
the sacrifices my family has made in
order for an order for us to have a
better life I'm getting like emotional
just talking about it I think it made me
more angry that he had said those things
because we were on the same standard we
went to the same
private school he was in private school
from kindergarten all the way up until
that point and I wasn't in private
school for like three years kept telling
me that his parent with multiple jobs in
order for him to be at the school and
even though my parents didn't have
multiple jobs it's still hard work and
hard money that went into our education
cuz he didn't understand that for them
to had the jobs that they have now or
for them to be where they are now was
through a lot of hard work and it just
it just didn't make any sense to me that
he would be like so angry at me for
being Asian and for having my parents he
didn't know or he didn't realize that my
parents were refugees or were you know
immigrants from a terrible war and
communism and a poor country number six
can you speak your language and yes I
can speak good amines but I understand
more than what I can speak if that makes
any sense I can read it phonetically but
I just don't know what I'm reading I've
been told when I was little I was like
super fluent and had a really hardcore
accent um like a hardcore northern
accent because my babysitter was from
the northern region of Vietnam and my
parents are from the southern region and
so now my Vietnamese is like a mix of
both dialects but yes I can speak it on
like a child's level but I'm very proud
that I can speak it there is a time in
Mosul another instance where me and
another vid amis friend of mine or a
couple of us we were speaking in
Vietnamese and I remember this one girl
I think she was the one we were talking
I don't remember but she turned around
and she was like really angry she was
like speak English you're in America so
he needed to speak American or speak
English but yes I can't speak Vietnamese
now my brothers on another hand they
don't speak a lick of it they don't even
understand it I have to like translate
every time we go someone number seven
how has being asian-american affected
relationship with your parents it it
really it didn't really affect my
relationship with my parents a lot just
because my parents were Americanized but
it did bother me growing up how strict
they were but I don't know if that like
pertains to our culture or anything like
that
other than that no not really
number eight how do you feel about your
heritage now do you identify with it I
absolutely love my heritage I don't
really like super like embrace it and
like I'm not like super passionate about
it but internally within myself I feel
more comfortable in my skin now than
what I did in middle school I really do
identify with Vietnamese
even though like people don't think I'm
gonna me as when they look at me but
when they realize that I am data means
I'm like I feel very proud like oh wow
you're Viet and I'm like yeah be it and
they like inquire and whether or not I
can speak it and it's really helped me
at work I've had a couple of patients
who are more comfortable speaking
Vietnamese than English and so I would
work more closely with them so I can
translate
there were times I had to be a
translator even though I'm not like the
best translator in the world it still
made them feel more secure and my work
space than anything else
and I love how my boyfriend loves me to
me food like he could eat a bowl like
nobody
business and he actually eats it the way
like like Vietnamese grannies and like
mini means like like housewives or like
mother just like people who cook but
what she did eat it he doesn't put any
sauce in it he like puts the lime and
all the vegetables in it but he doesn't
put any of the hoisin sauce and he
doesn't really put sriracha sauce in
there he eats the broth as it is and he
drinks it like there's nothing in that
Bowl when he's done he eats all of it
number nine what is your favorite thing
about being Asian American / your
heritage I think my favorite thing is is
that it just makes me distinguished it
makes me different but at the same time
it makes me feel like me I love how I
can like help others of my own ethnicity
like in my workplace I love how I can
translate and just make them feel more
at ease just because I'm Vietnamese or
just because I've greeted them in
Vietnamese or because I can speak to
them and like I can I can translate them
so that's it for this video I am so
sorry if it like if it like really puts
you guys off like I should have done a
different video for like my first video
back but I really did what to talk about
this and I really did want to kind of
like introduce it if you guys would like
to hear more about my family's
background and my family story I would
be more than happy to write a blog post
about it
I just don't want to be super detailed
in this video because it would take
forever and I think I would start like
crying if I like went into detail and
super detail about it I mean they
started tearing up a while ago when I
was telling that story I hope you guys
enjoy this video I for sure feel like I
am a mess when I edit this I'm gonna be
like I want to redo this whole video
again but we'll see how this goes
thank ya thank you guys so much for
tuning in and I hope to see you guys
back for more um yeah I'm always so
awkward with like my outros but that has
not changed at all
do you have a lot of things planned out
in terms of videos and blog posts so
please stay tuned for more I'll see you
guys the next one
[Music]
you