this is future Isabelle future I'm not
really like a eunuch
but this is me and today this video is
just gonna be kind of like a montage of
the things that I am grateful for cuz
it's like snippets so after a snippet I
have an explanation of like the days
that happened it's kind of categorized
in list of things that I am grateful of
I hope you guys enjoy this I've never
done a vlog in such a long time it's
crazy how much stuff I have for my
luggage not a lot actually because I
don't really need that much and then I'm
probably thinking of getting a bag yes
but yes you guys may be wondering is
well you've never done a vlog in such a
long time what makes you want to do it
I just wanted to document this part
there's so many things that I've filmed
but I haven't actually edited and got
myself to edit because this semester has
been pretty crazy I love it I
love it I just wanted to take the time
for Thanksgiving break even though I
will be doing some homework to catch up
for the bulldozing of the next semester
I mean the end of the semester but I
want to just document some of my trips
with my family and also friends so you
guys can see if you guys kind of know me
well enough or decently me and my family
moved to Fremont recently so this is
literally my first time ever since I
moved to Taiwan spending Thanksgiving
with my family which is so exciting
absolutely stoked my roommate left I'm
really sad about that I wished she to
clean some stuff and pack for some stuff
because I'm not entirely done
[Music]
future Isabelle speaking here that time
I was filming I did not know that I was
gonna miss my flight
um that's a lot of story but I missed my
flight thankfully United was able to
assign me another flight and I was able
to arrive safely from home I like 11
p.m.
oh right now that's my bed then my make
up for Thanksgiving I won't play it over
here which is just this cropped sweater
and also these pair of corduroy pants
but yeah so my friend Al Attar will be
coming over we later have this potluck
thing at 3 p.m. so excited to be home
really really excited it's like
incredible right now I'm catching up on
homework which I have to watch the piano
if you guys don't know it's a movie that
we had to do like film strip analysis
it's what I have to do kind of catching
up because there is a lot of homework
even though there's Thanksgiving break
so yeah I like my makeup I really did a
good job Eleanor
hey what up I'm gonna go find go to our
mom's friend's house for Thanksgiving
meal
pama Thanksgiving dinner I wanna build a
room
playing Catan Andrews here mom Oh
Thanksgiving potluck with one of my high
school friends Aladar I'm really
grateful for the friendship that we have
it's a long history
some things to do with liking him before
in the past and despite all these
complications that we had we still
managed to be close friends and even
though we don't talk very often it's
like one of those friends that you don't
talk with for a long time but once you
do you just start where you left off
I'm so thankful for LR for coming to the
potluck and also thankful for hot
Michelle for hosting that pot look it
was so fun you know it was just me and
my brother and Alan are like playing
Catan it was so amazing and how like
warming to have spent my first
Thanksgiving back here in California
even though I miss Taiwan so much it's
rainy here in Fremont California and I'm
gonna go find my friend Maddie because
we're just gonna it's like a whole thing
which I love love I'm probably gonna
bring my laptop and also some homework
because yeah it's break as I said before
but there's homework that I want to kind
of get into because it's a lot yeah yeah
see
we're watching to all the boys I've
loved before and that's Maddie and she's
made me food oh yeah Joss and also her
food yeah hey Mads holding two of our
bags because he went shopping we're here
at unions okay we're gonna walk to Union
Square later I saw a friend of mine
shoutout to Jessica if you're watching
love you
so right now we are at the tree it's
been really hard to take photos because
it's really dark yeah it's really dark
so we're just gonna vlog and then that
is just the gleaming right tree oh it's
here it works but yeah we're just gonna
go to forever 21 to like chop a little
just a little just yeah Maddie my best
friend I was just so happy to see her
she came to New York recently it was her
first time coming to New York and I'm so
thankful to have her ever since high
school back in eighth grade when she
came over to the international school I
didn't know that I was gonna be like
lifelong friends with her and I'm so
thankful for that we had so much fun
catching up talking about our lives very
warming to know that there was someone
there in California to just you can
always touch base with describe one word
what you feel
[Music]
[Laughter]
the last few days were more of family
days later on walked around to great
mall at a shop a little and I wanted to
go to this ramen place that I absolutely
love the spicy miso ramen is just so
freaking good
we later and watched one of my favorite
movies probably my favorite movie it's
us and them and my dad and my brother
cried and it was just so nice to have
all four of us in the living room
watching this beautiful beautiful movie
loved it absolutely loved it packing to
go back now got my backpack and luggage
is downstairs by California I'm gonna
see you in a month it was full like he's
gay
and then yeah bye fam say bye to the
vlog see you soon yay
oh well this was a video but okay we
didn't take a photo - yeah the last day
I filmed it all alone just by myself
except for my family in the end but it
really just showed how thankful I am to
have so many family so many friends I
mean I didn't meet all of my friends but
I was able to FaceTime Christine and
Cheryl I think being thankful should
just be on Thanksgiving but definitely
trying to think about like the little
things to be thankful of yeah so thank
you so much for watching