[Music]
hey everyone so it's may and may is
Asian American Pacific Islander Heritage
Month so I thought it'd be the perfect
time to do the Asian American tag so
this tag actually started circulating
about two years ago I think I saw on my
favorite bloggers gen him do it I know
well she'd take a bunch of her other
friends like wheelie and then I would
step on line and there's just a bunch of
people doing the Asian American tag on
YouTube so I thought it would be great
to upload my own version of it let's get
started all right so the first question
is what ethnicity are you so I am
Vietnamese although I can't be 100% sure
as you see in the title I'm actually
adopted so we don't really know if I'm
100% Vietnamese although when I do walk
into the nail salons and a lot of them
are owned by baiting these people here
in Portland people are like start
speaking to me Vietnamese I'm like okay
I guess that means that probably looks
somewhat Vietnamese I know my older
sister who was a doctor from bottom well
she actually wants to do like the gene
test with me so we can see like exactly
what if miss news we are so I may look
into that in the future question 2 is
what generation are you as I said
earlier I'm adopted so I'm not really
sure I don't really think that counts as
a generation I guess if anything would
be one kind of I didn't like come over
here on choice because that sounds weird
but yeah that's me
the third question is what is the first
experience where you felt the
demarcation of being a minority or
different and I always knew that I was
different when I was in elementary
school and before that my parents would
I say hey like just so you know you're
adopted we didn't come out of our body
we went to Vietnam and got you and they
would say like oh you're Asian Americans
they might like a little different and
so in elementary school I just thought
like okay if you have black hair then
that means your agent like me I didn't
really think too much about it but then
when I got to middle schools when I
really started to see oh wait I think
I'm really different like it was easy
for me to tell that I was different
because it was female that was pretty
easy for me to pick up on but in terms
of Asian American I
notice too much but how come you
asian-americans at my school and then as
I said when I got to middle school
actually that's when kids started coming
up and being like hey where you might be
like Portland like no were you really
friend I'm like oh I guess Vietnam also
she wanted to know and then they would
say things like oh you don't really look
Asian and you must be half white or
something so I realized on my way
friends didn't get asked that so I was
like well okay I guess I'm different I
guess I'm Asian American per share and
people can definitely tell this and it
was very interesting and then terms of
being adopted in middle schools also
when I realized it was really for me it
just seemed normal as well I actually
have a couple of friends that were
adopted to from Asia something okay like
people are adopted it's like no
different from not being adopted but
then when I got to middle school I
actually had this response from some guy
I said oh I'm adopted and then he said
oh that's sucks and I was just so thrown
off I know to say I was like I mean me
and then he felt really bad I apologize
profusely but it was just weird that
that was his gut reaction and so and
I've encountered that later on as well
where people were like have this idea
that like adopted and foster kids or
like messed up or something I there's
something wrong with them because they
didn't like come out of their mom so
that's me kind of weird and then also I
realize when I told this one girl miss
what I was adopted
it wasn't bad but she was just like oh
what's that like is it really different
at your house like what do you guys do
and I was just like uh that's pretty
much the same we dinner me watch TV you
play video games not really too
different it's pretty much the same I
don't feel any different these are my
parents parents
so yeah middle school is really when I
started to realize wow I guess I'm
pretty different in those perspectives
hmm and then the fourth question is was
there a time when you weren't proud of
your heritage
and I would say yes there definitely was
I think in middle school weekend that's
where you do let's the grill the puberty
all that pens dead so in middle school I
wasn't what say I wasn't like ashamed of
it I wasn't like oh yo in Vietnamese I
want nothing to associate with it I just
want to say I proved all Americans I
don't really see business to the same
thing and everyone in the media who I
saw as like Asian American was really
nerdy or really awkward or like a dweeb
and nobody like it was
desirable to be asian-american except
like you know I guess brenda song I
really liked her but there wasn't much
for us so I was kind of like I just
don't really talk about it I wasn't
super gun calm I'm Asian American I'm
Vietnamese yeah like I learned all about
it so I wasn't really like big on being
proud of my heritage back then which is
kind of sad because I think like
everyone should be proud of who they are
and their identity but I just didn't
really see that as a big part of mine at
the time the fifth question is what type
of stereotypes do you deal with and I
would say there were a lot definitely I
think in middle school a lot of the
stereotypes were more like
microaggressions which definitions
basically what happened in middle school
is I had a lot of kids say things like
oh I remember this one girls like wow
like you're really pretty for an asian
girl I was just like okay I'm not to do
with that again I'm pretty sure that's
just like one stereotype that there's
like this white ideal beauty and the
Asians like can't reach that so that was
really and then I also had a lot of
people say wow just because you're like
oh you're so good at school I got the
Asian genes and like you know people
might think well Johnny I realize it's
like it's a college people wouldn't
think I was it's a positive stereotype
like that's fine but it's really not
because you're saying oh I'm not smart
because I worked hard
you say I'm smart because I happened to
be Asian so those are hurtful as well
and then getting older as I can't go to
college and I'm like now I think the
biggest one I have to deal with is a
fascination of Asian women which is the
idea
Oh American woman like doing it a lot
they serve a great like my eyes and it's
just really weird and I was like oh I
love Asian girls are the best all like
again the chickadee you just want to do
it a lot because you're Asian good Asian
girls love doing yeah that's what I'm
sure I mean I know there are girls of
all races that love doing it it's on the
don't and has nothing to do with race
and the really fine line between
fetishization so
it's hard to deal with us I see what you
tend to date and stuff so another
stereotype dealing with right now Chris
with the coma 19 going on as a lot of
people think that it's like the Chinese
virus and that that Koba 19 was started
by any East Asian American looking
people and so recently as you've
probably seen there's been a lot of
violence and hatred and hate crimes
against Asian Americans so that's
something I'm doing this right now I
feel lucky that so far I haven't had
anything happen yet but it is weird to
have your mom say like hey please be
careful when you both side like try to
like that will definitely wear a mask
and I'm like what kind of come your face
like don't like of Asian American
because people are gonna like might beat
you up and literally kill you for that
so that's pretty scary and it's
something that's just this big
stereotype that we're dealing with right
now and just clarify for everybody the
virus is not the Chinese virus and just
because you look East Asian American
does not mean you have it please stop
being racist please and question six is
can you speak the language unfortunately
I cannot speak Vietnamese I wish I could
I did try speaking Vietnamese like
YouTube video tutorials / like a solid
week I think this is so hard I kind of
just gave up and if I school had offered
it I definitely will take it in in high
school but an our middle school and high
school I only offered French Mandarin
and Spanish and so I took French cuz I
know
Vietnam was colonized by the French so
they have lots of people who speak
French there some okay at least if I
ever go back which I'm actually playing
on hopefully doing nothing sometime
later this year but I've ever go back
then I can at least talk to some other
people think that'd be really cool
bonjour je m'appelle Carolyn Ashanti
Oh should we say boom
wow the axle is actually horrible
accidents are not my forte so
increasingly in as little as seven how
has being asian-american affected your
relationship with your parents I felt
really lucky that luckily I hasn't
affected it too much of my like you know
you can see it going like bad I can cry
and I think like the biggest thing is
they just don't understand a lot of
things they don't understand the way
for example there are a lot of
friendships and relationships you may
have where you're gonna have
conversations about race and it's gonna
be pretty difficult for you to navigate
and some friendships that you might have
to let go because you just have
different views on things and like I
never really realized this until I think
college I realized oh shoot like race is
something used to talk about and like
racism and if your friend like your
close friend doesn't get it it could be
really tricky and hard and sad and
hurtful it's hard to know what to do
with all those feelings I never
experienced this my parents I was like
oh we didn't know like that would happen
we didn't know how to handle that or
warn you and I was like oh my gosh no
like don't feel bad it's okay I think
sometimes yeah I can just be tricky when
I'm trying to explain things like Oh
today this thing happened to me it
really sad very like if I try to make a
joke because you know here is a good way
to kind of deal with some struggles in
life such thing at home and my parents
sometimes don't get it it was kinda like
it's all bad like I know they just kind
of get tired like say it a lot but other
than that they're really supportive and
they're always weighing tightly solutes
in which is really awesome and helpful
so that's the way it's affected my
relation of my parents question it is
how do you feel about your heritage now
I'll say I'm really proud of it now like
I said in middle school I don't identify
with it in high school I was a little
close for like the animation it's fine I
guess it wasn't like blue but then when
I got to college I actually I'm at the
college I took a class by dr. house
intro to culture in communications in
rhetoric and that was so high opening
for me because I didn't even know like
Asian Americans sounds wiegert's like I
didn't even know Asian Americans were a
group that were oppressed because the
model minority myth I totally bought
into that like I guess Asian Americans
are doing fine I don't really see
anything wrong beside the weird
microaggressions but in that classroom I
learned shoot I was like I already do
like I said okay females is definitely a
group that has problems I can see I get
you to weigh differently I am NOT valued
as much as others because I'm a female
but later I realized oh my gosh like I'm
also not valued because I'm Asian
American oh great so but I was like I
don't feel like I said because then I
started reading more into it I started
volunteering for like that if it go
penny
American Film Festival and really gonna
into wine to like spread Asian American
culture and specifically I visited meas
club on campus it was really awesome to
learn more about my culture and heritage
where I came from and now I would say
yes I am pretty proud to be Asian
American and specifically Vietnamese
American I think it's really awesome and
cool and it's like Who I am for my
identity and it's it's just cool I guess
man oh yeah
and also on terms being adopted I also
like got to be on this adoptee panel
which was really fun and to talk to
other doctors to kind of felt the same
way and get a lot of similar questions
as me but now I think it's really cool
and like makes it unique it gives me a
new perspective on life the last
question is what is your favorite part
about being asian-american / your
heritage I would say my favorite part
about community and specifically is bond
me love it it's my favorite food my
friend took me to this really good place
called best baguette it's actually in
Beaver Dam but I think they also have a
location in Portland there's a specific
kind of Vietnamese sandwich it is four
dollars and fifty cents for a sandwich
sometimes their sandwiches you can get
for less that is an incredible deal I
love saving and good deals and the
sandwich is amazing that's what I got
hands thing has my favorite bond means
I've ever had and I've had some like in
New York City I had somebody thicker I
tried some here oh my gosh get me
started there's a bunch of bomb me is it
a whitewash you're like what the heck is
that if it's not on a baguette you need
to question what you see get it that's
all I get just know that that's not the
traditional bond me was born me it was
like a fusion of France and Vietnam so
how's the Vietnamese flavor is a meat
inside and then it has the French
baguette my favorite one is the barbecue
pork or if anyone ever goes to get one
it's amazing but besides the Botany
sandwich specifically I think it's this
really awesome to share cultures I love
that I'm able to share that Vietnamese
heritage a lot of people here who may
not know about it and I think the cool
thing about being API is that it's so
diverse and so I'm always still learning
about all the different Asian cultures
and then all the subcultures within them
it's like you'll never be able to stop
learning about all of them and sharing
what you know about some of it with
other people and that's like my favorite
part about being Asian American
that's it for the video I hope you all
enjoyed it yeah I hope you all have a
great rest of me and that you're all
saying stain save you so much for
watching and I'll see you next month bye
baby don't worry wanna sleep white boys
in a hurry got bigger days
don't worry you ain't got a car