I would meet people and they would be like yo, I'm this
and like ya know but like like like what
No, what are you and that's when I
Where am I wrong
What's up you guys it's your girl
today's video is gonna be a little bit different from you
I guess it's a little bit more serious today
Say like genetics DNA
Heritage culture, etc. So, um
Let me gotta run down so
my principal was sick and I was will see her
Was telling her somehow
We got on the topic of
And I was just telling her like I always
So fast forward a couple weeks later when she got
ah, and she was like I'm
She sent it to me and it ended up being a 23andme
so I got the package and
I just never open everyone in time. She send
Etc, etc. And after that that wasn't
No, January, yeah, it was January
Almost here cuz it's it's November
I let it say say let it sit and
September I
Finally was like, okay. Let me
23 me and I'm also glad that I waited too because if
as possible that I wouldn't I
Wouldn't have God and
You know our description of where I'm from because
so and about I
Registered my kid
I'ma say well I
Feel like I'm kind of like over
Around September 16th, you know, I do all that nasty
And around that time I think you have to sender
I was like in September
I think that they were going to flood in so I'm
But every day and at all
I'm just trying I'm like burning
My kid was registered. I'm looking at my email
and then
October 2nd, my reports were ready
2018 so October 2nd
2018 my reports were ready and I've watched a ton of other
I arrived with a little time as y'all can
At least it was like Nene ready already. So let me get it a little
Honestly, I've never had the culture or like whether for
Think that they care about stuff like that. I think I'm the only one
She's a little ignant. So I don't think if I
I don't think she no
being
African-american I was being black
You wanna say everybody my family or
Grew up here most
grew up here most of the time in my
Very small portion of my life, but we moved it is
Family down there or nothing so I don't have
It's an upstate New York in this region.
And as for my father my father know much about where we came from.
you know had that conversation
To me to be completely honest. I never really thought about
now
Like I said, I am from New York
But I'm not from New York City from those of you who are
so
When I went to college, it was just like a culture
PWI predominantly white
institution but the percentage of black people
Good or whatever for the most part for
and
When I got there, you know
I was meeting people I left on campus and I
I'm dis this and now what are
and like ya know but like like like what
No, what are you?
And that's when I really
am I
Where am I firm because I would
Nigerian it would be from Ghana
I have a friend who's I think she's cubed a lot of
So it's just like and they are in those
My school are from New York
You know the five boroughs Browns
So down there, you know, it's very culture based and New
So once I got to college I
Like they got the only food and I think
And on this chicken a little chicky the loser cuz
Jack nothing else
I just always gonna have you thinking about it cuz my
Open up my mind to so
Yeah, ever since then. I've been wondering
so I'm really grateful that my
buy me this kit because
Lord knows I didn't even
party, and I never probably
would have found out about it
Yeah
so before prior to
I did look up a few videos and I noticed that they gave me
I'm probably and I was like, I'm
Five percent European because you know African
Um, you know, we always have a little bit of African in
Um, so yeah, my European percentage was not high at all. I did
We never had that culture talking my
Yes, so as far as what I thought I was because I got
From my school who were African
Most of the people that I'm at school are from there,
Nigeria and um
That's pretty much a dad
Just because of the
knowing that history
another thing people from my school is when I would just tell
400 years in history just
like they was like really an old that I
me I'm just like
Yeah
My bad job is
But like I was saying like they will forget that you know this whole
That are black
That don't know where they come from in Africa. I haven't message
I know that they like
And it just at that point it was kind of getting
You're in America. It's not like I'm living in Africa, you know then
Very familiar with what occurred here.
I'm pretty sure everybody in on the New York State area is
um
Yeah, that's another thing was a lot of
A lot of that and if anything in this video as a
I'm not trying to be offensive. I'm not trying to you
So I got my results back and
Chao was high so let's let's do it.
Because I actually sent
Because I was just so excited. So your
Ninety point four percent
I'm blacker than black black black black
Okay, and guess what was Gus was my highest percentage
Nigeria
I
Was thirty eight point nine, I
0.9 percent
Nigerian, so I'm gonna
after that, I say
16.04 said coastal West African
six point seven eight
percent
From the Congo Congolese. I'm not sure if I'm
You know, you know
say that a
Lot of these. I don't know
Six point one per se. I know
Southern East African one points one point four percent
Sort of knees. They're a point
Was would you mean that's
I was trying to be like cultural even though this is a low-key
I try to give y'all I try to give a little
It's green and
The yellow had to do because I don't have anything that's green
So yeah that mix up
1.6% broadly
Southern ease it just makes up a whole bunch of
so if i'm ninety
African how much my European
How much
Seven point eight percent
European
I'll take that and my highest percentage for being European
British and Irish
Scandinavian one point
0.9
Burley European one point for
This next one really shocked me
Growing up like oh, you're Native American.
Never got fed any of those lies
but according to this
East Asian and Native American. I am one
But I'm surprised that it existed.
one percent
that doesn't mean I don't
And I said drily north and northern
Burley Chinese and
So that makes up my 1.3 percent East Asian and
So yeah, I was extremely
Excited for you
But what I wanna do is
I kind of want to take the ancestry DNA one just
Accurate just because
I
Guess genetic pool to the tech exactly where
To me getting my reports
You know that did this with 23andme
Sub-saharan African that's it was like three categories
but I kind of want to
Do an ancestry DNA and I
but I only do it if you've got a really
seventy eighty dollars a
Irie go up large areas, or I know
but yeah, I was tight when I found
You know and I'm saying
back to school
Let me stop you copyrighted
Um, I was extremely inside I was in DC last week because it
And I hope any fellow Nigerians that happiness eaters.
I come from that country and that I
Because if I have to have kids I can tell them a little
Hmm I think that's gonna conclude this video, like I said,
I'm black. I'm black.
Nigerian air
Yeah, so that's pretty much it I'm sorry if I was
I was just super excited and um
Hope to see you guys
Comment below if y'all wanna see one