oh good morning i've got to get started
on my work day
this is my very first what i eat in a
day don't know how it's gonna go
what i will tell you is that i never eat
breakfast my stomach can handle
breakfast
it's been like this for my entire life i
immediately have to
go to the bathroom if i eat breakfast
we're gonna start off with some iced
coffee
as usual i made a new batch last night
[Music]
sorry that was so aggressive
oh that's good
oh that's strong first thing i do when i
wake up is check my calendar
it's 9 30 right now i have a call at 10
but i kind of
plan my day around sort of my meeting
schedule
truth be told i don't leave my house
during the week at all like not even to
go grocery shopping
but today i have to restock we're
filming a what i even a day girl
[Music]
[Applause]
i am actually a literal idiot
spraying my angle yet again in my air
max i've sprayed my angle and then once
before
i'll show you my braces on
it's kind of painful right now but the
show must go on
to make myself feel better i'm treating
myself to a baby belle
wheel of cheese i don't really snack a
lot but
if i do it's going to be something like
this this cheese will make me feel
better
literally reminds me of my childhood why
am i such a klutz
it's one o'clock now for lunch today
we're having shrimp tacos and the key to
these shrimp tacos
is the sauce the sauce is everything
[Music]
the
let it go
[Music]
when i met you
i
[Music]
am
take me
i'm so excited is going to be a mouthful
it's actually really spicy i put a lot
of cayenne pepper on the shrimp
but it's so good
oh so good
i've been on a korean drama binge
i feel like this video might be more
interesting if i answer some questions
because some of you in my last video
requested q a videos which i'm always
shocked to hear because i feel like i'm
just so not interesting
but let me upload on my ig story quickly
the story is up
we will wait for the questions to
trickle in
for dinner today we are making broccoli
cheddar
soup it is really cold in new york and i
was craving
panera's broccoli cheddar soup one day i
don't have panera often
but i was like that sounds so good right
now
so i went out and got some groceries to
make that a reality let's just get
started
[Music]
[Applause]
it's always
[Music]
is
anything you like
[Music]
don't you forget about me
oh yeah that's good that's
[Music]
all perfect i have my soup here in front
of me i'm so excited for this
i done goofed though because i forgot to
buy bread and obviously like
come on this is supposed to be eaten in
a bread bowl
the questions have come in quite a bit
to choose from so thank you
all of you for submitting your questions
but first let me take a bite of this
delicious soup
that right there that's that's
it that's it man i know in american
culture you're not supposed to make any
noise while eating your soup
but in asian culture slurping is good
and these asian spoons are made for
slurping first question is from
will jlp do you prefer dating
younger older or same age men if we're
up to me i would choose older but i'm
not
closed off to people my age i've always
hung out with people that have been
older than i am
so i feel like i just get along better
with older guys but again these are all
generalizations it really just depends
on the guy
how was your high school experience i
was actually
new to my high school and um i didn't
have a lot of friends in that school
district
i kind of hated high school and i was
really quiet and a bit anti-social
by choice i didn't even go to my prom
because i was like f this school i hate
everyone here
what songs are on repeat i have quite a
few
and it depends on my mood but currently
i have
a playlist called cheese and wine that i
curated and it's all
jazz it makes me feel very sort of
sophisticated and elegant and
feminine and this is kind of a playlist
i like to gravitate towards when i'm
just feeling very
zen and i want to wind down a little bit
you can follow it on spotify
but the last four songs are currently on
repeat for me
any korean artist recommendations i'm
really really into george lately
he's not that famous but he's this
up-and-coming r b
artist favorite song by george right now
is called look at me how would you
describe yourself
slash how your family and friends would
describe
you i think across the board it would
just be chill and oh my god look at that
sunset in the back
wow sorry i get distracted really easily
top three foods
you can't live without i can't live
without
halal kimchi and pho
do you have any random hobbies slash
things you like to do in your free time
boxing was a big one i was really really
getting into boxing before cloved but
all the gyms ended up closing down
obviously what in your opinion are your
best qualities
this could be a good and a bad thing but
i consider myself very dense not
the prettiest term to use to describe
myself but
what i mean by that is that i have a
pretty strong foundation
and i stay true to my gut and what i
know
i feel like i'm very grounded in my
values and beliefs
so it kind of makes me a very stable
person but it could be a bad thing
in the sense that i can be stubborn or a
little close-minded at times
but i try to remind myself to be as
open-minded as possible if i'm like
catching myself being close-minded i
tried to
you know check myself i'm iris kim asks
what do you do to practice self-love
especially when you're single
by the way love you really just building
myself
in every facet going to the gym more and
taking care of myself which
to be honest i haven't really been doing
a good job of recently it's not really
about like getting my
nails done and doing a face mask it's
really just deep diving into
who i am and working on
you know my flaws and trying to explore
how i can improve
what's your zodiac sign i am
an aquarius sun pisces moon and
rising capricorn any of you guys are
really really really good and into
astrology
let me know what that combination means
down in the comments because
i i love all things astrology related
how many tattoos do you have i only have
one on my arm it's a little hard to see
from the front if i turn around you
could see more of it
this is my first and only tattoo what
were three difficult things in your
childhood well
this one's kind of deep being a second
gen
korean-american if your parents don't
speak english then a lot of things
kind of fall on you and you have to sort
of help them figure out documents
and obviously you don't even understand
those documents because you're a kid
but you just have to kind of figure it
out another thing was that i was not
financially comfortable growing up
uh grew up in a very poor family so that
was
definitely difficult and three
difficulty
was i guess that my parents both my
parents were always working
is it the idea of fame that's attractive
to you or the potential to be your own
boss
without a doubt it's the second answer i
don't really care about clout
not a question but you seem like a big
sister i never had just so raw and real
thank you so much i love i love hearing
things like this i think it's really
important to be
authentic i've been answering questions
from sunset to
nightfall so i will wrap this up here
sorry if i didn't get to your question
thank you thank you thank you so much
for
always supporting and i will see you
guys
in the next one
[Music]