[Music]
it is important to share
my experience as an asian american
[Music]
so
what's going on you guys welcome back to
my channel i
woke up feeling so amazing i'm like
totally recalibrated
reset after the holiday break i'm
excited to actually
get into the groove of things and
fall back into a normal routine i
just have been in this major
slump for the past couple months and
stopped working out completely
and let myself go i gained
seven to eight pounds i'm not really
feeling myself
and it's definitely contributed to a lot
of
mental negativity that i've been
carrying with me over the last couple of
months
lately whenever i just look in the
mirror i'm like
yuck i hate what i see so
enough sulking about it i need to do
something about it and pull myself
together because no one will do that for
me
i already feel like i'm so much more
energized because
i i've worked out for like the past four
days
so i'm gonna start eating healthier too
i actually saw a really cool recipe
online and they were
by marion's kitchen she just posted a
bond me
lettuce wrap recipe that i really want
to try
it fits within my diet so i'm
about to head to the grocery store to
pick up some of the things that i need
[Music]
do
so excited
[Music]
so
i foreign so out of shape it's not even
[Music]
funny
i recently joined this new app called
clubhouse it is
unfortunately invite only but it's a
really
interesting space it's kind of like a
group
podcast or i also like to say it's
an audio reddit
like you can join these chat rooms that
discuss a range of different topics
sometimes it could get very career
focused sometimes it's just about
anything and everything
but i've been listening in on a lot of
chat rooms
talking about korean american identity
this has actually
been surprisingly one of my most
requested topics to
discuss in my videos but i've kind of
just
i don't know i never gave it the light
because i was like i don't know what's
so
interesting about my story but these
chat rooms in
clubhouse really kind of shed some light
onto why it is important to share my
experience as an asian american with
the platform that i have all right i'm
actually
gonna sit down for this one i
was born in flushing queens raised in
long island
i went to school k through 12 in long
island and then as soon as i graduated
high school i moved back to queens
throughout my entire life i juggled both
the
urban and suburban environments so i was
influenced by both and i understand
both my mom worked at a nail salon my
dad was in wholesale
i grew up in the basement of someone
else's
home in long island so whenever people
hear that i grew up in long island they
automatically assumed that i grew up
rich
or that my family is rich but that's
completely not the case at all
my parents intentionally lived under
shitty circumstances
just to put me in better public
schooling and long island if you don't
know is demographically
very white in my school i was
i think one of three asian girls total
in the entire class
when i was younger i was like i am going
to assimilate as
much as i could like i was going to
be white okay but that
meant conforming to all of the whiteness
i saw around me
and because i assimilated so well i was
actually pretty popular in school
i was popular in school yet so
incredibly embarrassed of my background
i was embarrassed
to be asian and poor in a
rich white neighborhood people obviously
found out i was
asian couldn't hide that but i tried to
conceal it as much as i
could and that came in the form of
things like the meals
i brought to lunch if my meals ever
required an explanation to my white
friends
then it was a no like i cannot bring
that to school that is social suicide
my mom knew never to pack me korean food
for lunch
she knew damn well not to pack korean
food for lunch i let her know
but the only asian food that was okay to
bring to
school was leftover chinese food because
all the white girls did that too
but being poor was something i was a
little bit better at hiding and that's
something i tried to do
um more of so whenever i had
play dates or friends decide to hang out
at someone's house
it was never my house it always had to
be someone else's house because
i lived in a shitty basement that's
embarrassing so i couldn't have
my friends see that and see how
i was living compared to their suburban
million dollar homes with pools and the
moment that i dreaded every
day was getting dropped off at school
in my crusty old
white dodge caravan i was so embarrassed
of that thing
because everybody was pulling up in
their like typical suburban
suvs the highlanders and even escalades
for the richer people
and i was the only one with the outdated
dodge caravan
as soon as i got out of the car i would
just look down
and scurry into the school building as
fast as i could
just to minimize the chance of anybody
ever
seeing me come out of that car i also
dragged my mom
to all like the fancy department stores
and the shops
that all my friends would go to to get
their clothes because i had to look like
them i had to be
then um but this drove my mom nuts
because she couldn't
afford a lot of these items like she
couldn't afford 150 dollar
uggs for her 10 year old child or
the 70 pair of yoga pants that
everybody else was wearing but i was
really adamant about
that and i was like if i'm going to be
accepted into this very white
crowd then i have to look the part i was
too young to understand
you know the financial circumstances
that we were in and what that meant
but in eighth grade my world changed i
moved to a new school that was still
pretty white but it was a much bigger
school
and there were a lot more asians the
white people here were different
and they weren't the people that i grew
up with
so i kind of just shut down and i was
like i'm not gonna fit in anywhere here
i kind of was a lone wolf throughout
high school
so this is the part where i started
hanging out in queens a lot
i was drawn to how everybody in queens
struggled the way that i did everybody
in queens
had that immigrant struggle that i could
relate to
that's where i felt like i belonged the
most
i felt normal just being in queens as i
got older
and the more comfortable i became with
my korean-american identity i
started meeting a lot of people a lot
more asian-americans and
i realized just how amazing
some people were and the things that you
know my peers and my mentors were doing
i was like damn you're asian american
like me
living in this very white world i don't
know i was just so inspired by
the cool people that i met i met a lot
of people in
the arts i met a lot of people in
entertainment
we have a lot to push through and we
have a lot to prove
in our society but i think it's just so
important
as asian americans to uplift each other
rather than compete with each other
because we're all just trying to
leave our mark in this world and i'm
just going to leave off by saying that
we all
just need to help each other grow
as an asian-american community and
cheer for one another because we're all
doing such great things and this
is exactly what our immigrant parents
came to america
[Music]
for