i hope you guys are ready get a coffee
get a snack because we're learning to
love ourselves today
big task but we're doing it hey guys
it's luna
[Music]
if you don't know me hey i'm luna if you
do how are you doing today we are doing
one of my absolute favorite videos to
film always which is a girl talk
this one specifically about body image
body positivity
self love i would say it's one of the
main reasons my channel kind of started
for me
it's definitely my mission and my
purpose here on youtube i have a
multitude of videos on this subject that
i will link below
my most recent one was about like half a
year ago and that was called accepting
my weight gain as a ballerina and if you
want to know kind of my whole story with
my body image from the age of 13 till
now then watch that video i'd love to
update you guys where my head's at when
it comes to body image because i feel
like
it helps you but most importantly it
helps me and i would say that i'm at a
different place than
i was half a year ago when i filmed that
video honestly a worse place which is
scary
again i want to talk to you guys about
it maybe we can handle it together
you guys know i ask on my instagram for
you to ask me questions so if you ever
want to be involved with a girl talk
follow me on instagram at luna montana
okay so starting off i got a lot of
questions about me
and how i'm doing a lot of you guys have
been noticing that i've been losing
weight you're saying
tends to change within me i think i lost
a
drastic amount of weight and i didn't
even realize that i did during my
breakup which was in
october it was a lot emotionally for me
a big lifestyle change
i just completely lost my appetite i
also just started dancing every day
for my head and my emotional being all
of that combined just
made me lose weight and i didn't even
realize that i did until people started
commenting on instagram my family
started
worrying it was a weird period but from
then till now i think i've kind of
leveled out and gained the weight back
weirdly enough and i've heard this from
a lot of people that accidentally lose
weight or whatever you get so much
praise and attention and
in that moment too of emotional distress
that i was going through like that
attention from other people
almost like validation gaining it back
like looking back and stuff like that
it's been really hard for me and it
wasn't even intentional at all
no one should ever comment on another
person's body no matter what because
what if i was going through
something during that time and i got
comments and praise and then that would
completely fuel my fire and trigger me
from then till now i've definitely
struggled with gaining that weight back
and being happy but at the end of the
day i have to remember the emotional
state that i was in at the time
mentally was not well at all i'm not one
to not have an appetite i'm a food
lover take the image off of your
physical body and just think about your
inner being and just remember that i'm
getting healthier and healthier each
month regardless of how my body looks
next question is how do i stop
sabotaging myself through social media
i feel you girl i get into like these
huge stocking
bowls stocking every single instagram la
model on instagram for hours and i come
out feeling like the slimiest version of
myself there was one time where i did
that and like i swear i
booked a lip injection appointment for
the next week like i convinced myself
i'd face to my photos i need liposuction
in my cheeks i
convinced myself that my nose was big
and i needed a nose job like genuinely
so damaging for me and i'm not one to
think like that i quickly snapped out of
it something that we have to remember
when this happens
is the person that i'm comparing myself
to on instagram that's a post photo it's
obviously a good photo of them they're
not gonna post
something where they don't look good
most likely face tuned or photoshopped
that's just the reality of it or they
have work done so i'm comparing myself
to the
idolized version of them it's just it's
getting me nowhere it's just not natural
even if that person was naturally like a
completely perfect person
every single person is beautifully
different there's something that that
girl wants that you have
vice versa for me personally i just have
to remember
like why would i want to morph myself
into that girl
who that girl is making me feel
completely insecure why would i want to
do that to other girls and i'm not i'm
not bashing on these people i'm not i'm
just saying
for me and my brand and what i've built
my youtube channel based on like
self-love and accepting yourself why
would i want to try and be this perfect
person to make others insecure like me
getting messages
from girls saying that i've helped them
feel more confident or help them with
any type of eating disorder is way more
validating and gives me purpose than
someone saying i look hot or
they wish i had my lips or whatever
that's the purpose of life
i know that that's my purpose is using
my brain and using my
knowledge and experience to help other
people and not
using my looks or like looks that i buy
to make other people feel insecure
and again i'm not hating on people that
do decide to get work done or do
anything i really am not
until a lot of people can think the same
way like society is just not gonna
change we're still gonna have these
beauty standards
so i encourage all of you guys to start
the change let's be the change together
so many of us fall into society's idea
of beauty it's not ideal it's not
natural it's not affordable
it's not something you're gonna be
remembered for when you're in your grave
you're not going to be remembered for
your huge ass lips or
your small thighs it's just not how it
is you're going to be remembered for the
effect that you had on the world your
purpose your brain
everything it's just way more important
to me that being said you guys i have
probably one of the most exciting
sponsorships i've ever gotten
something i'm super super proud to
promote which is better health so thank
you betterhelp for sponsoring this video
i'm so excited to be working with you
guys
betterhelp is an online counseling
service which is incredible it's
exactly what i would want to talk to you
guys about in this video i know for me
there are so many things interfering
with my happiness and
achieving my goals body image self love
confidence being one of them
and better help is amazing you guys so
with better help they will assess your
needs and match you with your very own
licensed professional therapist it's not
a crisis line it's not a self-help
it's a professional counseling service
done completely online there is a broad
range of expertise in betterhelps
counselor network
so you'll be matched with someone who
meets your needs and the service is
available for clients worldwide you can
log into your account anytime and send a
message to your therapist and you will
get a timely and thoughtful response you
can also schedule a video or phone calls
once a week so you won't ever have to
sit in an uncomfortable waiting room or
anything of the store it's all done from
the comfort of your own home
betterhelp is committed to facilitating
great therapeutic matches so if you're
not vibing with your counselor they make
it easy to switch
it's way more affordable than
traditional offline counseling and there
is financial aid available better help
once you start living a happier life
today
so if you're interested you will get 10
off your first month if you use my url
betterhelp.com luna that is
betterhelp.com
luna next question is how can i get a
healthy relationship with food this took
me a while
i could have never imagined like two or
three years ago when i was struggling
the most to
even think about like my friends going
to mcdonald's and like me getting
something i knew
it was a problem when socially it would
affect me so let's just put an example
of like you're at a dinner party with
friends and you're all having a big
pizza but you don't want to eat that one
piece of pizza because you're trying to
whatever diet and it's just making you
sad
for me all night i would be upset and
like staring at this one thing i'd
fixate on it
and socially everyone else was having a
good time but i wasn't just because i
didn't have a slice of pizza
think about in five years not like even
less than five years
honestly a month from now you're not
gonna remember that one piece of pizza
that you ate
quality of life the time you would have
spent with your friends like socially
you would have had a good time but you
weren't because you were so fixated on
that one thing so
intuitive eating is something that is so
important and it's one of the hardest
things to learn
i always feel a certain level of guilt
and i feel like that lives in with me
forever
one thing i really encourage you all to
try is just take the image off of your
physical body and think about your inner
being again what will make you happy
i use that example all the time but
you're gonna be laying in your grave one
day and the size of your thighs will not
mean a single thing that one piece of
pizza you ate will not mean a single
thing remember the grand scheme of life
remember your purpose what you're here
what you're set out to do
feeling guilt for eating when you're
hungry is like feeling guilt for like
breathing oxygen it's necessary to live
next question is how do you accept
weight gain so again i made a whole
video on this
but obviously being a ballerina weight
gain was always my worst nightmare
and it's weird because society's like
body beauty standard versus ballet is so
widely different like for ballet i just
never wanted a butt never wanted boobs i
wanted like no hips at all i wanted to
be square and then like and when i quit
and enter society it's a whole different
type of body image for me that was
almost in my favor because everything
that i was always fighting with my body
became like society's standard having a
butt having hips
having a waist like so in that sense i
was grateful but nevertheless
weight gain is something that's super
hard to accept i know you have to
remember that you are constantly growing
your body fluctuates like crazy
as long as you're healthy and treating
yourself right whatever shape or size
your body is
is what you were naturally made to look
like that's like your homeostasis right
if you're treating your body right
you're treating yourself you're happy
like with everything that you're doing
you're giving your body nutrients like
whatever your body looks like whether
it's this or this
that's your natural state that's
something that you can't change and
that's when you have to actually accept
what you look like that's what the
universe intended you to look like what
are some things you do that make you
feel good
physically and mentally so the number
one thing that is your homework
today that really helped me recently was
i went on instagram and i unfollowed
every single person that did not serve
me
a good purpose like i unfollowed every
single tick-tocker
model and i've never felt better i don't
know why i didn't do that earlier i only
follow people now that like inspire me
they have style inspiration other than
that i've been really trying to
self-reflect i
challenge all of you guys to write down
at least three things right now
that you absolutely love about yourself
pause the video i'll wait here
do you have them it doesn't have to be
physical here i'll do it for you right
now number one
i love that i get so excited about the
little things number two
i absolutely love my hair i love the
texture love the color number three
i absolutely love every single hardship
that i've been through in my life
and what it's taught me so that's your
homework i know it seems stupid and
ridiculous to stare at yourself in the
mirror and be like i
am worthy i am loved more and more you
keep doing it the more you're going to
start believing in it so
that is your homework how do i help
someone who's dealing with an eating
disorder
so again as a ballerina growing up in
the industry every single one of my
friends i would say
dealt with some sort of body dysmorphia
eating disorder
it's a really really hard thing to watch
i feel like for me i'm also just super
empathetic and
i feel so hopeless when i can't help
someone i do think it's important to
talk to someone just like a parent or a
counselor or a teacher or someone that
can help
i would really try and stay pretty
neutral i think commenting on someone's
body no matter what is damaging
just kind of be like i'm here to support
you no matter what you need like i want
to be here for you
i've had friends in and out of treatment
like it's a very very hard thing to
watch if you know someone that has
struggled who's
you know coming out of treatment or some
sort i know that meal times are very
very hard
so whenever those are around like try to
make it more comfortable more fun
a lot of times i feel like a burden and
it's hard when a lot of the attention's
on them especially when everyone knows
they're struggling so
try to make it more fun eat with them
always eat with them and just try to be
there and be of support as much as you
can but i know i know it's hard
my guy friends think self-love is
selfish what do i tell them they're just
saying that because they're threatened
that if you love yourself then
they'll feel lesser than so tell them
that they should try it sometime
confidence versus arrogance i really
don't think they go hand in hand because
confidence is just knowing that you are
the best version of yourself
not that you are above others because
society has already made it so hard to
love ourselves i really don't think it's
going to get that far
i don't think you have to worry between
that how to become more confident when
speaking okay this is actually probably
one of my biggest insecurities as of
late
i have found out that i'm actually
pretty shy when i meet people for the
first time and i'm
scared to say stuff and i i kind of beat
myself up over it because i feel like i
do have such a great personality and
obviously like
online i pour my heart and soul out to
you guys and i just i want people to
know my personality when i first meet
them like first impressions are huge for
me so i want people to know that i'm
like a cool person
stay so quiet because i'm so scared to
say something embarrassing or not cool
i found a tic toc that was like i'm
confident because when i speak i
simply choose not to feel embarrassed in
moments that i should be embarrassed
probably i just choose not to
so just be confident in your opinions
and your ideals and if that person
doesn't vibe with your personality or
what you're saying then like they're
lost it just doesn't click whatever
you're just delaying the process of that
if that makes sense how do i find the
difference between losing weight to be
healthy and losing weight to look
better okay so for me when i was
struggling really bad i would always use
it as an excuse that i want to eat
better to be healthier but in reality
i just wanted to lose weight it's weird
as i have quit ballet
and you know talk to normal people like
that live normal lives
it's so triggering for me to hear people
going on diets or people like
choosing not to eat bad or like whatever
because automatically my mind goes to
that but i have to remember
that you know there are situations in
which we live life
and we're not treating our bodies right
and we do need to take a step back for
example last week i was on set for a
movie
and i was on set nine to seven all five
days of the week on a movie set
they have craft services which craft
services says like doritos
chips ahoy fruit snacks stuff that i
never eat was never raised with
and i went crazy obviously i'm like
sitting on set all day and then
obviously i'm gone all day so i didn't
have time to do my normal workouts or
dance or anything so i wasn't moving
by the end of the week i literally felt
so gross i literally had pimples all
over my face i felt disgusting come the
weekend i told my trainer i was like hey
we have to grind this week like i'm
dancing every day this week and i'm
gonna eat clean and it wasn't
necessarily for my body at all
it was more for my inner being i felt
gross i didn't feel energetic
internally i wasn't feeling good again
you just have to assess your
motives and make sure that you're doing
it for the right reasons last question
how can i find myself worthy of love
again coming out of a breakup coming out
of a relationship where you
always had constant validation that you
were worthy at least for me because i
was in a healthy relationship
i ended the relationship because i
couldn't find that within myself i only
relied on outer validation from everyone
and then when i would try to find that
validation through
boys like and wouldn't get that back or
just entering this whole dating
la world like it made me completely
question my worth i did find a tick tock
and i'm gonna play it for you guys it's
selena gomez now
i have expectations where it's like if i
were to do this or if i
were to give you are you strong enough
are you capable
of being someone that's going to be in
my life
[Music]
that's how i approach things now i i and
i'm not being conceited i'm saying
it's actually an honor to be
with me because i think i'm a great
person and i
love people deeply and i won't tolerate
ever being treated the way that i had
been fox
as long as you know that you're a good
person find someone that's worthy of
that not someone that makes you question
whether you're worthy at all
each and every one of you are worthy of
love and especially worthy
of loving yourself do the things that i
tell you go and follow those people on
instagram
write down self affirmations i know it
seems hard but you have to start
somewhere you deserve to live a long
happy life
loving the body that you're living in
hopefully i could have helped at least
one of you guys out there feel a little
bit more comfortable
i know it's a long journey trust me i
struggle every single day with it
thank you for giving me the platform
that i do to be allowed to
even you know help me this helps me so
much to talk to you guys so i love you
to the moon and back
bye guys
[Music]
you