hey guys it's Karen I've been making
videos for quite a while now so I
thought I'd let you guys know some facts
about me let's start with some basic
facts as I said before my name is Karen
and it's actually spelled with an i
I am chinese-american and I was born and
raised in San Francisco my parents are
from China and if you're curious because
Chinese people love talking about where
they're from my parents are from
Guangzhou which is southern China so I
do speak Cantonese and my Cantonese is
actually pretty bad and I don't read any
Chinese I was in Chinese school for a
long time and I'm sorry mom and dad I
wasted all your money I was born and
raised in San Francisco and the only
other place I've lived in was Los
Angeles for school I mentioned earlier
that I took Chinese classes and I just
was a really bad student and didn't
retain anything there's a lot of
motorcycles outside so just to show you
how bad I am at languages but how much I
am in denial about how bad I am at
languages let me tell you about how many
languages I've studied so English is my
first language Cantonese is the next one
Mandarin because I went to Chinese
school Japanese I took in high school
for two years I think I pretty much only
cared about food for art history major
in my university you had to take five
quarters of language to fulfill your
major requirement I could have taken a
test on Japanese or Chinese but I was so
bad at both of them that there was no
way that I could pass a test so I took
two quarters of Italian and I was so bad
at Italian I was like saying random
Spanish
instead of Italian and I don't know why
because I never took Spanish I can't
take the next quarter of Italian because
I just my base was so bad right so I was
like okay go back to the drawing board
let's try a new language because that's
how my brain works so me being overly
confident about everything I do
I took an accelerated summer course on
French language 12 weeks of classes and
it's Monday to Friday 8 a.m. to noon and
you just learn French and this is
supposed to cover 3/4 which is a year's
worth of French in those 10 to 12 weeks
which is insane it was the worst idea
ever
I was lost by the first week it was it
was really rough you guys so that's the
story of how I learned 1 2 3 4 5
languages and I'm absolutely garbage in
most of them I really love traveling and
eating
hence the theme of my channel it's all
just travel and food and traveling for
food and I wish you could eat food to
travel but that doesn't work that way I
haven't actually been to a ton of places
when we were young we would do mostly
road trips because that's an affordable
way of vacationing and in California
it's great it's a very American thing to
do like leaving the country I've only
been to Canada in China when I was
little and when I grew up I began
traveling a little bit more so it
started when I went to study abroad in
France which I actually ended up doing
twice and I also have since visited
Japan and I really want to just keep
going all over the place it's my dream
is to see all of the major museums in
the world if you guys follow me on
little art talks which is an educational
YouTube channel on art in art history
that I run I am obsessed with art a lot
of people ask me how I afford to travel
so much and the funny thing is I'm
actually not travelling most of the time
I do have a lot of vlog footage that is
edited and posted after the fact so when
I'm done traveling I'll come back and
slowly edit a lot of video I saw a lot
of footage from Japan that I never
edited when I'm not traveling I do have
a not a regular job I do have a job I
co-founded a company with my sister
called Arden Cove where we make bags and
backpacks and our newest bag is a travel
bag because of what I do on this channel
it's kind of perfect its anti-theft and
waterproof and it's going to be launched
on any gogo in October so I've been
super busy preparing for that if you
want to check it out however to arden
koat.com and sign up for our mailing
list so you'll be notified when the
IndieGoGo is up I'm definitely the type
of person who has a few but very good
close friends I'm not a very outgoing I
hmm
I am kind of outgoing but not super
outgoing and I'm definitely an introvert
my myers-briggs personality type is int
P which apparently in Star Wars
Myer Briggs it's Yoda cuz yeah I really
love I have like a lot of different
notebooks and they're each for like a
different thing so I have one for this
vlog channel I have one for a little art
talks I have one for art and Cove I got
like my only camera when I
in elementary school too and it was just
like a regular point-and-shoot and back
then it was a film camera I would like
get my mom to buy rolls of film so that
I could use my look dinky little pointed
shoe but I would always use it indoors
instead of like outside and I wouldn't
use flash when I needed to use flash so
I just had tons and tons of pictures of
like just blackness I think at some
point my mom just refused to buy me more
film because she was like you're just
wasting all this money everything
changed when I got my first digital
camera which was in high school so I got
my own camera that I got to like carry
around I would bring it to school I
would carry it everywhere with me it
probably wasn't a good idea because I
couldn't have been robbed I've always
been a pretty like tech savvy person
even when I was a kid I learned you know
HTML and my own because I thought it was
cool to like decorate like stupid little
websites I did all sorts of weird things
I really like listening to music even
though I don't know a ton about music
I'll list some artists that I like and
if you guys know what they are you can
give me some recommendations of music
and that would be really fun you know
when you're a kid and they always asked
you what do you want to be when you grow
up and you have to like fill out some
paper and tell people when I grow up I
wanna be blah blah I would always say I
wanted to be a teacher I thought I would
grow up and be like my mom who was a
payroll accountant and that would have
been a really bad idea because I'm so
bad with numbers I always say teacher
because I liked teachers and I liked the
idea of being a veterinarian because I
liked dogs and cats but I always say
teacher because I knew how to spell
teacher which was way easier to spelled
in veterinarian my worst subjects in
school were spell
and arithmetic I'm very good at like
understanding concepts and applying
concepts but memorizing things are
really hard for me especially numbers so
fun fact I never memorized the
multiplication table like my parents
made my sister memorize the
multiplication table like they would
quiz her like with many things they got
to me and they're like I already did it
once with your older sister she figured
it out you'll be fine and I took a lot
of math classes like I wasn't bad at
math like in terms of grades which is
the craziest thing my favorite class in
high school was probably biology another
funny story about me as a kid is that as
someone who is very passionate about
education like I run an educational
youtube channel I was not a good student
for most of my life like probably not
until high school and that is a lot
because I daydreamed a ton in elementary
and middle school I just could not pay
attention at all I would just be like
off in my own little bubble I would
forget like homework assignments I would
just like not even know they existed
because I was daydreaming when the
teacher was talking about it I've never
broken any bones
knock on wood but I have twisted my
ankle twice and I'm pretty sure it's
been the same ankle I suffer from
migraine and I actually get ocular
migraines as well which basically it's
like when you get little white spots
like halos in your vision and some
people only get one or the other but I
get both which is really fun I'm
definitely a morning person the one
thing I need to wear every day is
sunscreen I studied abroad twice both
times in France but in different parts
of France so the first program was in LA
Nepal which is this
in Krita France by the French Riviera it
was beautiful by the beach we lived in a
freaking castle and then part of the
program was in parents and then I did
another program that was in sort of the
middle of nowhere a countryside of
France and I just painted and drew all
day every day that summer everything we
made we made about four hundred and
fifty things I think someone counted and
we picked out like a handful of our
favorites shipped them back to America
and burned the rest of them in a bonfire
yep
it was amazing a lot of times in my
videos I'm quite positive and happy and
smiley but I'm actually quite not not
really a cynical person but I'm quite a
sarcastic in in real life with my
friends so a lot of times I'll say kind
of harsh things knowing that they're
kind of harsh and I play off of that and
it's just my sense of humor so let's
talk about college for a while first of
all I'm 25 years old so I'm a couple
years out of college already I went to
UCLA I was a double major in fine arts
in art history I don't have a driver's
license which is actually kind of a
stereotypical San Francisco thing I have
taken the written test actually twice
now and I just haven't taken the test to
actually get my license maybe it will
happen this year I actually never
learned how to ride a bike either and
that's just another thing that my
parents taught my sister I never taught
me I only have one sister by the way
she's three years older if you've seen
my other videos you've seen her in my
videos and she is one of my best friends
she's amazing
I work with her obviously but I really
respect her and you know all throughout
life I actually owe a lot to my sister
because she is so smart and driven and
dedicated and giving and everything like
that um she has taken care of me a lot
when I was younger and even now I said
before I wasn't a really good student
until high school a lot of the reason
why I became a better student is because
of my sister my sister was a very good
student she was like straight A's
everything so when I reached high school
my goal in high school was to just be
the same if not better but like
especially just the same as my sister
and because I was just determined to
like be like not worse than my sister I
ended up having good grades and ended up
doing like pretty well in school and
going to a good school and stuff like
that so it's all because of you Carmen
can one of my facts be that I'm an
auntie because I kind of love being an
auntie when I was younger I was like I
don't know if I really like kids like
I've tutored kids a lot when I was
younger my experiences have always been
kind of mediocre which is why I'm like
not a teacher I would not be a good
teacher but since I've become abouty
like I was like oh yeah this kids not
too bad
it's just kind of hilarious being at
Auntie and like the best part is that I
can like just play with her as much as I
want you and then when she starts
getting Stassi I give her back to her
mom
I'm really freaking like just love
eating which if you can't tell from this
channel I just really freaking love to
eat like everything I'm not a very picky
eater there's only a few things I don't
really prefer but even if I don't prefer
them I would still eat them if I'm with
someone who is not a very adventurous
Peter I am that annoying person who will
be like you should try this you should
try this yep like this is this is so
crazy like you should try this part of
us because I want to share things I like
and like give them this new experience I
think is really exciting and part of it
is because I'm like making fun of them
for like having very arbitrary things
they don't like but if I like something
like I want to share things I love with
people I care about so it comes from a
place of love okay if I could only eat
one food for the rest of my life for all
of my meals it would be sushi and
viewers of my other videos now I say
sushi a lot instead of sushi or sushi
I'm working on that I've thought about
this because sushi you can eat for
breakfast lunch and dinner and it's not
super savory or super sweet sushi is
always just good you know I love that
you guys love sheshe too like my most
popular videos are my sushi videos and I
love that you guys love it because
honestly like now I can just have an
excuse to eat sushi all the time and
like video tape at all I'll be like this
is for people like people who want to
see this
my ultimate cheater answer for that
though would be like noodles soup and
just like be very general so that I
could eat all the noodle soups like I
can eat chicken noodle soup but also
like thaw and all the Chinese noodle
suits like 110 noodle soup and all the
Korean jumped like all of them if I were
to break up this question this is so me
I'm going to use all my facts on food if
you can only eat one breakfast one lunch
and one dinner
and one dessert what would you pick
lunch and dinner I don't really know
what the difference would be so maybe
that should just be sushi but breakfast
I could eat like avocado toast maybe
with some other things on top every day
I love avocado so much moly is so good I
really like ice cream but I can't eat it
a ton I am slightly lactose intolerant
so I try not to eat too much dairy but
you know ice cream is worth it I really
love macaroons
whatever however you say those things I
mean you like French pastry is so good I
would like have one every morning when I
was staying abroad or every afternoon
I'm not actually sure how many facts
that is cuz I wasn't keeping track I'm
gonna edit this video and count how many
facts that is and then do another video
to continue on to 50 because I have been
filming for ages and I can't think of
any more facts Oh
this video was fun for you guys ask me
any questions if you have any questions
and then I'll film a pret two onwards
250 and I'll see you guys next time