hey guys it's Karen's I've done a couple
videos about traveling now and a lot of
them have to do with safety I've talked
about common ways that leaves steal from
purses and also tips on how to stay safe
when traveling alone safety is
definitely one of the things on the top
of my mind when traveling and obviously
because I've also made a whole purse
dedicated to safety these are the
anti-theft waterproof crossbodies that
I've designed for Arden Cove and they're
launching on IndieGoGo if you're
interested in checking it out safety is
definitely at the top of my priority
list when traveling or even at home
living in a city but of course you
should have a ton of fun too so here are
my top tips of how to have a successful
solo trip my first tip is to have a copy
of your passport and very important
information you should have one copy for
your purse and then one copy for your
suitcase in case you lose your purse
hopefully you watch my video of how to
protect your purse so that you don't run
into a situation but just in case number
two is pretty obvious do what you want
to do you don't have a friend or family
member to accommodate to you don't have
to consider what they like or their
feelings about certain things so if you
are a huge space nerd you can go to the
planetarium and spend the whole day
there if you wanted to take this time to
do whatever you want to do and if that
means sleeping in until 11am hey guess
what you can because it's your vacation
you do you number three it's okay to not
do everything I know you're spending a
lot of money and you want to get the
most out of this trip but it's
impossible to do every single little
thing and if you end up over packing
your schedule you might end up not
enjoying your trip as much and so
instead I would suggest to prioritize
what you want to do don't overschedule
things if you end up having some extra
time you can do the next thing on the
list or you can just play it by ear and
wander around number four walk as much
as possible it's the best way to explore
the city and you'll bump into things
that you wouldn't have bumped into
otherwise
and you might find some really cool
stuff of course public transit is also
great when it's too far to walk number
five pack light if you see my packing
videos you know that i carry only one
back one possible i'll do carry on only
and it's great i don't have to check in
my bag I know I can carry everything
myself and toss it into the overhead bin
myself and it's also easy to navigate
the streets when I arrived so that I'm
not lugging my luggage around trying to
navigate the streets to the hotel during
the day I love traveling with cross
bodies especially our own obviously it's
great because it's hands-free and it has
security features and it's waterproof
it's ideal for traveling and really
comfortable so you don't carry too much
around the full size is great for days
when I'm going to be spending a lot of
time on trains so I can carry a kindle
with me a little novel or a journal the
mini is great when I'm on the move all
did because it's so small it's going to
not be in my way but it's big enough to
carry all of my essentials my sunglasses
my camera my portable charger my cell
phone and then obviously cards and keys
and that's all I need and it's perfect
number six is one how to be a smart
traveler as I said before I have a
couple videos on this and i highly
recommend that you check them out even
if it's not my own videos check out some
other videos or articles online so that
you're educated informed I don't want
you to be scared don't be afraid of solo
travel but definitely be educated stay
informed number seven is to meet new
people i know i just said to be safe and
everything like that being safe doesn't
mean being afraid of people you should
be afraid of certain people but not
afraid of everyone but if you're smart
about it meeting new people can be
perfectly safe and often very rewarding
if their local you can learn so much
about the place you're staying and they
can give you great recommendations if
their fellow travelers you can talk
about what you guys are doing and if
there's common interests you can
actually link up and make a group
because sometimes there's group
discounts for things which is really
nice and of course you make new friends
so it's great number eight is Larry
how to enjoy being alone and getting to
know yourself I know that sounds a
little bit silly because of course you
know yourself but when you're traveling
alone you're spending a lot of time by
yourself you're going to learn pretty
quickly your strengths and your
weaknesses what you're comfortable with
and what you're uncomfortable with for
example you might be just fine walking
around during the day by yourself but
you're actually not as comfortable
eating alone at a restaurant by yourself
in those cases I challenge you to face
those uncomfortable moments for example
if you don't like eating alone at a
restaurant to try it out and see how you
like it maybe after a couple of times
you end up really enjoying it you spend
more time actually tasting the food or
you do more people watching and enjoy
the scenery you might even end up
talking to the person at the table next
to you so it can be a really cool
experience that you might have not
challenged yourself to do otherwise so
the final thing I want to leave you guys
with is remember it's okay if something
goes wrong you can only try to deal with
a bad situation as best as you can and
then move on that being said some
unfortunate situations are preventable
such as picking a purse that it be will
not steal from you or at least make it
harder for the thief to steal from you
if you want to check out our anti-theft
waterproof crossbody we are on IndieGoGo
check out the link in the description
bar on how to get your very own I want
to leave off with the question for you
guys what are your best tips for a
successful solo trip I love to hear your
answer in a comment down below thanks so
much for watching I hope you guys
enjoyed it and I'll see you guys next
time
you