Hey guys, welcome back
So I recently asked you guys on my Instagram if you had any questions for me regarding college life after college
Finding a job career anything that had to do with school and graduation and there's over there's a good amount of questions
I typed out a hundred questions and I try to get them down to about
thirty
Maybe a little more. I broke them down into five sections
the first one will be about
Context and background about my experience when I majored in what school I went to what grades I got
I think grades are important and then the second section will be
Finding your thing or like finding your purpose finding your career
slash calling and then we'll talk about life post-grad my current career path
Which is mostly YouTube and media and the last section will be about life advices in general. So
Yeah, there's a lot of questions gonna try to get through them ASAP. And so let's get started
Thank you so much Skillshare for sponsoring this video
They're my favorite online learning community and you guys up and around you will know this by now
they're as always offering the first five hundred people a two month free trial against this a little bit later and
Let's start it
How does she know what you wanted to do I had no idea what I wanted to do graduating from college
I had no idea. I would be sitting here five years later
Making a video about my college experience. What was your major in college? What made you choose?
I majored in business and then I chose that because
It could double in a lot of things within business because there's marketing there's finance. There's accounting
there's so many things within business out allowed for
Flexibility for me to choose and for me to figure out as I go. How to be happy when you're in a university,
which is in your dream university? you can always transfer the only colleges
That I got into after high school were state colleges in California. Saw the Cal States and UC Riverside. I
Went to UC Riverside because that was the best option and they gave me a decent amount of scholarship
I knew going in like this is the most important part I knew going and I was going to sir
Regardless if it was one year two year three years. I was going to transfer to either a butter. You see better you see
UCLA UC Berkeley or I was in a transferred to USC and thankfully everything worked out within one year so as with anything in life
If there's a way if there's a will if there's a will there's a way you have to peel
Did you work during school and if so, how did you find balance?
I worked every summer starting from my junior year of high school. It's you know year of college. I was working
While I was going to school so I stacked there's something here that wants to come out
But it's not coming out. I stuck to my classes on Tuesdays and Thursdays. So it's from like 8 a.m. To 4 p.m
Or 6 p.m. All day
I packed back-to-back classes so that Monday Wednesdays and Fridays I could work and I was working at a social media agency. Are grades
important? and we stress about getting good grades so much that we don't live in the moment
This is tricky. I want to say no
But it's also a yes because it really depends on what you want to do after you graduate the internships that I have one was
out of granola bar company called this bar same size for every bar that you I they will give a
Life-saving bar to a kid in need. It's kind of like palm a for-profit before good one for one model
So I worked out companies like that
Most of my other friends are going to consulting and us my making
Because those are like the legit jobs and when you were in a hyper-competitive environment
Where everyone's studying business and I was in a business fraternity
you kind of get tunnel vision and you just want to be the best and that's kind of what the best things were but I
Was like I'm just gonna do me even if people think I'm not as legit, which they did
They thought I was in legit because I didn't have a fancy job
But I was like I just gonna do me someone I wanna be happy grand scheme of things
I don't think grades matter at all because the fact that we're alive and that we're breathing and that we were born
It's like a one thing a billionth chance. So why limit ourselves and wide to find ourselves by grades?
but then again
If you know a career want and grades are important then increase are important
Do you have good grades in university? I graduated with barely a 3.0. I think I had a 3.0 one or three
So no, but I'm proud of myself for graduating with a third point above a 3.0 GPA
How do you stay happy in college through all of this stress? so I say happy through
Drinking and partying and going to raves and having fun with my friends and I put more emphasis on that
Than I did on my studies
but the thing is I kind of shot myself in the foot because I wasn't even happy when I was doing that I was
Doing that because I was avoiding reality. I was avoiding my responsibility some of the thoughts in my head and I was avoiding myself
I was avoid facing myself. So what I
Wish this upon anyone else
I don't think so
But I would say that I think it's so important to enjoy our youths. I don't regret anything I did because now
That I'm here
I'm like, okay been there done that never want to be there again
But I know what it's like so I think it's important that omits airing yourself in books and studying
To your head out every once in a while. Oh, wow. Have fun with your friends go
Enjoy being a teen or like a 20-something year old because we're never gonna get that back the older you get the more
Responsibilities you have and I guess on that note if I could do it all over again
I would spend more time getting to know myself for sure
I didn't know how to do it back then looking inward reflecting asking myself the hard questions so that I'm not just like
Avoiding and running away all the time and also to not take office hours professors
School like offerings like our school or universities. There's so many resources that I just completely like I didn't care most important thing
I took for granted was the proximity and which I lived with my friends now. I'm in New York
most of my friends are in San Francisco or LA so it's like
You can't really you know
I suck at keeping in touch the phones and messages like I'm really good with people when I'm like face-to-face, but I'm terrible with
Keeping up with people. They're texting
so that's something I'm working on but
That's that. How to be mindful over your future rather than let fear of it stress you out?
So I'm reading this really great book called 10% happier, and I'm gonna quote "starving is fine
as long as is tempered by the
Realization that in entropic universe the final outcome is out of your control if you don't waste your energy on variables you cannot influence
You can focus much more effectively on those you can when you're wisely ambitious you do everything you can to succeed
But you're not attached to the outcome either
this is the most important you're not attached to the outcome so that if you fail you will be
Maximally resilient able to get up dust yourself off and get back in the fray"
Do you believe in 5-year plans or do you think you should take life as a hits yet?
So I was firm believer in the five-year plan in the one three five and ten-year plan. That was
Textbook Rowena, but over the years, especially when I started YouTube. I just realized that
Life is constantly changing cuz you want to control it. You can so I've learned to accept and embrace uncertainty as
My reality instead of trying to line everything down to the T because no matter how much you plan
Things are gonna happen
Things aren't gonna go according to plan
Historically. I've been a very J like a hardcore J from the myers-briggs like judgment
document pull
Something with the J. I've learned to become more perceiving. I've learned to become more go with the flow take life as it comes
Like enjoy the breeze and not to be so, you know with planning
So yeah, I think I'm more of the latter now take life as it hits. Yeah
That made me giggle. Okay. What can I do to support my bestie who is in college and horribly burnt out
No
I'd say kidnap your bestie to go on a BFF date and
If she's like I cannot leave my studies for more than X amount of time then just take her to grab food
Get her mind off of her studies when you're so in something
You need to be peeled out and peeled off and I think in retrospect
Me and all my friends as much as we might have not like do the moment
You're like ripping us away from our studies in the long run
It was like thank you think now looking back instead of like thank you for looking out for me
What do I do if I can't find a purpose right after school? I'm scared of becoming stagnant. The thing with finding your purpose
I was a solution when I thought that after I found my purpose my life would just be smooth sailing
Now you will find your purpose and then you'll be tested again and you'll kind of forget and you'll find it again and they'll kind
Of lose it again and they kind of find it again. I mean that's just life
We as humans are constantly changing and growing so our North Star
May be implanted in the sky for the foreseeable future, but the closer you get to it
You might be able to see it from a different perspective
so
Although your North Star doesn't change you're constantly changing and the way in which you get to that North Star or let fall of that
North Star may also change this wall. So I think what's most important is to never stop learning always stay curious with a growth mindset
you can't go wrong and you won't be stagnant because if you're always
Willing to learn if you're always questioning if you're always curious about the world around you
That's the recipe for not staying stagnant a few ways that I've continued to learn after I graduated
One is through reading. I love business and self-help books and I just recently got into more like fiction books
I think sometimes are too wild and crazy' for me
But it is great to let your mind explore and implant your brain into different
Universes every once in a while. And another way is through online courses like Skillshare
So Skillshare is an online learning community with over 25,000 classes and design business
Creativity anything arts you can think of how to edit videos how to paint
There's actually a course on there that I want to share with you guys
It's called Discovering success 7 exercises to uncover your purpose passion and hat
I think this is great for anyone who is kind of like what do I do?
I kind of have this creative thing that I want to do, but there's also this like more stable
Financially sound path that I want to walk like which path do I take?
She does a really good job of breaking everything down and I talked about these things in my older videos
but never end up like this, so it's like redefining what success means to you breaking free of
Going back to the beginning
Listening to what you love choosing a direction managing your time money strategies
so I think all of these are really
Important things and topics there's not as many crash courses on this like you don't learn about these things in school
This is something you're interested in the first 500 people will get a two-month premium
Membership trouble which will give you access to all of the courses on Skillshare. So
there's that
Moving on I got rejected from nursing school three times that I don't know what to do from here. Do I change paths? I
Think this comes down to how badly do you want to be a nurse?
If you know it is your life's calling if you know
I must be a nurse because you love helping people and you want to help save lives then
Keep applying and don't take no for an answer
And I think this is with anything in life any job that you're thinking of if you want something badly enough. You're gonna keep
Trying until you get it. Yes, but if you ask yourself and you're like
I think I want to be a nurse because
It's what is expected of me or it's what I thought I should do because of something other than what you wanted to do for
Yourself then maybe
Maybe it's a sign from the universe that you should pivot but these answers only we will know when we spend the quiet hours
with our own thoughts
Late at night or early in the mornings when you're just questioning everything
Okay. Advice on choosing the career you want versus the career that pays better? it's tough
So there's two things. The first thing I would say is the career that pays well is like a steady
Pay right and the baby by the time you're 60
You're like here the career that you want may not pay well in the beginning. There's three years five years. You might be making nothing
But the potential of it growing
Exponentially is a lot more than that like stable career path
Or there's a lot more potential and possibility for it to grow
So that's the first thing question that I ask myself is long-term fulfillment versus short-term satisfaction
I think a stable career path definitely falls into short-term satisfaction because you don't really have to think about most things and you
Have your life planned out for you long-term for fulfillment?
If you're gonna eventually do what you want to do, which is what I think most rational humans go through
That's why we have midlife crises
Where we doubt everything and we question everything and we look back and like why did I live my life for the past?
Five decades like this when it's not what I wanted to do or it's not who I am what really helped me
Stay true to my path and to not waver when I wave I wavered a lot actually
But what helped me stay grounded was that if you're going to go down this path eventually
Might as well go down went now how to stay positive when others are doubting my next steps?
I really think it's self-awareness. If you know yourself well enough, you know what you're doing if you know why you're doing what you're doing
Which can change?
and which can be
Cloudy at times, but if you have a decent enough understanding, it'll allow you to
Not care as much about what others say or tell you
But that being said it's good to it's good to listen
To what other people are saying and it's good to listen to their advices whether you take it or not. It's fully up to yourself
Okay. Advice for graduates who've decided to take creative and unconventional paths?
I don't know why that was so choppy and what I was just reading it
I think the hardest part is over taking that leap of faith leaving in yourself and
Working through all the knots and a mess in your head to be like, I'm gonna do this. So keep doing it
But also remember if you have to pivot and change your course and change your path as you walk this path
It's not failure, right? You're not failing
if you didn't do the thing you set out to do I think life is a continual process of
iterations and pivoting and
changing and I've always thought a path is like this but I think life is actually more like this and sometimes like
You know
Okay, what helped you find your purpose and how did you know that you found it? This question is gonna take way too long
I'll link to videos down below
I mean I hate when people do this because like just told me no
But seriously I have other videos one is about I created my dream job and the second is how I found my life purpose
So those two will be linked down below below how many years passed after graduation when you were content with your place and life
so I was content the day I graduated I was so happy the day I graduated I was like
Yes, I don't know school wasn't really for me. I don't really learn in that like school environment
I wasn't good at taking tests
I didn't let that define me too much because I knew I had strengths outside of taking tests
but when I
Finally felt like I could breathe and that I could look at myself in the mirror and tell myself you did
Well, Romina child, you did well
It was actually earlier this year
Most difficult adjustment you had to make going into life post graduation. I think the most
Difficult thing I think it's not comparing myself to those around me because the path that I chose for myself was very different
It wasn't what other people were doing
And it's so easy to look around me and to be like all of my friends already started working all my friends
Are you started making money all my friends?
They're doing the things already and it just felt like I was gonna fall behind
I already fell behind because I didn't go down that path but then I just kept reminding myself the whole
short-term satisfaction versus long-term game short-term satisfaction would have been to that my ego and to
Do what? I thought I should do a I knew long-term
That was gonna make me happy. What do you wish you had done in your final year to prepare you for life after graduation?
I think going back to what I said earlier. I wish I spent more time in here like trying to work out
this and like this and being a better friend to myself and trying to get to know myself better because
I did a lot of that after graduating, but if I started doing that in college
I think that would have helped a lot a lot has graduation helped define you as a person and what success means to you?
has graduation helped define you as a person, uh
Not really. I feel like I don't really talk about
USC
at all after
Graduating I realized I like found my definition of success and it definitely wasn't my grades
It wasn't the fact that I graduated
It wasn't the job that I would get nothing success to me at that time was just being able to find
The answer to what it means to live a meaningful and fulfilling life
I think that was what my definition was of success at that time
And it's constantly changing
I think now for me talks about this in my podcast with Eileen from lab and dare
I think success to me now me it just means like being able to go to sleep at night content with
how the day went I mean it's very like there's a lot of layers to that and
Me being able to go to sick content is that I did my best and everything that I could during the day for work
by helping people because my work is trying to help people in many different ways either through
Beauty within, or through my own personal channel
so there's a lot of layers to that by think at the end of the day like the our definition of success should
Be defined by ourselves, and it's normal if it changes over time
Because we're constantly changing as people
ever felt lost
Professionally post-college. If so, how did you deal slash break out of it? Yeah, dude
I felt professionally lost up until I'd say last year. So I graduated 2014
2014 to 15 16 17 18. Four years
Four years, I was like, what am I doing with my life? Did I make the right decisions? Why am I here?
What is the right path is there even a right path? And the answer I talked about in last week's video
I don't really think there is a right path. I think our path is a culmination of the decisions
We've made in our lives and eventually
It like it's there already
if you believe in fate if you believe in destiny like our path is there we just need to walk it and if so,
How did you deal?
Break out of it. Just have to keep walking. Even if it's blind faith
Even if it's with mustering
every ounce of courage you have in the depths of your soul - just like trust yourself and trust the universe to move forward and
It goes back to learning
staying curious
Trying your best and not being attached to the end results how difficult was it to move to New York City. Did you do it alone?
It wasn't difficult at all. And yes, I did it alone
How long did it take to fully transition from moving across the country to New York? I did
because I moved around so often when I was young it just like it wasn't a thing
I just knew I needed I want it to be in New York. And so I just went and I just
Lived and I it just kind of happened
Did you want to continue studying to avoid working?
Absolutely not. I hated studying. I couldn't wait to graduate from high school college
I think I had more fun. But I also know that I don't like studying at all
All right. Now we're gonna move to career /youtube.
I Think I'll do a separate video answering your guys's questions about YouTube starting YouTube wanting to start YouTube advice for starting YouTube
But this one is a little it's a little more broad
How do you decide what to do in life as a career when you're not sure. What do you enjoy?
I think just constant forward movement or just constant movement. It could be lateral. It could be vertical
it could be any type of movement but as long as you're trying as long as you're actively
Engaging yourself and everything in you to try new things
You will find your thing eventually when I graduated. I thought I was gonna start my own business that didn't happen
We can just say it failed. I thought I was gonna code cuz I love text startup
So I was like I could do that UX UI that seems really cool. But like that also didn't really go anywhere because I couldn't
Like I just I can
like the coding language just
Symbols and numbers just they didn't work with me and my neighbor's dog is just right outside. So if I hear the dog barking
went into media work never in a million years what I thought I would work in journalism or at a media company because
My focus was very a tech and business and then started my youtube channel and start helping on beauty within
It just kind of all came together as I like progressed in life
and there are this whole journey
it was a lot of a
Lot of wavering a lot of back-and-forth a lot of doubting a lot of questioning of what it's the right path
What is the right thing to do? That's why I said it or a little that there really is no right path
Just keep walking and keep believing in yourself. Keep questioning yourself, like healthily questioning yourself
I'm reminding yourself of who you are and what you're doing. Why are you doing what you're doing?
And then eventually the path will reveal itself as it did with me
Yeah, when should I really start applying for jobs?
This is really up to you
if you want advice as a Marshall School graduate
You would start your sophomore year of
college applying for internships because that's how competitive people are nowadays you get an internship sophomore junior year at a
Big firm, they will most likely give you an offer when you graduate your senior year
But if you ask Rowena Rowena, when's the best time to apply for college?
It's up to you. Maybe you don't want to apply to jobs. Maybe you do want to apply to jobs
What jobs do you want to apply for? I think those are questions that only we'll be able to answer for yourself
Do companies actually prefer someone with a college degree for a job in your industry
So I think it depends if you want to work on like the agency side
I think it helps to have a degree
To ten extent most corporations do look at your as a man
They kind of do care what that like you went to college at least
But what I am doing right now
Like as a creator you can have zero degree and you can create content anyone can create content
How to find work in the media industry when it's so competitive
So I think with this it's it doesn't matter if it's media
It doesn't matter what industry that you're going for
I think going back to the whole Dyson analogy of if you want something badly enough
You won't stop until you get a yes
and one thing that I was actually pretty surprised to find was that you can
Use your student card so hard so reach out to ten people on LinkedIn
who has a job that you might be interested in and ask for an informational interview and
What this means is that you can just ask them about their career ask them about
Their life their path how they got there and you'd be surprised at least two out of ten. People will say yes to you
It's a natural human instinct to want to help other people if you reach out as a student and you say like hey
I'm not really sure what I want to do with my life
Maybe you don't say that'd be a little more professional
but if you allude to that then the person reading it like a professional reading that would be like, oh
I remember what it was like when I graduated so like yes, yes. Yes
I will help you asking people who already there for their thoughts and their advice
that's really probably like the best way to go and
Also send your resume to as many people as you can don't be afraid of being annoying message recruiters
Keep in touch with recruiters
There's a lot that you can do go to career fairs get to know the recruiters from different companies that you want to work at
There's a lot yeah not being afraid of getting no and also not being afraid of being
mildly moderately annoying persistence for the most part will always work in your favor and
moving on to the last section of life advice
What are lessons you've learned in college that you still value today?
What did I learn in college ?
I Think I learned a lot about what I don't want to do and how I don't want to feel yeah
I think that's probably the biggest takeaway how lost and how
Alone and how down I felt it's really good gauge for me to never return to that
lifestyle and that
Stage of my life the partying the drinking the avoiding the running away the not facing myself not facing my reality
yeah, I think that's probably the biggest takeaway one piece of advice you give yourself if you went back in time to
Everything that I say will probably be very cliche, but I think the most important thing would be
You're not alone
Everything will work out
don't stop dreaming and
Keep fighting for what you believe in. Yeah, I think those are like the four most important things
Yeah
This is why my channel do this if I can help
Even one you guys for less alone and less crazy
for dreaming the way you dream and for wanting to do the things that want to do then I've
succeeded
Navigating life is never easy
finding your purpose is never easy finding your I is never easy and it's it's the most difficult because it's something that we have to
Do and we can only do?
On our own but we don't have to as in like the answers you will find yourself and it's like it's very personal
But the journey you don't have to go through that alone. And I think that's what I learned few years after I graduated so
with all of that
I hope this video was helpful and that you guys got something out of it
And if you have any questions, feel free to leave it down below
I'll do my best to answer to as many of the comments as I can and even if you guys
Read comments that you feel like you can answer or help each other by all means please do this is why?
We have such a beautiful community because you guys do help each other when you see it
So with that
Thank you guys so much for watching and thanks again to Skillshare for sponsoring this video if you want to continue learning if you want
To continue growing they're a great resource. And with that see you guys in next week's video. Byee!!
Also, follow me on Instagram if you want to ask questions like this, okay. Bye!!!