okay here we go
hey guys and welcome to my college Q&A
video in this video I am basically going
to be answering every question that I
had as a freshman and throughout college
to figure out how I can make the most of
my time at college specifically
academically so that I could get a job
after I graduate so now that I have
officially been a college graduate as of
one-week commencement was supposed to be
one week ago today and I'm now living in
Portland with my first full-time job but
getting a jumpstart on my career I
thought that it was time to do this Q&A
so I asked all of you guys on Instagram
to send me all of your questions about
college
resumes networking interview tips and
just how to get a job because that is
usually everyone's number one goal after
college so you guys sent me so many
amazing questions I actually am going to
be splitting them up into two different
videos so this video is specifically
talking about my college experience and
what I did in college and then like in
the last term coming up to graduation to
get a job and then in the next video
we'll be going more in depth about
actual like job application processes
interview tips in-depth networking
advice but I'm going to be talking more
generally about all of those things - in
this video so because this video might
get a little lengthy and you all might
be here for different types of college
advice I did include all of the time
stamps in the description box down below
to every question that I'm answering so
feel free and open that up jump around
to the different questions that you want
to hear answers to and hopefully that
makes it a little bit easier for you to
watch so with all of that being said I
do just want to introduce myself if any
of you are new here so that you know
where I'm coming from in this video and
my college experience so I just
graduated from Oregon State University
with an honors Bachelors of Science in
merchandising management a lot of words
and I got my first full-time job three
months before I graduated from college
as so
show media and marketing manager for a
local fitness apparel company now social
media and marketing manager doesn't
exactly fall under the umbrella of
merchandising management majors however
that was exactly what I wanted to go
into and you guys will see as you watch
this video that I kind of had my own
pivot during college and ended up going
the social media route anyways now that
you guys know a little bit about me I
would love if you followed along on my
Instagram at its Marissa underscore Kay
I post a bunch of everyday elevated
style inspiration on there
just little bits of my life as well so
with that I hope you guys enjoyed this
video and let's just get into the
questions I also just wanted to say
before we jump into this video you guys
can probably tell from my major but I
did major in business and fashion so my
college experience is coming from that
background and I went into marketing so
if that's an industry that you're
interested in a lot of this advice will
be super applicable and I will be
answering a question at the end
specifically about marketing and social
media marketing
I just wanted to preface my video with
that before I get into the questions
because I'm sure that the college
experience and career path of a business
student is very different than someone
going to school for like nursing to be a
doctor an engineer whatever it is but I
will try and keep my advice as
applicable in general as possible no
matter what you're thinking of going to
college for okay so I did write out all
the questions in a Google Doc and
they're sitting on my laptop right
behind this camera to make sure that I
stay on track with everything so if you
see me looking over there that's why and
question number one that I'm going to be
answering is how do you choose your
major when you don't know what you want
to be yet and I'll just breakfast this
by saying this is a question that I
think goes through almost every single
student's mind whether you're in high
school or in college or you're even
graduating in your life I got this major
and I still don't know what the heck I'm
going to be doing with it so you are not
alone in your decision and in your
struggles it's something that we all go
through so I think at the core if you're
struggling to figure out what you want
to major in you should think about two
different things
what you enjoy doing and what you're
good at because I do think like to put
it the most simply everyone's goal is to
major in something and have that kind of
be a segue into what they're going to do
after college and obviously you want
your career to be something that you're
interested in that you enjoy and that
you're good at I think that's not like
the base where you want to start and
trying to figure out what you want your
major to be and then as far as like
actionable things that you can do to
figure out what you're going to major in
I started by taking elective classes in
high school and then also throughout
college to figure out what I wanted to
do so my high school offered a variety
of elective classes if you were
interested in like computer science you
wanted to be an EMT childhood
development business law so I think
taking an introductory class to a
certain type of like industry or career
is a really good place to start while
you're in school and college offers all
sorts of classes like that - like
introduction to global health or
introduction to business management
something like that also if you don't
want to make a total commitment to
taking a full class to figure out what
you want to major in you can always join
student clubs or extracurriculars to
help you explore certain job paths or
industry as well something else I did
because I'm such a planner and I like to
get as much information as possible when
I was trying to figure out what I wanted
to major in I actually just read through
all of the different undergraduate
degrees and majors on University
websites and on those pages usually the
university will give like a complete
list of what types of classes you're
going to be taking to get that degree
and what types of jobs are expected for
someone who graduates with that major
okay and then one more actionable thing
you can do to figure out what you want
to major in is job shadowing and
informational interviews if there is
anyone in your network or anyone you can
reach out to who is currently working in
a position or industry that you're
interested in being able to even have a
30-minute phone conversation with them
or go and meet up with them for coffee
or lunch and just pick their brain a
little bit about what they do in their
job why they like it kind of
realities of the workplace I think that
is a great place to start and actually
here like firsthand from someone in the
workforce what it's like to be working
in that job and if they've been in the
industry for a while I don't think
probably also have some academic advice
for you too for the best academic path
that you can take to get that job so I
know choosing your major is like what
keeps a lot of students up at night
having this like quarter life crisis of
what the heck am I going to major how am
I supposed to choose what I want to do
for the rest of my life when I'm 20
years old like I have student debt I
don't even have a full-time job and like
it's it's just a lot and it can be
really overwhelming so what I wanted to
make sure I included it's kind of the
perspective that I picked up throughout
college and I've taken with me into my
career that really helped ease my mind
in figuring out what I wanted to do in
college so to me I see college and my
major is just a start and a launchpad
into my career I would look at your
major as an opportunity to learn as much
as you can about a topic and explore
something that you're interested in and
look at it as something to kickstart
your career that does not mean that what
you're going to major in is like the
end-all be-all fate of your career and
what you're going to be doing for the
rest of your life I promise you there
are so many opportunities throughout
college to pivot your major or once you
get into the workforce as you get
experience to jump to a new industry or
position in your major really is just
the foundation and the start there are
so many industry professionals that I
met and networked went throughout
college who said yeah I'm working in
this I majored in this and I just had to
find the path between the two to connect
it but realistically they have nothing
to do with each other and they still
have flourishing successful careers so
with that being said I'm going to tell
you guys my biggest College advice at
the start of this video I'm not gonna
make you wait till the end so I'm just
going to tell you guys right now that
your major isn't everything with the
exception of maybe like being a doctor
or a lawyer where like you need a
certain degree to have that job I can't
speak a lot to that though because I
majored in business but but anyways I
think what makes you the best
candidate is just focusing on your
overall college experience not just your
major but everything that you're doing
in those four or five or however many
years
to get as much as you can out of your
college experience I think it's a time
to really learn as much as you can about
yourself from your major from the
different jobs that you have along the
way it's a great time to learn about
your strengths and your weaknesses and
your experience and when you kind of
come to like the end of the college Road
and you're looking for a job employers
want to see who you are as a person and
what you did with those four years of
college they want to see who you are not
just what you majored in and that's why
I think it's so important to look at
your overall college experience and how
you can make the most out of those four
years even beyond your major obviously
try and have your major be something
that's useful and applicable to help
jump-start your career but you also need
to be working on other experiences
outside of your degree to be the best
possible job candidate you can be so
longest winded question done right off
the bat question number two that I got
is how do you find your passions and I
kind of split it up into two different
things I think finding your passion like
finding your major everyone has their
own path to doing that as far as finding
my own passions I kind of did it in two
different ways one was just
self-reflection taking the time to
really look inwards at what I enjoy
doing what brings me joy and
gratification and like what kind of work
do I like doing that doesn't feel like
work at all because I just love it so
much
the second way to find your passion and
this can even be applied to figuring out
what you want to do job and career-wise
is just to learn by doing I think it's
so easy to just want to get everything
right on the first try and so you kind
of just like stand at the edge of the
cliff trying to figure out like am I
ready for this am I qualified is this
the right thing for me and you're
spending so much time preparing that you
never actually do the thing that you're
set out to do so I think just learning
by doing and taking that leap of faith
into a passion or a job that you're
interested in it's the best way to
figure out if it's
wrong for you because even if it doesn't
turn out to be right you just figured
out okay this is something that I
actually don't want to do let's pivot
and try something else instead of
spending so much time just contemplating
and trying to figure it out and getting
it right on the first try and that is
something that I have been totally
guilty of for most of my life because I
can be a perfectionist I want to get
things right on the first try but what
college taught me is that you just have
to take that leap of faith and go with
your gut and you will figure it out
along the way okay so question number
three that I got is scholarships and I
actually got a couple different
questions about scholarships and college
finances are really a case-by-case basis
for everyone's financial situation so
I'm just going to talk briefly about my
college experience applying for
scholarships and just keep it a little
bit general honestly so I kind of split
up scholarships into three different
buckets if you will there's the private
scholarships
there's FAFSA scholarships and then
there's scholarships through your school
which is like super general and then in
addition to that scholarships can be
awarded for all different reasons they
can be specific to your major they can
be based on your academic merit
athletics are a big one sometimes there
is even scholarships for like minorities
or your financial situation so there are
all different types of scholarships and
it can be super overwhelming to figure
out okay like which ones do I even apply
to so I'll just briefly share my
experience with scholarships so I
applied to the bulk of my scholarships
my freshman year of college and my
freshman year I think was when I had the
most scholarships as well I think I had
one or two private scholarships I got
some through FAFSA and luckily that year
too they said like these scholarships
will carry over throughout your entire
time at college and then I also got some
based on my high school GPA that really
helped out for my freshman tuition so I
did the bulk of my scholarship
applications my senior year of high
school and then after that I continued
to apply for FAFSA every year and then I
to apply to my University's kind of Bank
of scholarships Oregon State just had
like one or two scholarship applications
where you just put in all of your
information and they would kind of
disseminate it from there and pick the
right scholarships for you so it was a
really nice like one and done
application and I didn't have to apply
to like a plethora of scholarships to
try and get money to help with my
tuition so with that being said
scholarship applications can be a super
lengthy process and I think that if you
have the time it is well worth it to
dedicate that time to scholarship
applications however my personal
experience was private scholarships just
weren't worth my personal time I did get
enough financial assistance from the
university based on my academic success
to help me with my tuition so I stopped
applying for private scholarships after
my freshman year but it's totally up to
you in your financial situation but just
some general advice what I've noticed
from different scholarship applications
is that they just want to see what sets
you apart from your peers what makes you
unique what is your story and what do
you plan to set out to do you know like
with your major and with your career
dreams so in a lot of ways you can look
at a scholarship application almost like
a job application you want to put your
best foot forward and show why you are
the best candidate for that scholarship
and for that opportunity
already I think we are on to question
number four now and my mouth is getting
dry from talking so much so okay so
question number four I believe is how do
you find a job in the career field
you're interested in during college to
see if you like the career okay so I
briefly touched on this and my answer to
figuring out what you want to major and
I think about starting with
informational interviews and job
shadowing once again amazing way to get
like hands-on first-hand experience with
a job position that you're in
and reaching up to your personal network
or your professors or the alumni network
at your school to find industry
professionals who are in a position that
you're interested in to see if you can
just have 30 minutes or an hour of their
time to talk to them about their job
experience also I don't think I've
mentioned this yet but LinkedIn amazing
amazing networking platform pretty sure
every business student swears by this I
have so much I can say about LinkedIn
and using it as a platform to your
advantage but I'm gonna save that for my
career Q&A coming baby soon but yes
LinkedIn amazing place to find
connections for informational interviews
and job shadows okay so we are just on
to question number five how do you
juggle work and school so this is a
question that I got from one of my
followers on Instagram so I share a lot
of my life on Instagram they know me a
lot better than you guys probably do so
I'll just share a little bit of like
what I was doing during college and why
I probably got this question so my goal
of the four years that I was in college
was to do everything I possibly could to
get a job after graduation that was my
number one goal of these four years and
I just did everything that it took to
set me up for success to get a job with
that being said I spent most of my free
time working part-time jobs that had
some sort of segue into my career or
building my own business as a fashion
blogger and social media content creator
so with that being said for the last
four years I was a full-time honors
student in college and also working 30
to 40 hours a week on top of that
between my part-time job and building my
business and looking back on it now I
was literally crazy to do that like I
like I don't I don't know how I got
through the last four years to be honest
I think that I have chronic stress and
I'm also a self-proclaimed workaholic so
that probably explains how I got through
it but also at the end of the day I just
didn't really mind putting in the work
because I knew that it would pay off in
the long run and you know what it did
because I got a full-time job and
exactly what I wanted to do three months
before I even
we did from college so hard work pays
off delayed gratification can feel
amazing when you actually get it in yout
for me juggling work in school I just I
just grinded through it honestly it was
sheer grit and work ethic and thinking
about how it was going to pay off in the
long run I just knew it was something
that I had to do to be successful also I
am like a super planner organizer type-a
person so I lived by my planner I did a
lot of time management and also
prioritizing all of my work and school
tasks to make the most of my time as
possible and be really productive every
single day and week I've actually been
thinking about doing a video about that
because I have a planner that I swear by
and kind of like a system for
prioritizing my tasks so if that's
something you guys would be interested
in let me know and I can make that video
too okay on to the next question another
big topic a lot of college students are
interested in which is internships more
specifically how do I get one and is it
essential to have an internship so also
depending on what sort of industry
you're going into the importance of an
internship
I'm sure varies however in general I
think that internships are an amazing
opportunity to get a real taste of the
job and career that you could be
possibly going into it is an amazing way
to set yourself apart experience and
resume wise when you're applying for
full-time jobs and it's also an amazing
opportunity to get experience working
for a company that you're interested in
because I also think that the company
that you work for is just as important
as the job that you're actually doing I
just think that like the overall
workplace culture and the people that
you surround yourself with are just as
important as the actual job that you're
doing so so figuring out the right
company for you is also a good question
to ask yourself with that being said I
don't think that it's absolutely
essential that you have an internship
during college to get a full-time job
afterwards I actually didn't have an
internship during college and I still
got a job before I graduated I think
more importantly it's about how you use
your time in college and if you can get
experience in an
in a way that doesn't explicitly have
the word internship and it that is
totally fine and still very applicable
my mindset about internships though was
totally different my sophomore in junior
year when I was gearing up to apply to
internships so backtrack to a couple
years ago when I was considering
internships I thought it was absolutely
essential to have one and my dream idea
was that I was going to intern at a
company I was interested in basically
like one of their kind of training
programs for college students and it was
almost expected that once you went
through that internship program you
would be offered a full-time job your
summer before senior year and then that
job would kind of be waiting for you
when you graduated
that was my like dream plan a what I
wanted to happen as a merchandising
major when I thought that I wanted to be
a buyer or merchandise or something like
that that was kind of like the dream
path that you would go in so a little
bit of a spoiler alert I did get to the
final interview of my dream company
dream internship what I had always
wanted to do I had my final interview
and I didn't get accepted to their
internship program and I was absolutely
gutted because my plan a of what I had
been working so hard for to get what I
thought that I was qualified for didn't
end up working out for me
and it took me a little bit honestly to
like pick myself up off the ground and
convince myself that I wasn't a failure
because that's what I felt like at that
time but honestly looking back now that
rejection was just a redirection for me
and a kind sight I am so glad I didn't
get that internship because it would
have set me down another path that now
I'd actually realized isn't right for me
I don't know what that story is
depressing or hopeful for you guys but I
hope that I can be living proof that you
don't need an internship to get a
full-time job and it's really just about
the overall experience that you have in
college that sets you apart as a
candidate so because I didn't get that
internship I buckled down and spend even
more time
building my own business and getting
experience in social media marketing
building out my portfolio through my
college classes because once I picked
myself up I was like you know what I
didn't get this internship I'm not going
to have formal experience in this area
but there are still so many things that
I can do getting like informal
experience and learning as much as I can
by myself to still set me apart as a job
candidate so that's what I did in place
of having an internship I just buckled
down and did the work myself made an
opportunity for myself and that is
really what benefited me in the long run
okay chugging right along next question
is how much networking should I do in
college okay okay my answer might be a
little bit biased I don't know if this
is the same for every single industry
but networking in business and as a
business student is like everything so
my answer is going to be network as much
as you possibly can in college
especially for business majors I really
think it's about who you know as much as
what you know there are so many
opportunities that just come up because
of the connections that you have in your
network and being being and knowing the
right place at the right time so if your
school has networking events please
please go to them especially at these
networking events like employers and
professionals are there because they
want to talk to students they want to
give you advice they want to connect
with you and this is just like a free
pass to shake the hand and introduce
yourself to a professional and like you
don't have to do any of the like work to
like cold call them or anything like
that they are there right in front of
you at that networking event and it's an
amazing opportunity to connect with them
employers also love to see initiative
from students if you are still a college
student and you're already introducing
yourself to people in the industry that
is amazing and proactive and please
please do it if you're interested in
learning more about how to network how
to leverage your network to get a job I
will also be talking about that in my
career Q&A so part two of this video
okay I think we've covered all of the
questions about like college experience
so we're kind of gonna jump
ship into more of like the job
application process as you're coming up
on graduation in your senior year so the
next question that I got is when do I
start applying for jobs so I started to
apply for jobs my Spring Break of senior
year which was about three months out to
graduation I felt like that was kind of
the sweet spot of like hey I'm coming up
on graduation I can start working at
this time so it was like close enough
that the employer would actually be able
to hire me in like a timely fashion but
I also had enough time to apply to a
number of jobs possibly get rejected go
through the interview process apply to
more jobs it was just like I think that
the three-month mark was just like a
nice buffer to prepare me for whatever
might happen in that timeframe but I
actually started to kind of prospect a
job search I would say my winter term of
senior year starting like I think it was
over a holiday break I was already
looking at job positions not necessarily
once I was going to applying to but just
seeing like okay what companies are
hiring right now what types of jobs are
available I was just being super
proactive and kind of feeling out the
job market six months before I was going
to graduate so yeah if you want to be
super proactive and on top of things you
know it doesn't hurt to start looking
early but I think that kind of
three-month last term or semester of
senior year is the best time to start
applying okay next job question I got is
how many jobs
should I be applying for so after giving
those questions some thought I think to
make the most of your time because like
first and foremost you're already a
full-time college student and now you
have to throw applying to jobs on top of
your already super busy schedule I think
to make the most of your time the best
thing that you can do is to compile a
list of job postings you're interested
in let's say like 10 to 15 that you are
interested in applying for of those pick
your top five and your top 5 jobs are
like I love this company I love the
sound of this position I think that I
would be a really good candidate for
this and focus your time and energy
on those five applications and make them
the best you possibly can instead of
like spreading yourself then over 20
different job applications and just
hoping that one of them comes back and
says that they want to interview you
I think prioritizing your time and
effort to the jobs that you are most
interested in is the best thing to do
and once you start hearing back from
those then start putting out your job
applications to the rest of your list
and kind of just go from there and the
reason that I think you should
prioritize your job applications is
because most the time your application
is the first impression that a company
is getting of you and you want to make
it the best possible impression that you
can so don't half-ass your job
applications don't just send the same
resume to every single place and hope
that one of them likes it I know this
video is already getting super long so
once again I'm going to be talking about
like resumes cover letters interview
tips portfolio those things like that
and my career QA but yeah hopefully that
answers your question of how many jobs
you should be applying for okay final
question is for anyone interested in
going into the marketing industry so I
got a question that says if I'm not a
marketing major how do I get into the
marketing industry and I feel like this
question was just made for me so I
majored in merchandising management
which is like a fashion and business
degree and I ended up getting a job as a
social media and marketing manager so I
think this question needs to be narrowed
down a little bit into what type of role
in marketing do you want because there
are so many different roles in marketing
and figuring out how you're going to get
your foot in the door in that type of
position really varies but like I said
before job shadows informational
interviews and looking for like an
entry-level job in the industry is a
great way to get your foot in the door
because I was interested in going into
like social media and advertising I did
a number of informational interviews and
advertising agencies to figure out if
that was something I was interested in
and like spoiler informational
interviews are a time for obviously
you'd ask them questions about their job
and the company but it's also an
opportunity to introduce yourself and
like if them your resume tell them about
your experience so that's how I leverage
those informational interviews and I
highly recommend that you do the same as
far as different marketing roles go
though there are a lot of ways that once
again you can get informal experience or
qualifications to kind of boost your
resume as a candidate so depending on
what kind of marketing role you are
interested in there are tons of
certifications that you can get like
Google Analytics HootSuite you can learn
about Shopify I'm just rattling off a
couple different things you really need
to do research on the types of positions
you're interested in and what
qualifications they typically expect
because a lot of those can be obtained
through like online marketing courses
that you can do in your free time I also
think that working on marketing projects
like if you're still in school is an
amazing way to have something to show
for like tangible experience it's
something that you've been working on in
the marketing realm and like any other
industry not just in marketing just try
and learn as much as you possibly can on
your own and get as much experience as
you can I am a firm believer to make an
opportunity for yourself if there isn't
one there so I really paved my own path
to get into the social media marketing
industry because I was building up my
own social media platforms and by the
time I graduated I had four years of
experience managing my own social media
accounts and that's what made me a
really strong candidate even though I
didn't major in marketing oh my gosh I
need to take a deep breath I need to
drink some more coffee because my mouth
is still dry you know what guys we made
it to the end of the college QA I have
been talking for so stinkin long I hope
I didn't bore you guys and that you
found this video informative if you're
still here at the end thank you so so
much for watching and I will be
answering all of your career questions
within the next week in a new video if
you have any other questions for me
personally about my college or work
experience feel free and leave them in
the comments down below or send me a
message on Instagram and I'll make sure
that I answer them and with that I won't
ramble on any more
and I hope to see you guys in my next
video bye