you guys welcome
back to my channel
today's video is going to be my
pregnancy Q&A I'm
really excited to film
this video and first
I want to give a
shout out to everybody
who participated
in my Instagram
polls and sent me
questions for this video
I'm really excited
like I said to answer
the questions I'm
just going to hop
right into the video
so I have been
needing to literally
write everything
down like I have it
all on my phone and
screenshot it and
everything but writing
things down makes it
so much easier for
me as far as these
types of videos go so
you can see every
what pregnancy Q&A
that I've done all
the questions that
everybody asked me
very first question
that I got is from one
of my friends she
said what were your
first symptoms
before you knew you
were pregnant so I
actually didn't have
any symptoms as far
as like pregnancy
symptoms ago before I
knew I was pregnant like all the
symptoms and everything
happened after I
found out so about the
time that I found
out that I was
pregnant I was having
like period symptoms
because I was due
for my period now
my periods like
normally like really
really regular so I
thought nothing of
it like the cramps
that I was having the
exhaustion none of
that was just like
out of the ordinary
for me um ma'am where's
your bone kkona
kkona where's your
bone what'd you go
find it so none of
the cramping or any
of the exhaustion or
like sore boobs was
anything like out
of the ordinary
because that's normally
what I get on my
period anyways it
just seemed like a
period to me so
that's what I thought
was coming yeah I
didn't really have or
noticed any other
pregnancy symptoms
until after I found
out I was pregnant
the second question
says how does it
feel what kinds of
cravings do you get
so as far as the
first part of that
question how does it
feel I think it's
always going to be
to each their own
like how I feel in my
pregnancy is gonna
be way different
than how one of my
friends or anybody
else out there is an
feel during their
pregnancy so as far as
how it feels personally for me
right now I just feel
like I don't have
enough skin for my
growing tummy and I'm
really hungry at the
moment like I'm
always always hungry
I'll leave a giant
meal and then an
hour later I'll be
starving again and
I wake up really
hungry so I haven't
had any like strange
cravings this is all
stuff I've always
liked pre-pregnancy I
just really really
really like them now
so my first craving
is pickles sounds
pretty cliché but
pickles are like
one of my favorite
snacks I just love the
crunch I love the
taste I grew up
eating pickles I was
born in Kansas and I
feel like it's like
a Midwest thing to
just kind of like
grow up eating pickles
like that I don't
know if that's just
me or anything but
my husband hates
pickles and I know if
it goes are like all
over the world but
I feel like it's like
a Midwest thing to
kind of just like
grow up eating lots
and lots of pickles
my second craving is
mango Navas they are
like a mango ice
cream which MO and I
mean I also like I
said I like fruit
like so specifically
oranges and grapes
as well as fruit
smoothies so I make
acai smoothies every
single day I add fresh
strawberries or
no excuse me frozen
strawberries and
then orange juice and
the chia seeds I
also really really
like cucumbers so
every day almost
every day I eat this
like cucumber salad
with avocados and
red onions and for
the dressing one of
the cravings is
actually olive oil and
lemon juice mixed
together that's
definitely one of
my cravings that I
have it just tastes
so fresh and so
delicious and so I
mix that in with my
cucumbers and my
avocados and everything
and the last thing
that I have been
craving my entire
pregnancy has been
tell aunty Caribbean
coconut ice cream
excuse me gelato
it's actually gelato
they have shredded
coconut in it and
it's just so good the
taste is amazing I
crave it I hate that
it only comes in
such a small little
container but it's
so good and it's so worth
penny that I spend
on it so the next
question my little
sister asked me and
the way she typed it
didn't really make
sense that I just kind
of reworded it so
it says do you feel
weird having a belly
since you've always
been skinny honestly
yes I'm so used to
be able and being
able to wear like crop tops and
high-waisted denim
pants and now I can
only wear leggings
and t-shirts because
that's the only thing
that's comfortable
for me right now
so yeah I've pretty
much always been
skinny my entire life
in fact I'm still
really skinny for
someone who is almost
6 months pregnant
pre pregnancy I was
about like 107 pounds
and then I lost
some weight in my
first trimester cuz I
didn't want to eat
anything and then in
my second trimester
I was fine so I
gained about like 5
pounds again and
then now I'm up to
120 pounds this
question says did you
have boy and girl
names ready to go
before you found out
the gender yes
basically I did have a
few names picked out
for boy and girl I
think now that I
have the boy name
settled I think I
have a girl name
settled too so in the
future whenever we
have a daughter
hopefully I still like
that name and we can
give her that name
this question says
what's the hardest
part about being
pregnant and what's the
easiest I think the
hardest part about
being pregnant is
waking up and not
knowing how I'm going
to feel for the
day so even though
I am in my second
trimester and
normally this is the
trimester when you
do feel pretty good
and pretty energetic
I still kind of
wake up not knowing
exactly how I'm
gonna feel for the
day like sometimes
I'm a little bit
cranky ER or sometimes
I'm extra extra hungry
which causes need
to be a little cranky
err or sometimes
I'm just really not
feeling good there's
just all these little
things that go on
that I can't really
help so I think
that's the hardest
part about pregnancy
is the easiest part
of pregnancy is
definitely the second
trimester first
trimester was horrible
it was awful we
went on vacation and I think
like one nap and we
were up pretty early
in the morning and
staying up pretty
late and I think I
only took one nap my
entire vacation so
that was like the
easiest part is just
like that spark of
energy that I got
there's like a few
questions like a few
people asked me how
did I find out I was
pregnant and did I
surprise my husband
did he already know
how did I break the
news to him so I'm
gonna combine those
two because it's
kind of like kind of
a story I guess so
at first I honestly
didn't think that I
was pregnant my husband
was the one who
was like I think
you're pregnant only
because my period
wasn't coming like I
said earlier in this
video my periods
are pretty regular so
for me to not have
my period there was
obviously just
something off but I
was just being in
denial about it I was
like no that can't
happen to me like
I'm not pregnant
there's no way and
then one day on his
way home from work
he brought me home
some pregnancy test
so I took them and I
was really confused
they were the ones
with like the lines
you have like your
control line and we
have your test line
and my control line
was lighter than my
test line and I was
really confused
so that made me
even more in denial
about me being
pregnant I was like so
why is my control line
light but my test
line is extremely
dark and it turns out
my HCG levels I think
that's what it's
called were just like
really high like
my hormone levels
were really high
apparently I had just
been pregnant for
a while to reassure
myself I got one of
those like clear blue
digital ones that
say pregnant or not
pregnant and I took
it about I'm gonna say
like a week later
and sure enough I
was pregnant I did
take those tests
while my husband was
home like he knew I
was going to the
bathroom to take the
test so when I was
done going to the
bathroom he would just
know to you know
come in and we would
just kind of watch the test stay
pregnant or not
pregnant together so we
found out together
which I thought was
really special and
he was so excited it
was a cutest reaction
he hugged me and
he kissed me and I
would think I was
more shocked I was
like holy freaking
crap this is a joke
like there is no way
this is real this next
question says how
is the kicking and
kicking is actually
really interesting I
started feeling the
baby kick
I was about 15 weeks
pregnant and that's
really really early
for some people but
I've read that if
you're like really
tiny and petite like
I am you can start
feeling the baby earlier
pretty much the
kid hasn't stopped
moving since then
like I feel him all
the time my husband
was like what does
it feel like and
there was no other
way to describe it
other than someone
being inside of you
and literally kicking
you which is
literally exactly
what's happening
that's the only way
I could describe it
the next question
says what are some
names you like but
aren't using I think
want to do a video on
that so stay tuned
for that
this question says
at what point in
pregnancy did you
have to buy new
clothes for the winter
time I just kind
of lived in like my
big sweaters and
t-shirts and leggings
there was going on
vacation and March to
the Caribbean so I
kind of needed some
comfy stretchy
outfits that I could
wear during my
pregnancy as well as
after my pregnancy
so I didn't buy any
like maternity
clothes I literally
went to brandy
Melville and she and
in fashion Nova and
I bought a bunch of
dresses so ending in
March which I would
have been like four
months pregnant at
that point I needed
to buy new clothes
because my denim
shorts and everything
that was just not
gonna cut it it was
too tight on me too
high-waisted like it
was just not gonna
happen
I ordered some stuff from Target
actually on a pair of
maternity leggings
so that's actually
the very first
maternity anything
that I purchased and
then I bought some
t-shirts and so much
stretchy tank tops
that I can wear in
the summer and just
be cozy and comfy
because there's
nothing I want more
right now than to
just be comfortable
this question says
has anything about
pregnancy surprised you lots of
surprises lots and
lots of surprises
some this one I don't
know if it's like
really a surprise or
just kind of like I
don't know but the
first one is now that
my boobs have grown
and my belly has
grown the bottom of
my boobs touches the
top of my stomach and
it's the weirdest
thing that has never
happened to me I've
always had mosquito
bites for boobs and
a flat stomach so
that's literally never
happened to me and now that it's
happening I don't
know how I feel about
it so like I'll
literally just be
sitting there in the
bathtub or no bra
and wearing my t-shirt
and I can feel
the bottom of my boobs
touch the top of
my stomach and it
feels so funny like I
don't know if it
just doesn't I don't
know it just feels
really weird another
surprise is the round
ligament pain that
I've been getting
so I do get round
ligament pain in my
uterus and basically
what that is is your
uterus is expanding
obviously to make
room for the growing
baby
so that hurts you
know and it kind of
feels like menstrual
cramps more just
like a dull pain and
it's just kind of
there and there's
not really much you
can do about it
the next thing is
pregnancy brain
pregnancy brain is the
realest thing I have
ever experienced in
my life I cannot express
how dumb I have
been feeling the past
few months at work
I've made so many
mistakes so I just
write everything
down that I possibly
can before I forget
it pregnancy brain
is crazy and usually
I'm not like on top
of things I have a
really good memory
I'm usually really
on top of things but
lately I just
I don't know where I'm
at my head's like
in the clouds it seems
the last surprise
basically is just
pregnancy overall like
I've never been
pregnant before so this
is like the realest
newest thing my body has ever
experienced like
everything every single
day there's something
new so I think
that's like a big
shock it's like
there's like always
something new going
on in my body and the
fact that there's
an actual human being
growing inside of
my uterus right now
is absolutely insane
and incredible at the
same time I got a
couple questions about
my daily routine
so like what changes
have you made in
your daily routine
what's the same in
self-care I think is
my biggest change
like I've been caring
for myself a lot
better now and kind of
like pampering myself
a little more I do
a lot more like face
masks and bubble
baths because that
just kind of helps me
soothe and relax
throughout the day just
because I do get
really really really
tight
really easily
especially after a long
day at work and then
I come home and I
take a bubble bath
and I do a face mask
and I just feel great
like it just kind
of energizes me a
little bit gives me in
a state of relaxation
and then I sleep
really well as well
because of that
another thing that
has changed is I do
take vitamins
so before like I tried
taking vitamins
but it wasn't
consistent it was more
like once every few
days but I do take
prenatal vitamins and
vitamin D vitamins
because there is no
Sun here in Chicago
my vitamin D levels
are really really
low so vitamin D
really important and
then my prenatal
is very extremely
important and I make
sure they have DHA
and m2 it helps the
baby so basically
overall a more
conscious of my health
like I've always had
problems with low
blood sugar and low
iron and just all
sorts of things that
make me feel really
weak so I've been
more conscious of my
health I eat a lot
better than I used to
even though before
it did eat pretty
well I wasn't eating
as consistent as I
should basically so
I've been eating
every two hours almost
I just been making
better choices with
what I have been
eating and I've been
drinking a lot a lot
more water than I
used to mainly because
I'm a lot more
thirsty but I've
been drinking a lot
more water next
question says what are
your thoughts on
using the epidural
during labor for me
I think I might get
the epidural because
I don't like pain
and if there's something
out there that
can help me not feel
the pain then I'm
all about it but at
the same time I'm
not sure how everything
is gonna go like
if I feel like I don't
need the epidural
then I'm not gonna
get it but if I feel
like I need it I'm
going to get it and I
do want to try and natural birth
sometime I'm just not
sure how I'm gonna
take it but that's
what our bodies are
meant to do we're
stronger than we think
and I think I'll
do a natural birth
eventually but I
think for this first
time I'm going to
get that maduro see
how it goes and then
if I don't like it
then next time I have
you get this other
question that I have
says what scares you
most about labor
I'm not really afraid
to push I'm more
afraid of like pooping
while pushing so
obviously like it
happens to almost
every woman who does
push our babies out
but I just I really
I'm gonna be scarred
for life man I think
I'm more afraid of
recovery rather than
actual labor itself
I'm afraid of tearing
and then needing
stitches or like how
bad that tear is
gonna be that's what
I'm really afraid
of it's like tearing
and then having
that burning when you
pee and just not
about that
yeah I'm not really
afraid like the
contractions like
yeah I'm afraid of
that but I don't know we'll see
obviously I've never
done this before I
don't know what I'm
talking about so
that's that the next
question says did
you consider waiting
to find out your
baby's sex or were
you like I need to
know I needed to know
I need to know the
baby's gender because
honestly finding
out that I had a boy
then you feel more
connected at the beginning of my
pregnancy I was like
like I know there's
a baby in there but
I just don't really
feel connected to
it like a lot of
people are like oh my
god I love my baby
like I can't wake up
a bla and honestly
I wasn't really
feeling that at the
beginning of my pregnancy
but now that I
found with the baby's
gender and have a
name picked out
we have some like
clothes picked out
I'm more I feel more
connected and I'm just
so so excited and
like full of joy
khones gotta be big
sister are you big
sister for his baby
brother so that was
actually all of the
questions that my
friends and family on
Instagram passed me
but yeah I hope you
guys enjoyed this video
I really enjoyed
answering all those
questions about
pregnancy if you guys
like this video go
ahead and give it a
big thumbs up please
subscribe to my channel
if you are new
and hit post notifications
so you guys
know when I upload
a new video every
week thank you guys
so much for tuning
in today
until next time I will
[Music]