hey everybody welcome
back to my channel
today's video is super
exciting because
I am showing you guys
I'm sharing my DNA
results
I took a DNA test
turns up I got my
results back yesterday
so I actually
feel my reaction
however the car ride
was just kind of like
bumpy and the mic
wasn't there like
it was just I don't
think the quality was
there so I decided
to sit down show you
guys my results
I'll go ahead and throw
in some clips in
my reaction because
I was actually
pleasantly surprised
I was really happy
to take this test
because I really
wanted to find out
my ancestry I even
told so many different
things from both
sides of my family
that I'm just like
hmm let's put it to
the test so I went
ahead I gave the
government a now they
can clone me and
here we are with my
results as you can see
I'm here the baby
boy he just woke up
from a nap and he
had some milk
so he is chillin right
now so the very
first thing I really
wanted to start
with was my background my ethnic
background both of
my parents are mixed
my mom is mixed with
Egyptian and white
and my dad is mixed
with black and white
he's mostly black
his mom was mixed
black and white but
his dad was black so
both my parents are
of mixed race right
off the bat I just
assumed that my DNA
results would come
back mostly African
European and I
expected some Middle
Eastern as well
throughout my life I
have been told that
we are Jewish that
we're Native American
those are two
things that I have
been told from both
sides of my family
the Native American
from both sides and
then the Jewish from
my mom's mom my mom's
dad immigrated
from Egypt to the
United States my mom's
mom I'm pretty sure
her family has been
here for generations
and generations
assume that my dad's
side of the family
is black I can assume
that they've also
been here for generations and
generations and
generations because of
the slave trade
that happened way
way back then so I
can only assume that
my relatives were
slaves I can also
assume that my
relatives may have
possibly been slave
owners and passed as
far as the Egyptians
side I don't really
know the Egyptian side
of my family when
people ask me what
I am I do say I'm
black white in Egyptian
because that's
exactly what I look
like but I actually
don't know Arabic
I don't know the
Egyptian culture I
don't know anything
about being egyptian
and I'm really
proud to be Egyptian
I think it's a
beautiful culture way
back from ancient
Egypt to current
date Egypt however I
don't know anything
about it I don't
know what it is to
be Egyptian all I
know is that I am
Egyptian my grandpa
came from Egypt and
I do wish I knew
more Arabic or any
Arabic for that
matter and I do wish
I knew that side of
my family but I know
some of them are
still in Egypt and
some of them actually
live here in the
states I think in
Houston Texas I
just never met them
before and hopefully
one day I get to
meet them and then
I'll insert some
clips of my reaction
as well but right
now this is just an overview of
everything that I am
I've already seen these results
yesterday was the day
where I actually
had a reaction and I
did want to film it
and I couldn't wait
because I was just
super super excited I
wouldn't have been
home until about 9:00 p.m.
and I wasn't
gonna film around
that time either so
I'll just go ahead and
insert some clips
of my reaction no
it is crapping his
pants right now sir
now that that's
taken care of let's
get back into the
video I'm gonna go
ahead and share with
you guys all of my
percentages do the
breakdown and then
give you a little bit
of information on
some things that I
found really interesting
so the very
first thing that comes
up on my ancestry
or poor is European
I am a 38% European
30 0.3% of that is north western
European so British
an Irish French and
German and then
broadly North Western
European I know that
my dad's mom I'm
pretty sure I have
been told that she is
Irish and then my mom's
mom's mom so my
great-grandma on my
mom's side I know
that she was like
British and Irish 30
0.3% Northwestern
European now the other
European part of
me is 2.7 southern
European so that
includes Italy Malta
Spain Portugal and
in broadly southern
European wait 8%
Italian 0.2% Spanish
and porch I believe
it came from the
Egyptian side of my
family so if you
know geography you
would know that
the Mediterranean
separates southern
Europe in northern
Africa and I honestly
believe that part
of our Egyptian
side is also like
Italian or Spanish
Portuguese because
it's right across the
Mediterranean Sea
so that's what I can
assume now it's
very possible that
it came from the
white sides of my
family the people who
came from like Great
Britain and Ireland
and France and
Germany but I really
truly believe that
it did come from the
Egyptian side just because
geographically that
would make sense to
me now I knew that
most of my map would
cover Africa because
I know my dad is
black and I know my
mom's dad came from
Egypt so he is
African so I'm 34.2%
sub-saharan African
now that is a little
bit less than how much your p.m.
it's
almost the same
amount but I am 26.8%
West African now if
you know anything
about the slave trade
you know that most
of the slaves did
come from West Africa
so I can only assume
that my ancestors
were slaves at one
point I am at 10.5%
Nigerian Nigeria
but 9.8% Ghanian
liberia and sierra
leonean see ya Leone I am 1.3%
Senegambia n-- and
Guinean I'm 5.2
percent broadly West
African so like I
said I believe that
West African came
from the slave trade
and my ancestors
who were more than
likely slaves and
then I saw that I'm 5.1 percent
Congolese and southern
East African now
I don't know what
that came from my
dad's side of the
family who is African
American who is black
or if that came
from my mom's side of
the family because
it is south of the
Sudan but you gypped
is north of the Sudan
and it's North
East Africa I would
say on a map it
looks like North
East Africa and so I
don't know if any of
this East African
came from my mom's
dad side of the
family or my dad's
side of the family
and he has African
ancestry on both his
mom and dad side so
I'm not sure where
that came from
but I feel like that
came from my mom's
side I knew that most
of my map would be
covered would cover
like all of Africa
technically because
I'm from both North
Africa and sub-saharan Africa
and so here it says
I'm 24.9% Western
Asian and North
African twenty-three
point three percent
of that is Arab
Egyptian and Levantine
seventeen point
six percent of that
is Egyptian three
point five percent
of X coptic egyptian
and two point two
percent of that is
broadly Arab Egyptian
and Levantine says
three point five
percent of my ancestry
is coptic egyptian
so it says making up
over ten percent of
Egypt's population
cops are Christian
minority who share in
ancient history with non Coptic
Egyptians that dates
back before the
first Pharaohs however
after the seventh
century of conquest
of Egypt by the
ration and Caliphate
the Christian cops
began to become
genetically distinct
from the Muslim
majority population
while the Coptic
language was replaced
by Egyptian Arabic
outside of a strictly
religious setting
today most cops live
in Egypt or Sudan
but there are also
large Coptic communities
living in the
United States Australia
and Canada so I
thought that was
pretty interesting and
if I'm translating
correctly I think it
means that like the
coptic egyptian is
like the egyptians
who were there like
way before like King
Tut which i think is
awesome what if I'm
related to like King
Tut or Nefertiti
and going back to my ancestry
composition it says
that I am 0.4% North
African and then one
point two percent
broadly Western Asian
and North African
the Western Asian I
can assume that it's
like hi I'm one
point two percent
broadly Western Asian
and North African
and then 0.4% North
African and I can
assume that's just
like the rest of
North Africa like
Morocco Libya and the
Western Asian part
would be Middle
Eastern
so I think that that's
what that means
again correct me if
I am wrong if I go
to trace ancestry it
says I'm point nine
percent trace
ancestry I think that
means just Native
American maybe because
it says I'm point
four percent Native
American and then
I'm point three
percent broadly southern
South Asian and
point two percent
broadly Central and
South Asian which
means like Sri Lanka
and India which I
thought was pretty
cool those are my
results I think that
it is beautiful I'm
from all of these
different cultures
and countries ton of
anything I'm just
like a little bit of
everything within
those countries so I
think it's awesome
I'm really really
happy that I got to
do this test because
again I just wanted
to know more about
my ancestry and this
was a perfect way
to find out so I did
take the 23andme
DNA test and I got
my results back in
like three weeks
super super easy but
something I did want
to point out was I
was told in my family
that we are like
both sides my family have Native
American and then my
mom said my family
has Jewish no I don't
know where they
got that from because
I don't see any
Jewish on here at all
like at all like
there's no Jewish in
fact if I go into
another report it
says they're 0.0%
Ashkenazi Jewish
which is what I was
told that we are so
I don't know but it
doesn't say anything
about being Jewish
here at 0.4% Native
American and I don't
know where what side
of my family that
comes from I don't
know anything about
that
I just know that I
was told I'm more
Native American than that like I
expected maybe like
15 percent Native
American I just want
to know like where
my family heard
this stuff or did
somebody just make
it up like I don't
know but I'm a smidge
Native American
and not Jewish at all
so that was kind
of surprising but
other than that my
tests were pretty
accurate to what I
expected them to be
I love it I think
it's so cool I'm so
glad than I know
comment down below
if you have ever
taken this test
tell me what your
results were if they
were accurate if
they shocked you if
they were exactly
what you thought they
were like tell me
what it is make sure
you subscribe to my
channel if you are
a new viewer thank
you so much for
tuning in today and I
will see you guys
[Music]