hi guys i'm back after two years
um i have been getting
an amazing response on my last video and
i did not expect that
thank you to everyone who commented on
my last video it literally means the
world to me
those of you who encouraged me on that
video or who shared their
college experience it literally means
everything to me i wanted to make an
update video for you guys
um let you guys know what has been going
on in my life
um i'm currently in
my apartment i moved out of my parents
house
in november um i moved to la
if you guys don't know i used to live in
chino and i've been loving it here so
far
um hold on let me move the camera really
quick
but yeah i recently moved to la in
november so i've been here
november december january february march
almost six months
it's crazy wait november december
january february march it's march
um i don't know about you guys but my
perception of time
it's gone i got accepted to cal state
fullerton
two years ago so i made that community
college video in april
and then i got accepted to cal state
fullerton in august
i should have made an update video um
but i just never did so yeah i was
actually on the waitlist i got in um i
got the email and i
literally cried because it was
such a big step in my school journey you
know i'm going
to a university finally i'm going to get
my bachelor's degree
and yeah i'll be graduating in
may so i literally have seven weeks left
of my semester i wanted to make this
update for you guys
and let you guys know that i'm okay
i got through um that part of my life
i work part-time as a social media
director
for a body care company and things are
looking up for me
i feel extremely grateful and extremely
happy
for all the ups and downs that i had to
go through to get here i knew that
things were gonna be okay and um thank
you guys for
believing in me i wanna create a
community on here i want to create more
videos for you guys
so um let me know down below
what other videos you'd like to see i
just watched
what i film right now there's so much
background noise um i think they're
doing
construction upstairs
yeah i'm so sorry about that i'm happy
i'm doing this update video finally it's
been so long
so next i'm gonna be talking about some
tips
that i have for you guys i feel like my
experience
transferring has been great i feel like
once i transferred to a university i
took school more seriously
and i really re-evaluated
myself and my time i committed my time
to school
and um really improved my
time management um when i transferred so
i'm going to give you guys a couple of
tips
for those of you that need it to help
you stay motivated
in college so the number one tip that i
have for you is
just to prioritize school um
i know that it's really hard to say no
to hanging out with your friends and
family i've had to say no
over the past two years i've had to say
no to hanging out with friends
to going to family events but i know
it's worth it
when you have that goal when you have a
goal in mind
stick to it be disciplined if it's
something that you really
want i know that sacrificing time with
friends and family and all those
important events um you know sometimes
you have to sacrifice
time to get the results that you want
the second tip
that i have for anyone that is
struggling in college
is to be extremely organized i noticed
that once i started writing everything
down in my planner
even reading assignments stuff that i
didn't have to turn in
stuff that i had to do for the day for
the week write everything down just so
you know exactly what you need to do
when it's due deadlines that you want to
give yourself
for reading assignments and write
everything down it will make everything
so much easier and seamless in college
so the third tip that i have for you
guys is sit
in the front in the classes that you
think you're struggling in i
took business calculus twice and i
didn't do well both times
i'm so sorry about the noise the third
time
i sat in the front i made sure i paid
attention came early to class
asked questions whenever i was confused
um that's another thing sit in the front
and don't be shy to ask questions
so that really helped me in my class i
have a very
short attention span so if i'm not
sitting in the front
i will go on my phone i will doodle on
my notebook
i know that it's really tempting to just
sit in the back
and chill on your phone but if you
really want to
excel in a class and stay focused i
advise you to
sit in the front and don't be afraid to
ask questions
when you're lost so the last and final
tip is to ask your professor questions
when you are struggling in the class
take time to go to their office hours
because most likely they're willing to
help you
willing to give you extra credit um i
know that when i was struggling
in the class i had constant
communication with my professor
and they remember that when they are
either going to bump your grade up or
not you want to have good communication
with your professors and build that good
relationship with them because
it will pay off in the end i just want
to thank you guys so much
for the positive response that i
received on my last video
and i wish you guys the best of luck if
you guys have
any questions at all feel free to dm me
on instagram
feel free to comment on this video i
still have a whole bunch of comments to
reply to on my last video
but thank you guys so much and i know
that you guys
are going to excel at whatever you end
up doing