yeah I'm not gonna cry today I want to
talk about my college journey and
basically what I've been going through
for so long if you guys are fans let me
know in the comments below I actually
really like this shirt and it's a good
fit so Breaking Bad all the way but on
to the serious part of this video and
basically what I've been wanting to make
a video about is my college journey it
has been such a long exhausting journey
I feel like I feel this way because I'm
comparing my timeline to other peoples
timelines and I'm just seeing other
people already in their career and it
just makes me sad because I have so many
passions outside of school and I just
want to start my career already but I'm
having a really hard time transferring
out of my Community College so I'm gonna
just go back from the beginning I
graduated high school in 2014 and my
grades in high school to be honest
weren't the best I really didn't care
about my grades and I applied to a
couple schools didn't get into a lot of
the schools that I wanted to go to so I
applied to see bu and if you guys don't
know it's California Baptist University
it's actually really easy University to
get into so I thought I wanted to go
there until I realized that the tuition
was way too high for the budget of my
dad and just my budget as well because I
knew those student loans would
eventually move on to me after I
graduated college so I took a semester
off because the deadline to register for
the community college that I wanted to
go to was already over I thought I was
going to see bu but I was pretty
disappointed that I didn't get to start
college right away but it really wasn't
a big deal in the grand scheme hopefully
I'll have that same perspective on the
same situation that I
I am in right now I decided to go to a
community college in Orange County
starting spring 2015 and honestly I
didn't have a lot of guidance and I
didn't do a lot of research so I ended
up taking a couple classes that I didn't
need I think I took one journalism class
that didn't give me any transfer college
credit so I really messed up there and
the whole first year of college I just
didn't get good grades which set me back
so much I thought I wanted to be a
sociology major because I really liked
the sociology classes and I did fairly
well in them I thought I wanted to be a
psych major
but I'm just realizing how much school
that those two majors required I just
didn't want to do that and then I got
introduced to marketing by a couple of
my friends and my sister who is
marketing major she's in the fashion
industry now but just realizing that
marketing was so broad and I always knew
that I wanted to do something creative
I've always been a creative person so I
changed my major to business marketing a
year and a half into school I knew that
I wanted to transfer soon but my grades
just weren't good enough so I had to
keep taking classes to improve my GPA
but I was just having such a hard time
at school and didn't know why I think I
just wasn't putting enough time and
effort into school like I was supposed
to and I thought that the effort that I
was putting in was enough but it really
was it so fall 2018 comes around four
years later and I am actually no no its
fall 2017 I'm applying for fall 2018 and
my parents wanted to go on a European
trip we did Italy and France which was
really fun but the only problem was it
was in the middle of the semester so I
pretty much I think I flunked one of my
classes and then
I got C's in the rest of them and I'm
not blaming it on the Europe trip
because I decided to go and I wanted to
go with my family I think that sometimes
life just happens and I knew that I
wasn't going to be able to do this trip
later on if I don't go with my family
now and we had such a fun time I don't
really regret going even though it set
me a year behind yeah so I just had to
wait so now I am applying for fall 2019
I got rejected by Cal State Long Beach
Cal State LA and then I got wait-listed
for Cal State Fullerton and Cal Poly
Pomona honestly when I saw that I was
rejected by two schools and wait-listed
by two I got really discouraged and I
feel like I don't know my creative
juices aren't flowing at the moment
there's so many things that I'm
passionate about I love yoga I love
helping other people I would love to do
social media marketing and for a
sustainable fashion company those are
just some of my dreams and I just feel
like I am so out of touch with my
creative side and just feel out of touch
with myself just because I'm being so
hard on myself about school I'm getting
emotional about it but I know that it's
gonna be okay because I'm only 23 years
old I mean in the grand scheme of things
it's not a big deal at all I'm so
grateful for the opportunity to go to
school because not a lot of people have
the opportunity and I don't know I'm
just being down on myself for some
reason talk about something uplifting so
this past weekend I stayed in LA with my
sister and on Saturday we got the
opportunity to volunteer for this
organization called Habitat for Humanity
so basically this organization helps
low-income families get a home and we
have the opportunity to help paint
houses for low-income families a lot of
these low-income families are actually
there that
a to help paint their own home which was
really cool we had the chance to talk to
one of the guys that was getting their
home through this organization they buy
their own home but I think they get some
help through the organization but he's
getting a home in Pasadena and they were
in LA but he was just volunteering for
the organization which was really good
and this opportunity just made me feel
so grateful for what I have and it
really opened up my eyes to the
opportunities that I have and I think
that it was such perfect timing because
all this school shenanigans has been on
my mind lately and yeah sometimes you
just got to take a breather and just
realize how grateful we should all be I
mean I always complain about living at
home but in reality I'm so lucky to have
parents that have allowed me to stay at
home for so long to save money to go to
school and actually you know go to
school for something that I really like
so I'm really grateful for that and I
know that I'm being hard on myself for
not finishing school in four years let
alone five or six and so many feelings
of I wish I tried harder in high school
I wish I tried harder my first year of
college so many feelings like that has
come up through my school journey but I
think it's just best to keep moving
forward and to find new ways to study
find new ways to get better grades I
feel like I'm finding new ways to become
a better student I feel like we've been
in school for so long but we were
actually never taught to properly study
and you know there are different study
methods for different types of people so
you know what even though this school
journey has been so frustrating for me
and so exhausting I feel like I'm
becoming a better person and learning
new things about myself that I wouldn't
have learned if my school journey was
easy so there are things to be grateful
about when it comes to being set back by
things that you see as failures but they
aren't failures
they're actually opportunities want to
end this video on a positive note and
give you guys some positivity when it
comes to school or just life in general
I hope you guys are having a great day
and I hope this video helped you in any
way please comment down below any
questions you guys have about community
college up to connect with people in any
way that I can I want to give you guys
advice on stuff that I would do
differently if I was 18 straight out of
high school so I definitely have a lot
of advice for you guys if you guys need
it but I know that things are gonna be
ok
and I feel like the internet needs more
of these videos because I don't know I
feel like Instagram YouTube Twitter
everything is so curated to make your
life so perfect bonus Lea this is what
I've been going through and even though
I like making fun videos like fashion
videos and get ready of me and vlogging
my trips that is not my complete life
and yeah thank you so much for watching
if you are and I just wanted to be
vulnerable about my school situations
that I can help you guys in any way that
I can for all you people in college or
just feeling like you're stuck in life I
promise that it's going to get better
and you're not alone all the cliches but
thank you so much for watching this
video that's pretty much all I have to
say thank you so much I'm sending love
to all of you guys and have a wonderful
day or night wherever you are I