hello everyone welcome back to my
channel so today I wanted to do a get
ready with me plus answering the growing
up Asian American tag so I'll just be
getting ready and answering each
question the first question is which
ethnicity are you and I am Tony's
American the second question is which
generation are you and my sister and I
were born here and my parents came from
Taiwan so I think that makes us
first-generation also I'm going to start
getting ready so I'm gonna put all of
the products that I'm using down in the
description below third question is what
is the first experience where you felt
that demarcation of being a minority
and/or different so the first time I
felt that was definitely and I think
third or fourth grade I was at lunch and
my mom had packed me basically like rice
with like veggies like different side
dishes that I could eat with my rice and
I remember everyone else was eating like
a sandwich that their parents packed or
they bought lunch so like pizza chicken
tenders that sort of thing and I
remember thinking like being really
excited for my lunch first off because I
love like Asian food and basically I
opened my lunch up and then everyone was
like oh what is that smell like what
what are you eating and I definitely
felt very obviously judged for what I
was eating and it made me feel really
bad and the way people were talking
about my food and just kind of judging
what I was eating made me feel like oh I
don't really want to eat this anymore I
want to just eat whatever anyone else is
eating even though I would have been
happier eating what my mom packed but
for all the questions and comments that
I was getting I basically going forward
I just always bought lunch like
had pizza and chicken fingers and
hamburgers at school and it's sad
because I was much happier eating my
lunch that my mom packed but because of
what everyone was saying I decided that
I wanted to buy lunch the fourth
question is were you always proud of
your heritage or was there a time you
rejected it there was definitely a time
I rejected it and I would say it was
definitely at those like late elementary
school years all the way up to like high
school maybe and it was tough because I
knew I already physically looked
different and I didn't want people to
just point it out or notice that even
more whether that be through the food I
was eating the stuff I was wearing the
things I was saying and that's why I
hated when people asked me like where
are you from because that was so just an
obvious question that made people sure
that I was different but I remember when
I was young when people asked me like
where are your parents from I would
always say Taiwan and then no one knew
where Taiwan was at that time this was
probably like early elementary school
nobody knew and people would say oh
Thailand and I would say oh no Taiwan
and then no one would know where that
was so then I would just end up saying
oh my parents are from China so I said
that for quite a few years actually and
then later on when I went to university
that's when I started saying Taiwan
again and people actually started
knowing where Taiwan was which was quite
impressive and I think Taiwan over the
past 10 15 20 years has definitely up
their tourism so that has definitely
helped it gain some more traction and
more people are just a little bit
familiar with the country this question
is what are some stereotypes that you
struggle with the very obvious one is
that as an
you're smart and you're expected to get
good grades and even though that is true
like our parents do expect us to get
good grades I think it gave me a lot of
pressure knowing that I had to be smart
I should have done better in class I
should have gotten a better score and it
also didn't help that people
automatically look at you and think oh
you're Asians are smart so you're a nod
so you're not cool and it made me kind
of wish that I wasn't smart I wish that
like I didn't have that stereotype and
people didn't think of me that way so I
remember when I was younger I would
always pretend that I didn't do as well
in class or I wouldn't be as interested
in academics as I actually was just to
appear cool and to fit in but now I'm
super proud to be known as smart I think
that's a great thing and I think
especially when you're working and
people have this smart impression of you
that's so beneficial I want to continue
growing my intelligence growing my
smarts and really building my knowledge
because knowledge is priceless this
question is can you speak your language
and yes if you pay attention to my
YouTube you know that I do speak Chinese
and I've been creating some Chinese
videos on here but my Chinese is
definitely not good as far as Taiwanese
I can understand Taiwanese and I can
speak a little bit but it just sounds
really funky eat seven how has being
asian-american affected your
relationship with your parents so it's
definitely affected my relationship with
my parents I remember when I was younger
I hated everything that they put me
through from extracurriculars like
learning to draw going to take piano and
just a ton of extracurriculars I
remember I hated it and I was like why
can't I just go home and do my homework
and
rest and then on Saturdays we have
Chinese school and that was even worse
because like all my friends only had to
go to school five days a week and I had
to go to school six days a week and
learn another language that I didn't
necessarily want to be learning so it
definitely created a lot of tension and
I remember fighting along with my
parents but I'm so grateful that they
put me through all these
extracurriculars and all these Chinese
classes and lessons because I'm so happy
I can speak the language at least
somewhat fluently and I'm so happy that
I don't know that I through doing all
those extra extracurriculars I was able
to build my own skill sets and really
understand what hard work is and
understand just like understand more of
hobbies cultures and what's out there
the eighth question is how do you feel
about your heritage now do you identify
with it and yes I'm so proud to be
Tony's American I definitely identify
with it I love everything about Taiwan
I love Tony's people whenever whenever I
see anyone who just came from Taiwan and
they introduce themselves and obviously
they're here in a different country I
try to really make an effort to let them
know hey like I'm Tony's - I'm Tony's
American I grew up here but I can speak
the language I understand Taiwan and I
want them to feel like they can come
fight and ask me anything and that I'm
here for them because we're all
Taiwanese last question is what is your
favorite thing about being Asian
Americans last year heritage so
Taiwanese American favorite thing about
being Tony's American is definitely
being able to see and understand both
world so the American and also the
Tony's Asian so that's a perspective
that I feel like you definitely don't
get to have unless you're both and I
feel like getting to understand
both cultures both environments both
types of people and just really seeing
the complexity of each culture and the
difference and variety in those cultures
is very astounding where's my Asian
American tag thank you so much for
getting ready with me and I hope this
gave you some perspective and additional
insight as to what it's like growing up
Tony's American in the United States so
thank you so much for watching if you
like this video give it a like leave a
comment letting me know what other
videos you like me to film and most
importantly you don't forget to
subscribe and yeah I'll see you guys
next time
bye