hey guys welcome back so I recently
asked you guys on my Instagram if you
had any questions for me regarding
college life after college finding a job
career anything that had to do with
school and graduation and there's over
there's a good amount of questions I
typed out a hundred questions and I try
to get them down to about thirty maybe a
little more I broke them down into five
sections the first one will be about
context and background about my
experience when I majored in what school
I went to what grades I got I think
grades are important and then the second
section will be finding your thing or
like finding your purpose finding your
career slash calling and then we'll talk
about life post-grad my current career
path which is mostly YouTube and media
and the last section will be about life
advices in general so yeah there's a lot
of questions gonna try to get through
them ASAP and so let's get started thank
you so much Cisco sure for sponsoring
this video they're my favorite online
learning community and you guys up and
around you will know this by now
they're as always offering the first
five hundred people a two month free
trial against this a little bit later
and let's start it how does she know
what you wanted to do I had no idea what
I wanted to do graduating from college I
had no idea I would be sitting here five
years later
making a video about my college
experience what was your major in
college what made you choose I majored
in business and then I chose that
because it could double in a lot of
things within business because there's
marketing there's finance there's
accounting there's so many things within
business out allowed for flexibility for
me to choose and for me to figure out as
I go how to be happy when you're in a
university which is in your dream
university you can always transfer the
only colleges that I got into after high
school were state colleges in California
saw the Cal States and UC Riverside I
went to UC Riverside because that was
the best option and they gave me a
decent amount of scholarship I knew
going in like this is the most important
part I knew going and I was going to
sir regardless if it was one year two
year three years I was going to transfer
to either a butter you see better
you see UCLA UC Berkeley or I was in a
transferred to USC and thankfully
everything worked out within one year so
as with anything in life if there's a
way if there's a will if there's a will
there's a way
you have to peel did you work during
school and if so how did you find
balance
I worked every summer starting from my
junior year of high school it's you know
year of college I was working while I
was going to school so I stacked there's
something here that wants to come out
but it's not coming out I stuck to my
classes on Tuesdays and Thursdays so
it's from like 8 a.m. to 4 p.m. or 6
p.m. all day I packed back-to-back
classes so that Monday Wednesdays and
Fridays I could work and I was working
at a social media agency are great
important and we stress about getting
good grades so much that we don't live
in the moment
this is tricky I want to say no but it's
also a yes because it really depends on
what you want to do after you graduate
the internships that I have one was out
of granola bar company called this bar
same size for every bar that you I they
will give a life-saving bar to a kid in
need it's kind of like palm a for-profit
before good one for one model so I
worked out companies like that most of
my other friends are going to consulting
and us my making because those are like
the legit jobs and when you were in a
hyper-competitive environment where
everyone's studying business and I was
in a business fraternity you kind of get
tunnel vision and you just want to be
the best and that's kind of what the
best things were but I was like I'm just
gonna do me even if people think I'm not
as legit which they did they thought I
was in legit because I didn't have a
fancy job but I was like I just gonna do
me someone I wanna be happy grand scheme
of things I don't think grades matter at
all because the fact that we're alive
and that we're breathing and that we
were born it's like a one thing a
billionth chance so why limit ourselves
and wide to find ourselves by grades but
then again if you know a career want and
grades are important then increase are
important do you have good grades in
university I graduated with barely a 3.0
I think I had a 3.0 one or three
so no but I'm proud of myself for
graduating with a third point above a
3.0 GPA how do you stay happy in college
through all of this dress so I say happy
through drinking and partying and going
to raves and having fun with my friends
and I put more emphasis on that than I
did on my studies but the thing is I
kind of shot myself in the foot because
I wasn't even happy when I was doing
that I was doing that because I was
avoiding reality I was avoiding my
responsibility some of the thoughts in
my head and I was avoiding myself I was
avoid facing myself so what I wish this
upon anyone else I don't think so but I
would say that I think it's so important
to enjoy our youths I don't regret
anything I did because now that I'm here
I'm like okay been there done that never
want to be there again but I know what
it's like so I think it's important that
omits airing yourself in books and
studying to your head out every once in
a while oh wow
have fun with your friends go enjoy
being a teen or like a 20-something year
old because we're never gonna get that
back the older you get the more
responsibilities you have and I guess on
that note if I could do it all over
again
I would spend more time getting to know
myself for sure I didn't know how to do
it back then looking inward reflecting
asking myself the hard questions so that
I'm not just like avoiding and running
away all the time and also to not take
office hours professors school like
offerings like our school or
universities there's so many resources
that I just completely like I didn't
care most important thing I took for
granted was the proximity and which I
lived with my friends now I'm in New
York most of my friends are in San
Francisco or LA so it's like you can't
really you know I suck at keeping in
touch the phones and messages like I'm
really good with people when I'm like
face-to-face but I'm terrible with
keeping up with people they're texting
so that's something I'm working on but
that's that how to be mindful over your
future rather than let fear of it stress
you out so I'm reading this really great
book called 10% happier and I'm gonna
quote starving is fine as long as is
tempered by the realization that in
entropic universe the final outcome is
out of your control if you don't waste
your energy on variables you cannot
influence you can focus much more
effectively on those you can when you're
wisely ambitious you do everything you
can to succeed but you're not attached
to the outcome either this is the most
important you're not attached to the
outcome so that if you fail you will be
maximally resilient able to get up dust
yourself off and get back in the fray do
you believe in 5-year plans or do you
think you should take life as a hits yet
so I was firm believer in the five-year
plan in the one three five and ten-year
plan that was textbook Rowena but over
the years especially when I started
YouTube I just realized that life is
constantly changing cuz you want to
control it you can so I've learned to
accept and embrace uncertainty as my
reality instead of trying to line
everything down to the T because no
matter how much you plan things are
gonna happen things aren't gonna go
according to plan
historically I've been a very J like a
hardcore J from the myers-briggs like
judgment document pull something with
the J I've learned to become more
perceiving I've learned to become more
go with the flow take life as it comes
like enjoy the breeze and not to be so
you know with planning so yeah I think
I'm more of the latter now take life as
it hits yeah that made me giggle okay
what can I do to support my bestie who
is in college and horribly burnt out no
I'd say kidnap your bestie to go on a
BFF date and if she's like I cannot
leave my studies for more than X amount
of time then just take her to grab food
get her mind off of her studies when
you're so in something you need to be
peeled out and peeled off and I think in
retrospect me and all my friends as much
as we might have not like do the moment
you're like ripping us away from our
studies in the long run it was like
thank you think now looking back instead
of like thank you for looking out for me
what do I do if I can't find a purpose
right after school I'm scared of
becoming stagnant the thing with finding
your purpose I was a solution when I
thought that after I found my purpose my
life would just be smooth sailing now
you will find your purpose and then
you'll be tested again and you'll kind
of forget and you'll find it again and
they'll kind of lose it again and they
kind of find it again I mean that's just
life we as humans are constantly
changing and growing so our North Star
may be implanted in the sky for the
foreseeable future but the closer you
get to it you might be able to see it
from a different perspective
so although your North Star doesn't
change you're constantly changing and
the way in which you get to that North
Star or let fall of that North Star may
also change this wall so I think what's
most important is to never stop learning
always stay curious
with a growth mindset you can't go wrong
and you won't be stagnant because if
you're always willing to learn if you're
always questioning if you're always
curious about the world around you
that's the recipe for not staying
stagnant a few ways that I've continued
to learn after I graduated
one is through reading I love business
and self-help books and I just recently
got into more like fiction books I think
sometimes are too wild and crazy' for me
but it is great to let your mind explore
and implant your brain into different
universes every once in a while and
another way is through online courses
like Skillshare so Scotia is an online
learning community with over 25,000
classes and design business creativity
anything arts you can think of how to
edit videos how to paint there's
actually a course on there that I want
to share with you guys it's called
discovering success 7 exercises to
uncover your purpose passion and hat I
think this is great for anyone who is
kind of like what do I do
I kind of have this creative thing that
I want to do but there's also this like
more stable financially sound path that
I want to walk like which path do I take
she does a really good job of breaking
everything down and I talked about these
things in my older videos but never end
up like this so it's like redefining
what success means to you breaking free
of
going back to the beginning listening to
what you love choosing a direction
managing your time money strategies so I
think all of these are really important
things and topics there's not as many
crash courses on this like you don't
learn about these things in school this
is something you're interested in the
first 500 people will get a two-month
premium membership trouble which will
give you access to all of the courses on
Skillshare so there's that moving on I
got rejected from nursing school three
times that I don't know what to do from
here do I change paths I think this
comes down to how badly do you want to
be a nurse if you know it is your life's
calling if you know I must be a nurse
because you love helping people and you
want to help save lives then keep
applying and don't take no for an answer
and I think this is with anything in
life any job that you're thinking of if
you want something badly enough you're
gonna keep trying until you get it yes
but if you ask yourself and you're like
I think I want to be a nurse because
it's what is expected of me or it's what
I thought I should do because of
something other than what you wanted to
do for yourself then maybe maybe it's a
sign from the universe that you should
pivot but these answers only we will
know when we spend the quiet hours with
our own thoughts
late at night or early in the mornings
when you're just questioning everything
okay
advice on choosing the career you want
versus the career that pays better it's
tough so there's two things the first
thing I would say is the career that
pays well is like a steady pay right and
the baby by the time you're 60 you're
like here the career that you want may
not pay well in the beginning there's
three years five years you might be
making nothing but the potential of it
growing exponentially is a lot more than
that like stable career path or there's
a lot more potential and possibility for
it to grow so that's the first thing
question that I ask myself is long-term
fulfillment versus short-term
satisfaction I think a stable career
path definitely falls into short-term
satisfaction because you don't really
have to think about most things and you
have your life planned out for you
long-term for fulfillment if you're
gonna eventually do what you want to do
which is what I think most rational
humans go through that's why we have
midlife crises where we doubt everything
and we question everything and we look
back and like why did I live my life for
the past five decades like this when
it's not what I wanted to do or it's not
who I am what really helped me stay true
to my path and to not waver when I wave
I wavered a lot actually but what helped
me stay grounded was that if you're
going to go down this path eventually
might as well go down went now how to
stay positive when others are doubting
my next steps I really think it's
self-awareness if you know yourself well
enough you know what you're doing if you
know why you're doing what you're doing
which can change and which can be cloudy
at times but if you have a decent enough
understanding it'll allow you to not
care as much about what others say or
tell you but that being said it's good
to it's good to listen to what other
people are saying and it's good to
listen to their advices whether you take
it or not it's fully up to yourself okay
advice for graduates who've decided to
take creative and unconventional paths I
don't know why that was so choppy and
what I was just reading it I think the
hardest part is over taking that leap of
faith leaving in yourself and working
through all the knots and a mess in your
head to be like I'm gonna do this so
keep doing it but also remember if you
have to pivot and change your course and
change your path as you walk this path
it's not failure right you're not
failing if you didn't do the thing you
set out to do I think life is a
continual process of iterations and
pivoting and changing and I've always
thought a path is like this but I think
life is actually more like this and
sometimes like you know okay what helped
you find your purpose and how did you
know that you found it this question is
gonna take way too long I'll link to
videos down below I mean I hate when
people do this because like just told me
no but seriously I have
other videos one is about I created my
dream job and the second is how I found
my life purpose so those two will be
linked down below below how many years
passed after graduation when you were
content with your place and life so I
was content the day I graduated I was so
happy the day I graduated I was like yes
I don't know school wasn't really for me
I don't really learn in that like school
environment I wasn't good at taking
tests in Foley I didn't let that define
me too much because I knew I had
strengths outside of taking tests but
when I finally felt like I could breathe
and that I could look at myself in the
mirror and tell myself you did well
Romina child he did well it was actually
earlier this year most difficult
adjustment you had to make going into
life post graduation I think the most
difficult thing I think it's not
comparing myself to those around me
because the path that I chose for myself
was very different it wasn't what other
people were doing and it's so easy to
look around me and to be like all of my
friends already started working all my
friends are you started making money all
my friends they're doing the things
already and it just felt like I was
gonna fall behind I already fell behind
because I didn't go down that path but
then I just kept reminding myself the
whole short-term satisfaction versus
long-term game
short-term satisfaction would have been
to that my ego and to do what I thought
I should do a I knew long-term that was
gonna make me happy what do you wish you
had done in your final year to prepare
you for life
after graduation I think going back to
what I said earlier I wish I spent more
time in here like trying to work out
this and like this and being a better
friend to myself and trying to get to
know myself better because I did a lot
of that after graduating but if I
started doing that in college I think
that would have helped a lot a lot has
graduation helped define you as a person
and what success means to you has
uh not really I feel like I don't really
talk about USC at all after graduating I
realized I like found my definition of
sex
and it definitely wasn't my grades it
wasn't the fact that I graduated it
wasn't the job that I would get nothing
success to me at that time was just
being able to find the answer to what it
means to live a meaningful and
fulfilling life I think that was what my
definition was of success at that time
and it's constantly changing I think now
for me talks about this in my podcast
with Eileen from lab and dare I think
success to me now me it just means like
being able to go to sleep at night
content with how the day went I mean
it's very like there's a lot of layers
to that and me being able to go to sick
content is that I did my best and
everything that I could during the day
for work by helping people because my
work is trying to help people in many
different ways either through beating
with it or through my own personal
channel so there's a lot of layers to
that by think at the end of the day like
the our definition of success should be
defined by ourselves and it's normal if
it changes over time because we're
constantly changing as people ever felt
lost professionally post-college if so
how did you deal slash break out of it
yeah dude I felt professionally lost up
until I'd say last year so I graduated
2014 2014 to 15 16 17 18 for years for
years I was like what am I doing with my
life did I make the right decisions why
am I here what is the right path is
there even a right path and the answer I
talked about in last week's video I
don't really think there is a right path
I think our path is a culmination of the
decisions we've made in our lives and
eventually it like it's there already if
you believe in fate if you believe in
destiny like our path is there we just
need to walk it and if so how did you
deal / break out of it just have to keep
walking even if it's blind faith even if
it's with mustering every ounce of
courage you have in the depths of your
soul - just like trust yourself and
trust the universe to move forward and
it goes back to learning staying curious
trying your best and not being attached
to the end results how difficult was it
to move to New York City did you do it
it wasn't difficult at all and yes I did
it alone
how long did it take to fully transition
from moving across the country to New
York I think because I moved around so
often when I was young it just like it
wasn't a thing I just knew I needed I
want it to be in New York and so I just
went and I just lived and I it just kind
of happened
did you want to continue studying to
avoid working absolutely not I hated
studying I couldn't wait to graduate
from high school college I think I had
more fun but I also know that I don't
like studying at all all right now we're
gonna move to career /youtube I think
I'll do a separate video answering your
guys's questions about YouTube starting
YouTube wanting to start YouTube advice
for starting YouTube but this one is a
little it's a little more broad how do
you decide what to do in life / as a
career when you're not sure what do you
enjoy I think just constant forward
movement or just constant movement it
could be lateral it could be vertical it
could be any type of movement but as
long as you're trying as long as you're
actively engaging yourself and
everything in you to try new things you
will find your thing eventually when I
graduated I thought I was gonna start my
own business that didn't happen we can
just say it failed I thought I was gonna
code cuz I love tech startup so I was
like I could do that UX UI that seems
really cool but like that also didn't
really go anywhere because I couldn't
like I just I can like the coding
language just symbols and numbers just
they didn't work with me and my
neighbor's dog is just right outside so
if I hear the dog barking went into
media work never in a million years what
I thought I would work in journalism or
at a media company because my focus was
very a tech and business and then
started my youtube channel and start
helping on beauty within it just kind of
all came together as I like progressed
in life and there are this whole journey
it was a lot of a lot of wavering a lot
of back-and-forth a lot of doubting a
lot of questioning of what it's the
right path what is the right thing to do
that's why I said it or a little
that there really is no right path just
keep walking and keep believing in
yourself keep questioning yourself like
healthily questioning yourself I'm
reminding yourself of who you are and
what you're doing why are you doing what
you're doing and then eventually the
path will reveal itself as it did with
me yeah
when should I really start applying for
jobs this is really up to you if you
want advice as a Marshall School
graduate you would start your sophomore
year of college applying for internships
because that's how competitive people
are nowadays you get an internship
sophomore junior year at a big firm they
will most likely give you an offer
when you graduate your senior year but
if you ask Rowena Rowena
when's the best time to apply for
college it's up to you maybe you don't
want to apply to jobs maybe you do want
to apply to jobs what jobs do you want
to apply for I think those are questions
that only we'll be able to answer for
yourself do companies actually prefer
someone with a college degree for a job
in your industry so I think it depends
if you want to work on like the agency
side I think it helps to have a degree
to ten extent most corporations do look
at your as a man they kind of do care
what that like you went to college at
least but what I am doing right now like
as a creator you can have zero degree
and you can create content anyone can
create content how to find work in the
media industry when it's so competitive
so I think with this it's it doesn't
matter if it's media it doesn't matter
what industry that you're going for I
think going back to the whole Dyson
analogy of if you want something badly
enough you won't stop until you get a
yes and one thing that I was actually
pretty surprised to find was that you
can use your student card so hard so
reach out to ten people on LinkedIn who
has a job that you might be interested
in and ask for an informational
interview and what this means is that
you can just ask them about their career
ask them about their life their path how
they got there
and you'd be surprised at least two out
of ten people will say yes to you it's a
natural human instinct to want to help
other people if you reach out as a
student and you say like hey I'm not
really sure what I want to do with my
life maybe you don't say that'd be a
little more professional but if you
allude to that then the person reading
it like a professional reading that
would be like oh I remember what it was
like when I graduated so like yes yes
yes I will help you asking people who
already there for their thoughts and
their advice that's really probably like
the best way to go and also send your
resume to as many people as you can
don't be afraid of being annoying
message recruiters keep in touch with
recruiters there's a lot that you can do
go to career fairs get to know the
recruiters from different companies that
you want to work at there's a lot yeah
not being afraid of getting nose and
also not being afraid of being mildly
moderately annoying persistence
for the most part will always work in
your favor and moving on to the last
section of life advice
what are lessons you've learned in
college that you still value today what
did I learn in college I think I learned
a lot about what I don't want to do and
how I don't want to feel yeah I think
that's probably the biggest takeaway how
lost and how alone and how down I felt
it's really good gauge for me to never
return to that lifestyle and that stage
of my life the partying the drinking the
avoiding the running away the not facing
myself not facing my reality yeah I
think that's probably the biggest
takeaway one piece of advice you give
yourself if you went back in time to
2014 everything that I say will probably
be very cliche but I think the most
important thing would be you're not
alone everything will work out don't
stop dreaming and keep fighting for what
you believe in yeah I think those are
like the four most important things
yeah this is why my child only do this
if I can help even one you guys for less
alone and less crazy for dreaming the
way you dream and for wanting to do the
things that want to do then I've
succeeded navigating life is never easy
finding your purpose is never easy
finding your Y is never easy and it's
it's the most difficult because it's
something that we have to do and we can
only do on our own but we don't have to
as in like the answers you will find
yourself and it's like it's very
personal but the journey you don't have
to go through that alone and I think
that's what I learned few years after I
graduated so with all of that I hope
this video was helpful and that you guys
got something out of it and if you have
any questions feel free to leave it down
below I'll do my best to answer to as
many of the comments as I can and even
if you guys read comments that you feel
like you can answer or help each other
by all means please do this is why we
have such a beautiful community because
you guys do help each other when you see
it so with that thank you guys so much
for watching and thanks again to Scotia
for sponsoring this video if you want to
continue learning if you want to
continue growing they're a great
resource and with that see you guys in
next week's video oh also follow me on
Instagram if you want to ask questions
like this okay bye