a lot of asian-americans talk about how
they can't identify as either Asian or
American but I couldn't really identify
as Asian American or Asian American
because all of the asian-americans that
were surrounding me were
chinese-american hello what is up
internet people today I have a very
special video to share with you guys and
that is the growing up as an
asian-american tag this tag was created
by vagabond youth so obviously I'm going
to be speaking about myself today which
is a Vietnamese American which is
different from her video which is about
being korean-american and I haven't seen
any videos like this so far about being
Vietnamese American so if you do know
any other videos that are similar let me
know so I can check it out so question
number one is what ethnicity are you
I am Vietnamese American question number
two which generation are you so my
parents immigrated here from Vietnam so
I'm the first generation born here what
is the first experience of where you
felt that demarcation of being a
minority or different so this question I
have a really long answer to because
it's kind of two parts the part of me
that realized that I was Asian which is
different from being white and the part
of me that realized that I was
Vietnamese which is different from being
any other type of Asian as soon as I
entered kindergarten I realized that I
was a different type of Asian than other
Asians because obviously kindergarten is
the first time I was like really
conscious of my classroom setting there
were a lot of other Asians in my class
and there were all Chinese Americans so
pretty much people would always ask me
if I was Chinese and I would have to
tell them no I'm Vietnamese and at that
age no one knew what Vietnam was so I
would basically have to tell everyone
that Vietnam is a different country
besides China and at that age I didn't
even have any concept of really what a
country was but I always told people
that it had something to do with the
Vietnam War because I knew that my
parents were refugees and that's why
they came here
but it was all very confusing for me and
all I knew was that all these other
Asians were all Chinese and they were
all different for me
so aside from realizing that I really
didn't have to deal with that many other
times where I realized that I was
different from people up until like high
school and in high school is when I
really started to realize that I was
Asian and that's different from being
growing up in the town that I did all of
these kids around me from kindergarten
to high school they had all been my
friends so I felt like they didn't treat
me differently for being Asian
however in high school when I was
thinking about my future I was talking
to my mom and I said I wanted to be an
English teacher and my mom taught in
schools before and she kind of
discouraged me from being an English
teacher because she said that the
students that I taught would tell me
that my English was poor because I was
Asian so back to the point of my
differentiating between being Vietnamese
or any other type of Asian this was
something that I struggled with for a
long time because all throughout high
school I found that I couldn't identify
with the Chinese kids because they
always went to like Chinese family
parties or Chinese school or Chinese
dance that was like really popular for
all the cool Asians but I wasn't a part
of any of that so growing up I didn't
have any other Vietnamese friends so I
was pretty isolated a lot of Asian
Americans talk about how they can't
identify as either Asian or American but
I couldn't really identify as Asian
American or Asian American because all
of the Asian Americans that were
surrounding me were Chinese American and
I didn't have really any kind of voice
in that community however I do think
that this played a lot into the person
that I am today because it basically
allowed me to form a complete
personality without having to do with my
race or ethnicity at all so I basically
focus all of my attention into my
athletics which at the time was running
track I kind of just built my community
around that rather than through my
cultural relationships with other people
in my school fast forward into college
college was the first time that I really
had exposure to other Vietnamese
American friends and it was definitely
the first time in my life that I was
like wow this is cool like you know my
food you know my language however at
this point in my life I had already
developed such a strong sense of self
like without the Vietnamese American
attached to it that I actually found
that I had not that much in common with
any of these Vietnamese Americans
because all of these people too had
grown up with other Vietnamese Americans
in Vietnamese communities and I just
found that the aspects of my personality
that
we're the strongest were the ones that I
developed free from race but other than
that I have a really good experience
growing up I really wasn't really
bullied by white people for being Asian
until actually college which i think is
really weird so when I was 18 I was
bullied for being Asian and I feel like
that's pretty weird into my adulthood I
noticed my being Asian a lot more maybe
it's because in the world that we live
in now people are kind of more racist I
don't know
the next question is were you always
proud of your heritage or was there a
time that you rejected it so during
those early years when everyone was
asking me if I was Chinese I thought it
would be really really convenient to
just be Chinese because then I wouldn't
have to explain to everyone what being
vain amis is all about I also feel like
my family kind of pushed on me to kind
of reject the Vietnamese side of things
specifically because with Vietnam at the
end of the Vietnam War my parents and a
bunch of other people had to leave the
country because if they didn't they
would literally be killed so for a lot
of Vietnamese Americans the Vietnam that
exists today is not the same Vietnam
that it was back then the country was
split in two and there was like
communist and non-communist people often
say it's like north and south but it's
not quite as obvious as north and south
because there were non communists in
both and the people from one had to flee
to the other to be safe from the
Communists basically so anyway my family
is non communist so they had to leave at
the end of the war and then basically
never come back so from an early age
they weren't really trying to force
being Vietnamese on to me like we did
speak Vietnamese in the house when I was
young but as I grew up we just spoke
English in the house however probably
around third grade or so or whenever my
brain was starting to develop into like
an independent consciously thinking
human being I was really proud that my
parents were refugees and I was really
proud of the way that they came to this
country that they survived that they
literally came here dirt poor couldn't
even like enter the country had to like
work in these terrible terrible jobs
didn't speak the language and they just
did whatever they could to build the
life that they have now and it was
something that I was like so so proud of
the majority of my chinese-american
friend
kind of just came here because their
families had money and could just move
here and like give them this life
whereas my parents literally had nothing
and we're able to still give me the same
kind of upbringing and I honestly am
just so so proud of my heritage now what
are some stereotypes that you struggle
with so this question is kind of funny I
think because I just think stereotypes
are like so funny
like sometimes I rooted in truth
obviously that's like how they come to
be because people just make these
observations and then say that it's true
about a whole slew of people which is
obviously not true but number one is
everyone thinking that I'm Chinese or
that all agents are Chinese it's my pet
peeve now it's literally like people
know that if they want to make me mad
just call me Chinese or like try to
speak Chinese to me and I know that for
a lot of people it's difficult to be
able to tell different types of Asians
but I also kind of think that you know
people my age should definitely be able
to tell the difference now at least
between East Asians and Southeast Asians
like at this point you should know that
like China and Korea and Japan those are
like East Asia and that Southeast Asia
is like Vietnam Laos Cambodia whatever
Thailand but not everyone knows that but
I just think it's kind of funny even
though it does really annoy me so please
don't ever call me Chinese I also do get
like a ton of comments on one of my
videos it's like the only video that
anyone ever watches but the video is
about living in New Zealand and so
everyone's just like we don't want you
in New Zealand go back to China club a
lot and I'm just like I literally say in
this video that I'm Vietnamese but ok so
the second big stereotype that I have to
deal with is everyone thinking that I'm
good at math I decided that I wanted to
study math in uni because I was so bad
at it in high school you know
Asians are stereotypically supposed to
be like good at math and science in my
high school I was placed into honors and
in honors I like got seasoned D's and
F's and then I overrode again into
honors even though they were like
suggesting that I go down a level I just
like wanted to be in honors because all
the other kids were in honors that I
felt like I should be with and just kept
getting FS in
there was one time that I got like a
thirty or something and I just started
crying and I was just like why am I in
this class and then I dropped down a
level and I realized I was like wow
actually I understand all of this like
it's not that I'm bad at math it's just
like I was in the wrong level basically
and then I realized that like it was so
cool to be a math teacher
and I just was like I just want to be a
math teacher because I want to show kids
that it's not that they're bad at math
it's just like the way people are
teaching them or the level that they're
at etc so basically it was like because
I was bad at math that I decided that I
wanted to study math to be able to prove
to people that even if you're bad at
something you can keep persevering and
you can do better so anyway in the
university I'm a math major or I was a
math major I've graduated now but the
first thing that you ask someone when
you meet them is like oh so what's your
major and I literally would just lie
about my major I would say I'm like
communications or nursing or something
because I would never want to tell
people that I was a math major because
well one I kind of was like yeah I don't
want to like be stereotypical Asian and
then two I didn't want to be made fun of
for actually being bad at math so if I
tell people that I'm a math major
they're always like oh classic
I'm just like what does that mean number
three is yellow fever it's the idea that
I'm exotic and fun well I am ecstatic
it's fun but not because I'm Vietnamese
or Asian but yeah all these guys are
like oh you Vietnamese goddess you blah
blah blah I'm just like okay there are
definitely certain types of stereotypes
about what Asian girls should be like as
a romantic partner but I am definitely
not any of those stereotypes and I feel
like it's pretty obvious once you meet
me that I'm not submissive the next
question is can you speak your language
I can speak my language probably at like
a third graders level so basically it
was my first language and then I only
use it to communicate within a domestic
household setting so all of the phrases
I can say have to do with activities or
food so I can say like I'm gonna go to
school or can I get a sandwich
I did go to Vietnam for the first time
last year and I was able to communicate
more or less enough next question is how
has being asian-american affected your
relationship with your parents growing
up my mom was like a pretty
stereotypical tiger mom but I also was
raised Catholic Christian and then she
switched and she became Buddhist and
then the Buddhism really affected a lot
of my upbringing really really really
really shaped the way I think and look
at the world now so that was a big part
of it and then also during that switch
she kind of switched to and became less
of a tiger mom that tiger mom this was
probably necessary as a kid because I
think when I was younger I was kind of
like a brat but she kind of like
disciplined me enough so that I didn't
become like a brat in my adulthood I
think if she had kept being really
strict I would have become really
rebellious and that would have like
ruined our relationship but she kind of
became more understanding and lacs which
is kind of part of the Buddhist
philosophy is like not being so uptight
about things so question number eight is
how do you feel about your heritage now
and do you identify with it I 100%
absolutely identify with my culture I am
so proud of being Vietnamese especially
now that I visited Vietnam for the first
time last year I finally feel like I'm
not like a poser anymore like I actually
am Vietnamese American it plays a huge
role in my identity today and in my
personality and I think that if you take
away my being Vietnamese I would be a
completely different person
and the last question is what is your
favorite thing about your heritage /
what is your favorite thing about being
asian-american I think that specifically
being Vietnamese American I'm more
cultured because in my experience I was
the only person that was Vietnamese so I
did have this whole Vietnamese culture
surrounding my family life but then
because I was only one in my whole town
I had to learn about all these other
cultures so I learned a lot about
American culture obviously like all
other Asian Americans but then I also
learned about Chinese culture for my
Chinese friends and Indian culture for
my Indian friends Brazilian culture etc
all the other friends that
had I really was able to be exposed to
all those things because I was forced to
because I didn't have anyone to relate
to but yeah I am very very happy of my
heritage and being asian-american and I
just feel so blessed to have been part
of the family that I was part of or that
I am a part of so yeah you want to see
more videos like this or more videos for
me please just subscribe to me as well
I'd really really appreciate that
and I will see you guys in my next video
bye