hello what is up internet people so the
last video I uploaded was sort of a
recap of my 22nd year I did a lot of
travel and I'm going to be doing a lot
of travel again this year just realize
that it would be a good idea to take you
guys with me and share more of my
experiences with you so ultimately
that's my goal in making these videos
but also I'd love for you guys to get to
know me I'd love to get to know you so
after watching this video please also
give a comment some fact about yourself
that way I can get to know you guys and
I hope you enjoyed this video my
favourite physical feature about myself
is I have two matching freckles right
here and I call them Pikachu cheeks but
yeah it's my favorite physical feature
about myself so I was born on the Lunar
New Year like I came out into the year
of the rat but we consider me a pig
because I was conceived in the year of
the pig and I was in the womb for the
entire year of the pig so I consider
myself a pig with like some rat
qualities similarly in terms of the
zodiac I was born on the cusp so a lot
of magazines and stuff will say that I'm
a Pisces but I was actually born like
into Aquarius so I identify as an
Aquarius with some Pisces traits I guess
both of these things make it so I have a
split personality
so yeah I'm also wicked indecisive so we
could say that it's because of that so I
can pretty much only do board sports
like I used to skateboard when I was
younger I started snowboarding when I
was in fourth grade I've surfed a lot
but I've never skied in my life and I'm
pretty bad at rollerblading and ice
skating I'm allergic to a lot of things
including cats dust and birch pollen so
a lot of fruits that are grown in my
area are pollinated by birch pollen so
I'm allergic to all of them so pretty
much apples pears peaches cherries plums
anything with like skin that's grown on
a tree that was grown around here but
like if I get foods that were like if I
eat an apple that was grown somewhere
else that didn't have birch pollen in it
then I'm not allergic to it
I actually used to be a scuba diving
assistant laws in college and I'm hoping
to get my dive masters in the next
couple of years I'm really really easily
motion sick so I throw up almost every
time I fly or I'm on a boat but
obviously I love to travel so it really
stinks for me and also I love to be on
boats because I love diving so pretty
much like everything I love also hurts
me I am a certified yoga teacher I'm 200
our prana value which is a type of
vinyasa
I have Grylls I hate being ignored or
ghosted like I know everyone does but
I'm not offended if you're just
straightforward with me and are like I
don't want to talk to you I love The
Fast & Furious series and Paul Walker
was one of my idols still is rest in
peace
to my homie so I've also met a lot of
other role models slash significant
figures in my life I met the Dalai Lama
Grant Gustin Michelle Phan Arden Cho tom
Felton rixton parachute Joseph Vincent
and probably a lot more I don't like
blood and I don't like needles but I do
love tattoos and I have one right now
and I'm getting a couple more I would
like to start getting them in like every
country I visit or like as sort of
passport stamps I get keloid scars so my
next tattoo is actually gonna be a
keloid scar cover-up my favorite author
is har ki Murakami these are two of his
books my favorite books by him are
Norwegian Wood Kafka on the shore the
wind-up bird Chronicles and hard-boiled
Wonderland and the end of the world my
favorite movie director is Hayao
Miyazaki these are my favorite movies by
him Princess Mononoke spirited away and
Howl's Moving Castle I also want tattoos
inspired by those movies my favorite
artist I love art I painted that it made
that my favorite artist is Lawrence I
just some for work though if you can see
but it's pretty dope so she's from the
Netflix TV show Tara's house which is
one of my all-time favorite TV shows my
other ones would probably be the office
and the flash my favorite anime was
Naruto I say that I've been to 20
countries because I'm not honestly sure
how to count like some different
countries so Vietnam Japan and
neasha Laos Thailand the US Canada
Australia New Zealand Dominican Republic
bone Aran Aruba are like technically the
Netherlands so I think that's one Spain
Mexico the Bahamas Fiji Guatemala
England Ireland Scotland I don't know I
want to call that one too and then China
and Iceland
so Vietnamese was my first language and
then English and then Spanish I did for
ten years and did an exchange program to
Spain and then in college I started
learning Japanese and I would someday
like to move to Japan love Japanese
culture the language everything about
Japan pretty much it's probably my
favorite country there's pretty much no
food that I won't eat like one example
of a food I don't love is cooked
tomatoes like I would rather just eat a
tomato raw but I'll still eat it even if
I don't like it my favorite cuisines as
a whole are American southern barbecue
American Chinese food like crab rangoon
sand general GAO's chicken and stuff
like I do love like citron food as well
but like American Chinese food is its
own thing I love that and Vietnamese
food however my favorite dishes would be
sushi shepherd's pie and ramen so my
favorite dishes don't actually fall
under my favorite cuisines I love spicy
food I prefer salty / spicy foods with
sweet drinks or I prefer to mix like
salty and sweet things so like when I go
to the movie theater I put sour patch
kids in my popcorn and it's fire
definitely try it I'll never just crave
chocolate but I'll crave ice cream
especially ice cream cake so I don't
really like bubbly or fizzy drinks and
if I have them I like stir them I've
been catfished before I've met up with
people on bumble hinge and tinder I love
nature and mountains and like looking up
at the sky at night starry sky like
definitely a nature person out of all
the nature I think I like the ocean the
best whether it's swimming surfing or
diving I just feel really alive when I'm
in the water I love learning about
different cultures and meeting new
people and learning new things and
new languages I don't believe in regrets
I prefer compliments about my
personality rather than my looks the
best compliment I've ever received was
that somebody called me resilient and
that meant a lot to me still does I have
friends all over the world but I believe
that the people closest to me and
closest to my heart people that know me
the best I don't have to see them all
the time or even talk to them all the
time if I could have any superpower it
would be to take away other people's
pain this was a superpower that Scott
had in Teen Wolf Monday is my favorite
day of the week
I love taking naps I can also fall
asleep if it's light out I've had pretty
much every hair color and eventually I
want to shave my whole head and then
like grow it out to all the stages pixie
and everything my favorite hair color on
myself as well as my actual favorite
color I think would be red and my last
fact is that I'm 23 years old it was
recently my birthday and up until this
year I hated my birthday specifically
like just something that gave me anxiety
up until this year anyway thank you so
much for watching if you made it to the
end of this I hope you learned some new
things about me I'm sure you did because
I never really shared stuff about myself
and also if you like this video if you
want to see more travel videos please
subscribe to my channel it would be so
nice and lovely I appreciate all of you
so much and again thank you so much for
watching I hope you're all having a
wonderful morning afternoon evening
nighttime whatever time it is wherever
you are in the world and I will see you
guys in my next video bye