good morning my frens
it's actually noon
hello my frens it's nina
and i am currently bare-faced
as you can tell by the title of this video
i am doing a get ready with me
i'm going to do my makeup with you guys because
i'm going to be talking about a certain topic
and i need to be doing stuff with my hands
so i'm doing my makeup
so i was sick for like 16 hours
i don't know what that was
i thought i was actually sick
i had a sore throat and all that
so i thought i was actually sick
and i was really shook
i thought i couldn't film a video
but i took one day to rest
then i'm fine now
i don't know what happened
that was a weird experience
but i'm okay for now
my throat is kind of okay
my nose, i might sound a little different
but that's fine
but as you can tell by the title of this video
i am going to be doing a get ready with me
as i talk about a certain topic
and i'm going to talk about a topic
that i feel like is interesting for you guys
and really just explains a lot about me
so i am korean american
i was born in america
but ethnically
my family is entirely from korea
i was the first one born in america
and so, korean american
i also don't know what that is
i don't know if it's a pimple or if it's a mosquito bite
whatever it is i haven't touched it
because i'm not dealing with it
i'm just gonna let it heal on its own
whatever it is
i don't know what you are but
you better leave soon
my makeup routine's actually really short
so i might finish my makeup
before i even finish talking about my story
so don't mind that
just, if you're actually getting ready
just keep going
anyway, so about being korean american
even though i'm the first to be born in america
i am a second generation korean american
now you're probably wondering how that works
well
so i was born in america
which makes me culturally very american
because that's all i've ever known
so my dad grew up in korea
he was born there
but then when he was 9 he moved to the US
with his family
with his mom and sister
and then started a life here
so he's considered the first generation or 1.5 generation
because he was the one to really first experience
transitioning to the american lifestyle
so his story is definitely very different from mine
because he was an actual immigrant
who came to the US and had to deal with a lot
anyway
he came here when he was still very young
so he was able to pick up the american culture
he had to pick it up really fast because
obviously he had to blend in with everyone else
and he was kind of like
he was the new kid, you know
there weren't a lot of asians where he grew up
i don't think there were really any koreans
or asians around him
but my dad definitely picked up
the american culture very fast
and he can speak english perfectly
he speaks both korean and english very perfectly
the first language he will speak is english
he'll speak korean if he has to
but otherwise he'll just speak in english
he spent literally most of his life in america
so he's definitely very americanized
now moving on from that, my mom
she came to the US for college so she spent
her entire adolescence and youth in korea
so culturally shes korean, very korean
i can't even tell if i finished my bb cream
the first language she will speak is korean
she's culturally very korean
she only really cares about korean
media and entertainment and culture and all that
so the next thing that happened was me being born
i was the first of my entire family to be born in the US
i was born in california, specifically the bay area
so i was fortunate enough to be
growing up in a place that is very diverse
we're very culturally diverse
so i never experienced being
the only asian or the only korean
i was literally surrounded by
a lot of asians and a lot of koreans
so i never felt different in that sense
where i grew up specifically in my city
there were a lot of asians so
i didn't experience that much racism
it was mostly chill because
if you were a racist, you would get attacked, so
so that was good
i didn't go to preschool
i spent most of my life [before school] at home
with my family
my mom my dad and my brother
my one brother because my other brother
was born 14 years after me so
it was first my older younger brother
so we were all just together
so my childhood before school
really was surrounded by my parents
and so i was exposed to both korean and english
which honestly got confusing
and really affected the way that i grew up
because i was having 2 languages
spoken to me at the same time
it did affect the way that i developed language-wise
so because i didn't go to preschool
i kind of missed out on that first year or two
of socializing with other kids
when i first went to kindergarten i actually didn't
understand the concept of going to school
i honestly didn't know what it was
so when my parents dropped me off on the first day
i remember leaving the classroom with them
because i was like
where are they going why are they leaving me here
so i was like following them but then my parents were like
nO you gotta stay here
and i was like
wHAT IS THIS
but yea so
kindergarten was my first exposure to other kids
i was always surrounded by, you know, like
my mom's friend's children
but other than that
this was the first time
i had to be in a social environment
it was terrifying
anyway moving on
when i was in school for the first few years
i experienced sort of being
behind most of my peers
and that was an obvious thing
because i didn't go to preschool
so i was already behind socially
but also
education-wise i was also behind my peers
because
i had both english and korean in my head
that i didn't pick up either language well
so i couldn't speak english that well
i obviously didn't know how to read that well
all that stuff so i was obviously behind my peers
and i was eventually put into an ELD [english language development] program
eVEN THOUGH
my first language was technically never korean
never, i never learned korean and then forgot it
like most people, no
it was never
my first language, or anything like that
so i was just literally developing slowly
just because
it was confusing
so i was put into ELD
which took a toll on my confidence in school
i already felt very behind my peers
and it was kind of just a feeling of
kind of, embarrassment
and shame that, you know,
why am i so behind already
and i was frickin, what, 5?
you know
give me a break
but i was put into ELD
but i left the program so fast too
it was my first year of being
in a social environment, so
i needed time to adjust
i had experiences in the past
where i would experience
kids being mean about me not being so smart
or not so quick
i actually had this one kid
make fun of me for being a slow reader
and i was like
looking back i was like
we're in first grade
what do you expect from me
but there were lots of moments like that
that just kind of
really affected my self-confidence
so growing up, for me, i became more and more distant
from my korean identity
just because as i got older
i was going through a lot of physical changes
and i just physically didn't look korean
or i didn't fit in that well
with my peers
i was tall
or at least bigger than most koreans
so i already felt this physical insecurity
that i didn't look korean
and i also, as i was growing up
because my dad spoke english in the house
and because i only went to american schools
i only picked up english
i didn't pick up korean
because i wasn't very involved
in korean communities growing up
i did have korean friends growing up
and they were a huge part of my life
and they still kind of are
but they're all kind of doing their own things as
everyone really does after high school and all that
i was mostly surrounded by korean friends
just because it was kind of like
being with people who you can relate to
but as i got older, personally for me
my insecurities were getting a little too out of hand
that it started affecting my relationships
with not only just other people but also with myself
i was becoming more self-aware as usually one does
you start to really think about yourself as you grow up
i already carried this insecurity
throughout most of my youth
of being behind other people
just because that's kind of how i grew up
i became more and more insecure about me
not being able to speak korean or
understand korean etiquette and culture
and that kind of stuff
and more and more, i would
make mistakes that affected my self-esteem
i went to korean church and all that
but whenever i was part of these communities
i felt this personal detachment from everyone else
just because i felt like, again
i wasn't blending in
i felt like i was lacking something
and when i was in these korean communities
they would be able to speak to each other
in korean for fun
and i always felt kind of embarrassed
that i couldn't participate like this
it was really more of like a personal insecurity
that i just couldn't communicate
even though it really didn't matter that much
because obviously they could speak english
and it was just a thing they were able to do
and obviously my upbringing was different than them
but because i wasn't very confident in myself already
it really took a toll on just how i felt about myself
and my identity and that kind of stuff
and communicating with korean adults especially
really affected my self-esteem
because i wouldn't be able to communicate with them
and it really just felt embarrassing for me
that i couldn't speak korean and i was just like
i just felt like they were judging me
and the way that i grew up
like
this korean can't speak korean what is she
so it was always a personal kind of feeling
i never really complained about it
just because i didn't want to
or feel like i needed to complain about it
but inside it was very
it was just disappointing for me
that i couldn't participate like this
everyone else could blend in so easily
between being an american and being a korean
and for me
i couldn't really identify with being korean
because i honestly couldn't
relate to the culture or speak the language
so it was just frustrating, really
i was already a pretty socially anxious person
so this adding on to that just
made knowing who i was really difficult
eventually this insecurity of
not blending in with my peers
really got to me and i just
kind of detached myself from these communities
just because i already felt like i didn't belong
even though it really didn't have to go to that extent
it's just personally it got to a point where
i kind of needed to leave
because i didn't feel great about
not being able to communicate in my own language
personally i already felt physically different from
other koreans just because
i have naturally curly hair [not today bc this is 2nd day hair]
which is kind of strange for an east asian
especially for a korean
that's really bright
i honestly still don't know how i have curly/wavy hair
physically i already felt like i didn't belong
and then culturally i obviously didn't
belong in that sense, so i was just like
then what makes me a korean?
and so
at that time i didn't understand the concept of it
so it really got to my self-confidence and my self-esteem
because i really didn't know how to deal with it
so in high school
i was surrounded by a different social group
because my friends were moving around
people were moving on, that kind of stuff
so naturally i went to a new friend group
and my friend group
was entirely not korean
just because that's how things turned out
ok see so i already finished my makeup
actually i should do my mascara
so naturally i had this different friend group
that was not korean
so i didn't have that opportunity to
be immersed in korean culture
just because there was really no tie to it
other than my parents and my family and all that
and nothing in my life really urged me to
be connected to my korean side
i was very much immersed in western culture
i was watching programs from the UK
and stuff from america, american tv shows that kind of stuff obviously
because i'm american
so that's what i was kind of into
i didn't pay much attention to korean media at all
i wasn't watching korean dramas or listening to kpop
or anything in high school, really
because that wasn't part of my social circle
my social environment
and so through that time i was really not emotionally
connected to myself
i was really kind of living every single day
just to get to the next day
and eventually graduate
and i was just having fun
i was very much still insecure in high school
but at that point i wasn't letting it control my life
or affect my life
i was living my life
in high school i really didn't think about being korean
it wasn't something i had to worry about
the crucial point in my journey of being korean american
really happened in my last year of high school
and on from that
there was a personal situation
that affected my entire family
and myself especially
and it was in my last year of high school
when my great-grandma
who was a huge part of my family really
she was dealing with alzheimer's
and she was getting old
and she was in the hospital, and
why did i put mascara on
i probably should've put mascara on after this
this was really wrong timing
in the last part of 2014/2015
my great-grandma
was in the hospital dealing with alzheimer's
we only got to visit my grandma about once a year
just because she lived in a different state
she lived in america
that's how my mom was able to come to the US
because my great-grandma also came
but my great-grandma was
sick and she was dealing with alzheimer's
so she already
couldn't really remember who we were
and because we were only able to visit her once a year
we didn't know
how she was doing, we didn't know
that she got to this point
and
and so she was in the hospital
this was the first time i was dealing with
a family member
being sick, and
at this stage in life
and it really was surreal for me
just because
just because i didn't know how to deal with it
because throughout high school
i didn't worry about this kind of stuff
even though obviously time was passing
and
for me it was something i couldn't comprehend
but when i visited her at the hospital
it was starting to hit me that, you know, she
didn't remember us
and after being so careless about
not about myself but
not really thinking about myself at a deeper level
suddenly it was all kind of hitting me at the same time
that
so much time passed and
there was so much that i wanted to do
that i didn't think about
why did i wear mascara
so at this point my grandma
didn't really remember us that well
my great-grandma by the way is my mom's grandma
so she was a very huge part of her life
she basically raised her
my great-grandma was a huge part of my life as well
when i was younger i would look forward to
her staying over with us
even though there was this
literaly language barrier
she was a huge part of my childhood
and i would be excited whenever she would stay with us
and when she would brush my hair every single morning
even though
my hair, you're not supposed to brush it
like the way that she did
she didn't really understand that
curly hair, you're not supposed to
brush it with a certain brush
she didn't really understand that but she still did
because she wanted to make my hair nice and pretty
there was that cultural difference that always made me kind of
laugh as i got older
as i understood my hair more
so she was a huge part of my life
but
the thing that kind of really hit me
when all this was happening
was the fact that
i realized i never really had a full
conversation with her
nor do i even remember having a conversation with her
so this sort of guilt
started-
so this sense of guilt was just
jumping out at me from nowhere
because i didn't think about it
i took it for granted
i always for some reason thought
my grandma was just going to be around for a long time
and this overwhelming sense of guilt
just came at me
and i was like
i really never had a conversation with her
because she can't speak english
and i never bothered to speak with her in korean
because i couldn't
and so
that was really when i started realizing
literally i don't know why i did my makeup
i should've just left my face bare
i also just felt
helpless
because at this point there was nothing i could do
she already didn't remember who we were
so it really was just a helpless time
that there was nothing i could do at this point
except be there for her
as much as possible
from then on that's kind of when
i took myself more seriously
and thought about how i can't really
be distracted from myself anymore
i really should think more because
things change so fast
so a few months later my great-grandma did
pass away
that was kind of the end of that part of my life
so that's kind of when i became more self-reflexive
and started taking myself more seriously
because i was really away from this part of me
that i could have spent more time on
so it was just a very frustrating time because
at the time too
i was still dealing with insecurities that i kind of pushed back
so moving on from that, i
graduated high school
it was my last year of high school when this happened
so i was about to finish high school
so i finished high school
and this was when i finally
was going to college
being independent, really learning a lot
being by myself, that kind of stuff
and because i was being more self-reflexive
and because i was analyzing my life a little bit more
this was when the process happened of when
i started becoming more aware of my background
and everything
in college i learned a whole lot more
about the self
i was taking a lot of psychology classes
sociology classes, all that kind of stuff
really just being more exposed to everything
and i was just becoming more educated about
a person
so i was being more self-reflexive
and more empathetic at this point
because before i didn't really care so much about
these deeper things
i was just going through the motions
just trying to get through life
that i never really
thought about people or myself
or anything at a deeper sense
so in college i was becoming more
aware of how people worked
just to say i'm not a psychology major
i'm
not an expert at this kind of stuff
but i was definitely becoming more exposed to it
so my mom never really showed us
how my great-grandma passing away affected her
i assumed she was heartbroken because
obviously if i was heartbroken
she would've been much more heartbroken
but i never really
realized how much this affected her
until she told me
as i got older my parents would just
talk to me about more things
and relate to me on a personal level
and there was this one day when my mom
told me
how important my great-grandma was to her
and it was because
my great-grandma she spoke only korean
she was culturally very korean
so this was how my mom was able to connect to
korea and connect to her old family
and so when my great-grandma passed away
that kind of side of my mom
just kind of vanished
and it just felt a little more lonely for her
and i never realized that
because i always kind of took
her speaking english
being able to speak 2 languages
being able to switch from culture to culture
i took that for granted
and i didn't realize that
it's still hard for her to
understand american culture
even though she's able to speak english
that doesn't mean she's part of the american culture
and so when my dad and i are speaking to each other
we can speak for a long time about anything
because we actually understand the context and all that
but my mom she sometimes doesn't understand that
it's just like how i'm not able to understand
or i wasn't able to understand
korean culture and etiquette
and i felt that shame and embarrassment
and that detachment
but i never pieced it together
and saw my mom was experiencing the same thing
but kind of the other way around
and so at this point i realized that my mom too was
very
heavily affected by my great-grandma passing
and this kind of side to her was gone
and she didn't really have someone she can
fully 100% communicate with
heart to heart
even though she had family here
there was still that cultural difference no matter what
and it really was just difficult to understand
but because i was becoming more
aware of things outside of myself
i started to really see the value
in owning my korean identity
being part of my culture
because it's not just
being able to speak a language or not
it really affected me
at a much more personal level
because i realized that
if i'm not able to speak korean
if i'm not able to have a sense of korean culture
i'm gonna have this distance from my mom as well
and i didn't want that
i just got tired of
this distance and this detachment
just looking back i wish i was
just more secure of myself
so i could just be part of it because
being distant from your culture
it really is a lonely feeling
and so at this point, because i was really
by myself
and i had nothing to lose
i wanted to immerse myself more
in the korean culture because
i didn't want my mom to feel so lonely
and for myself, i didn't want to feel detached anymore
and at this point social media was becoming a bigger thing
i had the internet
i finally had these resources around me
that i was like
i think it's time to just own it
and just immerse myself more because
i really had nothing to lose
i would only be able to gain this part of me
that i was always kind of afraid to gain
and kind of always far from
even if people might not think i'm a korean
even if i'm not able to communicate with other koreans
or relate to them
no matter what it's still 100% a part of me
my entire family is from korea
even though i was born in america
it's still 100% part of me
even if other people don't think so
it's still who i am
and that kind of just took too long for me to realize
sorry my camera died
but anyway
there was just nothing stopping me from
finally being immersed in my culture
i was 19 and
i became much more aware of myself
and all that, that i just
didn't want to be ashamed anymore
of trying to be myself
you know obviously growing up i may have
developed slowly
i may have not been able to
personally related with other koreans
but that was when i was younger
and i can't let that affect my life anymore
so from then on i decided to
finally start learning korean
because i finally had the internet
i had resources to finally teach myself korean
but also an important part of me
finally being proud of my korean identity was definitely
kpop
my parents have always exposed me to kpop
i grew up with bigbang and girls generation
i knew about kpop since i was a kid
there wasn't really this stan culture
of kpop in high school
obviously things have changed
and kpop is a huge thing now
but when i was in high school
even though it really wasn't that long ago
there wasn't that kind of culture
i wasn't able to really be immersed in kpop
and actually
my mom
introduced me to bts
which was my first kpop group that i started stanning
my mom actually introduced me to them
because it was the billboard music awards
and my mom was talking about bts
getting the nomination and all that and i was like
huh
kpop
cool
and then i for some reason wanted to check them out
and then it changed my life
but because of that it was kind of this gateway
into korean culture
i started watching more korean dramas
listening to more korean artists in general
just finally being able to find stuff to
relate to with my mom
my mom was always watching these korean dramas and all that
and i never knew what she was watching or talking about
and now i actually understood
and it kind of just felt
nice
that i was finally able to relate to my mom
in some kind of sense
obviously kpop's not the epitome of korean culture
but it definitely is a part of it
and it helped me kind of be more exposed to
whatever my mom cared about
and i'm very much in love with all of it
and it definitely shaped me
to become the person i am today
for the last year and a half i've been
learning korean and i'm definitely better
i still have a slight insecurity about it
just because growing up i used to get teased
for trying to speak korean
there's still, i'm not perfect
there's still that underlying insecurity
oh if i speak korean it's gonna be embarrassing
so even though i don't speak korean all the time
i speak it with my mom
and i speak it with my dad sometimes
but i'm definitely able to understand it more
now i'm actually able to speak to my grandma
my dad's mom
in korean, because
we always spoke in english to her
and we never bothered to try to speak in korean to her
in my first few months that i was learning korean
i surprised her by suddenly starting to speak korean
and she was so surprised
she was so happy
and really appreciative that i was actually learning korean
and it was really just such a nice experience
i want to be able to make my family's life easier because
even though we're all in america
it wouldn't kill me to speak in korean with them
and just make their lives a little bit easier
but that is really my
experience so far growing up korean american
i was very much afraid
to be connected to that side of me
because i always felt like i wasn't enough
and i felt like i couldn't relate to other people
this doesn't just have to do with being korean american
this applies to anyone who
is a child of immigrant parents
coming to a country where
you're not the dominant people
it can be difficult to know who you are because
you may not feel confident enough to
own your ethnical background
but you obviously physically
don't fit in with everyone else
and it's just really weird and hard
and it really can affect you negatively
but there's really just nothing
wrong with identifying as the ethnicity that you really are
i only gained more by identifying with this part of me
there was nothing that i lost from it
this journey so far of learning is
just so eye-opening and rewarding
i still obviously don't always 100% feel korean
it's still-
it's still hard for me to blend in with a korean community
especially at my school
there's a huge korean community
but obviously there are some differences
but now i'm just not taking it so personally
because
oh well
and also lately in korea they've been
styling their hair to kind of
make it wavy
and it kind of just makes me
feel
both happy but also triggered at the same time
because i always used to be so ashamed
not ashamed but like, i used to kind of
be sad that my hair wasn't straight
but now people are appreciating different hair styles
and so
that's nice i guess
but now it's just, i'm not afraid to
be in touch with my korean side
there's nothing wrong with identifying as my ethnicity
that was my experience
growing up as a korean american
it honestly, the past 20 years
have been a lot, but
it's been a lot of growth
and there's just a lot more for me to learn
and it's just a nice journey and it's a lot of fun
i hope that you guys can also
if you're also dealing with something like this
you can
not be afraid to be in touch with your ethnicity
even if people don't think you're enough
who cares
this is my background this is who i am
i'm going to do as much as i can on my part
to learn about my ethnicity
and own my nationality as well
people should learn more than one language honestly
the world is so interesting
and
people are trying their best, so
people should learn more
i hope this video was interesting
and eye-opening
and, wholesome, idk
let me know your upbringing, your story
let me hear it, i wanna hear it
that is all i needed to say
i'm emotionally tired
that is it for this video
thank you so much for watching
we are going to end it with a hug
and
i hope that in your journey of knowing yourself
don't care about what other people think about you
just own your own identity
and just do the best that you can
okay?
that is it for this video
goodbye my frens i will see you next time :')))