hey what's up you guys it's again
michaela and welcome and welcome back to
my youtube channel
so today i'm so excited to finally be
filming a q a video
you guys sent me in some bomb questions
y'all came through with the questions
in my community tab and i'm so so
grateful for every single question i
received please know that
so i do not want to ramble for too much
so grab yourself a snack got yourself
some water some popcorn whatever
and if you want to know more about me
keep on watching so the very first
question i received is where are you
from and i am actually from california a
lot of people don't know that about me
but i'm from california and to be more
specific i am from the bay area
i was born and raised here my family's
from here
my dad is from sunset if you guys don't
know where sunset is it's just a
district in san francisco
and my mom is from vallejo so the bay
area is home for me
the next question i received is how old
are you and i am 20 years old
next question is my most popular
question i get online and
in life in general and it's what is your
ethnicity
and my ethnicity is drum roll please
it's literally not that serious i am a
japanese
german and filipino so i am white and
asian
that might come as a surprise to some
people because a lot of people do think
i am latina
i mean it makes sense i did grow up in
like a predominantly spanish-speaking
neighborhood
and i am a little bit of filipino to the
point where some people like
have called me like really rude terms
because they think
like i'm not asian if that makes sense
so for example i was talking to a
co-worker one time
and i was telling her that like i wear a
yokura when i walk around my house which
is like a japanese house robe
and she was like you're a culture
appropriator you take japanese culture
you're
racist against asian people and i was
like i'm japanese and she's like oh my
god i'm so sorry that you're mexican and
i was like
oh okay but with that being said cause i
literally talked about this question for
so long
um i am white and asian so the next
question i received
is do you have any siblings if so how
many and are you the oldest or the
youngest
so i actually do have siblings i have
four siblings and
i have four brothers and they are all
older than me so i am the youngest girl
out of five
somebody asked what is your zodiac sign
and my son sign as a libra i resonate
with my son sign so much but
obviously i resonate with all of my big
fives the next question is
do you have any pets i do have one pet i
have a dog she's a golden retriever and
her name is
maggie she's i think 10 years old
somebody asked me what is your favorite
movie
i have so many movies that i like
thoroughly enjoy
but if i'm gonna recommend one movie to
you guys right now it's what happens on
monday it's on netflix
i saw it like two years ago and it will
forever be imprinted in my brain
love that movie but like my favorite
movie of all time
would have to be the last song with liam
hemsworth and miley cyrus i just i'm a
sucker for that movie
so the next question i receive is what
is your favorite type of food slash what
is your favorite fast food
my favorite type of food is definitely
italian i feel like i was italian in my
last life
i love me a good penne vodka pasta
italian food hands down
my favorite fast food is chick-fil-a but
honestly i don't even consider
chick-fil-a fast food anymore because
like that is a two-hour ordeal that is
not no fast food like
you gotta plan when you go to
chick-fil-a um so
actual like fast food fast food like i'm
driving home it's
12 a.m i'm just trying to go home after
work and like knock out but i need
something in my system type food
taco bell 100 love me a good
nacho fry with a baja blast freeze the
next question is
what is your favorite musical artist
slash what music do you listen to when
you get ready
i think some of you guys know this by
now but i am a rap
listener i like rap music um i think
it's just the culture that i grew up in
everyone around me has always listened
to rap music so that's kind of the music
that i listen to when i get ready
but as for like who is my favorite
musical artist of all time
it's actually ariana grande if i could
listen to like one
artist for forever it would be her music
i love how versatile it is
and i just think she's so bomb and so
talented so she's my favorite musical
artist but my favorite music to listen
to when i get ready is hands down
rap music so the next question is are
you a student if so what are you
studying
um i am a student and my major might
surprise some of you guys i
am a double major in media broadcasting
and theater actually so with my majors
obviously you guys can tell that i love
to be in front of the camera i love to
talk to people so i'd love to be either
a news anchor
or a sports news anchor or even just
like celebrity news
anchor like i'd love to be any type of
broadcasting position
i love being in front of the camera and
i think it's so obvious to you guys that
i
love like doing what i'm doing the
theater major requires you to take a lot
of on-camera classes
and it works perfectly with my
journalism major when i'm a broadcaster
because i know how to present myself in
front of a camera
so i love my theater major if you guys
have ever like wanted to work on your
public speaking or ever wanted
a job where you're going to speak in
front of large groups i definitely
recommend that you
look at minoring in theater like it is a
great addition and it's super super
underrated
i feel like when people think of public
speaking majors they their minds first
goes to communications
um but definitely check out theater i
did major in communications i do have my
aaa in communications
and it was okay but i did prefer my aaa
and theater it was like so much more fun
but it actually works out perfectly
because in both positions i get to work
in front of the camera and learn how to
speak to a bigger audience and that's
ultimately
what my dream job is and i actually got
a question what is your dream job
and like i said my dream job is to be
some type of news anchor broadcaster i'd
love to do that but also
one of my like secret dream careers is
that i really want to be a working
actress i would love to book just some
major role with somebody so the next
question i received is do you have a job
outside of youtube and i do have a job
um i work at a movie theater which goes
perfectly
with my like being in front of the
camera wanting to major in journalism
wanting to be an actress type thing next
question is do you drink coffee if so
what is your order
i do drink coffee i drink coffee every
single morning i make myself a
toffeena iced coffee and then i pour
hazelnut creamer and caramel drizzle in
it and it's a fire
i usually don't get coffee when i go out
just because i like the coffee that i
make at home i'm very like precise about
my coffee
um but if i do order coffee at starbucks
i'll get an iced coffee
with heavy cream and four pumps of white
chocolate mocha so the next question is
have you ever played any sports how were
the coaches and i played literally every
single sport that you can think of
growing up like
if you can think of a sport i played it
like even football like i played the
flag version but literally i played
every single sport
and i've always had really awesome
coaches i've never had like these super
scary ones
if i had to think my basketball coach
was probably my scariest coach but like
even so he was pretty nice
but the last sport ever played was
varsity swim
i was on the swim team when i was in
high school um
and that was it that was like the very
last sport i played next question i
received is do you
like to be called kayla or michaela and
it's so funny that you guys asked me
this is because i feel like
if you have been here since i had like
200 subscribers you would know that my
name on youtube used to be michaela
wegner which is my full name
um but i did switch it to kayla and the
reason why i switched it to kayla
was actually because somebody took the
liberty to go in my comment section and
leak my address for some reason they
like put my zip code but my whole
address put my
area code and everything the town i grew
up in like they was putting all my
information
in the comment section and i was like
for what so i had to switch my name on
youtube from my full name
to jess kayla i know some people met me
as michaela so they prefer to call me
michaela but some people met me as kayla
so that's what they call me
i honestly do not have a preference but
that is the only reason why if you guys
are wondering like why i switched my
name or what should you call me
that's the reason why i switched it but
honestly like call me whatever like you
feel comfortable doing
so what is your biggest pet peeve and
honestly i
feel like i have so many pet peeves but
obviously because i'm recording i just
blank out on
it but the first one that comes in my
mind when i think of my pet peeves
is when people purposefully like wear
their mask underneath their nose like
it's one thing if it like slips down
like that's okay
y'all like like it happens but when
people purposely like place it
underneath their nose i feel like
they're like flashing me i'm like
pull it up a little bit pull it up so um
that's one of my pet peeves but
i'm sure i have a lot more pet peeves
that i just like am blanking on right
now
what do you like to do in your down time
and honestly if i have like complete
downtime like no homework
no work no nothing um i just like to sit
down and watch youtube videos i am like
a little hermit like that i can honestly
like my screen time y'all is kind of
ridiculous like i will sit down and
watch youtube videos for eight hours
straight and literally have no problem
doing that
i genuinely like to watch other people's
videos so that is a big thing i like to
do
so i got the question of do you have a
boyfriend if so how long have you guys
been dating
i actually do not have a boyfriend right
now i'm chilling just because i
am going to probably move soon in the
next couple months
it's not set in stone but i am in the
process of trying to move
so i do not want to get into a committed
relationship right before i move
so i'm okay right now the next question
i received is do you want children and i
actually do want children if i could
have it
my way um i would want to be like my
parents and have
five kids four boys and one girl but
honestly my main goal is just to have at
least four kids like minimum four kids
so the next question i received is what
is your biggest dream
so i did confide in you guys already i
did tell you guys but
my biggest dream of all time is to work
with netflix i literally don't know how
i'm going to do it
but i'm going to find a way i do i want
to work with netflix like that's my
dream the next question i received is
would you ever start a brand and a
hundred percent
i don't even think i mentioned that for
one of my biggest goals but one of my
biggest goals as well is to start my own
brands
i don't know what it would be i don't
know it would be perfume or makeup or
clothing or like
a stationery if you guys don't know that
about me i love pens
or if i would write my own book but i
want something to my name
so i would love to make my own brand one
day so i just have to think of ideas and
work my way there somebody said what do
you want people to know about your
personality and
something i would love for you guys to
know is that i am a very very driven
person
um i am somebody that's constantly
wanting to create and do new things
i think we all have that one person in
our life where they talk to you and it's
like every single time they talk to you
they're doing something new and
it's so funny because i feel like i have
like people in my life that kind of evil
eye me
like i have like family members or
friends and when i tell them i want to
start a new project they're kind of like
oh like why don't you finish the last
one you started but that's just never me
i'm constantly on the move and i'm
constantly wanting to grow
and i am just like i have big dreams and
big goals and i plan on attaining every
single one of them
so if i could let you guys know anything
about my personality is that like
baby i dream big and i i go for it so
everything i want in life i genuinely
go out there and i put my effort in to
achieve so that is something i would
love for you guys to know about me
so now we're gonna go more into like the
youtube based questions because i
received a lot of those but i was saving
those towards the end just because i
wanted you guys to get to know me
on a more personal level first a whole
bunch of people ask me what made you
start your youtube channel so i think it
is very apparent that i do love talking
in front of the camera but that is
actually not the reason why i started my
youtube channel
i started my youtube channel genuinely
because i love talking to other people
not just talking to a camera so i
started my youtube channel to talk to
the camera but i continued going and
continue to make videos because of the
comments that you guys
leave to me i don't think you guys
realize that when you guys leave me a
comment that makes my entire day
way that you guys can tell me about how
your day's going and tell me what
products you're into
and telling me like you know just
anything about yourself
makes me so so happy and that's really
why i started my youtube channel was
just to get to know other people and to
make friends and just to
you know grow in who i know in this
world and i think that's so beautiful
about youtube is that how
i have friends literally in the
philippines right now i have friends in
new jersey right now
i have friends all over the world you
guys tell me you're from the uk or india
and it just makes me so happy
and that's why i started my youtube
channel was just to talk to people like
you guys the next question i received is
how long have you been monetized
slash how long have you been doing
youtube so i have been monetized i think
since like
february like 15th or 16th some some day
like that
um somewhere in mid february um and how
long have you been doing youtube it
honestly depends what you consider
um because i used to make like i think
in like 2017 i made one video
i think in 2018 i made one video i think
in 2019 i make two videos like
you know what i'm saying like it depends
what you really consider
when did i start consistently making
videos was
in december so december of 2020 is when
i consistently started making videos
the next question is how do you deal
with hate and i don't know if you guys
know this but i
actually do receive a lot of hate which
was funny but not funny
because i didn't think i would get hate
until i became like a bigger channel i
do could still consider myself a small
youtuber
and i never thought i would receive hate
like at the amounts that i did
but one thing that i always remind
myself and it's funny because jasmine
said this in her video and i
it's so when she said that my jaw
dropped because i literally tell my
friends that
same exact thing all the time and it's
that people that like send me hate
online
would never have the audacity to say
that stuff to my face like
you literally would not be able to walk
up to me and talk to me the way that you
do
and it's just funny how like behind the
screen people just get this wave of
confidence to be rude to other people
and it's like okay but would you say
that to my face though
so that's something that i remind myself
is that like you know people
are this way just because it's the
internet but one of the biggest things i
do to help myself with hate
is genuinely look at the nice comments
for every hate comment i receive
i receive like 20 nice comments and that
genuinely keeps me going that's the main
thing i do if i ever receive a hate
comment i will just go and i'll find a
positive comment and i'll read it i'll
remind myself
that there are really really awesome
people out there in this world and you
just gotta choose
to acknowledge them over the shitty
people next question is
what is your all-time favorite scent
bear vanilla by victoria's secret of
course
somebody said what supplements do you
take slash recommends i unfortunately
cannot recommend you guys any
supplements since i'm not your guys
doctors
but i will let you guys know what
supplements i do take personally
i take b12 for energy because i don't
really eat meat like that
so i do take b12 i take a cranberry like
gummy i don't take the pills i take the
gummies um i take a woman's
multivitamin and that's basically it i
don't really take a lot of like vitamins
or supplements
um but yeah i do use protein powder in
my smoothies but like that's just
protein powder somebody asked how long
did it take you to perfect your routine
it's still going my routine is not
perfect literally i
promise you guys there are things where
i every single day i learn something new
about my body and i
learn what works and what doesn't work
for me so i'm still working on it i'm 20
years old
we still we still thriving like it is a
journey self-care is a journey
somebody said must have skin care
products i will be making a skincare
routine but i promise you guys my
skincare routine is super simple like i
do not do
too much um favorite vanilla scents
i'm gonna make a whole video talking
just about my favorite gourmand scents
i'm just trying to get all my products
together
um but at the moment um i've been loving
the eos vanilla cashmere lotion
bomb um i love the ogx shea body wash
bomb and then of course bear vanilla
like come on y'all know me y'all know i
love me bear vanilla but i will be
making a whole video talking about
my favorite vanilla scents don't worry i
got you boo so the next question is
what got you into fragrances so i've
always been into hygiene i've been
watching haichi and youtube since i was
in like sixth grade like that's how long
i've been watching the hygiene side of
youtube
it was a very small community but like
it was still there
um so i've always been into the hygiene
side but i didn't get into fragrances
until december so i started watching
tick tock and there was a
like hygiene like shower tick talk and
on shower tik tok everyone was obsessed
with a thousand wishes and into the
night from bath and body works
and i didn't know what those were so i
was like okay so i just went onto the
bath and bodyworks website
and they happened to have a 5.95 body
care day the day that i
searched it and i was like oh okay
everything's on sale i'll just buy like
a whole bunch of crap so like i just
bought a whole bunch of stuff
and my package came in and i was like
you know what i haven't made a youtube
video in a cool minute i'm gonna record
this
so i recorded it and it literally
changed my life you guys like
loved that video and i met so many
awesome people through that video
so i'm so blessed and so grateful that
you know i was able to make that video
and then once i made that video you guys
started like sending in recommendations
and asking me to try out certain scents
and that's how i really got into
fragrances so if you guys did not know i
didn't get into fragrances until around
january of this year so the last
question that i received is one that i
specifically saved for last
and it is how are you and i thought this
was a great question just to end off on
so thank you guys so much a lot of you
guys asked me how i was so
thank you right now your girl is a
little stressed
it is that time of the school year where
teachers are just really cracking down
on their assignments so
i have a whole bunch of assignments i
have work as you guys know like i said
earlier i do
work full time so i work like four days
a week and i also go to school four days
a week
and now i have my beautiful youtube
channel so i am a little stressed trying
to balance everything out with that
being said i am so abundantly blessed
and grateful
and i like to view all the things that i
see as stress in my life as good stress
so like instead of viewing it like oh
like i have school work to do i'm always
like oh well at least i'm getting my
education
like i always try to flip things on me
and remind myself that the things i
stress about are good
stressors and they're healthy for me and
they just help to
boost me to where i want to be
eventually in life but with that being
said i am going to end off today's video
if you watch the end please comment down
below because i don't know who
would watch to the end of this video but
if you did just know i love you
you're my you're my fave so i am going
to talk to you guys very very soon
i love you i love you i love you have an
amazing rest of your day and i'll talk
to you very soon
bye