let's talk about growing up asian
american
i'm going to be showing you my like
struggles of growing up asian american
the language barrier and everything
there has been a lot of asian hate
rising due to
covet i think that's really scary and
sad
so i'm here to show you my experience
growing up asian american
so we're gonna start from the start so i
am half vietnamese and i'm half
chinese i grew up with the vietnamese
culture though
and i didn't really learn any chinese or
anything
and so my first language was vietnamese
i would probably say
that i'm a elementary level speaker
of vietnamese right now and
i never noticed that the language was
different until preschool
so once i entered preschool i was barely
learning any english so i was very
confused on what the kids were saying
i couldn't really communicate with
others since they were speaking
english and i was very confused it was
like this alien like
language and i think that was like the
first moment where i
realized like something was different
about me and my language
okay heading on to second grade so
starting second grade i kind of knew
english a little but it was still hard
for me i had to like
think about like the sentences i was
saying and stuff
so i remember we had this like parent
conference where
i remember specifically this teacher
said that i wasn't learning anything
i looked like i was spaced out and it
was because i did not understand it was
like i was hearing another language that
it was hard to process and i was trying
to learn another subject
and i remember people like kids who need
extra help get taken out of class
sometimes
to get like extra help i remember having
that and i was very confused on why
everyone is still better at english than
me let's talk about unnecessary
stereotypes so
one of the stereotypes that you are
probably heard for it's pretty common
is all asians are smart and i think this
is a really
unnecessary stereotype that people make
like
oh you get bees i thought you're
supposed to be asian like
it doesn't really make sense and i got
that
a lot growing up racism was
also a problem i had people would be
asking me
if i ate dogs and no i do not eat dogs i
eat
the same thing that every human eats
and i think it's really offensive
someone to say like i remember this one
specific time in
4th grade this kid asked me why
asian eyes were so small and then he
continued to like pull
his eyes back and imitate the look
and i was very surprised about this and
i didn't realize how much just goes on
until now thinking about it this happens
a lot
these small comments from here to there
did have
a change or a toll on my perspective of
being asian american
um once i was sick my grandma brought me
this meal instead of taking a school
lunch
and it was just like i don't really know
how to describe it but
anyways it was this like asian meal and
my i was like kind of ashamed of it i
hate to admit it but i was
and i would be like i don't know what
that is
what is that like you know well what
that is like
pretending not to know what it was and
this was in like
third grade and i ended up not eating it
and i ended up throwing it away
which i feel really bad for sometimes
you would
also be called like ling ding like
ching chong like you would actually be
caught that and it's
really sad and surprising that people
actually say these
daily to like asian people and i've
experienced some of that like i have
been called some of those names
sometimes and it's
and all of this like asian hate stuff
going on with covid like asians being
hit killed accused like it's really
scary also seeing a lot of
like elderly people getting hurt that's
like someone's grandma
someone's uncle someone's grandpa
that you're hurting because you're
accusing them of causing the virus when
they did nothing
it's really sad to think of and i hope
this like asian hate stops
and i have also caught myself making
these jokes to myself
because i think that's how i coped with
dealing with
how everything was going on i feel like
we get
so much unnecessary hate and again i
am proud of where i'm from now
i really like my culture and everything
i enjoy speaking the language and yeah
that is it i really hope this hates up
soon