hello i went to a thrift store and i got
a few items
i went to savers since i think savers is
the best option for clothing
at a thrift store since they have more
options than the other stores
so i went to savers and i found some
pretty good stuff i am not disappointed
so i'm going to do a town hall and maybe
i will do some thrift flips on
some of these items and so here are my
items and i'm
obsessed i didn't film my trip
inside of savers since i'm very awkward
and
and i don't think i can handle the
embarrassment of talking to the camera
so i didn't really do that but i still
have the stuff to show you
the first item i found i was so excited
about this item because
i've been really into quarter zips and
collars
so i was really excited when i found
this top it is
just a plain top it doesn't have any
designs it
is a bit smaller than my liking since i
like to wear really oversized sweaters
or sweatshirts
so the zipper works just fine everything
works the collar is a bit weird though
it's a bit
flimsy in a different material but
overall
i think it's the cutest tub and i got
this for around five bucks this is
it that was really awkward
yeah i don't know what i was saying but
let's just focus on this quarter zip so
here's the quarter zip
again with the length i would prefer it
to be much longer and oversized but i
can't really complain because it was
pretty cheap and i found a thrift store
and yeah i could see myself wearing this
on a chilly day over some like straight
like jeans
and i think this is a really preppy and
nice look
the material is on the thinner side but
that's fine
so next i have this brandy top i have
been trying to
steer close of stairways too close
i don't know but like i have been trying
to get away from brandy
some brandy stuff since i think i have
too much
and i'm trying to have different
variations in my closet besides brandy
but i think for for it being like
1 4 of the price i had to take it
so it's this top there's buttons
on it and it's just it's cropped
but not very cropped at the same time
it's like medium cropped
and yeah i'm pretty surprised that i
found these at the thrift store
okay so here is the top i like it
it is a bit too plain for my liking so
i'm probably gonna use it as like a
layering top
under something else the buttons work
okay i don't know why i said that
obviously buttons do work
yeah i was really surprised when i found
this top since
you don't really often find brandy
clothing at thrift stores
it is also a very hugging material
so this is my next find i wasn't very
surprised by the spine since it is a
plain top
and it isn't very fun i did crop it i
forgot a crop on camera but it
is crap since it was a really awkward
length where it wasn't long
or medium at the same time so yeah i did
crop it
but it is a bit boring for me so i might
embroider something on it
okay like i said this top is pretty
boring
but wait until the end because i'm gonna
do like a small thrift flip on this item
material is kind of like a knit thermal
material
when i cropped it it didn't thread
everywhere so
i'm pretty happy with that i don't know
to where to stop in the winter or the
summer time
since it is long sleeve it's cropped at
the same time
so on my second saber strip
i found this top oh that's backwards i
found this top
it looks kind of odd on the hanger but
like i promise you it is the sleeves are
a bit tight as you can see i have really
small wrists and they are still a little
tight
but besides that i really like the top i
got it for also five bucks
and just here it is it's from pretty
little thing which i'm pretty surprised
about did you see that
pretty pretty sorry i don't know why
this is so weird
okay here it is i'm gonna be doing a try
on haul so i'm not gonna really try to
hold them up as well
since you're gonna see them anyways
here's the top during the try on portion
i kind of hated this top
i was looking at it and it wasn't as
cute as i thought
but i would still wear this i don't know
i'll maybe try to fix it somehow
because i think it's a really awkward
lane i think what got me to get this top
was
when i saw the collar because i've been
really into collars like i said
so i think that's why i got it and i
liked it
yeah but like i can definitely see me
wearing like mom jeans with this top
i know our gal sweaters are
pretty popular at the thrift store you
can find them there if you are looking
for arthouse
sweater i definitely recommend hitting
up the thrift store
so i found this argyle thing it gives me
very
preppy school vibes vibes
i don't know i always say vibes for some
reason so
here it is i think it is so cute it has
like
this collar which is a little long kind
of weird in my opinion
and get this it's motherhood maternity
this is a maternity shirt you can't
really tell that it's a maternity shirt
though
i'm pretty sure i'm gonna be doing after
flip on this i'm gonna be cutting it and
crop cinching it anyways
so i don't think that like bulkiness
look wouldn't be a problem for me
but the design is pretty cute do you see
that it's like
three argyle squares are these squares
i don't know my shapes anymore they're
raw misses or
rock or diamonds whatever you want to
call them
they do have a stain right here but
that's not a problem since
i am going to be cutting out the sleeves
since it isn't a full
shirt underneath it's actually just
sewed on to make the illusion
of like underneath polo so i am going to
be cutting off the white part of the
sleeves but not the collar because i
actually like the collar on this shirt
trying on this top i really like the top
and i was really considering not
cropping it but the length was a little
too awkward to not crop
and the sleeves are also really awkward
as you can see so i will be cutting off
the sleeves
i was actually on the hunt for an argyle
sweater you can also find them in the
men's section they have a lot of those
you can crop those or you can just wear
them oversized
and yeah i happen to find this in the
women's section
and this is a pretty good find and it
almost
looks like school uniform
since i didn't buy that much stuff than
i thought i would
so i'm now gonna do like a small thrift
flip
right now so i'm gonna use this top
since it's the plainest top i have so i
already cropped it
but i i'm thinking of doing like
embroidered design on it
so right here i have my pattern that i
printed out
and i'm going to cut it so it's easier
to move around
and then i'm going to use some thread
and i'm going to trace around the
letters
after that you would remove the paper
and without disrupting the thread
okay so i now finished tracing my
pattern
or my wording and here it is i dabbed it
with water
so it would come out easier and this is
how it looks after removing the paper
and yeah that is the brandy shirt
underneath i actually like this pair
you can see that there's still a little
bit of paper in between the letters
which does come out after you put in the
washer
and i really like this top i think it's
a really
cool design and yeah that is it