all right we're just gonna do this real
casual
it's time for the talk let's go
hey everyone it's your girl t and
welcome back to my channel
today we are gonna be talking about my
stories
growing up as an asian american my
experiences
with racism and just what it's like
being asian american
i want to start off this video by saying
that this is not the oppression olympics
i am not trying to compete
or compare or say that i have it worse
than other pocs or other minorities
that is not what this video is about i'm
just sharing my experiences because of
the
uprise in asian hate crimes recently i
feel a responsibility
as a creator of color and as an asian
american
to speak on these issues on behalf of my
parents and my family
my friends and any of you who is
watching this video right now
who might be asian american too or asian
that feel scared i just hope that you
find this video to be relatable
or comforting in any type of way and
just know that you're not alone
i'd also like to add that i have a link
treat in my description box and i always
have this in all my videos it's under my
social media
and it has not only my social media but
also resources and links
if you want to help protect asian lives
and support
asian lives and stopping asian hate
crimes i also want to mention that i
have a new tic tac
right here called nunu and that's where
i talk more about me
my life if any of you like the content
that i post on here or on instagram
about positivity
kindness loving yourself happiness
self-care
or my experiences and stories as an
asian american i talk more about just
like
me i'm really excited to share more
about me and my life on this new account
so go follow me there
let's briefly talk about my school so my
elementary school had about 400 people
predominantly white but are you really
surprised and there was
little to no diversity and when i mean
little to none
i mean like none i was the only asian
person at school
the only chinese person at school and
one of two pocs in our entire
school it didn't help that i grew up in
a small
town in the suburbs so people here were
very close-minded very racist to begin
with
plus they had no exposure to people of
color
growing up asian-american meant that
people would constantly pull their eyes
back
to greet me and sing chinese japanese
people would constantly mock my eyes and
say
are your eyes even open like they're so
small people would make fun of my facial
features
say that they're too flat to say that i
look like a pancake
people would say that my skin is weird
because it's
yellow people would make fun of my
culture
and my language by mocking me and saying
i know chinese too
it meant that i was my school's
laughingstock when it came to lunch time
because my mom would always pack me cold
lunch
and it would always be traditional food
from home
and people would always say i bet you
eat cats and dogs and that's why it
smells so bad and looks so weird it's
kids telling you to go back to your own
country
go back to where you came from why don't
you just go back to china
when you were born in the u.s like i
hate to break it to you tom
but i was born in chicago so sit down
it's working hard in school and then
having people discredit your hard work
because you get good grades and tell you
things like of course you get good
grades like you're asian
asians are naturally smart it's in your
genetics
like please if it is in my genetics then
why
is it that i suck that math it's
constantly being treated
as a perpetual foreigner when people
hear you speak
and say things like wow your english is
so good
when did you come to the u.s where did
you learn english
you sound just like a native english
speaker these are just
a few simple examples of everyday life
that we experience
as an asian american like there's so
much more that i could say about it but
this was just a very brief
breakdown overview of what it's like so
let's start off with kindergarten
basically in kindergarten i had a
teacher
who liked to do this thing called star
of the week and star of the week was
essentially
show and tell so each week our teacher
would have one student present
a item an animal a toy basically
anything that they want to share with
the class
and this is a fun way to get students to
learn how to present build speaking
skills and build
confidence well i was a very energetic
happy
bubbly outgoing kid and i would raise my
hand each week very politely
hope that my teacher would call on me
and she would not so it's been a few
months
and nothing happens so i come home from
school one day really depressed and i
just tell my mom like hey
kids at school have been able to present
for start of the week for like two or
three times already and i have yet to go
once and my mom was like why didn't you
tell me sooner
i'm sitting there obviously just really
innocent and naive of what is happening
and i just told her like oh i never
thought about it i thought i just
had to wait my turn because every time i
asked my teacher she was just like it's
not your turn yet
my mom was so furious and my mom is just
a strong independent asian
woman she will go and call you out if
you are racist towards her
so she dragged me back to school this
was like 4 p.m when i came home from
school she dragged me back to school
into the principal's office and she told
the principal what happened then my mom
got to talk to my teacher
and basically nothing really happened
that day she spoke her thoughts i was
really thankful that my mom spoke fluent
english and she was able to speak up for
me she basically told her this is not
okay you should not be discriminating my
daughter just because she is asian just
because she is chinese and she's
different
so more months go by and nothing happens
until it is the last week of school
it is the last week of june and i
finally
get called on and it is my turn to be
star of the week
something that i've always wondered is
whether or not my teacher would have
given me a chance
had i not told my mom and had she not
complained to the school
but honestly letting me present that one
time was also just kind of like a slap
in the face because it's basically her
just telling me like
hey i gave you what you want you asked
for it i gave you a chance to present
and that's it that's all you're gonna
get
my school life was not the best because
people always bullied and discriminated
me
for being asian and so i was always left
out and i didn't really have a lot of
people who played with me during recess
so there was this one day in
kindergarten where it was
pouring rain okay i just remember
vividly it was pouring rain and i was
just
sitting on the blacktop by myself
because i had no one to play with
and there was this group of girls that
was playing red light green light
and they invited me to join them and i
was just genuinely so excited i was like
oh my gosh
like maybe this is the day that i make
some new friends
and so i go play with them everything is
great
until this one girl stepped on my
shoelace
middle school okay so this teacher miss
k did not like me you know some teachers
their first impression of you no matter
what you do they just do not like you
she was one of those teachers she
absolutely hated me
and she made it clear that she did not
like me one day during passing time i'm
trying to rush and grab my textbooks for
my next class i'm at my locker just
trying to grab my textbooks
shoving them into my backpack i just had
no time it's like five minutes you guys
know how it is
and people are running behind me in the
hallways right trying to get to class
and my teacher is a mile away down the
hallway okay
she sees me she blows her whistle at me
she had a little whistle that was like
on a necklace
she blew her whistle and she was like
young lady you better stop now
and change out of that outfit or i'm
sending you to the principal's office
keep in mind my mom was the one who came
up with my outfits for school
even when i was in middle school so this
was mom approved because she was the one
who picked my outfit okay
my family is very conservative when it
comes to how much skin exposure i have
and in general
i have like a very modest style too like
i don't really show
anything you know so this was completely
appropriate for school but my teacher
had to call me out
you guys i was wearing a yellow
long sleeved hollister top it had
hollister on the side of the sleeves
the neckline was just like this one
right here very high i made sure that it
was not see-through by wearing
a white tank top underneath and then i
wore gray leggings on the bottom
my teacher told me that my outfit was
way too inappropriate because of my gray
leggings
which were distracting for the boys in
class i talked to my friends and we just
all didn't understand but we all came to
the conclusion that she was just
concerned
about either camel toe or my butt
showing i made sure when i went to
school
that everything was covered i was so
skinny in middle school like there was
no butt
okay i had no butt that existed and yes
she was so pressed about my outfit that
i had to go
and change into my gym clothes otherwise
i would have been called to the
principal's office so this was high
school
and my geometry teacher had us do
homework the night before
and so i do my homework and then i come
to class and i find out that i
have been picked to be the volunteer to
write down like my answers
on the board and so i do it and i sit
down
we go through the answers and come to
find out that i actually got the answers
correct and turns out i spelt the word
theorem wrong but like i got the actual
answer correct
so we should have just moved on but my
teacher proceeded for the next 10
minutes
to laugh about how i could not spell
that word
and he was just being so dramatic like
he was like repeat after me
t h
e o r
like he literally was having me spell
out every single word so i'm in
university i'm an english major and i
also certified in teaching english as a
second language
and there was not a lot of asian people
who were in this department and any pocs
that we had in class were mostly
international students we're sitting in
linguistics class and our teacher asks
only the international chinese students
to talk about what problems they faced
while learning english or any words that
they struggled pronouncing
so obviously i'm just sitting there
quiet because i'm not an international
chinese student so i'm just sitting
there
and listening my teacher thought she was
real smart and she goes and picks on me
tina you've been quiet all class let's
hear about your experiences
in china so i'm sitting there unsure
what i should say
and so i open my mouth and i'm like miss
with all due respect
and she cuts me off and says oh my gosh
you sound just like a native english
speaker where did you learn
english like your english is so good and
i tell her
i was born in chicago miss and she
replied with well how was i supposed to
know it's not like you spoke up and told
me first of all she blamed me for not
speaking up
when obviously i wouldn't speak up
because she was asking for only the
international
students second of all she just assumed
by my face
because i was asian that i was an
international student and i had learned
english and that my english was so
good and then she got upset at me the
following week we had a final exam in
her class
and she docked off four points from my
exam
otherwise i would have gotten a perfect
score she knocked off four points
and the question wasn't even a yes or no
answer so technically nothing should be
a wrong answer and therefore i shouldn't
have lost those points like she asked
an opinionated question she said in your
opinion
what do you think of this and this and
it was a long answer question
so i answered it very thoroughly and she
gave me zero points for that question
and i lost four points and so i go to
her office hours
and i ask her why i got the question
wrong and she told me
because your opinion is wrong apparently
you can have
a wrong opinion my mom and i have always
loved going to tj maxx because of the
variety of things that are there
and we love buying suitcases and purses
and things like that
and every single time we check out and
we buy a suitcase or a purse or a
backpack
they always look at us as if we're
stealing things from the store
like they are checking every single
pocket every single crack they're just
like
flipping everything inside out to make
sure that we're not stealing anything
my mom has confronted them multiple
times before
asking them are you discriminating me
right now
why is it that you have to check all the
pockets and they always tell her
ma'am it's just a store policy but the
interesting thing
is there's always white people in front
of us
who buy purses and bags and just get to
check out and
leave without having them check the
pockets or anything like that they don't
check
anything and they just leave so how are
you going to tell me that this is store
policy or store
protocol but not do it for all
this other time i was shopping alone at
the mall and i called my mom to see if
she needed anything
and she told me yes so she was listing
off different things
and then i was reciting them back to her
all in chinese mandarin because even
though my mom speaks english it's just
easier and faster for her to speak in
mandarin and so i respond to her in
mandarin because i'm on the phone with
her
and this white woman stops me
while i'm in my conversation with my mom
and she tells me
this is america
we speak english here
and i'm like ma'am i'm on the phone with
my mom
do you mind and she was like i do
mind if you're going to talk to her then
speak in english
what does me talking to my mom have to
do with you
like i do speak in english but do i
really have to speak in english with my
mom
on the phone when i'm asking if she
needs anything
this woman really just went out of her
way to tell me that i needed to speak
english because this was america
this story is not mine but it's from my
cousin and this was roughly about 15
years ago he was walking around college
campus
and all of a sudden he got jumped after
he got
jumped they beated him until he passed
out
and proceeded to steal all of his money
and belongings that he had
in his backpack this pandemic i used to
think
that everything ended with verbal
harassment or verbal bullying
verbal abuse but now i see that people
have become
so violent and their hatred is so deep
to the point
that they are murdering our people that
they are killing
and burning and stabbing our people all
because of what all because of the
chinese virus
the china virus the kung flu
it is way too late to go back now
but saying these things were never okay
to begin with
and asians and asian americans were
warning
people that this was going to end up
very badly
if you just generalize a whole group of
people
as a virus
it is not a chinese virus or an
asian virus and it is sick that people
have made it that way
and now i fear to go out of my house
i fear to allow my parents to go outside
of this house
when i was little my parents owned a
restaurant and there had been plenty of
encounters that i've had with racist
people
when people would come and grab their
take out there were many people who were
very rude
and they would just chuck their money at
us throw their coins like that
and it just felt like we were treated as
dogs it felt like we were being treated
as less than
and the reason why i say dogs is because
in like the chinese culture
being treated like a dog is kind of just
a form of expression to say that we are
being treated
very poorly speaking of dogs every year
when it's around the holiday season we
get really busy at the
restaurant and so that year it was on
christmas eve
the bar was packed with people waiting
for their orders
and this woman comes in this white woman
comes in
and chucks her food onto the bar table
spills her takeout onto the table
and demands me to give her a refund
instantly i noticed one thing
and that is the bag and the containers
were not even from our restaurant and
the dish
was not from our restaurant so this
person had bought takeout from some
other place
and came to our restaurant and expected
me to give her a refund
for something that we didn't even sell
to her she yells on the top of her lungs
i want a refund because you
fed me dog food i fed this to my dog
and even my dog threw up the last
scenario that i'm gonna talk about
just sets a fire in my soul
and perhaps it's because ironically it
does
involve a fire one day my dad came home
and i gave him a hug
and he smelled like smoke and i asked
him like daddy
what happened why do you smell like that
like you smell burnt
and he tells me very quietly under his
breath
that there had been a fire at the
restaurant
the person who set the restaurant on
fire was not
happy that a chinese restaurant was
doing better
than the white restaurants in a
predominantly white city
and i come to find out that this isn't
even the first time that it happened
our restaurant had been set on fire
twice
by two separate people just because we
were doing well
what did we do to deserve that my mom
and dad
worked 364 days a year
with no breaks in between and they
worked all day long at the restaurant
so that they could make a living for me
and for our family and someone was so
upset
that my parents were just trying to make
a living that they would do that to our
family restaurant
it didn't really ruin the infrastructure
of the actual building itself
but it is just upsetting and it is scary
to see that people will want to set you
on fire
while we were having customers and
employees
inside of the building it's not like
someone set the building on fire during
after hours and no one was there
let's talk about k-pop so as you can
tell from the background i am a k-pop
stance specifically a pts
army and i have a tick-tock account that
has over 82
000 people that seems like a huge number
right
because it is i've had multiple of my
videos
go viral over a million views so tell me
why when weeks ago i started to talk
about my experiences growing up as an
asian american
and how hurtful and harmful these recent
actions have been towards me
and towards the traumas that i have
faced in my past and me
asking people to speak up and if you
can't speak up
then please share links and share infos
and share my videos
about what is happening to the asian
community tell me why when i
asked people to just do the bare minimum
to just
care to just give me some of their time
that my videos
ended up getting like 50 views but in
comparison to 82
000 people in comparison to the fact
that i know i can have viral videos
that people couldn't make one of those
videos where i'm talking about
serious things viral i'm not complaining
about
views i'm not asking you to make me go
viral this is not about me
it's about a whole community that i am
involved in
that i take part in that involves you
the people who support k-pop because
your idols
are asian and you're within the asian
community you are in taking
asian culture this is not about me
complaining about give me viral videos
this is not about me but views and
shares and comments is what is going to
boost the algorithm
so more people see it more people hear
about it and more people hear people
like me
tell you that people need to speak up
that more people need to talk about this
issue
and that we can make a difference if we
all just said something or shared
something
it's upsetting to know that media
doesn't really do anything
it's upsetting to me because then i
question
how much people love asians in asian
culture
when you are watching k-pop when you are
watching anime when you are eating asian
food chinese food whatever it is
you are consuming asian culture what's
upsetting is that you guys
only choose the parts of our culture
that you enjoy
you only choose to accept parts of the
culture that is palatable to you
you only choose parts of the culture
that is trendy or aesthetic
we are not your aesthetic we are not
your trend
when you say you like asian culture or
korean culture because you
like k-pop then do something for the
asian community if you don't want to be
a part of the struggle
the actual issues that we are
experiencing if you don't want to care
about people like me
who are not your idols fine but think
about your idols
who are asian-american themselves i hope
that when you think about it that way
that it can encourage you to speak up
about this issue because i'm honestly so
hurt and disappointed by this community
what we're getting is just
crickets i'm not saying that every
single person has not spoken up about
this
but just by looking at my mutuals list i
see
giant creators in the k-pop community
who are directly affected and
involved with asian and asian americans
and just people of color this is a fight
for pocs too this is not just about
asian americans only
and i do not see these creators doing
their part in doing their share
when you have a platform use it it
doesn't matter how big or small of a
following
but when you have a bigger following it
does reach
more people potentially but then you
also might be in my situation where i
thought that i had a big following and
it would reach a lot of people
but people just don't care enough and so
those videos flop
armies are so powerful we can make
a huge difference for this movement and
on top of it all i get messages from
people asking me
why haven't i posted as much content as
i usually do
if i'm being honest i don't want to post
about bts at all during this time
because it makes me upset and it reminds
me of how people are not talking about
the situation
and i know kpop is just a genre okay i
shouldn't take things too personally but
i'm sorry
because this directly involves the asian
community
it's really not as far-fetched as you
think it is
i made a video on my new tik tok account
today that had only six
followers and i reached far more people
than it did on my other account which
had 80
000 followers the number of your
following doesn't matter if you truly
care about this
issue then please speak up if you don't
want to speak about it that's fine too
share my videos please share them share
them on your socials
share links share resources share
petitions
share my link tree please just do
something and don't stay silent
because silence hurts more than anything
else alright so we talked about a lot of
things today
and i know that i kind of got pretty
heated and excited about a lot of things
because
these type of topics are never easy to
talk about and it does get me
kind of upset i hope you guys found this
video helpful
or insightful or comforting i just hope
that this video benefited you
in some type of way i'm really curious
about your stories and your experiences
growing up as an
asian or asian american and what acts of
racism
you might have faced or any struggles
that you have faced growing up
and so if you have anything that you
would like to share with me please
comment them down
in the comment section below i'm trying
to compile some of your stories
i'm trying to make a separate youtube
video where i talk about your guys's
asian american
experiences so help me out and let me
know some of your stories if you feel
like sharing them
if you have any stories please leave
them in the comment section below
because i will try to incorporate your
stories
in my next asian american videos as
always please
like and share this video subscribe to
this channel for more videos like these
and join the ladies fam remember to
follow me on all of my socials i have
them in my link tree which also has the
links and resources to stopping asian
hate crimes
remember you are precious you are worth
it
and you are so loved if you feel like
nobody loves you just remember i do
okay you are deserving of all the love
and happiness
in this world and i truly hope that you
are having a great day wherever you are
and i'm sending you all the love until i
see you guys in my next video
bye
[Music]
you