everyone's experience is different and I
am simply here to share mine if you
would like to share your own experience
of being asian-american please I'd love
to hear from you in the comments you can
also find me on Twitter or Instagram I
think it's really important to reach out
and share each other's stories and I'm
really excited to share mine
I got this video tag from youtuber Jen M
she is korean-american I've linked her
video down below so you can check this
out after watching mine let's just let's
just get into it
I am Filipino American let me just look
this up real quick number one results on
Google first generation are Filipinos
who were born in the Philippines and
have migrated to the United States
second generation Filipino Americans are
born in America so by that definition I
am second generation in 1973 my mom
immigrated from Manila Philippines to
Natchez Mississippi to work in a nursing
program so she came here on a work visa
then in 1974 my mom moved to Chicago to
reunite with her older sister my awesome
aunt who was already settled in so my
mom was just loving working in Chicago
until she got a broken heart she was
dating someone for a while and then they
broke up and then my mom came home to
the Philippines to surround herself with
family and just kind of heal from that
and that's where she met my dad the
whole cording to getting married thing
was such a crazy quick whirlwind because
they were married within months after
meeting each other it was definitely a
love at first sight thing they got
married in June 1981
but guess what my mom had a job and the
life in Chicago so shortly thereafter
she had to go back home she wasn't going
on honeymoon she was going back home to
Chicago to work but not lose her work
visa and then she worked on getting my
dad over to Chicago the spouse visa my
would come home to the Philippines and
visit my dad whenever she could in 1983
in June that's when I was born but my
dad was now working in Saudi Arabia let
me give you some political background on
what was going on in the Philippines at
this time you can look up the history of
the Philippines of what was going on
I'll just give you a really quick
overview there was a lot of chaos with
the Marcos regime at that time I'm
calling it a regime because that's what
it was a lot of people who had the
opportunity were just looking to get out
of there so my dad took the opportunity
to go work in Saudi Arabia just so he
can get out of there so over the next
three years my parents were keeping in
touch via mail and phone and my mom said
that the phone bill would go up to $500
$500 in the 80s I mean that's like crazy
now can you can someone figure out the
inflation on that like that is true love
finally my mom became a US citizen and
she was able to petition my dad to come
over and that's exactly what happened
so my dad finally came over to the u.s.
Chicago Illinois in 1986 I was born in
the south west side of Chicago market
Park were you at and then the
neighborhood was turning there was more
gang presence violence happening my
parents found it necessary to move me
and my brother outside of Chicago and
into suburbia that's where we ended up
in the southwest suburbs the first time
I felt different was pretty young I
loved Chicago my neighborhood was so
diverse that's where I saw that people
were just people and and that people
could look different they could have
light skin and dark skin and medium skin
and everything in between and I never
felt weird about that but it did happen
when our class was rehearsing for
religious ceremony of some sort I went
ooh a Catholic grade school a bunch of
us kids were standing around a couple of
these kids were saying stuff like yeah
look at this girl she's like Chinese so
they were like Chinese eyes and I was
like what is going on right now in that
moment is where I felt really different
there were other Asian kids in my class
so that was just really weird that they
were picking on me for that so yes that
was my first instance of feeling like oh
I guess I am different but so are you
you know what I mean so it's I think I
have some perspective now looking at
that like now I just see okay you kids
are just being dumb yeah yeah they're
both both I'm proud now growing up
Filipino American the move from a really
diverse neighborhood in Chicago I loved
my neighborhood I loved my school my
friends were all kinds of ethnicities I
really felt like it was this little
United Nations of people and then when
my parents moved me and my brother from
there to the southwest suburbs in 1992 I
was the only person of color in my
school and I think that really did a
number on my personality because I never
considered myself super shy until I
moved to the suburbs
imagine being not only the new girl but
also the only girl of color and an
otherwise very homogeneous environment
that was a really difficult time like I
left my really good friends and I didn't
know anybody in my neighborhood I didn't
know anybody in my class and people just
acted different it was like being thrown
in the deep end of an icy cold pool I
didn't know what to do in this new
environment so I just stayed quiet I
I need friends but I used that
opportunity to just envelop myself in
studies in reading and watching TV
because my parents were also very
protective I think it was kind of the
effect of coming from a bad neighborhood
they really wanted to make sure that
they had eyes on us at all times so for
a time I just kind of put away that side
of me which was really difficult because
like when you see my face like I can't
you can't hide who you are there wasn't
any real effort to take me in either the
new girl okay
cool you're over there all right welcome
to our class and we'll stay over here I
rejected it yeah I'll have to admit it's
hard for me to say out loud but yes I
did actively from grade school up until
my sophomore year of high school I just
didn't make any references to being
Filipino that's always fun stereotypes
are fun uh-huh thankfully I'm at a place
now there's more awareness of being
inclusive and encouragement of diversity
I've been watching a couple of these tag
videos and some of the things that have
come up that I agree with are the model
Asian stereotype you know it being
studious and being super smart luckily
because I didn't have any friends I
stayed inside and studied all day and
night so that seriously though yeah
there was some frustration that was a
struggle for me I had to work three
times as hard to be in honors classes
and I was because of that pressure I've
definitely had some bullying moments so
in my own neighborhood I have a home
with my husband and my dog your standard
suburban living I was walking outside
one day and then there was a car that
drove by with a bunch of dumb kids
inside and then they started yelling
stereotypical really derogatory
ching-chong sounds out of their car I
feel weird even just saying that
it's so disrespectful I was the only one
outside and they were definitely aiming
that at me and I didn't know what to say
like and then I started just hating my
neighborhood after that and hating
everyone after that and that was just
one instance of bullying I can't imagine
people who deal with that on a regular
basis and how they feel about themselves
and other people and their environments
I remember telling my husband like you
know this neighborhood sucks like we got
to move out of here there's no diversity
it's definitely getting better out here
in suburbia I am feeling better about it
if this is a stereotype the
fetishization saying like oh yeah
Filipinos are beautiful and both of the
smart stereotype and the beautiful
stereotype they're like nice stereotypes
but you know what they're still
stereotypes like nobody wants to be put
into this big group to just be lumped
together that's always just awkward you
know and then it becomes like about that
person's weird fetishes and hang-ups and
then it's like not even about you as an
individual anymore suddenly you're faced
with like some person's weirdness I was
always weirded out by the what are you
question what are you human and I've
heard the arguments well they're just
being curious about you they just want
to know more about you and expand their
own horizons and yeah but then again
that's about them and you're not
considering the feelings of the person
that your other that's what I have a
problem with the other ring would you be
asking me that if I was Caucasian
probably not oh my gosh there was just
one time at a bar my husband and I were
just sitting outside minding your own
business there was another couple
sitting at another table one of them the
guy comes over and he's like I'm sorry I
just I just gotta know if you're
asian-american you know when you're
gonna get the question like your spidey
sense tingle and then you're like
running through all the different kinds
of answers that you could have at that
time depending on your mood I was in a
very chill mood at this time I got a no
where are you from
I know what that question means cuz then
I'm gonna say I'm from Chicago and then
he's gonna say no where are you really
from and then I have to be like my
parents are from the Philippines and
then oh okay yeah I'm glad it's okay for
me to be here now I'm sure he means well
and he just wants to connect but at the
same time I don't appreciate the other
ring oh you're not from here are you and
then it's just frustrating because hell
yeah I'm from here I was born here I was
raised here but I understand that's like
the struggle that Asian Americans
struggle with and I don't even want to
say struggle it's a very strong word
it's just like an internal it's a
questioning it's a questioning if you're
watching this and you've asked someone
that question it's okay don't feel bad
just know that you know we might not be
cool with that um maybe you know there's
some people who are cool with that if
I'm just kind of navigating my own life
going about my business kind of one of
the last things I want to hear is like
hey you're different what are you like I
don't really owe you that answer comment
down below if you have experience with
that either way or if you've asked
someone what they are or if you get that
question a lot this might be kind of
going off topic a little bit we this is
about being proud of our heritage
I can understand Tagalog but I cannot
speak it and I think that comes from me
learning it at a young age and then
slowly growing out of it but I know for
a fact that if I spent a couple solid
months in the Philippines I would be
able to pick it back up again because
that's exactly what happened when my
parents took me and my brother back to
the Philippines for a couple vacations
so my parents would speak Tagalog to
each other and then they would speak
English to me and my brother I think
that comes from them really wanting us
to assimilate to American culture and to
not be
for a lack of a better term held back by
speaking Tagalog I think they just
really wanted us to become American they
had worked so hard to get here and they
wanted to make sure me and my brother
assimilated
I really wish they kept teaching us at
preserving that but hey you know if I
wanted to continue learning I could have
done that on my own and I didn't I am
actively excited to take it all in and
to relearn I'm excited about exploring
my roots it's it's something that I'm
constantly working on it's definitely
gonna be a lifelong process
my cousins who were born here they kind
of have the same thing they don't really
speak the language because our parents
encouraged us to fully assimilate I
think we could have assimilated while
still preserving the language but it's
really interesting how that's not an
uncommon story with Filipino American
kids kids it's 35 being a kid
among Filipino Americans in my
generation oh man language was never a
barrier between me and my parents since
they speak English
extremely fluently I could have complex
conversations about anything with my
parents where there is a barrier was
culturally oh my goodness because my
poor parents they grew up one way and
then they come to this new country
they're struggling to figure out what's
normal in America what is a good way to
raise my kids in America while
preserving the values that I have like I
imagine that's a struggle that they
dealt with where I was coming from my
parents were stuck in the old ways and
this is how kids are in this generation
and in America I had to convince them
that sleepovers are normal but they
didn't grow up having sleepovers that's
weird
for them right so can you imagine your
kids telling you that and you never
experienced that and you're like that's
a thing like that's I don't think so I
don't think you should be going over to
other people
houses and sleeping in them that was one
of many cultural generational clashes
that we would have oh my gosh high
school high school was such a struggle
because that's where you do so much
growing so quickly and it was again a
constant battle of yes it's normal to go
out hang out with friends to stay out
this late to do this and to do that and
I swear I wasn't trying to pull the wool
over their eyes I just wanted to do
normal American kid stuff that's where
we were coming at from both sides
because I was living a life that they
couldn't even in that sense I give them
mad props for taking themselves out of a
place that they know and going to a
completely new place and trying to raise
a family in it that's that's insane they
did a phenomenal job and I do thank them
for it through the struggles through the
fights they instilled really good values
in me and my brother and that's those
are values that are really strong within
me today family working hard and that
sense of entrepreneurialism being loving
and being kind that's something that can
transcend culture if you have those
values and they're passed on that's
that's a really good foundation for
future generation that I am thankful for
my parents are amazing my parents are my
heroes how long do you have
I could wax on about how incredible my
mother is and how hard-working she is
and she really set that example of
putting your nose to the grindstone and
working for what you want my dad has
been so instrumental in being an amazing
example for me and my brother about the
importance of friendship and the
importance of fostering a relationship
with people who mean so much to you
whether that's your actual family or
chosen family what I am super grateful
for with my parents is that they never
once were like oh you have to go into a
meadow
goal or professional feel they saw right
away that I was a creative person and
they did everything they could to foster
that and to encourage that so they
invested in all of the art classes all
of the art tools everything and they
definitely held fast to the adage that
whatever you want to do make sure you do
it well that's what I did and they're
amazing for that I love it I'm proud to
be Filipino American which is why
exploring my roots is going to be a
lifelong process I would love to learn
the language again I would love to
really dig my heels into the history of
it again because after a time in my
younger years of rejecting it I think
that had to happen for me to fully
appreciate it so I wouldn't change a
thing about my struggles with accepting
Who I am or a time from fourth grade
when I moved to the southwest suburbs up
until I was a sophomore junior in high
school I was actively rejecting my
heritage and then it wasn't until high
school when one of my really good
friends who was Caucasian that she had
to do this report on another country and
she chose the Philippines which I felt
two ways about it I was like flattered
but I was also a little bit confused
like well hi I was like there's so many
other cooler countries that's awful but
that's how I felt at the time I was
being lifted from this pool of rejecting
my heritage so that's what my friend was
doing for me she had this book to do her
report and she was showing me all these
amazing pictures of the lands and the
people and the food and she was like oh
my god the food is amazing
whoa is this what you grew up eating and
I was like yeah I was having flashbacks
to family parties where my aunt who is a
caterer she would bring over amazing
Filipino food and my grandma who lived
with us for a time she would make
Filipino food all day every day so yes
that's another we're
dilemma I would reject being Filipino
but I would also consume Filipino food
at home because my grandma would cook it
all the time my Lola you know what it
was it felt like being two people it
felt like I had to be I was one way at
home and then I had to be another way
outside of the home I was just really
embarrassed if anybody asked me about
what I was or I was like out here with
my Batman mascot so that's why I would
really throw me off on anybody
outside of the home would asked me like
oh are you know what are you and I'd be
like whoa whoa I'm out here with my with
with my mask on what are you doing
asking me about that stuff I'm outside
of the house not in the house so my
friend who was really getting into this
report it was fun
rediscovering the Filipino culture
through her eyes because it made me
appreciate it she had turned on the
light bulb of appreciation for my own
culture she was asking me all these
questions
I felt really a shame that I didn't know
a lot of them in a way I was kind of
doing my own personal report on the
Philippines she was like oh my gosh next
time you have a big family party can you
invite me so I could have all the food
and I was like yeah yeah sure totally so
she came over and had some food and she
was just like loved and everything and
it was really cool to see because these
were foods that I had spent my childhood
keeping a secret from other kids at
school there was this one incident where
I brought this dish called pancit for
lunch this kid in my class saw it and he
was like being super rude about it he
was like oh what is that that's so gross
oh my god what is that I just remember
just sitting there and like shamefully
just eating my food and keeping my head
down while this was making fun of my
food and it just kept happening I think
that was the beginning of me rejecting
my culture but that's okay because that
rejection I wouldn't change a thing
because it really makes me appreciate my
heritage and my culture even more you
know I
appreciate the experiences that I have
been through and that have enriched me
as a person and now I have something to
contribute to the world also I really
love the values that I've learned that
idea that you don't really quite feel
Filipino and you don't really quite feel
American that was so prevalent during
one of my trips to the Philippines I was
in high school and it was really crazy
going there because everyone kind of
looked like me and I really felt a sense
of belonging but that was until I had to
talk to anyone and it became very
apparent that I was American my mom and
I were eating at a restaurant one day
she kind of leans over to me and she's
like hey those girls behind you they
were kind of commenting on me I think it
was more fascination than being rude
again maybe a cultural thing my mom was
like they can tell you're American and I
was like what how do they know the way
you walked the way you hold yourself
you're very American another example of
that weird dilemma was this one time we
were at a carnival and I was doing
bumper cars and my bumper car broke down
mechanic came over to help me and he was
instructing me to do something in
Tagalog but I couldn't quite understand
him it was loud and he was speaking
really fast you know I probably have the
vocabulary of a four five year old so I
really felt out of my element like oh my
god I look like everyone but I don't
quite fit in I was able to figure it out
that was another incident which told me
Wow okay so you belong here but you also
don't now I think of that approach as
not being a negative but being a
positive it really adds dimension to my
personal experience and I am grateful
for that and I think that's one of the
things I love about being Filipino
American I also love the rich history of
the Philippines there is so much more
for me to learn I have a lot of cousins
my mom's side there's ten of them
on my dad's side there were eight those
are a lot of babies so can you imagine
just how many cousins bulk of them in
the Philippines Canada all throughout
the United States
rather a few in China oh I think there's
one Australia that's what I love about
my family specifically is that we are
everywhere and to me that makes the
world feel like a smaller place I feel
like I can go and visit them and say hey
I have family here we have family all
around the world now and that's what I'm
gonna take away from it gosh this was a
heavy one guys I mean I wasn't crying or
anything but and hey hey hey hey sorry
my dogs they're getting crazy that's one
thing that I've really admired about the
Filipino people we are resilient and we
can adapt we can bounce back we can make
things happen
we are entrepreneurial we take
initiative we are innovative and I am
pretty darn proud of that so I want to
hear from you if you have a story about
being not just Filipino American but
Asian American anything please share
your experience in the comments below I
think people are ready to hear more
about us and from us let's get out there
let's share our stories I'm out here
sharing mine and I would really really
love to hear from you I feel like I've
really connected with you and I hope you
got something out of it so if you did
please give me one of these thanks for
watching and I'll see you in the next
one bye