i don't know if this is going to get any
better
like this angle is going to get any
so we're just going to go with it so
hello everybody i am back
and today we're going to do a little
q a so i did a little story on
instagram and i asked people to send me
questions
about youtube and twitch and just like
social media in general i guess
um and so
i got some pretty interesting questions
and there are some things that i did
want to talk about
um that have like come up within the
past few days
and so yeah we're just going to roll
with it
grab your coffee whatever you want to do
you can get a snack
come sit down and we're just going to
chat today
all right so first question um would you
do a collab with any other youtubers or
twitch streamers um
i have done collabs with other youtubers
specifically girls that went to ucla
with me
uh there were four of us that pretty
consistently did
youtube around the same time and our
content was kind of the same
and if you guys want to watch that then
i will link it up here
basically we did a podcast it was
supposed to be a four series but then it
was a lot of work
so we only did one episode but it was
basically
what you would talk about or teach
younger people that are going to ucla
like advice that you would give them
so that one came out um i did that with
alice
nia elaine and
i so the four of us did that and
honestly i really liked it like i loved
getting different personalities and
different people's opinions on certain
things like not just my own
so that was really fun so for twitch
streaming i'm a little bit
newer so i haven't done
i don't know if squad streaming is only
for partners but
i haven't done like a collab with any
other twitch streamers yet
um i just i'm pretty small and so
you know i think the time will come when
like i will get the opportunity to do it
but i just don't
i don't like have that exposure yet so i
haven't done it but i'm really down to
do it like i'm down to
play games with other streamers or like
i i usually do play with other people
but sometimes like we're either
like neither of us is streaming or one
of us is streaming so
um yeah that's definitely something like
to plan for but i am down for that
um question number two the hardest part
about doing it
there's a lot that comes along with this
question
um consistency criticism
um and just kind of being okay with
sharing your private life and you know
having people judge that and i think
that
for someone like me i am definitely i'm
like two people in one i'm very
sensitive
but i'm also very like i don't give a
what people think but i am also
sensitive so like it does bother me if
people like have something to say about
it but like
at the same time like my mental is like
okay this is gonna make me like a
like a stronger person it's gonna make
me not care about these comments right
uh consistency because i have recently
run into like burning out um
and that was from twitch and so i was
streaming
probably every other day consistently
for a while
and then um recently like
two or three weeks ago i just got this
like
feeling that i just didn't want to
stream like i didn't want to socialize
i didn't want to have people like look
at me on
camera and i stopped streaming for like
a
like almost a week or more uh and then
now i've been streaming probably once
every four days
and so it's been really hard to get back
into it because
right now i'm thinking like i just want
a chill night like i watch people stream
and i'm popping the chats and everything
and like i just want to have a chill
night with my friends and
you know relax watch some anime watch a
movie
play some valor in and i it like makes
me really happy
but then at the same at the same time
there are days when i miss it i'm like
man like i really want to talk with my
chat i want to see what they're like up
to like i just want to catch up so those
are the days that i do stream
um but yeah hardest part consistency
consistency is everything with both of
these platforms like the algorithm
really works with you if you're on a
consistent schedule
um criticism because
you know you need to have like a strong
mental for this
strong mental and sometimes creativity
like the three c's
uh you need to think of new ideas like
so that people don't get bored or like
if you know that
this kind of content isn't working then
you have to try another thing like
planning filming timing hair makeup
outfit it's just a lot sometimes but you
know
i enjoy it what's the weirdest
interaction that you've had with
chats and comments weirdest interaction
there have been a few mostly from twitch
um i've gotten like
are you free february 14th that's
you know it's not weird it's just kind
of
uh okay i had one guy say like
can you do that ahegao face and i was
like what the
is i go and then i looked it up and
it's some like japanese
porn stuff and like i'm like okay i'm
banning you
so then i banned him um
another thing i think something that's
consistently
a little bit weird for me is
when people that i don't know
ask to play and it's like i'm the kind
of person where i feel bad if i say no
and like that was me at the very
beginning i'd be like oh yeah
like i'm down like we can
um maybe like after this game and then
after that game i like end stream
because i would forget that i had
something like i had to play with
someone but like
i didn't actually want to play with them
like one i don't know you two
like i don't yeah i don't know like it
might be awkward
um and so that's something that i really
struggle with
um something also that was hard was that
like
when i did play with a viewer and i was
ranking
we just were not on the same level like
we weren't in the same rank
like my friends and i like
we were all on the same page like we
kind of knew what we were doing but like
this person like
it was just hard and my elo got trolled
and like
i was just like you know what i'm not
playing with like random people that i
don't know anymore
especially in a ring theme like i'll
play unrated with you like that's fine
but yeah it's just i don't want that to
happen again
so yeah that's like a weird interaction
i haven't had like too weird i've had
like sims in my channel and everything
but like
um who is my favorite youtuber or
streamer
my favorite twitch streamer is jessica
kim
she one is so real like she is
so
funny i love her she's cute she's like
entertaining to watch um you know she's
very down to earth especially like when
she handles like mean comments and stuff
like that it's just like what the
are you
talking about like to the person that's
like commenting these things
um two i love her editing like
her editor for youtube is honestly so
good like they're so
the timing is just so great um i love
her
emotes i like her sub badges
everything about her twitch stream in
general is just
everything i aspire to have um
okay so favorite twitch dreamer jessica
kim
or plu i love blue um but
favorite youtuber would definitely have
to be
whaley whaleyhong
wallytv sofia chang but she's like
friends with them so it's like jen
sophia i forgot her name
whaley i just love their vibe like
sophia's vibe of her vlogs it's just
really like
it makes you feel homey like it's very
down to earth that's just
that's definitely what wally tv vlogs
bring to me like i rewatch their old
vlogs just to like pass time throughout
the day like
it makes me feel really comfortable i
love watching those and i love when they
do like travel vlogs camping vlogs i
love that
um yeah so if you guys haven't checked
them out definitely check them out
but i also love chonde jonde like joan
kim
her vlogs are just everything i was far
to do in korea like i just want to live
in korea
soon someday uh next one if you had to
choose one game to play for the rest of
your life what would it be
and i'm going to say this because i've
spent way too much money on this game
and all my friends played valerian
i've spent probably almost 500 on this
free game
don't come for me because i love my
skins they're so nice they're so pretty
yeah now uh
next question this has nothing to do
with the topic but it's a very
interesting question so
would you date a poor great looking guy
or a rich ugly guy
if we're excluding personality and the
way he treats me and just morals in
general
you know that's a hard one because i
really take morals and
personality as a big thing like it
doesn't matter how much money you have
if you're like a good guy and then
you're like really nice to me and you're
really sweet
like genuine like nothing else matters
but
i guess i would date the rich ugly
looking guy because i'm not
not superficial but then again i am
materialistic in that way
so that's a double-edged sword i feel
like i lost either way if i answered
um what made you want to start streaming
or creating content
i feel like i've always been a very
creative person
i've always loved making stuff so when i
was younger it was like drawing
it was paintings stuff like that
when i got into high school i would
watch vlogs
because i i watched vlogs
of college like what it's like to be in
college what it's like to go to ucla
and that was when i was really depressed
because that was something that like
kept me going it like made
me want to do something with my life
um and so when i got into college i was
like you know what i'm going to make
this video because like i want people to
see
what my life is like i want to document
things so that i can look back on it
so you know his memories for me it was
memories for other people it was just
information for the people i love making
content like
i love putting myself out there and for
people to get to know me
um that's where my enfj comes out but my
infj
that i sometimes test as um
you know it's kind of like i don't want
people to judge me i don't want people
to see how many like flaws i have but
you know
i feel like that comes along with it so
it's like you know i'm accepting
how perfectly imperfect i am and that's
perfectly fine with me so but
creating content i i just love it in
general like i
went to twitch because youtube was just
so slow at the time like i
didn't have i didn't have content to
make
and i wanted to do something and twitch
was perfect like i love it i love
streaming
i love drawing um i like drawing my
emotes my sub batches
and yeah i i love it it's the best of
both worlds
um what do you value in friendship and
what can you see it being valuable in
the future
honesty realness
sense of humor um
you know being down to earth and i feel
like if we vibe
then you know it'll work like if we're
just being very genuine with each other
like if you're
trying to be friends with me for the
same reason that i am like just
like for friendship not to like gain
anything from it
then you know that's a healthy
relationship but um
you know if you're in it for other
reasons and like i find out the hard way
then
but what can i see being valuable in the
future honestly like
i make friends just to like if
like my friends that i've made recently
are
honestly kind of like my family like
where we tell each other things like we
come each other we come to each other
when we have problems
um you know we're there for each other
like when we're having a bad day we're
not having a good day we hype each other
up like
it's honestly like probably the
healthiest thing that i've found
and not everyone that you meet online is
going to have that same intention
and i have learned that the hard way so
what inspired you to get into these
platforms
youtube um i was watching at the time
i think i was watching wally tv i'm
pretty sure i was watching walleye tv
because there weren't very many vloggers
around that time
and you know i was like you know what
this is really cool but like
i'm nobody nobody's going to want want
to watch my life like
my life is not interesting when you
think about it it's kind of like
these people started the same way like
they had a passion for something
they didn't really have anything you
know to offer besides their experience
and what they're bringing to the world
and because they were real with it
you know it works and so it's kind of
like the same thing if you have
consistency if you're
you know passionate about what you're
doing people are going to see that and
they're going to want to watch it
but for twitch um you know i saw i was
watching jessica for a while
um i had no intention of streaming
because i didn't think
that i was i had the personality for it
uh
two i didn't have a pc at the time
and so when i did build my pc i was like
you know i am terrible at games i have
never played an fps in my life
i don't know how to do this like no one
is going to want to watch me
but as i started to stream more and i
started to like
you know gain viewers it wasn't about
how good i was at the game
because they can watch professionals do
this
any time of the day and so the reason
why they were watching me
is like for my personality and for you
know having conversations with me and my
chat and people in there
and seeing the friends in there and so
that was kind of like the best part
um and so i think it was initially
a jessica stream that made me want to
start streaming
um so a last topic that i wanted to talk
about
was i just like
something that bothered me was
i think going back to the topic of
criticism and being judged um
i have no problem taking criticism
from people that you know have
experience in this like if you know what
you're doing
and you're like you know like you could
really fix some of these things blah
blah blah
that's fine i'm gonna be like i have no
idea what i'm really doing i'm winging
it i've been winging it for like
three years and i've been on here um but
if you're going to
come at me like whoa what the is
she doing like
like why the is it taking her this
long to do this like
i think i think that like that made me
so mad
is because like people that i expected
i don't know it was kind of fake the way
that like
something happened there's like a
scenario in my mind that happened
and you know if you're saying like no
we're just trying to help you we're just
trying to make you better
that way that you're trying to
teach me how to do this because
that is not how you do it welcome to my
ted talk
um but anyways so
so yeah if you like this video if you
liked the question
and answer kind of thing i might be
posting more in my stories
for you guys to answer questions um
but yeah if you guys enjoyed this video
um please give it a like and i will see
you guys in the next one
bye
i sound like such a hater
okay bye guys
you