hello guys so today I'm going to be
doing a more I don't know personal video
because I feel like all my videos are
like I don't know not personal and you
know telling you anything about me
so today I'm going to be dedicating this
whole video to telling you stuff about
me um yeah I don't know who this would
be interesting too but we'll see
basically I combined to get to know me
tag together so I've like questions from
both and so there might be like repeat
questions go right now I have 78
questions to answer
grab a snack grab a drink you know get
comfy because we might be here for a
while I don't know I don't know yeah I
talked really fast so hopefully that
will aid us in getting through this
faster so let's get started I am drink
two coffees before I started filming
this so it might be a good time to look
at it oh my god question number one
what's your name my name is Emma my full
name Emma Francis Chamberlain which gets
us into our second question what's your
middle name my middle name is Francis so
where are you from I'm from California
the bay area to be exact what do I do
for a living nothing as nothing what is
your favorite color okay this is like a
loaded question I relief I like a bunch
of different colors for a bunch of
different reasons so I don't have an
answer but I like all colors um yes as
long as I match to my aesthetic you know
just kidding um what is your star sign
my star sign is a Gemini it actually
literally I am sketch my sign like every
aspect of a Gemini is me like talking
too much
that's basically it favorite music genre
I don't really know I know which ones I
don't like I don't really like pop music
I'm not the biggest country music fans
but I like you know alternative kind of
indie stuff you know get the like
hipsters well um who is your favorite
musician so I like a bunch of different
musicians like if you're talking about
like I like 50s music I like 70s and 80s
music so like with 50s I like Doris Day
and Bobby Vinton when it comes to 70s
and 80s music I like Elton John The
Beatles like I don't even know like like
a bunch of different stuff but like
recent artists like new or
artists I like real-estate beach house
Matt DeMarco love Matt Marco Taemin
Paula The Strokes let me go to my
Spotify right now two L's later sweet
foxes two door cinema club Vampire
Weekend
I like beach fossils okay I like a lot
of artists but those are just a few of
them favorite food honestly it kind of
changes all the time I do really love
sushi but I'm vegetarian so like veggie
sushi yeah I'm like a fake sushi fans
but whatever I like to smoothies
favorite drink okay three number one my
strawberry smoothie that I make that's
just strawberries lemon juice and water
and then blend it up and it turns into a
slushie really good another thing I like
it's sparkling water with lime squeezed
into it really good then last not least
my favorite drink of all time iced
almond milk latte it's not decaf tea cap
is for weenies no skidding subject okay
favorite snack I feel like I eat a bunch
of small snacks throughout the day like
I never eat like a big meal I just eat
snacks honestly I like to drink like my
favorite snack is those strawberry
smoothies that I drink where's just
strawberries lemon in water really good
favorite holiday I like Christmas
because I'm basic I mean like I don't
know every other holiday just seems to
be like not as awesome as Christmas the
best vibes the most like I don't know I
slept that time of the year Christmas
favorite pastime I like I mean you know
exercising taking that editing videos
filming videos taking more naps so yeah
my main form of pastime is like doing
videos right now and go to the gym
favorite sport probably to my favorites
I did competitive cheer which i think is
a sport some people you know don't come
at me but like I think cheers the sport
when it's competitive and so probably
that or track because I did track this
year at school and I really liked it
what is something you are talented at
personally I don't like this question
because like I don't know like I don't
really know if I'm talented at anything
because like you're your own worst
critic so like I kind of think I suck at
everything but like that's kind of human
nature so I don't know when I'm talented
at honestly I don't have an answer for
that what is something you wish you were
talented at I mean I wish I was talented
everything I wish I was a good saying
I wish I was like a good dancer I wish
that I was I don't know I wish I was
good at a lot of things I wish I was
like a really fast runner I don't know I
wish I was talented that everything
honestly are you competitive II it like
depends like I can be super competitive
in certain situations where I just like
need to win but then other times I'm
like it I don't really mind moving so
it's like it's kind of in between
describe yourself in a single sentence
oh my god this is getting really hard um
I don't I don't know how to like put it
new Sens I think I'm like pretty hard
working and like you know like if I get
my head okay just mechanism it if I like
get set on something like I will not
stop till I like get that thing and
that's a sense about me what is the best
compliment you ever received
I think whatever people say like I'm a
really like nice person or my kind
person or people say that to me that's
like probably the nicest compliment I
could get because it's something I like
strive to do is like be a kind person
and be nice or whatever so when people
say that I succeed at that it really
makes me super happy so probably that
what are some of your bad habits
probably like overthinking a lot I
definitely think about things like way
too much I overanalyze every single
situation ever
that's probably probably um favourite
things about yourself I would say is
like what I said earlier how I like
don't stop until I like succeed at
whatever I wanted to see that and
obviously sometimes I don't succeed but
if I like reach the end or like I push
myself to like the highest point that
was like successful point I can get to
probably that what is on the top of your
bucket list honestly I don't really have
like specific things on my bucket list
but I know for sure I want to I
definitely want to travel more I mean
that's like a really like cliche answer
but like go outside of the country or
maybe go to like I don't know Bali looks
really cool kind of wanna go there like
just like really like unique places just
like explore more you know three
long-term goals honestly I would just
say like overall I'm not even going to
say three because I only have one just
like wherever I'm at in my life at any
point be like really happy and like just
genuinely happy whether that means like
whatever that means in the other aspects
of my life like I don't care about that
I don't care what I end up doing is that
except just overall being happy and
also really cliche but like the truth
three short-term global we're not that
short-term that would probably mean
today and that would mean try to not
take it off and then try to not drink
more than three coffees within one hour
it's hard and I don't know if I'm gonna
succeed but I think that I might be able
to so I'll let you know what are you
doing today to accomplish those goals
well I haven't done anything for either
of those today taking a nap wise it is
currently 12 p.m. and I have not taken a
nap yet so we are going strong in that
aspect the coffee thing I already had
two today so I'm not doing so well on
that one but I think I think if I really
control myself and I can wait another
like 20 minutes I might be able to only
have one more coffee today so we'll see
what is your biggest accomplishment
becoming more confident and happy and
summing that sexuality a big
accomplishment although starting a
YouTube channel because I always wanted
to and it was kind of an interesting
story about how it happened so one day I
will do a story time and tell you why I
started YouTube because it's actually
really interesting but I had a channel a
long time ago like in like fourth grade
and I did like outfits on there and it
was like horrible and I can't find those
videos anymore luckily like literally
thank God they were so embarrassing but
I'm probably also like starting a
YouTube again because I always wanted to
and now I'm doing it so that's cool
what didn't I feel first date for you
okay well I don't go on dates very often
sadly this is also kind of cliche I
don't like things like going to the
movies I don't like things like a dinner
because I just like really boring to me
like just so like awkward well with a
movie it's just awkward because you
can't talk and it's just weird and then
do you like went to dinner you're like
force like look at the other person in
the face and then they have to watch you
eat I don't know do something about
that's just too boring um something like
really fun like in adventure like
driving somewhere kind of far away like
driving to the beach or something like
swimming in the ocean at like 2:00 a.m.
or something okay that's actually good
not really fun something like that it
would be like really memorable and like
special so what is something you look
for in a partner I'm 16 and I have
basically no experience in this topic
but I would say just like somebody who
is like willing to put in
people effort into the relationship but
also like somebody who you can trust in
like the trust is mutual so like you're
not worried about like where they are
all the time or who they're talking to
or whatever like somebody like trust me
enough that like I could like hang out
with another guy friend and like the guy
wouldn't care you know also just
somebody who's like genuinely kind and
like thoughtful of me and my feelings
because I'm like emo I'm kidding um but
like yes so he's like really like
considers your feelings I'm bad at this
stuff who is your role model I would say
like definitely my parents I mean for
sure like that's an obvious one I was
something like a really inspirational
person is like Casey nice - a youtuber
he's a great person I don't know he's
really inspirational to me which one of
your parents are you more like depends
like really similar to my dad because we
like the same music we like doing the
same things he has a YouTube channel too
we both like to like go like explore in
the city and like you know I get coffee
and stuff except I think we have a lot
of like I also think I'm aligned with my
mom because you know we both like enjoy
it sort of women parts of like life like
shopping and like stuff like that so it
kind of depends which one of your
parents are you closest to this is also
kind of like I don't have one or the
other I'm close with both equally in
like different ways because I'm an only
child
only children get really close with
their parents so both honestly what is
the last book you read um I don't read
like I genuinely do not read ever
because I hate it I don't know why I
just don't like reading and let them
find like a really really good book that
I like really love I just don't read so
I don't have an answer for that what is
your favorite fairy tale I help freaking
know like I ever like what what even is
a fairy tale like I mean I know but like
I know I don't have an answer what is
your favorite quote I hate reading
quotes out loud like something about
that is so corny to me but let me look
at my Pinterest on my quote board and
I'll just read one that I find how the
keep it simple good things are coming
that's a good one
remember that kids keep doing that good
mindset you know favorite subject in
school probably science it's the most
interesting to me it's also one of the
hardest classes in school for me but I
do enjoy science so probably that I like
biology more than chemistry definitely
subject you were best at honestly like
depends because like I don't think I'm
very like it depends on like if you mean
like which I personally think I strive
at or like
which one has a better grade like that's
just different but like I think I'm okay
like history and stuff like that but I
absolutely hate it so it's like I
vennett like I'm probably better at
history in English so I am it like math
and science but like I enjoy math and
science more don't ask me why
favorite teacher honestly I don't have
an answer I liked all of my teachers in
elementary school in the second I got to
high school the relationships weren't as
good in high school and I'm still in
high school yeah it's just a lot more on
the line a lot more tension so that's
that we look the biggest impact on your
life probably my parents because they've
always been there my whole entire life
so there's really nobody else in this
entire universe who could have more of
an impact on me than my parents because
I've been around them my whole life
and I'm an only child and they're like
the biggest influence on me what do you
use most probably Instagram or visco
what these are technology could you not
live without
honestly I don't just have one phone
laptop very important and camera also
very important but if for some reason I
couldn't have a camera the phone as the
camera so probably phoned in laptop what
countries have you visited well I've
been out of the country twice I went to
Ireland and then I went to the Dominican
Republic what countries would you like
to visit if it was up to me I would
visit every country in the entire
universe
so most embarrassing memory oh my god
okay this is really good so basically
like I did cello in fifth grade um which
is weird considering I literally four
foot six inches and probably weighed 50
pounds and was basically the size of a
cello but anyway it was the end of the
school year and we had like our last
recital saying parents were their
grandparents were their uncles off
everybody you can think of was there the
crowd was going wild when we finally
finished our fifth grade Orchestra
performance and all of us sucks we
probably sounded like actual crafts
considering we were literally just dry
turned and barely had brains developed
yet just kidding that's not true but you
don't mean um anyway so obviously it at
the end of the year they gave out awards
for people who are really outstanding so
I was sitting there in my chair you know
I wasn't expecting to get an award
because well I
just didn't play like I literally move
my fingers and just like lightly put my
bow the bow I'll insert a bow across
like the thing I wouldn't even make any
noise with my actual cello I would just
kind of like fake it the whole time
so I wasn't really expecting an award
because I really didn't deserve it
basically I heard our conductor guy say
like all of the people who play cello
stand up that's why I heard in my brain
okay I don't know why I've heard this
because that is not what he said he said
blank name stand up I thought he said
all the people who play cello stand up
but it turned out he said like this
cello player stand up and it said her
name and then she stood up well I'd sit
up with her but I didn't win me Awards
oh okay moving on how many relationships
have you been in haha one in fifth grade
so but I mean I guess in you're 16 you
don't need to be in a relationship so I
guess it's fine but I'm no I'm just
getting good I'm good single life is the
best life you know if you could give
your younger self any advice what would
it be
you will never regret being kind one
thing that you know now that you wish
you would have known as a kid that's
like the same question and I'll say it
again you will never regret being kind
ever okay like I just remember how me
and everybody was in middle school to
each other and it was just the norm you
know second grade self girl would steal
your sticker and talk about a freaking
fight and like at this point in my life
I've learned you know just be the bigger
person always be kind no matter what
anybody says it up to you being kind you
will never regret it
okay tea or coffee okay coffee I'm sorry
that's just like not even a question I
don't even like that we don't even need
to discuss it okay coffee how tall are
you I am five three and a half but I
think I'm 5'4 now so I don't know cats
or dogs um dogs I mean I don't know I
just like dogs better sorry I'll do cat
people know hey I have cats and dogs so
like yeah but dog alert is better don't
everybody who doesn't like dogs doesn't
on one so like that's the answer to that
funniest moment throughout school on
stage like all moments in school are
absolute hell rather than anything funny
I usually am NOT laughing during 12
usually crying hysterically constantly
because of how much I actually despise
being there if I think of one later I'll
let you know but like for right now all
my memories are just absolute terror are
you in slash have you gone to college I
am going to be a junior next year stone
no what was your worst subject in high
school um while I'm in high school now
and worse subject honestly I think my
least favorite would have to be English
I just think it's so boring but I think
the one that I was like the worst outlet
had the worst grade was probably like
chemistry but like I actually really
liked chemistry so it's kind of like a
love-hate favorite animal okay I really
I really like all animals I think it's
easier to say the ones that I don't like
I have a actual phobia like no joke
dead-ass phobia of caterpillars I hate
them but I don't even like I don't care
about snakes I spiders or if you like if
they're near me I freaked out but is
there like 10 feet away from me I don't
care
um like I'm cool doll that caterpillars
just really make me lose it like I just
I can't if they're near me if I see a
picture of one like I will initiate I
don't know I don't know it's mental what
sports do you play so have you played
well earlier I mentioned that I did
cheer and track but I also did okay this
is going to take a while I did karate
Taekwondo when I was like six so that
happened so I did ice skating I did
gymnastics I did I never did any like
ball sports I can ever do softball or
soccer I never did any of that and then
I did cheerleading competitively then I
also did in high school two year for
like a half of a year and then I did
cross-country for one year and then I
did track for one year and I did both of
those track and cross-country slash your
favorites book
oh I don't really have one but I did
really like okay I don't know if anybody
remembers these books but it was like I
need to look up the title you'll have em
like literally myself so that I can find
it okay I finally found it so I'll
insert a picture here but it was this
series and it's like if you're reading
this it's too late and no
not talking about the Drake album cover
I'm talking about these books and I was
like younger when I read them but like
no joke if I read them today I would
still enjoy them because they were so
good like I don't know why they're like
teen books but they're so good like I I
need to read them again because I
haven't read them since like seventh
grade but they were like my favorite
books read like no joke it would be like
a 500 page book and I would go through
it in like no joke three days and like
it's I like reading if I find a book I
like it's that I don't like that many
books I don't care how old you are I
don't care how just you get when you're
like you know 17 looking in the preteen
book section I don't care these books
are so good no matter what your age is
who are some of your favorite youtubers
okay this um literally like this is one
you need to like grab a popcorn I have
so freakin many favorite favorite
youtubers I'm going to pull up my
subscriptions right now and like tell
you all them because I have no jokes so
many I love KC nice that I love Tana
mojo
I love Olivia Jade I love Mel joy she's
also a Bay Area girl shout-out to you if
you ever watch this which you won't but
you know I love Haley sany sany sany and
Mail fanny I don't know if you'd say me
I don't know how to say my name I loved
Sidney Carlton I love Sienna mirabela
I love Callie Kaiser I love oh my god
there's so many I love jennxpenn I love
Aspen and Parker oh I love Shane Dawson
yeah basically oh and then my absolute
literal luck to my life like a love with
them they're just not this is like my
youtube guilty pleasure but I love the
don't wig wick they're just the cutest
thing in my entire life like I can only
dream that they would watch this video
but they ever did like just I'm just
letting you know like I love I'm over a
rant over what is your favorite movie
one Napoleon Dynamite watched it 100
times great solid best movie ever I love
it too Coraline if you don't like
Coraline I'm sorry but I just I don't
get it look I love that movie and I all
forever loved that movie and if it
creeps you out
you need to man up because that's a
great athlete okay next
remember I've came - great movie love
that movie as well super just
aesthetically well done last but not
least I loved the walls and gromit movie
you know they're not only movies are
kind of like episodes but like I kind of
consider them movies single or taken
taken obviously I'm single I'm very very
single okay
the only twins if you're watching me do
you speak any difference in any
different languages and how well well I
speak español um a little bit because
you know with last year took Spanish too
so I can say like the basic stuff like
see hola como estas you know do you have
any siblings
no and that explains a lot doesn't it
how would you describe your fashion
sense it's like a combination of just
like random it's so random it just
changes all the time like I love
accessorizing okay whatever I like to be
like effortless I guess like it's not
really ever listed just like I don't
like to wear a lot of makeup
that's just economic that I don't like
to do a lot of my hair I don't like to
like do a lot of extra stuff I just like
to do what comes natural to me statement
restaurant I like Asian box I don't know
if they have them everywhere but Asian
box is really good favorite TV shows
right now I'm watching the office I also
watched Pretty Little Liars for a little
bit I didn't think that I was going to
stop but it just everybody everybody
else always says like we all just kind
of drop like flies because it went too
long like it just kept going and like I
just couldn't watch it anymore PC or Mac
Mac all the way I'm sorry I've never had
a PC in my life and I never ever will
and honestly if I do like come to my
house and slap me but like I just love
Apple I always have I've always been
into it I've grown up with Apple like
when I was a wee little tot like I
little iPods were coming out and we were
just growing up together hand in hand
like BFFs from start you know what phone
do you have
iPhone 7 plus matte black of course of
course I got it in matte black it's like
I'm trying to be Kylie Jenner I'm doing
everything I can possible to be just
like her last question of this entire
video honestly this is so long like I
don't even know if my computer's gonna
have space for all this one of my bad
habits would be oh I already went over
that question okay because like I
basically what I did was I went combined
to so like this is the most random
amount of questions and stuff and
there's like repeats because I combined
two tags together because I didn't feel
like just 30 questions with
so in debt instead egg is like 75 I
don't know whatever I mean I'm an extra
but we work with it that is it for
today's video but yeah I hope you
learned a little bit about me I hope you
enjoyed this video if you did give it a
thumbs up subscribe to my channel let me
know down below any kind of video
requests you have for me any kind of
questions you have for me anything go
check out my other videos you know
everybody says the same thing in every
outro of every video so I think you
already know the basic gist we'll see
you next time
[Music]