[Music]
hi I'm Kate Roy welcome back to my
channel I know that it's been like three
months since I've uploaded a video I've
just been really busy with work but I
finally had a free morning to film and I
really miss filming and editing even
when it's just like a sit down video
today I thought that I would do the
Asian American tag which I believe was
started by Amy
aka vagabond Hughes and I've actually
wanted to do this type of video since I
saw Wei Lee upload one called growing up
Chinese American I will link both of the
videos I just mentioned in the
description box so I've had like a
running note in my phone of just my
thoughts on this topic
but I thought instead I would just do
the tag to help structure the video a
little better so let's just begin which
ethnicity are you I am Korean I've
actually gotten comments of people who
didn't know that I was Korean which I
thought was weird like I thought Choi
was mostly a Korean last name but yeah
Korean which generation are you I am
second generation so my dad moved to the
US when he was eight so he's actually
pretty Americanized or he's just
completely Americanized I've heard that
being called 1.5 generation because even
though he is a first generation
immigrant he pretty much acts like he
was born here because he came here when
he was so young so my dad moved when he
was young he's like 1.5 generation my
mom moved after college after my dad and
my mom got married so she is
first-generation a first-generation
immigrant and I am second generation
what is the first experience where you
felt different I think it was pretty
early on because my elementary school
didn't have a lot of Koreans let alone
Asians I can remember maybe two other
Asians in my school in elementary school
two of my closest friends one of them
had blond hair and blue eyes and the
other one had like light brown hair and
hazel eyes and I was always really
jealous that they had such beautiful
pretty eye colors and
I think one of the earliest memories I
have a feeling different is being in the
bathroom together because girls go to
the bathroom together and we were
washing her hands and I remember looking
in the mirror that was above the sinks
and just not wanting to look at my face
and if that sounds really dramatic and
sad when I say it that way but it was
just I saw how big and pretty their eyes
were and how like slim their faces were
as you probably know Asians typically
have flatter faces with a lower nose
bridge and with monolids instead of
double eyelids or an eyelid crease so
just seeing the difference in our faces
I was really uncomfortable and just
didn't want to look at that I wouldn't
say that was an ongoing struggle but it
was something that I would be reminded
of here and there and be like oh right I
look different than most of my friends
were you always proud of your heritage
or was there a time when you rejected it
I wouldn't say I've ever rejected my
heritage there were definitely times
when I was embarrassed by it one time in
elementary school I think like my mom
was picking me up from school and so I
was like coming out the gate and she
like wasn't noticing me and so I was
gonna call out to her but I was
embarrassed to say oma because everyone
else they say mom mommy
and um just sounds weird and foreign so
I remember not feeling very proud in
that moment I was also always
self-conscious of my middle name because
my middle name is my Korean name and my
friends in school their middle names
were like Kimberly and Erin and mine was
weird so that was also something that I
was really aware of and embarrassed by
and I just wanted a normal middle name
what are some stereotypes that you
struggle with I think the only
stereotype I struggle with right now is
that Asian women are bad drivers
whenever I make any sort of mistake I
just feel like oh god I hope they don't
see me and then you know I'm just adding
to this stereotype of Asian women being
bad drivers so that is something I
always thinking about when I'm driving
I've had a couple times recently where I
was talking to somebody for the first
time and they commented on how good my
English was so I guess there's that
stereotype still of Asians all being
foreigners so that's something that I
don't struggle with on a day-to-day
basis but it does pop up here and there
can you speak your language Kumar sees
Anita orders a toy or mother hungry okay
Tanya so cool
yo society hibachi unconscious Harrison
edik Rizzo hands on Sheba's Agumon mani
sokyoku um Parma Gannon Hondo castle
where many take a Yaqui Locker -
Seungyeon sir tell Sunita how has being
asian-american affected your
relationship with your parents I know a
lot of people my age who have parents
that immigrated to the u.s. together
they often struggle with a language
barrier I feel very fortunate that I
don't struggle with that as much
I definitely don't struggle with that
with my dad my mom is you know there's a
bit of a barrier there but it's still
like she's lived in the States for quite
a long time and also because my friends
in elementary school weren't Asian so my
mom's friends who are my friend's moms
they also weren't Asian so it's been you
know a long time of her coming out of
that comfort zone speaking Korean I
think just on my end as I grow older I
feel much more grateful for the
struggles that my parents have been
through in order to to raise me and give
me a good life with a good education and
a great family environment so I think
that's something just like on my end it
has affected my relationship with my
parents in terms of me being more
grateful as I grow older and realized
that more and more and that's not just
for Asian Americans I think that goes
for all people who have parents that are
immigrants there's that level of
gratitude that you you know you build as
you grow older how do you feel about
your heritage now and do you identify
with it I talked about how at my
elementary school there were only like
two other Asians
my school but by the time I got to
middle school in high school there were
Koreans and Asians everywhere and I
started to feel much more comfortable
and in college I was really involved in
my church fellowship and it was pretty
much all Korean so I was I went from
like when I was younger like not being
surrounded by any Asians to just
completely being surrounded by Asians
and mostly Koreans there are times when
I'm self-conscious of that and I'm aware
of my friend group being mostly people
who look like me and have a similar
background when I am with friends who
aren't Korean or Asian I am very proud
of my heritage and I do try to bring it
out and I teach them about it I would
say that now I've come to a place where
I am proud of it there are times when
I'm self-conscious that most of my
friends are Korean and I want to branch
out more but overall I'm very proud that
wasn't the question it was do I identify
with it and I do identify with it I
think korean-american is like a specific
community compared to Korean and the
American and I do strongly identify with
that korean-american part of me of
taking things from both sides what is
your favorite thing about being
asian-american basically what I just
said of how I can take aspects from my
Korean culture and then from the
American culture which is already like a
mishmash of a bunch of cultures and have
that be my identity I love that I can
speak Korean I love Korean food I love
visiting Korea and slowly learning more
about Korea's history because admittedly
I don't know too much about it but just
knowing the resilience of my people or
the peat my ancestors is amazing and I
love that I'm American too and that I
can claim that as my identity and I love
specifically like being from Los Angeles
and the culture that comes with that so
my favorite thing would be all the
things just being able to combine all of
that and that is what being American is
really and being asian-american that's
it for this video I hope you enjoyed and
I hope
thought you could relate to some of the
things that I was saying let me know in
the comments below if you did and I
don't know answer answer the questions
in the tag yourself - I'd love to see
your stories because this is a tag after
all I'm going to tag my friend Katie who
lives in Korea right now and we actually
met in London because she was doing an
internship there and you would have seen
her in my previous video of what I ate
in Korea she uploads vlogs and other
lifestyle content right now related to
her living in Korea but she has some
videos also from when she was in London
and things like that so do go check her
out and subscribe I'm pretty sure my
foot has just completely fallen asleep
now so thank you for watching and I will
see you in the next one bye
[Music]