hi I'm Kate Roy welcome back to my
channel as you can see I am sitting on
the floor in front of my office setup
here it's where I have been spending a
lot of time since I've started working
from home and social distancing myself
and I have a list of a few videos that I
plan to film this weekend and just when
I have time in the evenings now that I'm
not going to be going out for a little
bit I know that the assumptions tag is
pretty old the trend has kind of come
and gone but I still wanted to do it
because I do have quite a lot of new
subscribers and I don't have too many
videos that are about me so hopefully
this can help you get to know me a
little bit better before we dive in if
you want to see videos about consulting
career and travel then hit the subscribe
button as well as a notification belt so
you know when I have any video coming
out as usual I went to Instagram to get
your submissions for your assumptions
about me and I went ahead and copied
them or typed them into a note on my
phone and categorized some of them so
there were two really big themes that
came up one was around general
motivation and discipline and another
one was about school and academics and
then there were some just other
miscellaneous assumptions so the one
that had kin the most assumptions around
it was again around motivation and
discipline so you've got your
together you're diligent do you have
your life together you're a self
disciplined person you're efficient and
productive they all kind of seem to fit
in together I do feel like on the
outside it appears that way because I
also appear to be a pretty calm person
on the outside and I'm sure I've talked
about this in some videos in the past
just like in passing but I come off as a
pretty cool calm collected type of
person but I'm actually the opposite
like I'm very anxious and paranoid all
the time and always overthinking things
but I think I just do a good job at
hiding it so I feel like with that it
can appear like I have all of my ish
together all the time but I definitely
have days that I feel so unmotivated so
lazy like even last night I was like you
know what I'm gonna go to sleep early
I'm gonna wake
early go for a run I ended up watching
YouTube videos until like 1:30 a.m. and
I have not gone for a run today and it
is like 6:00 p.m. right now and I'm
filming this YouTube video when I had
ambitions to film a couple today so I
think on the whole yes I skew more
towards being pretty disciplined and
motivated but it doesn't mean that I
don't have really really off days
another assumption that's sort of
related but there's kind of an
additional assumption added on to it was
you work hard but you also earn a lot
with several OS there I mean I think on
average like if you look at the average
salary across America then sure I earn
more than average but I don't think it's
as much as some of you might think of
course what a lot of money means or what
a large salary means depends on so many
different factors I work in the states
where the standard of living and the pay
just tends to be higher in general so
there's that I also work in consulting
where the salary tends to be higher than
that of let's say teaching just as an
example but compared to some of the
people that I know I what I'm making
might have been what some people started
making when they graduated college so it
is all relative
I live comfortably and I'm able to you
know get everything that I need so I'm
not saying that I don't earn a lot in
general or had all but I maybe it's not
as high as what you're assuming so the
other big bucket of assumptions had to
do with school and academics so starting
with I think that you were an A student
in school I was before college in
college I was not an A student I got I
got better like as the semester went by
but I remember getting like a c-minus on
an English paper during my first year of
college and that was a very humbling
moment for me so I'm not like on here to
brag about anything but yes I did
try very hard at school and was able to
get good grades you know throughout high
school and all of that I don't really
think I had too much of a social life
like my social life was made up of my
extracurricular activities like swimming
and piano
things like that when I got to college I
didn't try as hard as I did in high
school
I still managed to get pretty decent
grades just was not a straight-a student
in college it was when I went to grad
school that I really tried hard and that
of course is when I really started my
channel or started uploading frequently
to my channel so I had a lot of vlogs
where I would go and study or go write
for my dissertation so I can definitely
see where that assumption comes from
this one I thought was funny I hope from
the sound of your voice
I thought you are 30 in a good way well
I am 29 so I am close to 30 and I'm
excited to be 30 so yeah I think I do
take it in a good way very conservative
I actually I struggle with this I think
I am actually socially pretty liberal I
grew up in Los Angeles which is very
diverse and also the high school that I
went to was pretty liberal and I was
part of a humanities program where we
studied philosophy art history and our
11th grade year we actually had like
units about racism sexism classism etc
so I feel like early on I was introduced
to very liberal social perspectives and
issues but I would say because of my
Korean upbringing because of course I
was raised both Korean and American I am
still conservative about other things
you're a picky eater I don't think I'm a
picky eater at all like I will try
anything once the thing that I am picky
about is that I really don't like
crustaceans
so like shrimp crab etc I'm actually not
100% sure of shrimp as a crustacean but
anyway basically things that look like
bugs in the ocean now I don't mind
having like a lobster mac and cheese or
like crab cakes or like a crab hand roll
like it's not the meat of the crustacean
or shellfish that's what shrimp is
shellfish so I know literally nobody
cares about this but I had to get to the
bottom of it so I looked up what is
considered a crustacean and it seems
like shrimp actually are considered
crustaceans so then I was like why did I
always think that
shrimp were shellfish and then I saw
that shellfish is actually an umbrella
term for a crustacean or Crustacea and
mollusks so again not that anybody cares
but just thought that I would clear that
up so I'm not spreading false
information out there about shellfish
and crustaceans because that's obviously
very important it's not the meat of it
that I don't like it's like I don't like
it when I have to freaking use like
pliers to open up my crab leg and get
like a little sliver of meat and also
with seafood and shellfish usually it's
like the butter or like the lemon or the
like Cajun seasoning that is actually
the tasty part of it so I just don't
really eat too much seafood I never
crave it but it's not like I won't eat
it it's just not gonna be my choice but
other than that I don't think I'm picky
at all I used to not like mushrooms now
I love them used to hate olives love
them so I think you know as I grew older
I acquired more tastes and became less
and less picky over time sort of on a
like related note another one was health
conscious and I in general yes I think
I'm health conscious but I there was a
period of my life where I was pretty
strict about what I ate if you look back
on my channel I have lots of vegan and
plant-based recipe videos because for
about two years maybe I was really
really into eating plant-based and Whole
Foods and all of that and that was a
great time of my life
I saved a lot of money when I was living
in London and cooking only plant-based
meals I felt great you know all of that
but it got to be a little bit difficult
to maintain which you know you could say
it's just lack of motivation or
something but I still do you know try to
be try to eat less me to try to eat less
dairy and all of that
I just don't restrict myself anymore
it's also harder you know when I travel
for work to be so you know strict with
my with my eating because you don't
always have too many options but I do my
best
I am health-conscious I do try to
exercise regularly since I grew up being
a swimmer and
late so I I do my best but it's it's not
like I don't have any like really strict
regiment regimen regimen around my diet
or my exercise that you didn't go to
church so that's actually kind of true
so I grew up when I was younger I went
to this church my family went to this
church and it was actually like almost
an hour away from our house because we
went there because it was like my
cousin's family's Church or not their
church but they attended that church so
I grew up going there from like when I
was like in first grade to like fifth
grade so let's just say through
elementary school then I started to take
too much of a toll on our family to be
going that far every single week every
single Sunday so we stopped and then
sort of like hopped around at a few
churches near where we lived but I
pretty much stopped going to church like
through middle school from middle school
through high school part of that was
it's just hard to like find a community
to fit in with I was really busy with a
lot of other things you know like
extracurriculars like I mentioned and
when I was in high school I just was
against going to church however when I
went to college I decided to join a
fellowship a church fellowship I went
with some of my friends from high school
who were in college with me who are at
Berkeley with me we decided to join a
fellowship together that's when I
started going to church again regularly
when I was in London I attended reality
Church London for my year there yeah I
go to church today I sometimes skip some
weeks when I'm traveling and it's kind
of hard to make it to service and now
that we're in this social distancing
phase I'm watching sermons via the web
so doing that on Sunday mornings as my
church you are a big Harry Potter fan
back in the day yes I was a big Harry
Potter fan back in the day and I am also
a big Harry Potter fan now when I first
read Harry Potter books 1 2 & 3 had
already come out so I actually read the
third book first and then I read the
first book and then I read the second
book and like the third book again and
then from like 4 through 7 that's when I
distinctly remember like getting the
book after the date
it was released or the day after it was
released staying up all night to read it
and then also going to watch the movies
of course and I didn't go to midnight
screenings for all of them but I
definitely did for the very last movie
so Deathly Hallows part-2 that was when
it was my senior year of college I think
and I went to a thrift store he had got
some ties for myself and for my friends
so he dressed up as Hogwarts students
for the last premiere you seem to be
very good at saving money yes so from
the first job that I had in high school
I learned to just save a portion of my
paycheck as soon as I got it before I
spent it on anything else so I still
have that habit to this day and I have a
video on how I saved fifty thousand
dollars to go to grad school in London
so I will link that in the description
box if you want to see that you have a
jet-set style of life but you find time
for friends I think this can be true
because when I have like a business trip
in a certain city and I know that I have
friends who live there then I will try
to meet up with them so if I have a
meeting in Philly then I'll meet up with
my friend who is in school there I do
try to fit friends in with business
trips specifically if I can usually most
of the time I don't have time for that
or there isn't anybody there in that
city that I would see so it doesn't
always apply it on the whole I think I'm
kind of bad at regularly keeping up with
people I just tend to be pretty
independent and I don't mind if a friend
and I haven't spoken for a long time
but then we meet up and we're able to
catch up so I'm totally fine with that
but I know some people like more regular
contact and check-ins I lean more
towards the you know catching up with
like more time in-between but with my
close friends yes I you know keep up
with them a lot more frequently but it's
just a very small circle you don't get
homesick very often I think that's
pretty true I get homesick from time to
time but not very often at all when I
was in London there were times I think
right at the beginning that I was a bit
homesick because I missed Korean food
and Mexican food but again I'm a pretty
like independent
type of person so even though I love my
family and love when I do go home
to see them I don't get too homesick
often and now because I do so much
travel you know with my job obviously
not right at this moment but in general
I get to visit home a lot so so that
helps so yeah this is another
interesting one you have anger issues or
at least used to I don't know about
anger issues but I definitely get
irritated pretty easily and I get really
upset with like inconsiderate people
with like people are like slowing other
people down like when people are being
indecisive or not like not trying to
provide a solution themselves but just
are pointing out like things that are
negative like I just I don't really like
when people are being too negative at
the same time I can be really negative
when I'm in a bad mood so I'm being a
hypocrite for sure so I wouldn't say
anger issues maybe being irritated and I
do think it's gotten better over time so
the at least used to portion of the
Assumption makes sense and the last one
here is you're a genuine person and
thank you first of all I thought it's
very kind and a really nice compliment I
do try my best to be as authentic and
genuine as possible sometimes I'm a
little too blunt
maybe so it can it can go to a negative
side sometimes this brings this one time
to mind when I was studying abroad
during college and I had my kind of
group of study abroad friends and we
were talking about what we kind of
assumed about each other when we first
met each other so like what were our
first impressions and then like what we
thought about each other now basically
like what was different about our first
impressions of each other and you know
now that we had gotten to know each
other you know what had changed and one
of my friends had told me that nothing
really had changed for me that I was
just kind of the same as when they first
met me so I hope that that's how I am
for the most part and I try to be that
way and I think most people do try to be
genuine and
Suntech so I don't think I'm anything
special for trying to do that my foot
has completely fallen asleep now I can
like not even feel the floor like I can
barely feel the floor when I'm touching
it with my foot so I think that it is
time now for me to end this video I hope
this helped you get to know me a little
bit better as always leave comments for
other things you'd like to see on this
channel because it really does help me
come up with different ideas and I
really appreciate you supporting my
channel and watching this video so with
that I will see you in the next one bye
[Music]