yay oh my god i haven't done this in so
long hi friends uh
this is new so y'all have never seen
this room before i'm actually
in my very first apartment but today's
video is going to be a ginormous winter
try clothing haul all the pieces in this
haul are actually from princess polly
you can actually satisfy all your winter
clothing needs at princess poly just
because they have such a huge variety on
winter clothing and if you want to make
some new additions to your winter
wardrobe everything is going to be
linked down below so if you want to buy
anything if you want to twin with me
links down below also have a coupon code
for y'all use my code jq20 it'll give
you 20
off your purchase and princess polly
also offers after pay so it makes it so
easy to pay for your purchase and on all
orders that are over 50
princess poly actually offers free
express shipping within the united
states so you could get your package in
like three to four business days
so quick so i'm gonna be showing y'all
some clothing pieces
okay so i guess i'm gonna start with
what i'm wearing so this top is actually
from princess paulie um
this is so comfortable it is this
beautiful like olive green color
i feel like this color really
complements tan skin especially during
the winter time like i don't know about
y'all but i get really pale so colors
like this really bring out my tan
and the melanin so i really appreciate
it this is such good quality it's really
thick material and during the winter
obviously
it gets cold so this material does keep
you warm and it's a ribbed material and
it's just like a button-down cropped
cardigan type top and i really love the
fit of this it just shapes your body
okay how am i gonna show this to y'all
let me stand up as you can see the crop
is like right under my boob
it's like just perfect to where it like
flatters your waist make me look like i
have a snatched waist so yeah it's like
one of my new favorite tops i got it in
an extra extra small and it's just
amazing and i guess i'll just show you
my sweatpants too because they are also
from princess polly these sweatpants
are so comfortable like
uh they have this like check not checker
board it's kind of like a quilted
pattern i don't know how to explain it
but it looks like these
and the texture is really cool it has a
thick waistband
so it's so comfortable and it just
cinches you in fleece sweatpants are so
baggy but this thick waistband
gives you a little bit of a shape so you
don't look too much like a
blob and it's a nice light gray color so
it goes with like
everything and it cinches in at the
ankles so it's like the typical jogger
fit it's so soft
and um i love these sweatpants so much
10 out of 10 do you recommend if you
want new sweatpants
okay next i want to show you a skirt
because um i am in love with this color
so this is the rescue me pleated skirt
and i got it in a size zero and i love
this skirt so much i actually own it in
white and i wear it
literally all the time so i decided to
pick it up in this beautiful jade
sage green color this is a really thick
material again really good for the
winter time because this will keep you
warm and it's such good quality it
stretches out the waistband so you know
you have room for a food baby
oh my god this is so adorable this is
the skirt
see it's just the cutest little pleated
skirt ever it just flares
it really makes you look like you got an
itty bitty waist it just makes me feel
so girly i love it
i feel like a princess i also decided to
pick it up in this pink color because
i love pink oh it just looks like a
little bubble gum color
okay i'm gonna try this one on okay this
is the pink one this color is so
adorable
it's the cutest bubble gum pink and
again just cinches you in
oh she's skinny okay i
recommend these skirts they also have
them in so many other colors so
might have to cop the skirt in every
other color available so since we're on
the
pink trend i'm gonna go ahead and show
you this adorable pink jumper this is
just a cropped cardigan it is really
cropped i will say that but it's such
thick material so it does still keep you
warm i actually live in texas
so we do get winter here but it's not
like the coldest of colds like it's not
like snowing like it is in new york but
it still does get pretty chilly and
where i'm at right now i'm actually in
lubbock texas because i go to school at
texas tech university
reckon but um it actually does get cold
here like
it snowed last week like what and now
it's 70 degrees outside
like i just which is why i love stuff
like this because it's cropped but it
still keeps me warm but it is just an
adorable pink color again i
freaking love pink this is the rosalie
jumper and i got it in extra small small
um hello this is literally so adorable
this is the cardigan i love how puffy
the sleeves are it is so comfortable
just so much room to breathe it has this
really beautiful
pink and white gingham gingham gingham
gingham pattern looks like a picnic
tablecloth but um i love it
also i tend to sweat when i'm cold i
sweat when i'm hot too
i just sweat armpits they get pretty
spicy but this leaves a lot of room to
breathe and it is pretty cropped but it
stays in place nothing is going to be
exposed and you can also
unclasp the buttons but i'm not going to
be doing that because that is not what
this type of video is
i'm going to put some jeans on to see
what this would look like with denim
okay these jeans are also from princess
paulie these are just the holly
asymmetrical jeans i bought these a
couple months ago with like my own money
and i've been wearing them non-stop ever
since i've gotten them but um this is
what it looks like the jeans i kind of
love this
okay so now i'm gonna try on this top
and this is the lovers thief top and i
got it in black
and it's just like a basic black crop
top with buttons
but i need a few basics for the winter
because you know how winter is all for
layering so i got this
uh let's try it on oh my god i love the
fit of this top i was scared it was
gonna be too cropped but
this what um oh you know in bahras this
is really embarrassing
anyways it's like the perfect crop so it
cuts off right around the waist area at
least for me
so it looks so flattering it has a bunch
of buttons i think i would like it
better
if it were like unbuttoned a little bit
just so it doesn't look like i'm choking
maybe like three buttons a little
scandalous
okay i like that a lot better this
material again is really thick such good
quality
i really love this this is such a good
basic top next i want to show you all
this
coat that i got or jacket what's the
difference between a coat and a jacket
is that a stupid question i don't know i
live in texas but you know
it's winter so we need jackets and coats
to keep you warm so i got this jacket
right here i got this in a size 2. i
wanted it a little bit bigger than my
normal size oh this is so
cute oh i feel bougie so what this is
the jacket it just has really neutral
colors it's a bunch of shades of brown
and then
some white in there and it's a nice
gingham pattern can you tell i
love that pattern it's a really thick
kind of like fuzzy coat i don't know if
you can see
the texture but it's really nice
again super thick this is like thick
like thick with like maybe like five c's
like this is
she's thick and it just looks like this
looks really good with
blue denim again because the colors are
so neutral it'll go with
essentially any color and they have this
jacket and a few more colors so you can
also pick it up in like a darker variety
of these shades but i personally like
really light colors so i got this one
it is a little crop but it works for me
because i'm five two
so short so like this is like normal
fitting on me but i'm assuming if you
were taller it would be more cropped
and it has pockets hello pockets just
like everything better so anything with
pockets
just like thumbs up but yes i will be
wearing this
coat a lot this winter okay and then i
got this top oh my freaking god i cannot
emphasize how
soft this is it literally feels like
what i would envision a cloud to feel
like even though we can't touch them
if you could touch clouds i feel like it
would be this texture
it's just so soft it's just a white
ribbed kind of sweater top wow this
is so comfortable i'm never taking this
off this is so comfortable
and it is like a really nice clean
bright white it looks like i'm wearing
snow
it is so soft young and it's so
form-fitting like and it just hugs your
curves correctly and it really just
flatters your figure
i have a little bit of the buttons
unbuttoned again trying to be a little
scandalous
this is just what it looks like it's
just another basic top again perfect for
layering
okay moving on i got this pair of pants
it's pink
again a checkerboard gingham pattern are
we surprised
no i will say this is a little bit of a
thinner material but i
feel like if you layer properly and wear
coat and everything this will still be
good for the winter okay let's try this
on okay so these are the pants as you
can see they fit me like
snuggly i feel like wearing these with
like black boots or even white boots
would be really pretty
like just boots in general i think pants
and boots is such an iconic combo and as
i mentioned i'm five two so i have
pretty freaking stubby short legs
so pants were a little long on me so all
i did was fold it over wow these pants
are so comfortable
i have no pants that are pink so i'm
really excited to style these honestly i
feel like this looks good together just
because there's like white in the pants
and then the white matches the white in
the top
an outfit okay and here is the last
thing i'm gonna show y'all it is another
jacket and this is a corduroy jacket so
and it buttons down
it's this nice like blushy pink color
it's more on the mauve side and it's a
little muted so i would consider this
more neutral
and this is just what it looks like i
got it in a size zero but i kind of wish
i
sized up like one more just so it'll be
a little bit more oversized
but i honestly don't mind this it's
still a really nice fit it is really
loose so it has a little bit of an
oversized feel i'm excited to style this
i feel like wearing this with a skirt
would be really cool too but honestly it
doesn't look too bad on these pants
because it's like corduroy material i
feel like this will definitely keep you
warm i'm honestly sweating right now
because it is not cold right now in
lubbock texas it's like 70 degrees this
jacket is making me sweat
but i will be wearing that when it does
get cold
okay so those are all the clothing
pieces that i have to show y'all today
but yeah just remember that if you want
to buy anything from this video
everything's linked down below and don't
forget to use my code jq20 for 20 off
but if you enjoyed this video go ahead
and give this video a thumbs up it'll
just let me know that y'all want to see
more clothing hauls and if you made it
this far into the video go ahead and
comment down below this emoji it'll just
let me know that you made it this far
it'll be a cool little exclusive club of
like two people
super exclusive and yeah if you're not
already go ahead and subscribe to my
channel it'll really help you girl out
yeah i hope you guys enjoyed this video
and i will see y'all in the next one
bye