hi friends
so this video is actually supposed to be
an entire portion in my last video which
is my quarantine glow up transformation
if you haven't seen it go ahead and
watch it but this portion of the video
actually had enough footage for me to
make a completely separate video so here
it is enjoy so here i have a variety of
different foundations that i purchased
when i thought i was a freaking makeup
guru
yeah that used to be me guys that used
to be what this channel was
these are definitely expired already and
i don't think any of these match me
so also you all know how i tanned for
this transformation well it's been like
three weeks since i tanned so i'm kind
of pale again so that's cute but
whatever
um this is definitely too dark and these
are all
too dark i'm pale damn it um
i have some lighter foundations but i
know those have mold in them i just i
know it um
[Music]
this is my favorite foundation so maybe
i don't know why i'm smelling it okay ew
it's like crusty because of like the
residue on the spout thingy like it
crusted up
oh freak i forgot a step damn it
so i have a very oily face it's very
oily it's
disgusting you could fry a freaking egg
on my face with the amount of oil that
it produces so i learned this from
another youtuber jackie i know
oh my god there's dust on this too
disgusting i used to watch her really
religiously when i was really into the
beauty community
but now it's low-key in shambles she
would always talk about this trick where
you put translucent powder on and you
set your
what is this called primer i'm such a
beauty guru anyway you would set your
primer with like translucent setting
powder in like the places that you get
oily so i get really oily
sorry a bird just flew by my freaking
attention span of a peanut got
distracted
anyway i don't even remember what i'm
saying awesome y'all i don't know
why but this part of my forehead not
even my entire forehead just the parts
above my eyebrows they're
always shiny and it pisses me off so if
you know how to fix that
let me know thanks leave it in the
comments oh i just poked my eye with my
beauty blender oh my god
okay now we can put on foundation oh my
god this clip is not holding my hair
back my hair is too
freaking thick for this clip so now i'm
going to take my beauty blender
and i know i'm talking like this i think
this is my alter ego of like my beauty
guru self i'm like channeling
my 15 year old self oh wait
loki is just my color i'm just being off
the dramatic because like loki's might
be my color
whoa cool awesome i'm just gonna
pat this into my face so i can have an
overall
even complexion i really hope
i don't i feel like i say this now and
i'm like manifesting it into the
universe and now it's gonna happen
i love my paranoid minds um i really
hope my
face doesn't break out from this
definitely expired foundation
oh my god where my foundation covers up
my five o'clock shadow
from my thick mustache that grows on my
face wow should i wear foundation every
day what the heck
oh my god my skin tone looks so even i
love this
why don't i wear foundation more often
what the heck but i don't really like
putting foundation on my forehead
don't like that feeling okay do i need
to like blend it down to my neck
i just i don't feel like doing that
so yeah i don't want to do that okay now
we get to put on some concealer
where's my concealer oh
jessica being dramatic part 592. wow is
this sponsored by nars my foundation was
nars my concealer is nars you just could
just get cute for 20
of your purchase i wish no nars doesn't
even know who i
am
put some on my forehead cover up that
scar that i created on my face when i
was one years old
time to blend it out ew i saw myself in
the viewfinder and
my face when i blend out she's ugly
oh my god oh my gosh i forgot how good
concealer is what the heck
i look so awake right now and it's crazy
because i don't even know why i have
bags under my eyes because i'm like a
grandma and i go to bed at like 9 30 p.m
i get eight hours of sleep every night
but for some reason these bags decided
to show up on my face
love that basically what i'm getting
from this is that i need to start
wearing makeup again because this is fun
what the heck and the thing is i used to
be so good at makeup i would do
eye shadow looks that look like they
were done by okay maybe i'm giving
myself way too much credit but from what
i remember
i think i was pretty good at makeup told
me to do my own horn and now however
comma i do not possess those skills
i'm gonna try to like pat that into my
face my face looks like it doesn't have
any blemishes on it that's crazy
i'm gonna put some blush on because i
freaking love blush haven't been able to
wear it as of recently
because corona has led us all to wear
masks all the time so what is the point
of wearing my beautiful glossier cloud
paint i watched this
youtube video the other day it was so
random because i have been watching
stephanie sue
so religiously so like all my
recommendations is all stephanie sue and
like some bts and some like twice videos
and then there was this one makeup video
it was like talking about placement of
your blush and i always put my blush
here on my cheeks but i have a very
round face so that's probably
not the most optimal way of putting on
my blush because it probably makes the
face look rounder
person in the video said to like place
it on like your cheekbones so it'll like
snatch your face and make it look more
like angular and structured you put it
like right here like where
you typically put highlight she like
blended it out
to like the contours of her face but i
just i'm the type of person that just
really likes putting blush like
everywhere so this is probably going to
end up on the rest of my face but right
now we're going to try the whole angular
type of vibe see it already ended up
like on my under eye i just can't help
it it's in my nature to put blush
everywhere does that look any different
does my face look lifted
probably not definitely put too much
oh my gosh low-key freaking out oh my
gosh
now i'm gonna put it on my nose because
i freaking love that look
it looks like i got punched in the face
okay anyway we're just gonna move on
just gonna move on oop that
i did not blend that one oh this is okay
the more i touch my face the more i do
wrong so i'm just gonna i probably need
to wash your makeup brushes too there's
like dust all over them
too
cute oh my god i look like a cutesy
little doll
i love blush
eyebrows and mascara i feel like those
are the two things that really
transform my face the most i'm gonna
shut up so i can focus on my eyebrows
now
okay
yay oh my god i feel pretty i love when
i do my eyebrows i
coco i don't know where my dog is y'all
i'm home alone right now
and my dog keeps disappearing and it's
scaring the out of me
coco okay i remember when i used to wear
makeup a lot i took a lot of pride in my
highlight because i used to have really
good cheekbones um
they're still there but now i have this
layer of fat over them so that's fun
shout out birth control oh my god i
remember i used to use this palette a
lot and i did a review on this palette
on my channel hi guys it's me jessica
and welcome to another video on my
channel i'm going to be filming my first
impressions
on the anastasia glow kit sweets palette
it was a little baby
dang i need to buy a new bronzer soon i
hit pan on it i've gone through this
bronzer
so many times because i love it oh my
god it's another nars product
sponsor me okay i think i'm gonna do the
eye look that i used to always do
alexa play how you like that by
blackpink
blackpink on amazon music
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah um this is turning out disgusting
this is so sad it looks so gross
okay i'm really sad with how my eye
makeup turned out
um i have never been the biggest fan of
like
lipsticks and stuff like that like i'd
buy them but i realized like i just
don't like the way that they look on my
lips i'm just gonna add a little bit of
lip gloss
yay oh my gosh i have a full face of
makeup on i did not put on lashes
however come on i did not put on lashes
because i don't know
if it's like my eye shape or i'm really
just uncoordinated but i cannot
put lashes on my eyes they don't look
good
i just don't think like they fit my eye
shape i'm just really unskilled in the
area of putting on false lashes so i've
never been able to live out my dream of
being an abg
um but yay we're done with the makeup
i'm gonna go ahead and put on a cute
outfit we're gonna take some pics
and we're going to be done with a
transformation
okay so that's the end of the video i
hope you all enjoyed and if you want to
see the rest of my transformation i'll
be linking it down below but yeah give
this video a thumbs up it'll help you
girl out subscribe to my channel it'll
also help you girl out yeah i hope you
guys enjoyed this video and i will see
y'all in the next one bye