[Music]
hello everyone
and welcome back to the inner thoughts
podcast this is your host abigail
and today's episode is another solo
episode
and i wanted to talk about something
that might be a little bit controversial
for those who don't really
know me beyond surface level because
this inspirational kind of subject came
from i have to give a little backstory
so
basically i did not go to church on this
particular saturday because i had worked
the night before and i was really tired
but unfortunately i missed a really good
afternoon program in which
they kind of sought like inspiration
from one of those jubilee videos if
you've ever seen
it's like they get a group of people and
then they ask them a certain question
and then they have to line up on a
certain line which is like agree
somewhat agree neutral
disagree somewhat disagree something
like that right and so they did it with
some youth
in our church and they asked them a
couple questions
and they only asked them four because
there was like a ton of them
and they had to like expound their
thoughts
so i think there was actually originally
supposed to be ten questions so
i only have the four that they asked at
that time and i'm going to answer it
myself
but if they do a part two which is most
likely going to happen i will definitely
like do a part two of like this episode
because i think like these topics are
very interesting to talk about
so let's get started i know it's gonna
be quite
short but i think it'll be okay i'll try
my best to expound as much as i can to
fill up the 30 minute mark of a podcast
but at the same time
of course if it's like short then it's
okay too so let's get started
so the first one is i like christian
music
so i don't know where to stand on this
one because i think
when you ask that kind of question like
christian music that is a very broad
you know kind of genre you can even say
religious music is a broad genre because
you can have like traditional hymns you
can have christian pop
rock you can have gospel you can have
worship
so i guess i can go into how i feel
personally about those
four categories that i just said within
christian music
so let's start with hymns which is
something i'm more
of used to i guess because i grew up
with that and i
am okay with it you know i like hymns i
like playing them every now and then
when i don't have anxiety on the piano
but do i go out of my way to listen to
it i do not
only like on sabbath of course when i'm
at church and you know doing things
there then i will listen to it like
obviously
but i don't go out of my way like during
the week to do like listen to it
which honestly is kind of like a guilt
thing but
you know i just don't you know it's just
a thing that i don't gravitate
fully towards you know and it's kind of
sad because usually like
you should be listening to you know that
kind of music like it not
should just not be on the sabbath you
know you should you know if you want to
listen throughout the weekend
throughout the week but personally for
me i don't gravitate towards
you know going out of my way to listen
to it but i have no problem with it i
like it that's what i'm used to
and now we go into worship music
and so i am like generally okay with it
and i guess you could like say
worship and pop rock christian are kind
of together
i'm generally okay with it although it's
kind of awkward
because i noticed that when i used to go
to university you know
back in america in a private university
and they would sing these kinds of songs
and
i don't know these songs and it's like
they kind of assume that people do or
they kind of introduce it and it's like
they're singing it gets really awkward
because they're singing
like their ad-libs or whatever so you
don't really know what the real
tune is of the song so it's like kind of
awkward but nevertheless i like it you
know
i like the ambiance of it um sometimes
more than traditional hymns like i have
no problem with it although
and this might get me in trouble with
some friends that are into that kind of
genre music
i don't like the drums thing because
it's a little bit too
loud and something i'm just not
particularly used to because it sounds
like a rock concert in a sense
and i know that's such like a
traditional
christian kind of viewpoint but that's
just personally me
i have no problem with the genre it's
just like sometimes the drums is a
little bit too much that i'm like
ah this is kind of odd but you know it's
something i'm getting
used to because more recently within the
past one or two years
our youth have actually started singing
these songs more in the worship services
if you guys have seen my vlogs like
usually i would vlog like every saturday
and you can see
like they're actually doing it and i'm
okay with it but i know that some church
members are still not okay with it
because
it's either like a message or the song
or just the progression of it
sounding like you know not what they're
traditionally used to which is hymns
but in my thinking i guess i didn't
really answer the hymns part
i when i say i like hymns i would say
like strongly agree i guess
and then pop rock worship christian
music
i would be like i guess neutral
to like somewhat agree like in that
little bit of there
it's just like certain aspects like the
drums or just you know the message of
the song maybe not
sounding so near and
dear to the heart of god rather than you
know something else
like the message can be conveyed as
something else i guess and then the
drums thing which i said like it's
something i'm still getting used to
um i don't necessarily agree with it but
that's just personal taste
so there's that and i guess you could
say the last one which is gospel music
now we don't really have those i have
been to churches where that's like the
predominant
you know type of music that they sing i
have no problem with it
i you know like the ambience of it
because everyone's singing and things
like that
although i will say and i can say this
for christian pop rock and sometimes
worship music
sometimes the interlude is so long that
like song service is like
15 minutes long and you know what i
shouldn't like
feel like this because you know we're
praising god things like that but
sometimes it's so long that i'm like
kind of okay like let's just go we're
just
waiting for the sermon kind of thing
like let's keep moving
so that's my only thing but otherwise
like i think
like gospel music is so beautiful i love
the harmonies i love the praise
like aspect of it like yes like work
like it's so
like you just feel so good after
listening to it and everyone's like
kind of like you know it's like a
community like
kind of singing and rejoicing together
it's just so beautiful so
i guess for gospel music
i'll put somewhat agree so you can say
in the genre of
christian music if i like it or not i'll
take the medium answer and it's
somewhat agreed that i like it so
there's that
i hope that was not too long i think it
was because it's already seven minutes
all right second question my parents are
always
right obviously this is a
hard disagree because we're all humans
we make mistakes you know
and one of the kids actually said like
they disagree because you know sometimes
their parents say things and they're not
true
like hey go get my wallet it's like
on the dining room table but it's
actually not it's in your purse in the
car where you are you just didn't bother
to look so obviously you're not always
right it's like
things like that and it's so true
because like usually when you think
if my parents are always right you're
thinking of like kind of like an
abstract kind of view right
like they're telling you this and that
and you're thinking oh yeah they are
always right when they tell me what to
do or some things but
the thing is with parents and i guess
like humans in general we're always
learning every day right we always make
mistakes every day
so it's not always right
like they're not always gonna be right
and that's
life that's how things are um obviously
your parents
or my parents i will say are right in
some degree
with like you know their life decisions
or the advice they can give me and the
knowledge that they know but it's not
always always right like i feel like
always when you say always it's
a very big superlative and that's
definitely not true
so i will definitely say that it's a
hard disagree that they are not always
right because like i said
usually when i think of that question i
think like if i have to like do
something for my parents
and they're telling me to do a certain
thing like for example like
fix a computer issue they're going to be
like no it's this i'm like no
it's obviously not you guys don't know
how to do it i know how to do it
so this is how you do it so it's not
always right however i will say
with certain things like obviously
nursing because they come from a nursing
background with parents
they're always right or almost always
right with you know some things in their
knowledge because they've been nurses
for years so i feel like
if you're like an expert on something
then yeah you're gonna be
almost always right or somewhat always
right but not necessarily
always always always so in the end it's
a hard disagree that
your parents are always right but you
will have to agree that there are times
that they
are somewhat right so
in the end i will say somewhat discreet
it's just like going around around but
that's how i feel i guess and the number
third one is
god loves everyone equally i will
definitely say
strongly strongly agree now people will
disagree
and they can like look in the bible and
things like that and say like
well how come this person went through
this like jonah and the whale
or joseph like you know getting sold by
his brothers and things like that or
like other
people who have like perfect lives you
know
but it's more for me i think
god loves us all equally right but there
is a point in our lives
that god puts us through tests and
it might happen to you now it might
happen to you later
you know for example at the time i'm
recording this i had a really bad night
you know for a shift like i just wanted
to go
i wanted to leave as soon as possible
and once i gave report i was out the
building
and you know it was a really hard night
but i am still thankful that i made it
through and
god blessed me in the end because worser
things could have happened but we made
it through
and there are some days that i have the
best day and the calmest patients in the
world
and there are some days like this where
everything's just going wrong
and wrong every single hour of the night
and i don't know what to do with myself
but am i gonna blame god for that
absolutely not because i know in the end
there is always a light at the end of
the tunnel
and i am grateful for the things that he
has given me
and i know like my life i could say
for the most part has been quite good
and i am very blessed
to have the life that i have now have i
had like really hard struggles
of course everybody has them that's part
of
life and the life that god gives us you
know he
like i said before puts us through these
trials you know to test us
to test our willpower and our trust in
him and
you know other people start off their
life really really bad but in the end
you know later down their life maybe if
they trust in god more like
you know and help themselves as well you
know maybe they can go off to a better
future
you know because in like in life i feel
like god blesses you so much
the fact that your life is already a
blessing so you should be ready thankful
for that
but you know god blesses us
but at the same time if we don't like
help ourselves like how is he gonna
bless you right
like i'll say for example i talk like my
dad because i'm
rambling so much but i'm also trying to
make that 30 minute mark
but anyways so for example i'll say
you know it took me two years to pass my
nclex right and it was not an easy road
if you guys have watched my video i kind
of like talked about my backstory about
like not doing so well in school and not
taking things seriously but like
somehow making it and then like when i
come here
you know like i realized like well
there's really nothing to work
for like you know in school like there's
always like a new deadline and things
like that but
in real life after graduation you are
the one making your own deadlines in a
sense right
so my deadline was to you know
pass my nclex and start my job start my
career and start my life
so what did i have to do i had to start
working for it but
i was under the promotion i mean i
i trusted god but at the same time like
i i've doubted him a lot because i'm
like
you know i'm just kind of doing this
test especially my first one like
whatever
like i'll be okay and i knew i wasn't
gonna pass but i still
did it anyway i don't even know why and
i did it and i was crying and the second
and third
same thing you know did it didn't really
do my part still crying incessantly and
then i
came to the realization which i wish i
kind of had more realizations like this
in other aspects of my life and maybe i
will in the future you know
god's not gonna bless you if you also
don't put in your
due work as well you know because god
gave us wisdom he gave us willpower
so i put in my work and i really trusted
him
although there was a little bit of doubt
because i you know i'm a
terrible test taker with anxiety and
didn't
you know try my best so i felt like
whatever
like i'm just gonna go with the flow
right but in the end god bless me and i
was really shocked but also like so
absolutely thankful like had i not
trusted him
with my life in that moment or for that
past couple of
months studying what he had blessed me
with his uncles did i deserve it
you know probably not because i didn't
do my job
so when i feel like when people say just
like i'll do everything kind of thing
that puts a lot on him but it's also
like you need to do your job too you
know what i mean
but back to the topic of like god loves
everyone equally
it kind of like relates because like god
loves me so much
that he you know blessed me with this
career
but he also gave me the wisdom and he
loves me to bless me with that wisdom
so i could work hard and get what i want
because you know
i trust him so much and with that trust
and love
comes like great rewards so i am
absolutely thankful for all of that so
yeah
even though some people's lives might be
the best but there are rocky roads
always like it's not always like a
yellow paved road like a sweet
ride up to the top right there's always
gonna be something that's gonna
make your life hard but that doesn't
mean that god doesn't love you you know
like
jonah he was stuck in the whale didn't
want to prophesy
to other people you know he still
trusted god and
you know things worked out for him job
too i think job is like
a perfect example for that and people
try to tear them down and say your life
sucks like why don't you just like you
know
dismiss god or whatever because he's
obviously like doing all these terrible
things to you but you know in the end
things got better right so i think
god loves us all equally strongly agree
you just got to put your trust on him
and see where he takes you but also do
your part in the relationship
too because a relationship is a two-way
street it's not just one person putting
in 100 of the work you got to put in the
work too
so yeah and then the last question
is i would date someone not my religion
i feel like i have talked about this
with people
so much and
it's quite a controversial topic for a
lot of people in
my religion and i guess maybe other
religions too because obviously
when you think of marriage you would
want to be on the same boat right you
want
someone to have the same ideas with you
and more so
your children in the future like for
example i have a lot of relatives and
friends too that the husband and wife
are two different religions and the
children
are kind of confused on what to believe
in because their parents are strong in
their beliefs but they couldn't come to
a compromise per se
and i never want to have that i mean to
be honest i am
a product of parents with two different
religions but
my mom ended up converting you know to
my dad's religion which is how we all
grew up
but actually in the marriage very early
on
even like past i was born like maybe
four or five i think
my mom would say that my dad was
generally okay with things but at the
same time he was kind of like
as long as you don't eat you know things
you're not supposed to eat in front of
the kids
it's fine so they won't get confused
right so my mom would have to like sneak
off and like hang out with friends and
do what she wanted to do kind of thing
but she didn't want to live like that
so she ended up you know converting well
actually what also happened was my dad
and her had to talk about it whoever can
kind of like
convert the other person better you know
kind of
wins the argument that sounds really bad
but it's kind of like
if you were so strong in your beliefs
you would fight
to be the same as your partner kind of
things so
i guess it's kind of like that but for
me
i guess because seeing like a product of
my parents and other
like strong marriages with you know
husband and wife being two different
ones and hopefully converting i would
hope to be the same
which is why i'm like somewhat open
to like date people who are not the same
religion as me because
i feel like i have grown so much in
learning about my religion and knowing
what i personally believe it and not
just
what i grew up with based on what my
parents believe in and kind of
like you know being in the same mindset
as them like believing what they believe
in
and for their reasons but no like
discovering it myself
and really taking it to home and
understanding
like what i believe in in this religion
like certain things like that especially
like diet is like the biggest thing in
you know my religion so um i
do not mind entertaining other people
because
i feel like when i meet guys that are in
the same religion me
or have met it's either they're super
conservative
or they're super liberal like there's no
in between like
i want to go to church every single
saturday but you're also gonna catch me
at a bts concert because i like them
or like any korean concert you know what
i mean it's like things like that like
you gotta have it like a little leeway
but honestly
sometimes i think about how there's
someone in the same religion as me
because like maybe they're there for me
because they're waiting for me to you
know submit my life and change
my way of living for god so i don't know
it's kind of like that too but
as of right now i am very open to the
fact of it
and i'm also thinking about like in the
future like
maybe that other person that other
religion is waiting for me
to change their life and to bring them
closer to god
not that they're not closer to god but
like you know like something
else and i feel like like i said before
like i
am quite strong enough to kind of
convince them to go my way but obviously
like it's not gonna work it's not gonna
work
um but also if it does happen i mean i
hope we would come to a compromise of
things happening
especially with the intention of
marriage like i was thinking before
that i wanted to date only for the sole
intention of marriage but i feel like
that's cutting a lot of people off
because
obviously marriage is such a big thing
especially if you're meeting someone
that
only has the attention of it so i don't
mind
i guess entertaining is a wrong word but
like meeting people and getting to know
people who are different religions as me
or
maybe not a religion but you know i
don't think there's anything wrong with
that
and you know who knows because i could
be a blessing in their life
but i'm definitely not opposed to it
because i feel like if you're
only like looking at your own religion
you are really closing off
some like good people out there whose
maybe it might be the one for you if
you're not closing yourself off to only
one demographic you know so
it's kind of like that but again like i
would say
i somewhat to strongly agree that i
would date someone
not my religion because i want to be
more open-minded you know
especially when i went to the
philippines i met so many people that
even though i went to a private
university of my religion
i met so many people of different
denominations that it kind of opened my
mind to different things
so i feel like after that experience and
coming from
a place that was only people i met were
solely my religion
it was so nice it was like a breath of
fresh air to meet new people
and to you know learn about a lot of
things
so it just opened my mind better and
made me happy to know
you know there's actually like sometimes
better people out there
than people you meet only in your own
religion and sometimes i feel kind of
bored
like what i said before with the men
i've met in my own religion because they
could either be really toxic which
some of them were and some of them were
kind of like
like kind of like too good for you and
kind of suffocating because of the way
they live and
you they look at you and they're like
ugh you kind of like that
makes you look like a bad you know
christian kind of thing so i felt like
insecure feeling like that so i guess
that's why i was like
i have like now the mindset of like
being open to people from other
religions but
yeah i would say strongly agree that i
would date someone not very religious
when it comes to marriage i'm still
not quite sure of that i think from what
i've been saying before that i'm leaning
more towards the
i would rather have someone of the same
religion but if it doesn't work out the
way and the one that's meant for me is
not my religion
i would hope that we'd come to a
compromise somehow and
more so on the i really would
like to convert him to mine but
obviously if it doesn't work out then it
doesn't work out
and we have to compromise somehow
because it's going to be hard so
i think that was all the questions i
really drew it out because
i felt like it was going to be so like
short
with all my discussions but to recap
i like christian music i went through
all the subcategories but the median
answer was somewhat agree
my parents are always right disagree god
loves everyone equally
strongly agree and i would date someone
not my religion strongly agree
so with that there will be a part two
eventually
when they decide to do it again i did
say
like if they will do it again i would do
it like in person and live because i
will not miss the afternoon program this
time but
if they don't and they do it again
online then i will answer the questions
again on another podcast episode but i
hope you guys enjoyed it and gained some
insight of me as a person in terms of my
religion
and kind of you know understand what i'm
coming from and maybe you can relate to
it
and you know if you want to answer these
questions yourself and let me know of
your answers and we can have
a nice healthy discussion about it you
know because maybe there's like an
opinion i haven't heard
but i'm also open to hearing just let me
know in the comments down below or
you can personal message me i guess so
yeah
i guess this was gonna be it for this
episode thank you guys so much for
listening and i will see you next time
goodbye
you